<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:41:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman’s Engagements with Tunisian Government Officials and Civil Society Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-of-state-wendy-shermans-engagements-with-tunisian-government-officials-and-civil-society-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman held a virtual meeting with Tunisian Prime Minister Hichem Mechichi to discuss the U.S.-Tunisian bilateral relationship. They discussed promoting democracy, protecting human rights, addressing economic challenges, and working together to respond to the COVID-19 global pandemic. Deputy Secretary Sherman also met virtually with women leaders from Tunisian civil society and spoke with Tunisian media professionals. In her meetings, Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated the United States’ unwavering support to the Tunisian government and the Tunisian people at a crucial time in the country’s democratic transition 10 years after the revolution. The United States views Tunisia as a partner of choice, grounded in our shared commitment to democratic values, and to promoting regional security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman held a virtual meeting with Tunisian Prime Minister Hichem Mechichi to discuss the U.S.-Tunisian bilateral relationship. They discussed promoting democracy, protecting human rights, addressing economic challenges, and working together to respond to the COVID-19 global pandemic. Deputy Secretary Sherman also met virtually with women leaders from Tunisian civil society and spoke with Tunisian media professionals. In her meetings, Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated the United States’ unwavering support to the Tunisian government and the Tunisian people at a crucial time in the country’s democratic transition 10 years after the revolution. The United States views Tunisia as a partner of choice, grounded in our shared commitment to democratic values, and to promoting regional security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Youth Moderated Discussion on Democracy and Human Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-youth-moderated-discussion-on-democracy-and-human-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p>Chief of Mission Residence</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Hello, everyone. We are live on – with Antony Blinken, the new Secretary of State of the Biden administration. Hello, Mr. Secretary of State. You are the voice of America in the world. You are actually on an official visit in Europe. You met German Chancellor Angela Merkel and you are going to meet French President Macron in a moment.</p>
<p>We are going to talk about several topics – the threats against democracy, police violence, climate, and racism. And to talk about this, we have 34 young people we invited to have a discussion with you. So you will answer their questions. But I’m talking to you, watching live. You can ask your questions in the comments section and we will try to relay a few of those. My phone is here and I’m reading the comments.</p>
<p>But first of all, Mr. Secretary of State, we will be able to have this discussion in French because you lived in France for a few years, correct?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Indeed, I moved to France when I was nine. I used to live in New York. I lived here for nine years. I graduated high school here in Paris. I came back to Paris a couple years later to work. And I have friendships that started in school that are lasting, that have lasted over 50 years.</p>
<p>I’m delighted to be here to talk with all of you here today and those who are on the network. There’s an important reason why I wanted to have a dialogue such as this one. I believe that we’re faced with a challenge and also an opportunity. We’ll have to strengthen the links between our countries, and this will be done through you, whether it is through direct contact or on social media. You will be the ones who will build this partnership for the new generation. In my opinion, this is more important than ever. Our history is long-lasting, but it is particularly important today.</p>
<p>I think back to the challenges that we’re facing today, issues that affect all of our lives: the pandemic, COVID, the climate challenge, the impact of technology, new technology just as we’re seeing today. This impact can be good but not always – just like any topic that has an impact on your lives. And what we can see is that whether it is in France or in the U.S., a country that acts alone does not have the ability to face challenges on its own. And that goes for opportunities as well. We cannot build a wall high enough, we cannot build a solid wall to stop this from happening.</p>
<p>More than ever, I think that today there is a need for us to find a way to cooperate between countries so that we can work and act together. This ability is made possible by the ties that link our countries through our mutual values. And those relationships are living. The relationships are made by artistic pursuits, and by trade, and by working individuals. So for me, this is also an opportunity to listen to you, and to see what is important to you, and how you’re seeing the future of our relationships and of our ability to work together.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) We are getting many questions in the comments. It’s true that you are lucky enough to be with us today, but us French still cannot go to the U.S. So one question: When will the borders reopen?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I cannot give a date but I hope it will be soon. As we do in democracies, we have set up a working group with the EU in order to come back again to this freedom of travel. But we must be guided by science, by the experts in the medical field. We shouldn’t take political decisions, but decisions based on facts and data. I hope this will be very soon. We really want this. I hope it will be in the coming weeks, not months.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Yes, what would be the timeline? Can we imagine going to the U.S. during this summer for holidays?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I hope so. I cannot provide a date. But we must be careful. We are seeing that we think we’re – we have security, but then there is a new variant of the virus spreading. We see this in certain European countries. We have that same variant, the Delta variant in the U.S. So we really have that desire to reopen quickly, but this needs to be based on facts and science.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Maybe there will be criteria for vaccinated people?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) The experts are looking into it. I think there are different possibilities. I don’t want to talk too much about this. This is not my area of expertise. But I want to tell you that we are very actively working on this because we want to find a way to reopen further.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) People are very impatient around this. And let us now turn to the audience and give the floor to the youth. First question from Fatima, from the south. She’s 18 years old. A question around the importation of the racial issue into France.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) Hello. Thank you for listening to me. Xenophobia and racism are on the rise on both sides of the Atlantic. What are the reasons, and how does the U.S. face such violence?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Yes, this is the main topic these days, one of the main topics, unfortunately. We have this experience and we witness this here, too. And there are some very substantial issues that are hard to face. For instance – we could speak about it for an hour or two. For instance, we talk about the role of media and social media. A little time ago in France and the U.S., there was almost a monopoly of the media; there were big groups controlling the media, three main channels, a few national newspapers like <em>The New York Times</em>, and everybody got their information through those channels. And now, in the past 10 to 15 years, we have seen more democracy or information media being larger, but this also creates issues because there is no middle man anymore to check or limit access. Because we deeply believe in freedom of expression, but in the past when there was some excess or exaggeration, we could do something. But now with social media and the large platforms, they are not based on the same law than newspapers, for example. So that’s a question.</p>
<p>So how can we manage this without restricting freedom of expression? That’s an issue. But there are some deeper issues as well, and we are also witnessing in our societies issues with people that are left behind. These people don’t feel like they are being heard, that they are seen, and that people are taking care of them. And sometimes they express this issue, unfortunately, through hatred and even through violence. And we need to look into this as well.</p>
<p>But ultimately, most importantly, we must be able to respond to this and not accept such actions, such expressions, and this starts with national leaders but it’s not enough; this must also come from the society as a whole, and I hope from your generation. Because what we’re seeing – and that’s what makes it difficult these days – if you look at progress over the past 15 or 20 years, there is clearly progress in terms of security, opportunities, and even tolerance. And those of your generation are much more tolerant than my generation. So you need to speak out, to say what is acceptable and what is not. And in a democracy, we need to listen to you. And this speech, this way to speak on social networks, is also very important, and we must listen to those voices as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE</strong>: An opportunity to speak about social media, let me remind you, we are with Antony Blinken, Secretary of State.</p>
<p>In a year, there will be elections in France. Regardless of the result, will you keep the same relationship with France?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I don’t want to speak about French politics. But I can tell you that for a long time now, regardless of the government – in the U.S. or in France – we have acted together, we continue to do so, and as long as we work based on the same values, which is the link between us. The question is: Should Marine Le Pen be elected in 2022? I don’t want to speak on assumptions. I am very much focused on the present time, on now, and we are working remarkably with France.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Lea from Bordeaux has a question, has to do with the defiance towards politicians.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) Conspiracy theories are prospering in the U.S. Does – do you think that you can regain the confidence of citizens in the face of this growing defiance?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) This is a key question, indeed. The answer is fairly simple, in a way, even though it’s difficult to implement. There is a democratic depression that has lasted for 10 years, or even 15. We’re seeing a democratic withdrawal, so to speak, in most countries, including the most democratic ones. And it is very clear there is a lack of confidence, sometimes in democracy itself. And the answer is to show that democracies can deliver for their citizens and for the citizens around the world outside of those countries. So that is the challenge of our time, to show that democracies can act, and act in such a way as to improve the living conditions of our citizens. If we do this, and we yield results, and if the large majority of our citizens can see progress, and if their governments can take into account their wants and needs, I believe that we will see a new wave of support for the system.</p>
<p>However, if this does not happen, the crisis that is ongoing at the moment runs the risk of getting worse. And I’ll get – go back to what I said earlier: We will be more efficient in terms of yielding results if we work jointly, if countries work together, and if we cooperate within countries also. A government is not enough. Most of the problems that we’re facing require a response from the government, of course, but also from the – from civil society, from the private sector, from NGOs and so forth, more than ever. Those of us who work within government have an obligation to broaden the way we work. It is not enough to work amongst ourselves or with other governments. We need to focus on other ways and means, and to make sure that others are heard, and take part in the creation of our approaches. If we succeed, I think we will see a new impetus for democracy.</p>
<p>But the question that we are seeing now in autocracies is, well, we have a better capacity to act in an efficient manner to fulfill the needs of our people, and democracies are collapsing. Well, our job is to show that it is quite the contrary.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) You were talking about social media and freedom of speech; there’s a question here. Trump was banned from Facebook; do you believe that this is against freedom of speech?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I don’t want to speak on this, to this particular matter involving the president, President Trump. We talked about this briefly earlier; there is a challenge in the – indeed, that is very difficult to tackle, that has to do with balancing freedom of speech on social media. Where does the responsibility lie? Is it with the government? Is it with the platforms themselves? How do we manage this while maintaining this principle of freedom of speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So what is your position on this?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Personally, I’m leaning in favor of freedom of – the freedom of speech, and I think we should fight against bad ideas with good ideas. But I’d be the first to admit that this is not so simple.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So in the case of Donald Trump, the fact that it is a private company that says, well, this person can no longer speak out, isn’t this sort of a democratic issue?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Well, yes, indeed, it is a democratic issue at stake here, but in our constitutional system the government overall does not have the right to restrain people’s freedom of speech. It’s different for a private company. They have more of a margin, constitutionally speaking. But this being said, the principle remains fundamental.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So does this mean that we need a reform?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Well, once again, this is above my pay grade. I’m in charge of working on managing foreign policy, but as a citizen, as an American citizen and as a citizen of the world, since social media is a world in and of itself, I believe that we need to find a way to manage this issue with the utmost respect for freedom of speech.</p>
<p>At the same time, when it comes to social media, it’s a little bit simplistic to say, “Well, social media is just here to assure technical support; we’re not in charge of the editorial content, and we’re not responsible.” In my opinion, this is going a bit too far. The way the conversation is managed, with the algorithms that are used, all of this has a profound impact on content and on what people see and listen on social media, and what they don’t see or don’t hear on social media. I believe that social media companies need to assume part of the responsibility. When the government enters this realm, then there are regulations involved, and sometimes it can go a bit too far. It’s best to get your results that will come out of the social media themselves.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) We have a question from Laura.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) Recently on American bases, certain flags have been banned, including the Confederate flag, seen as racist. This new ban also includes the LGBT flag. Does this ban send an alarming message?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I’m responsible for the Secretary of State, and we have now the possibility for each embassy or each head of mission to show the flag, including the LGBTQ flag. This decision was made a few months ago. With regards to our diplomatic foreign missions, this is part of the scope of responsibility of our ambassadors. I cannot speak in the name of our colleagues from the Department of Defense or Pentagon. They have had a rule for a long time now that says that the only flag outside of the American flag that can be shown is the one that is a symbol of the American soldiers that are combat.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) We have now a question from Jean around the Uyghurs. He’s 17, coming from Maubeuge in the north.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) The U.S. have been mobilized against the violations of the Uyghurs’ rights in China. You, for instance, banned cotton importations from Xinjiang. Are these restrictions enough?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) That’s an excellent question. And one could answer no, because if the result is not here – that is, stopping the abuse against the Uyghurs – one could say that this is not enough, because what matters is the result. That being said, there are two important aspects when we witness human rights violations, including such serious violations as seen in Xinjiang. We need to at least speak out; not only speak out but taking action with the available means. And in that regard, we shouldn’t be complicit with this situation, hence, the idea of trying to make sure that products that are made with the workers in Xinjiang cannot be imported. And we must also make sure that our countries do not export technologies to China, technologies that could be used to control those communities.</p>
<p>But it’s more complicated than this. I am – I admit that sanctions are an important tool, but it can also have perverted consequences. For instance, if because of those sanctions the life of those we’re are trying to help gets worse because they are not able to make a living or they do not have access to certain products, including humanitarian products, we must raise that question and we must look into the issue specifically and always ask ourselves the question: Does our action overall have a positive or a negative impact?</p>
<p>But with the current situation, which is ongoing right now in Xinjiang against the Uyghurs, we should at least as an international community to shed a light on what is happening, to clearly speak out and say this is not acceptable, and through sanctions, to try at least to pressure those who are leading such policy, change their policy.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Well, actually, we’ve heard that those sanctions might not be efficient, so how far are the U.S. ready to go on this issue?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) I don’t want to get into hypotheticals. The situation is ongoing and what we’ve seen over the last few months is that more and more countries are speaking out and acting together, including by way of coordinated sanctions.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Some people are saying maybe it’s not going as far as it should because you’re in the face of China; it’s a large economic power, while the reality is that we cannot avoid China, it’s the reality.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) At various levels we need to engage with China and I hope that this engagement can lead to a policy change, but at the same time, we are using the tools at our disposal to try and show that the policy carried out by the Chinese Government has a cost for China itself as well in terms of their political and diplomatic isolation, and also a cost that could potentially be economic as well.</p>
<p>On various challenges and issues, the reality is that there is rarely – sometimes there is, but there’s rarely an easy and quick answer as if you were just flipping on a switch. It just doesn’t work that way.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) So we answered the questions by those who asked about this – many people asked. Don’t hesitate to ask your questions, we will ask them. We will now be giving the floor to Safwan (ph), who is 17 years old and who is from (inaudible) in the Paris region.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Via interpreter) In May, you went to Israel and to the West Bank. How can the U.S. – or how do the U.S. intend to work towards peace in the region?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) This is a question that is timely today that we could have also asked last year, five years ago, 10 years ago, 15 years ago – the question doesn’t go away, because the solution is still not there. At first, we had a major issue, the conflict in Gaza. We wanted to put an end to violence as soon as possible, which is what we did. Lots of damage, lots of human loss, but the violence did end and at the moment there are immediate challenges with humanitarian assistance for those who live in Gaza, but there’s also a need to reconstruct Gaza. All of this is ongoing at the moment.</p>
<p>Avoiding in the days, weeks, and months to come any type of provocation or sticking points that could give way to new bouts of violence is another focus of ours, and we also want to work on establishing more confidence and trust between Palestinian and Israelis in order to put in place conditions that are not currently in place to lead to a potential peace process and the establishment of a two-state solution. At this moment in time, these conditions are not in place and we need to work on them, and that is what we’ll do. But in the immediate future, what we need to do is to help the people of Gaza who were caught in the crossfires.</p>
<p>Over the last few weeks, the U.S. has reestablished its diplomatic relations with the Palestinian Authority and the Palestinian people through humanitarian and economic support, as well as defense and security support. And we are in the process of reopening our consulate, which was closed a few years ago. This is an ongoing process; it takes some time, but it starts with a recommitment on the part of the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) We can now move on to a question by Illian (ph) who is 18 years old and is from Toulouse.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Via interpreter) The question is around democracies in South America and Central America that are threatened, pushing many people to leave their country. Joe Biden had promised for a more humane immigration policy. By which concrete ways can this be achieved?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) Yes, this is an issue that we face almost on a daily basis, but let’s take a step back. Men, women, children who try to come to the U.S. don’t do it because they just wake up one day and think, “Wouldn’t it be nice today to leave everything I’ve known behind –my family, my country, my language, my friends, my town – take an incredibly dangerous trip, be at the hands of traffickers, and end up at the American border which is actually closed? That would be a good way to spend my day.” No. To get to that, there must be certain conditions where there is no alternative, that only the – almost the only way to survive is to leave. And in order to address this issue I think we must resolve those conditions, what pushes people to leave everything they’ve ever known to go to the U.S. or to go to Mexico, et cetera.</p>
<p>And this is President Biden’s policy. We are implementing a program to address what pushes these people to take that trip. Deep issues around security, around governance, corruption, and most importantly, a lack of opportunities. If you don’t have the minimum ability to make a living, to feed your children, then you go to something else.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Via interpreter) Well, actually a question around what Vice President Kamala Harris said, which shocked a few people in Guatemala saying to the people, “Do not come.” Do you think this is a mistake?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) No. People must understand that the border is currently closed. So having these people risking their life at the hands of traffickers and putting themselves in danger only to realize that there is no access, then we must be very clear because some very dishonest people who are trafficking people are trying to say even through social media, they’re trying to say, “Come, the U.S. are open. You can come and we’ll help you for $5,000.” So she wanted to be very clear on this, and it’s important people hear that. But at the same time we have a tradition, which is also a French tradition despite the difficulties that we are both facing. The tradition is to say, “If people want to seek asylum, then they can do it, and we will study their case. And should they meet the criteria, we can let them in the U.S.”</p>
<p>Same for refugees. We have this amazing tradition, which is to welcome refugees. We have lost that a little recently, but we are trying to rebuild our capacities on this topic. And we need also a functioning system, because the existing system as you seek asylum in the U.S. is absolutely overwhelmed by demand and we are unable to manage that. So we not only need to act on what pushes people to take the trip, but also acting on the resources available to study those cases and see if somebody can come to our country.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Let’s move on to the Brut questions. I would like to thank you all for your comments. We are going to take those 10 to 15 minutes to ask a few questions from the comments. We have quite a few. We launched some contribution from yesterday, many questions around Julian Assange. He is facing extradition in the U.S. There have been many calls in France and Europe to drop the charges against him. What do you want to answer to this?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) It’s not easy for me speak around this issue. There is ongoing legal process, so I will let that legal process continue. I understand the questions, the emotions around this case, but I cannot really speak on this issue.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE</strong>: (Via interpreter) Yes, this is quite recurrent, and the question was around how come a whistleblower does not get much protection because this has been a recurrent issue for several years, this issue around extradition.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) I understand the question. I understand the emotions. But I must let the legal system work.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE</strong>: (Via interpreter) Is that something raised by your administration?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) Probably because this is ongoing case.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Ongoing, okay. Another question from Danny (ph) in the comments. “Do you intend on closing Guantanamo? We know you wanted to, but what’s the timeline? We – even during other mandates, we heard about closing Guantanamo, but when will that be done?”</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> (Via interpreter) The simple answer is yes. This is part of our policy and we are working on this. There are still around 40 inmates at Guantanamo, and when you have that type of number – 40, not hundreds – then by definition these are the most complex cases. However, we are actively working on this at the moment. We are trying to find a way to act on each individual case.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Could you make a commitment now that Guantanamo will be closed by the end?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) That’s our objective, but I cannot guarantee that or provide a date. But that’s definitely the objective.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So to sum up, your objective is to have Guantanamo closed by the end of the mandate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) Yes. I wish it could faster than this, but unfortunately it’s complicated. For example, in certain cases you need to find a country that is ready to welcome the person in question. It’s not easy. This requires a lot of diplomacy. And on our part – this might sound weird but if, let’s say, you’re considering sending somebody from Guantanamo to another country in order to close Guantanamo, we must have a guarantee that the rights of these people will be protected in that country. That’s not easy either.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Another question on Instagram on an issue that we handle on a daily basis. It has to do with climate change. What is the policy of the Biden administration on climate change?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) On the first day of our administration, we rejoined the Paris Accords. It was symbolic but it was also important on the substance. President Biden convened a summit on climate in April, just three months after getting into office. He gathered a large majority of those leaders that have the most impact or can have the most impact on climate with a view to having a wider sense of the situation and to also elevate the climate issue. We are currently working towards COP26, which will be held in the U.K. at the end of the year.</p>
<p>There are a couple of things that are important. At the same time, we – with this, which is what we’re trying to do – we must right away, not in 2040, not in 2045, but as of now, this year, but especially this decade is to save our capital because the goals for 2050 will not be attainable if we’re not able to act within this decade, and we’ll never be able to get back the capital that we use. We’ve seen countries that were sort of leaning back and that have now become more involved.</p>
<p>And the second point is that we need a large amount of financing in order to help those countries that do not have the capabilities to do so. For example, to acquire expensive technology or to improve their resilience in the face of climate impacts. There is a fund that we have contributed to and we will continue to do so, and we are trying to make sure that other countries do the same.</p>
<p>On many specific details our government is acting. We’re trying to do this by showing by example. I’ll just dwell on this for a couple of minutes if I may.</p>
<p>There are no big issues that have a bigger impact on our lives that can be managed without cooperation between countries. Climate is one of those. The U.S. is responsible for about 15 percent of emissions in the world. If we did everything perfectly at home, there remains 85 percent of the problem in other countries that need to be managed. And we are trying to do this in a joint manner with the other emitters.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Right after this meeting – and actually there is one last question: You are going to meet the President of the republic Emmanuel Macron. What will you be covering together?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) The problem is that we have so many things to cover and that we’re working on. We could spend hours. I just spent – I was meant to spend 45 minutes with my friend and colleague Jean-Yves Le Drian, the minister of foreign affairs, but we actually spent 90 minutes together and we could have gone longer.</p>
<p>We’ve done a great deal of work within the G7 at the summit, the NATO summit, and at the EU-U.S. summit as well as when President Biden and President Macron met. Our current mission is to continue this work, to continue exchanging on the next steps. For example, at the G7 summit we worked together in order to ensure that 1 billion doses of COVID vaccines would be distributed throughout the world. Now we’re working on how we can work together to increase production capacity in other countries, namely in Africa, and I know this is something that will be brought up because President Macron is a leader on this. And we will also talk about security in the Sahel and so forth. There are many different issues. Many things.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) What topic did you not cover here that you might be covering with the president?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) In a way, everything is on the agenda. But what I’d like to underscore first and foremost is what President Biden said when he met President Macron during the G7 summit: Not only do we want but also we need to work together. France is our longest-standing ally. As soon as we became independent and even before, France was at our side and this is still the case today. And I’m confident that in next – rather, I’m confident with the work that we’ve been doing in the first six months. And today, we will continue working together.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Thank you, Mr. Secretary. Many people are watching us and are seeing that your French is stellar. Thank you to the 34 young people who came here from all over France, including the six individuals who posed questions. Thank you to those who watched us. You are used to the way this works. It will be available in replay mode and we will be back soon. Have a great day and see you soon on Brut.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p>Chief of Mission Residence</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Hello, everyone. We are live on – with Antony Blinken, the new Secretary of State of the Biden administration. Hello, Mr. Secretary of State. You are the voice of America in the world. You are actually on an official visit in Europe. You met German Chancellor Angela Merkel and you are going to meet French President Macron in a moment.</p>
<p>We are going to talk about several topics – the threats against democracy, police violence, climate, and racism. And to talk about this, we have 34 young people we invited to have a discussion with you. So you will answer their questions. But I’m talking to you, watching live. You can ask your questions in the comments section and we will try to relay a few of those. My phone is here and I’m reading the comments.</p>
<p>But first of all, Mr. Secretary of State, we will be able to have this discussion in French because you lived in France for a few years, correct?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Indeed, I moved to France when I was nine. I used to live in New York. I lived here for nine years. I graduated high school here in Paris. I came back to Paris a couple years later to work. And I have friendships that started in school that are lasting, that have lasted over 50 years.</p>
<p>I’m delighted to be here to talk with all of you here today and those who are on the network. There’s an important reason why I wanted to have a dialogue such as this one. I believe that we’re faced with a challenge and also an opportunity. We’ll have to strengthen the links between our countries, and this will be done through you, whether it is through direct contact or on social media. You will be the ones who will build this partnership for the new generation. In my opinion, this is more important than ever. Our history is long-lasting, but it is particularly important today.</p>
<p>I think back to the challenges that we’re facing today, issues that affect all of our lives: the pandemic, COVID, the climate challenge, the impact of technology, new technology just as we’re seeing today. This impact can be good but not always – just like any topic that has an impact on your lives. And what we can see is that whether it is in France or in the U.S., a country that acts alone does not have the ability to face challenges on its own. And that goes for opportunities as well. We cannot build a wall high enough, we cannot build a solid wall to stop this from happening.</p>
<p>More than ever, I think that today there is a need for us to find a way to cooperate between countries so that we can work and act together. This ability is made possible by the ties that link our countries through our mutual values. And those relationships are living. The relationships are made by artistic pursuits, and by trade, and by working individuals. So for me, this is also an opportunity to listen to you, and to see what is important to you, and how you’re seeing the future of our relationships and of our ability to work together.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) We are getting many questions in the comments. It’s true that you are lucky enough to be with us today, but us French still cannot go to the U.S. So one question: When will the borders reopen?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I cannot give a date but I hope it will be soon. As we do in democracies, we have set up a working group with the EU in order to come back again to this freedom of travel. But we must be guided by science, by the experts in the medical field. We shouldn’t take political decisions, but decisions based on facts and data. I hope this will be very soon. We really want this. I hope it will be in the coming weeks, not months.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Yes, what would be the timeline? Can we imagine going to the U.S. during this summer for holidays?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I hope so. I cannot provide a date. But we must be careful. We are seeing that we think we’re – we have security, but then there is a new variant of the virus spreading. We see this in certain European countries. We have that same variant, the Delta variant in the U.S. So we really have that desire to reopen quickly, but this needs to be based on facts and science.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Maybe there will be criteria for vaccinated people?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) The experts are looking into it. I think there are different possibilities. I don’t want to talk too much about this. This is not my area of expertise. But I want to tell you that we are very actively working on this because we want to find a way to reopen further.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) People are very impatient around this. And let us now turn to the audience and give the floor to the youth. First question from Fatima, from the south. She’s 18 years old. A question around the importation of the racial issue into France.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) Hello. Thank you for listening to me. Xenophobia and racism are on the rise on both sides of the Atlantic. What are the reasons, and how does the U.S. face such violence?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Yes, this is the main topic these days, one of the main topics, unfortunately. We have this experience and we witness this here, too. And there are some very substantial issues that are hard to face. For instance – we could speak about it for an hour or two. For instance, we talk about the role of media and social media. A little time ago in France and the U.S., there was almost a monopoly of the media; there were big groups controlling the media, three main channels, a few national newspapers like <em>The New York Times</em>, and everybody got their information through those channels. And now, in the past 10 to 15 years, we have seen more democracy or information media being larger, but this also creates issues because there is no middle man anymore to check or limit access. Because we deeply believe in freedom of expression, but in the past when there was some excess or exaggeration, we could do something. But now with social media and the large platforms, they are not based on the same law than newspapers, for example. So that’s a question.</p>
<p>So how can we manage this without restricting freedom of expression? That’s an issue. But there are some deeper issues as well, and we are also witnessing in our societies issues with people that are left behind. These people don’t feel like they are being heard, that they are seen, and that people are taking care of them. And sometimes they express this issue, unfortunately, through hatred and even through violence. And we need to look into this as well.</p>
<p>But ultimately, most importantly, we must be able to respond to this and not accept such actions, such expressions, and this starts with national leaders but it’s not enough; this must also come from the society as a whole, and I hope from your generation. Because what we’re seeing – and that’s what makes it difficult these days – if you look at progress over the past 15 or 20 years, there is clearly progress in terms of security, opportunities, and even tolerance. And those of your generation are much more tolerant than my generation. So you need to speak out, to say what is acceptable and what is not. And in a democracy, we need to listen to you. And this speech, this way to speak on social networks, is also very important, and we must listen to those voices as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE</strong>: An opportunity to speak about social media, let me remind you, we are with Antony Blinken, Secretary of State.</p>
<p>In a year, there will be elections in France. Regardless of the result, will you keep the same relationship with France?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I don’t want to speak about French politics. But I can tell you that for a long time now, regardless of the government – in the U.S. or in France – we have acted together, we continue to do so, and as long as we work based on the same values, which is the link between us. The question is: Should Marine Le Pen be elected in 2022? I don’t want to speak on assumptions. I am very much focused on the present time, on now, and we are working remarkably with France.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Lea from Bordeaux has a question, has to do with the defiance towards politicians.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) Conspiracy theories are prospering in the U.S. Does – do you think that you can regain the confidence of citizens in the face of this growing defiance?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) This is a key question, indeed. The answer is fairly simple, in a way, even though it’s difficult to implement. There is a democratic depression that has lasted for 10 years, or even 15. We’re seeing a democratic withdrawal, so to speak, in most countries, including the most democratic ones. And it is very clear there is a lack of confidence, sometimes in democracy itself. And the answer is to show that democracies can deliver for their citizens and for the citizens around the world outside of those countries. So that is the challenge of our time, to show that democracies can act, and act in such a way as to improve the living conditions of our citizens. If we do this, and we yield results, and if the large majority of our citizens can see progress, and if their governments can take into account their wants and needs, I believe that we will see a new wave of support for the system.</p>
<p>However, if this does not happen, the crisis that is ongoing at the moment runs the risk of getting worse. And I’ll get – go back to what I said earlier: We will be more efficient in terms of yielding results if we work jointly, if countries work together, and if we cooperate within countries also. A government is not enough. Most of the problems that we’re facing require a response from the government, of course, but also from the – from civil society, from the private sector, from NGOs and so forth, more than ever. Those of us who work within government have an obligation to broaden the way we work. It is not enough to work amongst ourselves or with other governments. We need to focus on other ways and means, and to make sure that others are heard, and take part in the creation of our approaches. If we succeed, I think we will see a new impetus for democracy.</p>
<p>But the question that we are seeing now in autocracies is, well, we have a better capacity to act in an efficient manner to fulfill the needs of our people, and democracies are collapsing. Well, our job is to show that it is quite the contrary.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) You were talking about social media and freedom of speech; there’s a question here. Trump was banned from Facebook; do you believe that this is against freedom of speech?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I don’t want to speak on this, to this particular matter involving the president, President Trump. We talked about this briefly earlier; there is a challenge in the – indeed, that is very difficult to tackle, that has to do with balancing freedom of speech on social media. Where does the responsibility lie? Is it with the government? Is it with the platforms themselves? How do we manage this while maintaining this principle of freedom of speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So what is your position on this?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Personally, I’m leaning in favor of freedom of – the freedom of speech, and I think we should fight against bad ideas with good ideas. But I’d be the first to admit that this is not so simple.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So in the case of Donald Trump, the fact that it is a private company that says, well, this person can no longer speak out, isn’t this sort of a democratic issue?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Well, yes, indeed, it is a democratic issue at stake here, but in our constitutional system the government overall does not have the right to restrain people’s freedom of speech. It’s different for a private company. They have more of a margin, constitutionally speaking. But this being said, the principle remains fundamental.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So does this mean that we need a reform?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) Well, once again, this is above my pay grade. I’m in charge of working on managing foreign policy, but as a citizen, as an American citizen and as a citizen of the world, since social media is a world in and of itself, I believe that we need to find a way to manage this issue with the utmost respect for freedom of speech.</p>
<p>At the same time, when it comes to social media, it’s a little bit simplistic to say, “Well, social media is just here to assure technical support; we’re not in charge of the editorial content, and we’re not responsible.” In my opinion, this is going a bit too far. The way the conversation is managed, with the algorithms that are used, all of this has a profound impact on content and on what people see and listen on social media, and what they don’t see or don’t hear on social media. I believe that social media companies need to assume part of the responsibility. When the government enters this realm, then there are regulations involved, and sometimes it can go a bit too far. It’s best to get your results that will come out of the social media themselves.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) We have a question from Laura.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) Recently on American bases, certain flags have been banned, including the Confederate flag, seen as racist. This new ban also includes the LGBT flag. Does this ban send an alarming message?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) I’m responsible for the Secretary of State, and we have now the possibility for each embassy or each head of mission to show the flag, including the LGBTQ flag. This decision was made a few months ago. With regards to our diplomatic foreign missions, this is part of the scope of responsibility of our ambassadors. I cannot speak in the name of our colleagues from the Department of Defense or Pentagon. They have had a rule for a long time now that says that the only flag outside of the American flag that can be shown is the one that is a symbol of the American soldiers that are combat.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) We have now a question from Jean around the Uyghurs. He’s 17, coming from Maubeuge in the north.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Via interpreter) The U.S. have been mobilized against the violations of the Uyghurs’ rights in China. You, for instance, banned cotton importations from Xinjiang. Are these restrictions enough?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) That’s an excellent question. And one could answer no, because if the result is not here – that is, stopping the abuse against the Uyghurs – one could say that this is not enough, because what matters is the result. That being said, there are two important aspects when we witness human rights violations, including such serious violations as seen in Xinjiang. We need to at least speak out; not only speak out but taking action with the available means. And in that regard, we shouldn’t be complicit with this situation, hence, the idea of trying to make sure that products that are made with the workers in Xinjiang cannot be imported. And we must also make sure that our countries do not export technologies to China, technologies that could be used to control those communities.</p>
<p>But it’s more complicated than this. I am – I admit that sanctions are an important tool, but it can also have perverted consequences. For instance, if because of those sanctions the life of those we’re are trying to help gets worse because they are not able to make a living or they do not have access to certain products, including humanitarian products, we must raise that question and we must look into the issue specifically and always ask ourselves the question: Does our action overall have a positive or a negative impact?</p>
<p>But with the current situation, which is ongoing right now in Xinjiang against the Uyghurs, we should at least as an international community to shed a light on what is happening, to clearly speak out and say this is not acceptable, and through sanctions, to try at least to pressure those who are leading such policy, change their policy.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Well, actually, we’ve heard that those sanctions might not be efficient, so how far are the U.S. ready to go on this issue?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) I don’t want to get into hypotheticals. The situation is ongoing and what we’ve seen over the last few months is that more and more countries are speaking out and acting together, including by way of coordinated sanctions.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Some people are saying maybe it’s not going as far as it should because you’re in the face of China; it’s a large economic power, while the reality is that we cannot avoid China, it’s the reality.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) At various levels we need to engage with China and I hope that this engagement can lead to a policy change, but at the same time, we are using the tools at our disposal to try and show that the policy carried out by the Chinese Government has a cost for China itself as well in terms of their political and diplomatic isolation, and also a cost that could potentially be economic as well.</p>
<p>On various challenges and issues, the reality is that there is rarely – sometimes there is, but there’s rarely an easy and quick answer as if you were just flipping on a switch. It just doesn’t work that way.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) So we answered the questions by those who asked about this – many people asked. Don’t hesitate to ask your questions, we will ask them. We will now be giving the floor to Safwan (ph), who is 17 years old and who is from (inaudible) in the Paris region.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Via interpreter) In May, you went to Israel and to the West Bank. How can the U.S. – or how do the U.S. intend to work towards peace in the region?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) This is a question that is timely today that we could have also asked last year, five years ago, 10 years ago, 15 years ago – the question doesn’t go away, because the solution is still not there. At first, we had a major issue, the conflict in Gaza. We wanted to put an end to violence as soon as possible, which is what we did. Lots of damage, lots of human loss, but the violence did end and at the moment there are immediate challenges with humanitarian assistance for those who live in Gaza, but there’s also a need to reconstruct Gaza. All of this is ongoing at the moment.</p>
<p>Avoiding in the days, weeks, and months to come any type of provocation or sticking points that could give way to new bouts of violence is another focus of ours, and we also want to work on establishing more confidence and trust between Palestinian and Israelis in order to put in place conditions that are not currently in place to lead to a potential peace process and the establishment of a two-state solution. At this moment in time, these conditions are not in place and we need to work on them, and that is what we’ll do. But in the immediate future, what we need to do is to help the people of Gaza who were caught in the crossfires.</p>
<p>Over the last few weeks, the U.S. has reestablished its diplomatic relations with the Palestinian Authority and the Palestinian people through humanitarian and economic support, as well as defense and security support. And we are in the process of reopening our consulate, which was closed a few years ago. This is an ongoing process; it takes some time, but it starts with a recommitment on the part of the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) We can now move on to a question by Illian (ph) who is 18 years old and is from Toulouse.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Via interpreter) The question is around democracies in South America and Central America that are threatened, pushing many people to leave their country. Joe Biden had promised for a more humane immigration policy. By which concrete ways can this be achieved?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) Yes, this is an issue that we face almost on a daily basis, but let’s take a step back. Men, women, children who try to come to the U.S. don’t do it because they just wake up one day and think, “Wouldn’t it be nice today to leave everything I’ve known behind –my family, my country, my language, my friends, my town – take an incredibly dangerous trip, be at the hands of traffickers, and end up at the American border which is actually closed? That would be a good way to spend my day.” No. To get to that, there must be certain conditions where there is no alternative, that only the – almost the only way to survive is to leave. And in order to address this issue I think we must resolve those conditions, what pushes people to leave everything they’ve ever known to go to the U.S. or to go to Mexico, et cetera.</p>
<p>And this is President Biden’s policy. We are implementing a program to address what pushes these people to take that trip. Deep issues around security, around governance, corruption, and most importantly, a lack of opportunities. If you don’t have the minimum ability to make a living, to feed your children, then you go to something else.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Via interpreter) Well, actually a question around what Vice President Kamala Harris said, which shocked a few people in Guatemala saying to the people, “Do not come.” Do you think this is a mistake?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) No. People must understand that the border is currently closed. So having these people risking their life at the hands of traffickers and putting themselves in danger only to realize that there is no access, then we must be very clear because some very dishonest people who are trafficking people are trying to say even through social media, they’re trying to say, “Come, the U.S. are open. You can come and we’ll help you for $5,000.” So she wanted to be very clear on this, and it’s important people hear that. But at the same time we have a tradition, which is also a French tradition despite the difficulties that we are both facing. The tradition is to say, “If people want to seek asylum, then they can do it, and we will study their case. And should they meet the criteria, we can let them in the U.S.”</p>
<p>Same for refugees. We have this amazing tradition, which is to welcome refugees. We have lost that a little recently, but we are trying to rebuild our capacities on this topic. And we need also a functioning system, because the existing system as you seek asylum in the U.S. is absolutely overwhelmed by demand and we are unable to manage that. So we not only need to act on what pushes people to take the trip, but also acting on the resources available to study those cases and see if somebody can come to our country.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Let’s move on to the Brut questions. I would like to thank you all for your comments. We are going to take those 10 to 15 minutes to ask a few questions from the comments. We have quite a few. We launched some contribution from yesterday, many questions around Julian Assange. He is facing extradition in the U.S. There have been many calls in France and Europe to drop the charges against him. What do you want to answer to this?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> (Via interpreter) It’s not easy for me speak around this issue. There is ongoing legal process, so I will let that legal process continue. I understand the questions, the emotions around this case, but I cannot really speak on this issue.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE</strong>: (Via interpreter) Yes, this is quite recurrent, and the question was around how come a whistleblower does not get much protection because this has been a recurrent issue for several years, this issue around extradition.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) I understand the question. I understand the emotions. But I must let the legal system work.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE</strong>: (Via interpreter) Is that something raised by your administration?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) Probably because this is ongoing case.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Ongoing, okay. Another question from Danny (ph) in the comments. “Do you intend on closing Guantanamo? We know you wanted to, but what’s the timeline? We – even during other mandates, we heard about closing Guantanamo, but when will that be done?”</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> (Via interpreter) The simple answer is yes. This is part of our policy and we are working on this. There are still around 40 inmates at Guantanamo, and when you have that type of number – 40, not hundreds – then by definition these are the most complex cases. However, we are actively working on this at the moment. We are trying to find a way to act on each individual case.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Could you make a commitment now that Guantanamo will be closed by the end?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) That’s our objective, but I cannot guarantee that or provide a date. But that’s definitely the objective.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) So to sum up, your objective is to have Guantanamo closed by the end of the mandate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) Yes. I wish it could faster than this, but unfortunately it’s complicated. For example, in certain cases you need to find a country that is ready to welcome the person in question. It’s not easy. This requires a lot of diplomacy. And on our part – this might sound weird but if, let’s say, you’re considering sending somebody from Guantanamo to another country in order to close Guantanamo, we must have a guarantee that the rights of these people will be protected in that country. That’s not easy either.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Another question on Instagram on an issue that we handle on a daily basis. It has to do with climate change. What is the policy of the Biden administration on climate change?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) On the first day of our administration, we rejoined the Paris Accords. It was symbolic but it was also important on the substance. President Biden convened a summit on climate in April, just three months after getting into office. He gathered a large majority of those leaders that have the most impact or can have the most impact on climate with a view to having a wider sense of the situation and to also elevate the climate issue. We are currently working towards COP26, which will be held in the U.K. at the end of the year.</p>
<p>There are a couple of things that are important. At the same time, we – with this, which is what we’re trying to do – we must right away, not in 2040, not in 2045, but as of now, this year, but especially this decade is to save our capital because the goals for 2050 will not be attainable if we’re not able to act within this decade, and we’ll never be able to get back the capital that we use. We’ve seen countries that were sort of leaning back and that have now become more involved.</p>
<p>And the second point is that we need a large amount of financing in order to help those countries that do not have the capabilities to do so. For example, to acquire expensive technology or to improve their resilience in the face of climate impacts. There is a fund that we have contributed to and we will continue to do so, and we are trying to make sure that other countries do the same.</p>
<p>On many specific details our government is acting. We’re trying to do this by showing by example. I’ll just dwell on this for a couple of minutes if I may.</p>
<p>There are no big issues that have a bigger impact on our lives that can be managed without cooperation between countries. Climate is one of those. The U.S. is responsible for about 15 percent of emissions in the world. If we did everything perfectly at home, there remains 85 percent of the problem in other countries that need to be managed. And we are trying to do this in a joint manner with the other emitters.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) Right after this meeting – and actually there is one last question: You are going to meet the President of the republic Emmanuel Macron. What will you be covering together?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) The problem is that we have so many things to cover and that we’re working on. We could spend hours. I just spent – I was meant to spend 45 minutes with my friend and colleague Jean-Yves Le Drian, the minister of foreign affairs, but we actually spent 90 minutes together and we could have gone longer.</p>
<p>We’ve done a great deal of work within the G7 at the summit, the NATO summit, and at the EU-U.S. summit as well as when President Biden and President Macron met. Our current mission is to continue this work, to continue exchanging on the next steps. For example, at the G7 summit we worked together in order to ensure that 1 billion doses of COVID vaccines would be distributed throughout the world. Now we’re working on how we can work together to increase production capacity in other countries, namely in Africa, and I know this is something that will be brought up because President Macron is a leader on this. And we will also talk about security in the Sahel and so forth. There are many different issues. Many things.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE: </strong>(Via interpreter) What topic did you not cover here that you might be covering with the president?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>(Via interpreter) In a way, everything is on the agenda. But what I’d like to underscore first and foremost is what President Biden said when he met President Macron during the G7 summit: Not only do we want but also we need to work together. France is our longest-standing ally. As soon as we became independent and even before, France was at our side and this is still the case today. And I’m confident that in next – rather, I’m confident with the work that we’ve been doing in the first six months. And today, we will continue working together.</p>
<p><strong>MR BUISINE:</strong> (Via interpreter) Thank you, Mr. Secretary. Many people are watching us and are seeing that your French is stellar. Thank you to the 34 young people who came here from all over France, including the six individuals who posed questions. Thank you to those who watched us. You are used to the way this works. It will be available in replay mode and we will be back soon. Have a great day and see you soon on Brut.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian at a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-french-foreign-minister-jean-yves-le-drian-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 17:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p>Quai d’Orsay</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) (In progress) Welcome back. It is excellent news for all of us that America is back. It has come back to the values that we share, come back to an imperative that we share, democracy. It has come back to multilateralism that we built together, and it is our responsibility to continue with it intensively.</p>
<p>These values, universal values, these democratic (inaudible) demand and this joint horizon, such are the foundations of what we share. And this is what France and the Europeans had to fight for alone far too often for four very long years against these attacks that continue. I’m very pleased that we are back together and we – that we can work together in order to preserve this international order based on cooperation and the law.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year, together with Antony Blinken, we’ve been working in order to sustain this momentum by renewing a constant and confident – constant and confident dialogue which is indispensable for both our countries. Indispensable because the challenges that we face need all of our determination and all of our energy when it comes to the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate emergency, the fight against the global inequalities. And the time as well, it is indispensable because we are, at the moment, witnessing an international life which is becoming more and more brittle. It is therefore a strategic imperative that we strengthen our alliance and meet at a bilateral level or within the relationship between the EU and the United States or within the balanced nature.</p>
<p>Like President Biden and yourself, you commended the efforts made by the Europeans within NATO to play their role. We all acknowledge that we are stronger together, stronger when it comes to fighting terrorism. And as you know, in the Sahel in particular and in the Levant and in the Sahel, we are undergoing a deep transformation of the French (inaudible) that is underway, and we’re very – like I told the Secretary of State, we very much wish the United States to continue to provide their support to the initiative.</p>
<p>We’re stronger as well when it comes to dealing with global crisis when that threatens our security interests. We were in Berlin two days ago, and we want to make sure that when it comes to Libya, we can obtain together the removal of the foreign forces, mercenaries, in compliance with the timeline for the political transition and in view of the elections on the 24th of December.</p>
<p>Stronger regarding Libya, but also on the Iranian matter, we are expecting the Iranian authorities to take the last decisions, probably difficult ones that will enable us to quickly come back to the full implementation of the Vienna accord.</p>
<p>It is true as well when it comes to the crisis in Lebanon, dear Tony, and I am pleased that this morning we noted not only that we share the same views, the same analysis of the situation: the terrible collapse of this country, the inability of the political leaders of this country to meet any aspect of the challenge. And we both also acknowledge that it would be such a tragedy if this country was to fall apart, would disappear. We noted all of that and we, ladies and gentlemen, decided to act together – to act together in order to exert pressure on those (inaudible). We know who they are, and it is not – the solution is not about immobility. So we agreed to take together some strong initiatives in order to unlock the situation. It is a matter of respect for the Lebanese people (inaudible) in order to preserve the stability of the Euro-Atlantic region, and some major decisions were taken on the occasion of the recent NATO summit. So we will be able to implement – to continue the strategic reflection initiated in 2019.</p>
<p>We will continue to feed the dialogue with Russia, particularly on arms control, and we share to that effect the same stance and approach of firmness made within NATO or within the European Union in order to continue our joint action.</p>
<p>We also talked about Armenia and Azerbaijan. We will continue to exchange on this matter and to coordinate our actions.</p>
<p>Being stronger, it’s also about being stronger in the Indo-Pacific region, which must absolutely remain a free and open space, and that requires a balanced approach vis-a-vis China. Of course, we discussed this matter as well in order to try and define this balance, and we agree on the necessity of our cooperation to adopt a lucid and pragmatic approach to what China means to us. That is, China is both a partner, a competitor, and a rival.</p>
<p>In addition, dear Tony, the relationship between France and the United States is a historic friendship, and we both, you and I, share some special responsibility. It is about respecting this background, but also keeping it alive.</p>
<p>And so to conclude, I have the pleasure of mentioning a beautiful project which (inaudible) couple of days, a network of (inaudible) on the American factory (inaudible) Albertine (inaudible) Villa Kujoyama in Kyoto. We will now have a Villa Albertine in the United States, but with a very new concept, (inaudible) to conclude my words to the press on this.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, this is a summary of our discussion this morning. We will continue our discussions in July on the occasion of my visit to the United States in mid-July, and we will have an opportunity to see each other again and to continue these very friendly and dense discussions on that occasion.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> (Via interpreter) Dear Jean-Yves, thank you for welcoming me so warmly. On a personal note, I would like to say how delighted I am to be here in France. It’s my second homeland, and I lived here for 10 years – over 10 years.</p>
<p>(In English) I’m also delighted that we were able to reunite so soon after the G7 at the NATO summit, the U.S.-EU Leaders Meeting. I think it’s a signal of how important, how foundational the friendship between France and the United States is to both our countries – our oldest ally and an alliance that we are now revitalizing even more for the challenges that we have to face, as you said, together.</p>
<p>As a kid in Paris, I learned how the values that the American people cherish are also cherished by the French. We throw these words around, but we actually give them meaning. France gives them meaning; the United States gives them meaning, at least on our best days – liberty, freedom of speech and thought, equality, every person’s right to be treated fairly and with dignity. I experienced how our cultures are so profoundly entwined, how French kids, at least when I was here, listened to American music. American kids watched French movies – actually now, French TV.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) The Bureau, Call My Agent, and Lupin.</p>
<p>(In English) If I have circles under my eyes, it’s because I stay up too late at night binge-watching these programs. (Laughter.)</p>
<p>And of course, I learned at a young age how much history our countries share, going back to the very start of the United States when France stood with us in our fight for freedom. Our partnership has been indispensable over so many years in meeting the challenges of the past. But it is, I think, even more indispensable now as we meet the challenges before us and that are having a real impact on the lives of our citizens, like stopping COVID-19, rising to the challenge of climate change, maintaining our joint security, defending our democratic values. As President Biden said again at the EU last week, the best way for our countries to deal with these challenges is by working together.</p>
<p>That includes through multilateralism. I’m visiting France, Germany, and Italy on this trip because, in addition to being our closest and strongest partners, these are also the only three countries that are members of the EU, NATO, and the G7. In the lead-up to the three summits and then at the summits themselves, our countries did important work together. And now we need to follow up on the steps we took – that’s exactly what we were doing this morning with the foreign minister and what I look forward to doing with President Macron later this afternoon – and also lay the groundwork for future collaborations. That includes our work at NATO to ensure the Alliance has the capabilities it needs to meet new threats, our agreement at the U.S.-EU summit to cooperate on setting the highest standards for trade and technology, and our work through the G7 to provide a billion vaccines to the world, to end support for coal-fired power plants, to move ahead on much-needed infrastructure development and projects in developing countries through the Build Back Better World initiative.</p>
<p>We very much look forward to working closely with our French counterparts and with France when France becomes president of the Council of the European Union in January. Jean-Yves, I think that’s an important moment for continuing to raise the level of ambition in the U.S.-EU relationship, and I think you agree with that proposition.</p>
<p>And as the foreign minister said, we are key partners together in dealing with regional and global security challenges. Together we’re going to support a sovereign, stable, unified, secure Libya, as we discussed together in Berlin just a couple of days ago. And we’ll see each other again in Rome in a couple of days to strengthen the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh and to address the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Syria, particularly through cross-border assistance.</p>
<p>We greatly value France’s leadership to counterterrorism in the Sahel region. We will continue to stand together in the Sahel. And with France, we’ll help our African partners work to address the drivers of economic, political, and social instability and bring security, stability, and good governance to their people.</p>
<p>We’re also working together to address the horrific violence and humanitarian crisis in the Tigray region of Ethiopia and the governance and economic crisis in Lebanon, as Jean-Yves discussed. For over a year and a half, the Lebanese people have demanded transparency, accountability, and an end to the endemic corruption and mismanagement that is causing such hardship. The United States, France, the international community stand ready to help Lebanon – a Lebanon that is committed to meaningful change, but we need to see real leadership in Beirut.</p>
<p>And of course, we’re pursuing a shared approach to dealing with the challenges posed by China and Russia to the free and open rules-based international order.</p>
<p>Let me just briefly as well mention that, of course, we are very, very important economic partners. We’ll keep growing our trade and investment relationship. The United States is the largest foreign investor in France. We’re the top destination for French investment. Hundreds of thousands of Americans work for French companies, and vice versa. Deepening our economic ties will be critical not only for our economic recovery but also to our future competitiveness. And we’ll keep sustaining our people-to-people exchanges, and I am very enthusiastic about the initiative that Jean-Yves is launching. Thousands of American students come to France every year to study and discover for themselves how welcoming and, indeed, life-changing this country is, as I experienced myself. And we will continue to stand for our shared values of human rights and democracy around the world.</p>
<p>Democracies are facing new threats, also new opportunities. We have to bring together new ideas to the table to help democracies become more resilient, more effective at promoting representative, equitable societies. Together, we must and we will demonstrate that democracies can deliver for their citizens and for people around the world. I think that’s the challenge of our time. We have no better partner than France in pursuing it. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) Are you the moderator?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> (Via interpreter) Yes. First question, Virginie Robert from Les Echos on the French side.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> (Via interpreter) Good morning, Mr. Minister. You talked about the importance of the economic ties between France and the United States, which are very much troubled today by the impossibility of traveling to the United States. Could you please tell us when that will be possible again?</p>
<p>And Minister Le Drian, you talked about a more balanced relationship within NATO. Nonetheless, there are some stronger disagreements as to this organization. How – and China – how can you deal with that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> With regard to travel, look, we are anxious to be able to restore travel as fully and as quickly as possible. We’re very much guided by the science, by our medical experts. That has to be the foundational principle on which we’re looking at this. We have a working group established with the European Union on this question, and all I can tell you – I can’t put a date on it. I can tell you we’re working very actively on this right now, and we are – like France, like our other partners in Europe – both anxious and looking forward to restoring travel. But we have to be guided by the science. We have to be guided by medical expertise.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) What was the question? (Inaudible) “Chinese-ation” of NATO? I was not aware of your concept because I can’t see the connection between the Atlantic Ocean and China. Is there a border? It is something very new today.</p>
<p>There were no disagreement between us as to the future of NATO, quite to the contrary, and I believe that this summit gives some – is a new start for NATO. It clearly identifies its purpose, putting back at the forefront our community of values, which are very much at the heart or the foundation of our Alliance, and saying as well – and that when we have a community of values, if there are some disagreements within the Alliance, they are to be dealt with based on the concept we agree upon. These values – you see who I am referring to – and we also agreed, as President Biden has said very strongly, that the European Union was a central element in the new relationship that we want to put in place within the Alliance when it comes to giving some new momentum to the Alliance. And we also agreed regarding the relationship with Russia.</p>
<p>As to China, I believe as well that things are clear between us. That was not the issue. Like I said earlier, we have a very close analysis with the three pillars I mentioned. We have both partners. China has partners, and we have to be partners when it comes to a number of issues, which are relevant to the entire planet. Given the importance of this country that – on climate, biodiversity, health, we are partners, but we’re also competitors because (inaudible) to a number of major economic, technological issues or innovation. We are competitors, so we had to make sure that we – our own interests are being respected and make sure that the same standards are applied on both sides so that it is fair.</p>
<p>And then we are rivals because on a number of topics, we (inaudible) to different models, ours and theirs. And in this respect, we stand very firm as to our demands, and I have in mind in particular the situation in the Xinjiang. This is it. So the three pillars will have to be combined depending on the particular point in time. The emergency or the focus might be more on one or another at different point in times, but we agreed to strike the right balance and – given that we share the same views on China. This is what I can tell you about China and NATO.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Let me just add if I can, I think I wouldn’t have changed a word of what Jean-Yves just said. I think what we have seen, especially over the last few weeks, both at the G7, at NATO, and at the EU is a convergence of views on how to deal together with the challenges posed by China. And to the foreign minister’s point, we see it the same way. It’s, for all of us, a complicated relationship that has adversarial aspects, competitive ones, and cooperative ones. But the common denominator is that we’re going to be much more effective in engaging across these different aspects of the relationship if we do it together, and that’s what I think you saw come out of the three summits that we had, as well as the meeting between President Macron and President Biden.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b> Our first question goes to Shaun Tandon of the AFP.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you very much. Mr. Secretary, if I may begin, Afghanistan. President Ghani is in the United States today. There is an intelligence report warning that Kabul could fall as soon as six months after the U.S. withdrawal. How concerned are you about this? Is this motivating you to expedite contingency plans, particularly to protect the embassy and other U.S. interests?</p>
<p>If I may, can I ask both of you about Russia?</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Mr. Minister, what is your message to European countries that are responding to the issue of a meeting with President Putin?</p>
<p>(In English.) And on the same question on Russia, President Macron has talked about having a seat at the table in arms talks with – to the United States and Russia. Does the United States support that? And would you support France and Germany moving along with Putin? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> I’m happy to start. Let me just quickly start with the last question you asked. When it comes to strategic stability talks, arms control talks, there’s a very basic and simple principle, which is – for our friends and partners, which is nothing about you without you. So of course, European interests are implicated in any discussions we may have with Russia about strategic stability, and we will be in close coordination with France, with our partners if and as these talks move forward.</p>
<p>With regard to Afghanistan, a few things. I just want to reiterate an important point that sometimes gets lost, which is that even as we are withdrawing our forces from Afghanistan, we are not disengaging from Afghanistan; to the contrary. We’re working very hard to sustain a strong, diplomatic presence – not only our diplomatic presence, but with partners as well to sustain many of the programs that we’ve had in place to support Afghanistan economically: development assistance, humanitarian assistance, assistance to the Afghan security forces.</p>
<p>And President Ghani in Washington will be talking about all of that with President Biden, and I know the President will be reaffirming that ongoing support for Afghanistan, support that other countries will continue as well. At the same time, we’re watching the situation very, very closely, very carefully. We’re also working to make good on our obligations to those who helped us with the Special Immigrant Visa program, and I know the White House has discussed that in recent days.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) A few words on Russia given that you asked me about it. Two things, simply: First, we can only acknowledge the authoritarian trend in this country in various aspects, but in particular with something which is very much of a symbol, Mr. Navalny. We also see then there is a trend of intimidation by this country, and recently, we saw it in particular close to Ukraine. We can see also a trend of interference. So in each of these situations, we condemn, we adopt sanctions, and we stand extremely firm.</p>
<p>That being said, it is important to talk to Russia. Of course, it’s not about being naive about – talk to Russia. This is what President Macron did in August 2019 when he invited President Putin to come and talk. This is what President Biden just did because it is a great country. Because first it is our neighbor, and also because it is important that we have a stable relationship with this country, (inaudible). And it is in the name of these principles that we would like to maintain this dialogue. It does not prevent us from standing firm, like we said earlier.</p>
<p>But of course, Europe, as well, need to talk to Russia at a high level, and mainly because there is a major issue, which is arms control. And over the past few month, we witnessed the de-organization – deconstruction of the regulation system of weapons that – the system that was put in place in – at the end of the ’90s on the strategic armaments. And luckily, we have New START being extended, but we also have the issue of the intermediate nuclear forces. And all of these regulations are a matter of security to prevent any accident or incidence, to provide some relative transparency. All of that does not exist anymore, so this is what is at stake – the interest to rebuild, to begin to rebuild all of that. It was discussed by President Biden and President Putin, and this is what we will be working on together based on a common agenda.</p>
<p>So we need to talk to have a strategic stability, to have relational stability between the Europeans and the great neighbor. And all of the initiatives aiming at talking with a willingness of dialogue are there. And they’re not – the Americans, while they’re specialist in dialogue with Russia, and the Europeans are special experts in sanctions, we need both, and this is what we’re doing.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> And I’m sorry, I realized I didn’t get to the part of your question on Afghanistan. We are seeing elevated attacks on the Afghan security forces and in certain parts of the country compared to a year ago. No increase in attacks on our forces, on the NATO forces that remain. Had we not begun the process of drawing down our military forces, based on the agreement reached by the previous administration with the Taliban, our assessment is the status quo would not have held. The attacks that we’re seeing now and other attacks almost certainly would have commenced, including potentially attacks on provincial capitals.</p>
<p>So the status quo was not an option. But we’re looking very carefully at the situation on the ground in Afghanistan, and we’re also looking very hard at whether the Taliban is at all serious about a peaceful resolution to the conflict. We continue to be engaged on the diplomacy, but actions that would try to take the country by force are, of course, totally inconsistent with finding a peaceful resolution.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> (Via interpreter) Question from Alexandra Brangeon, RFI.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> (Via interpreter) Mr. Minister, good morning, Secretary of State. You both mentioned the fight against terrorism in the Sahel. Since the inception of the G5 Sahel, France has been asking for this force to be under a mandate of the United Nations. Secretary of State, given the reduction of the staff or the transformation of Barkhane, is that a game-changer? Could it have an impact on the American policy? And like an American colleague of mine was asking, what’s the “can”?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, I think I will – if it’s all right, I will – we’ll stick with English, but let me just say a few things here. As I said earlier, we are strong partners in the Sahel, and I actually had an opportunity very early on in my tenure as Secretary of State to take part in the G5 Sahel summit. That was back in February. We are continuing to strengthen our own approach to the region, but we have been the closest of partners together, and that partnership will continue. We very much understand the work that France is doing to recalibrate the approach, and I think we share the view that working to build the capacity of local partners to take on counterterrorism is the right approach. It makes a good deal of sense. But we’ll also very much continue to support the ongoing efforts that France is leading in the region.</p>
<p>As to structurally how this goes forward, that’s something that we’re talking about. But I can tell you that in terms of our support for the ongoing efforts in the Sahel that France will be making, that, that we’ll be making the other – that support will very much continue. We’ll continue to coordinate very closely, and to support one another in pursuit of our shared regional interests.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b> Our final question, we’ll go to Karen DeYoung of <i>The Washington Post</i>.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) If I may, a few words on this topic, which I know somehow. First of all, I can only rejoice about the fact that our decisions are properly understood, and – about the American willingness to continue to cooperate with us in the Sahel. The good understanding of our decision means that we continue to consider counterterrorism as a priority, in particular in the Sahel. So this fight will continue, but in a different military format. And it is not the first time we’ll adapt to the new deal of the threat.</p>
<p>And like I was telling Tony Blinken earlier, when I was at the time minister of defense, when we launched the Serval Operation in the Sahel and then we launched the Barkhane operation, and now we’re launching a new operation. It doesn’t have a name yet, but it is about adapting to the situation, it is about having a new model, probably with a less of a presence, of a footprint, but a stronger determination to cooperate with greater Sahel involvement, more of an international element, and more involvement of the special forces specialized in counter operations – counterterrorism in particular with – thanks to the Europeans and in particular in the Takuba Operation. France will remain the key element in it. We will have other opportunities to talk about this in Rome early next week.</p>
<p>I believe there was one last question. We agreed to take four questions, and then we’ll have to get &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you. I’d like to ask a question about the Iran talks to both of you. Actually, it’s a question that has three parts. The State Department said yesterday that the talks cannot go on indefinitely and that at some point, if an agreement is not reached, the United States and its partners would have to regroup. Is there a point at which Iran’s qualitative gains in advancing its nuclear program would go too far and it becomes impossible to return to the JCPOA as written?</p>
<p>Also, there’s been no announcement as of yet of an agreement between Iran and the IAEA to extend the temporary monitoring agreement that expired yesterday, and I wonder how much of a concern that is to you.</p>
<p>And finally Iranian President-elect Raisi has been accused by numerous human rights groups of serious rights abuses dating back to the 1980s. Can the United States in all consciousness – conscientiousness, lift its sanctions against him without a proper international probe into those allegations? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Thank you, Karen. A few things here. We still have serious differences with Iran with regard to returning to mutual compliance with the JCPOA. Our teams are going back for a seventh round of indirect negotiations in the coming days. We’ll see if we can bridge the differences, but they’re real, and we have to – we have to be able to bridge them. I would tell you that with regard to the IAEA this remains a serious concern, a concern that we’ve communicated to Iran, and it needs to be – needs to be resolved.</p>
<p>At some point – you’re right – if Iran continues to spin ever more sophisticated centrifuges at higher degrees, if it pursues other aspects of its program that were prohibited by the JCPOA, there will come a point, yes, where it will be very hard to return back to the standards set by the JCPOA of ensuring extensive breakout – breakout time – that is, the amount of time it would take Iran produce fissile materials for a nuclear weapon if it makes that decision, which I think adds some urgency to this effort. But we haven’t reached that point. I can’t put a date on it, but it’s something that we are conscious of. Having said that, we are only going to reach an agreement with Iran if it makes good on its obligations under the JCPOA. And again, we’re just not there yet, so we’ll see.</p>
<p>In terms of the last question, look, this is about pursuing our fundamental interests. And an Iran with a nuclear weapon or with a capacity to produce one on very short order is an Iran that is even more dangerous than it already is – an Iran can act with even greater impunity when it comes to supporting terrorism, destabilizing the region, engaging in proliferation. So we have a national interest in trying to put the nuclear problem back in the box that it was in under the JCPOA that unfortunately it is now out of. And at the same time in doing that, we will retain all of the necessary tools to deal with Iran’s actions in other areas that are profoundly dangerous and destabilizing.</p>
<p>In fact, I think we’ll be in a better position to do that, particularly since we’ll be united with our allies and partners on this. So our focus – irrespective of individuals, irrespective of leaders – is in pursuing the national interest, and we believe that if we can get back to compliance with the JCPOA, an agreement that was working that had put the nuclear program in a box, it would be in the national interest.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Inaudible) have to add to the Iranian issue further to what Tony just said. Except maybe, but he knows that well that the United Kingdom, France, and Germany held on good for the sake of our house for a number of years, which means that today we can revive the JCPOA. Without the determined vigilance on our part to keep the Vienna Accord alive, today we would not be renegotiating. And I must say that the coordination between the teams of the three European states and with the negotiators of the United States, all of that is happening and going well.</p>
<p>It’s been six weeks since the negotiations started again. Some progress was achieved, and we will now be entering the most difficult times. It will require some strong and courageous decisions on behalf of the new Iranian authorities, but now is the time. We are at the end of the process in the hard time, but there is some spirit, a mindset which I hope will remain and will enable an agreement, because, of course, it would be pointless to continue for too long. At some point in time, we’ll have to be back to the JCPOA, the 2015 accord.</p>
<p>It’s important even though we are not there yet, even though there were some major gestures, including on behalf of the United States of America. But then that will not be the end of it, like Tony was saying, because beyond the JCPOA there will be the issue of the sustainability of preserving the military nuclear element beyond the dates of the JCPOA.</p>
<p>We will also have to include in the regional dimension – make sure there is a forum in order to stabilize the region. And we will also need to take onboard the old issue of arms transfers, of the missiles coming from Iran. And we will have to articulate so the end of – we will have to articulate the JCPOA with all of these issues, and we are being optimistic – moderately optimistic, but nonetheless optimistic. Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> It is the end of it. I’m sorry.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p>Quai d’Orsay</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) (In progress) Welcome back. It is excellent news for all of us that America is back. It has come back to the values that we share, come back to an imperative that we share, democracy. It has come back to multilateralism that we built together, and it is our responsibility to continue with it intensively.</p>
<p>These values, universal values, these democratic (inaudible) demand and this joint horizon, such are the foundations of what we share. And this is what France and the Europeans had to fight for alone far too often for four very long years against these attacks that continue. I’m very pleased that we are back together and we – that we can work together in order to preserve this international order based on cooperation and the law.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year, together with Antony Blinken, we’ve been working in order to sustain this momentum by renewing a constant and confident – constant and confident dialogue which is indispensable for both our countries. Indispensable because the challenges that we face need all of our determination and all of our energy when it comes to the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate emergency, the fight against the global inequalities. And the time as well, it is indispensable because we are, at the moment, witnessing an international life which is becoming more and more brittle. It is therefore a strategic imperative that we strengthen our alliance and meet at a bilateral level or within the relationship between the EU and the United States or within the balanced nature.</p>
<p>Like President Biden and yourself, you commended the efforts made by the Europeans within NATO to play their role. We all acknowledge that we are stronger together, stronger when it comes to fighting terrorism. And as you know, in the Sahel in particular and in the Levant and in the Sahel, we are undergoing a deep transformation of the French (inaudible) that is underway, and we’re very – like I told the Secretary of State, we very much wish the United States to continue to provide their support to the initiative.</p>
<p>We’re stronger as well when it comes to dealing with global crisis when that threatens our security interests. We were in Berlin two days ago, and we want to make sure that when it comes to Libya, we can obtain together the removal of the foreign forces, mercenaries, in compliance with the timeline for the political transition and in view of the elections on the 24th of December.</p>
<p>Stronger regarding Libya, but also on the Iranian matter, we are expecting the Iranian authorities to take the last decisions, probably difficult ones that will enable us to quickly come back to the full implementation of the Vienna accord.</p>
<p>It is true as well when it comes to the crisis in Lebanon, dear Tony, and I am pleased that this morning we noted not only that we share the same views, the same analysis of the situation: the terrible collapse of this country, the inability of the political leaders of this country to meet any aspect of the challenge. And we both also acknowledge that it would be such a tragedy if this country was to fall apart, would disappear. We noted all of that and we, ladies and gentlemen, decided to act together – to act together in order to exert pressure on those (inaudible). We know who they are, and it is not – the solution is not about immobility. So we agreed to take together some strong initiatives in order to unlock the situation. It is a matter of respect for the Lebanese people (inaudible) in order to preserve the stability of the Euro-Atlantic region, and some major decisions were taken on the occasion of the recent NATO summit. So we will be able to implement – to continue the strategic reflection initiated in 2019.</p>
<p>We will continue to feed the dialogue with Russia, particularly on arms control, and we share to that effect the same stance and approach of firmness made within NATO or within the European Union in order to continue our joint action.</p>
<p>We also talked about Armenia and Azerbaijan. We will continue to exchange on this matter and to coordinate our actions.</p>
<p>Being stronger, it’s also about being stronger in the Indo-Pacific region, which must absolutely remain a free and open space, and that requires a balanced approach vis-a-vis China. Of course, we discussed this matter as well in order to try and define this balance, and we agree on the necessity of our cooperation to adopt a lucid and pragmatic approach to what China means to us. That is, China is both a partner, a competitor, and a rival.</p>
<p>In addition, dear Tony, the relationship between France and the United States is a historic friendship, and we both, you and I, share some special responsibility. It is about respecting this background, but also keeping it alive.</p>
<p>And so to conclude, I have the pleasure of mentioning a beautiful project which (inaudible) couple of days, a network of (inaudible) on the American factory (inaudible) Albertine (inaudible) Villa Kujoyama in Kyoto. We will now have a Villa Albertine in the United States, but with a very new concept, (inaudible) to conclude my words to the press on this.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, this is a summary of our discussion this morning. We will continue our discussions in July on the occasion of my visit to the United States in mid-July, and we will have an opportunity to see each other again and to continue these very friendly and dense discussions on that occasion.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> (Via interpreter) Dear Jean-Yves, thank you for welcoming me so warmly. On a personal note, I would like to say how delighted I am to be here in France. It’s my second homeland, and I lived here for 10 years – over 10 years.</p>
<p>(In English) I’m also delighted that we were able to reunite so soon after the G7 at the NATO summit, the U.S.-EU Leaders Meeting. I think it’s a signal of how important, how foundational the friendship between France and the United States is to both our countries – our oldest ally and an alliance that we are now revitalizing even more for the challenges that we have to face, as you said, together.</p>
<p>As a kid in Paris, I learned how the values that the American people cherish are also cherished by the French. We throw these words around, but we actually give them meaning. France gives them meaning; the United States gives them meaning, at least on our best days – liberty, freedom of speech and thought, equality, every person’s right to be treated fairly and with dignity. I experienced how our cultures are so profoundly entwined, how French kids, at least when I was here, listened to American music. American kids watched French movies – actually now, French TV.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) The Bureau, Call My Agent, and Lupin.</p>
<p>(In English) If I have circles under my eyes, it’s because I stay up too late at night binge-watching these programs. (Laughter.)</p>
<p>And of course, I learned at a young age how much history our countries share, going back to the very start of the United States when France stood with us in our fight for freedom. Our partnership has been indispensable over so many years in meeting the challenges of the past. But it is, I think, even more indispensable now as we meet the challenges before us and that are having a real impact on the lives of our citizens, like stopping COVID-19, rising to the challenge of climate change, maintaining our joint security, defending our democratic values. As President Biden said again at the EU last week, the best way for our countries to deal with these challenges is by working together.</p>
<p>That includes through multilateralism. I’m visiting France, Germany, and Italy on this trip because, in addition to being our closest and strongest partners, these are also the only three countries that are members of the EU, NATO, and the G7. In the lead-up to the three summits and then at the summits themselves, our countries did important work together. And now we need to follow up on the steps we took – that’s exactly what we were doing this morning with the foreign minister and what I look forward to doing with President Macron later this afternoon – and also lay the groundwork for future collaborations. That includes our work at NATO to ensure the Alliance has the capabilities it needs to meet new threats, our agreement at the U.S.-EU summit to cooperate on setting the highest standards for trade and technology, and our work through the G7 to provide a billion vaccines to the world, to end support for coal-fired power plants, to move ahead on much-needed infrastructure development and projects in developing countries through the Build Back Better World initiative.</p>
<p>We very much look forward to working closely with our French counterparts and with France when France becomes president of the Council of the European Union in January. Jean-Yves, I think that’s an important moment for continuing to raise the level of ambition in the U.S.-EU relationship, and I think you agree with that proposition.</p>
<p>And as the foreign minister said, we are key partners together in dealing with regional and global security challenges. Together we’re going to support a sovereign, stable, unified, secure Libya, as we discussed together in Berlin just a couple of days ago. And we’ll see each other again in Rome in a couple of days to strengthen the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh and to address the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Syria, particularly through cross-border assistance.</p>
<p>We greatly value France’s leadership to counterterrorism in the Sahel region. We will continue to stand together in the Sahel. And with France, we’ll help our African partners work to address the drivers of economic, political, and social instability and bring security, stability, and good governance to their people.</p>
<p>We’re also working together to address the horrific violence and humanitarian crisis in the Tigray region of Ethiopia and the governance and economic crisis in Lebanon, as Jean-Yves discussed. For over a year and a half, the Lebanese people have demanded transparency, accountability, and an end to the endemic corruption and mismanagement that is causing such hardship. The United States, France, the international community stand ready to help Lebanon – a Lebanon that is committed to meaningful change, but we need to see real leadership in Beirut.</p>
<p>And of course, we’re pursuing a shared approach to dealing with the challenges posed by China and Russia to the free and open rules-based international order.</p>
<p>Let me just briefly as well mention that, of course, we are very, very important economic partners. We’ll keep growing our trade and investment relationship. The United States is the largest foreign investor in France. We’re the top destination for French investment. Hundreds of thousands of Americans work for French companies, and vice versa. Deepening our economic ties will be critical not only for our economic recovery but also to our future competitiveness. And we’ll keep sustaining our people-to-people exchanges, and I am very enthusiastic about the initiative that Jean-Yves is launching. Thousands of American students come to France every year to study and discover for themselves how welcoming and, indeed, life-changing this country is, as I experienced myself. And we will continue to stand for our shared values of human rights and democracy around the world.</p>
<p>Democracies are facing new threats, also new opportunities. We have to bring together new ideas to the table to help democracies become more resilient, more effective at promoting representative, equitable societies. Together, we must and we will demonstrate that democracies can deliver for their citizens and for people around the world. I think that’s the challenge of our time. We have no better partner than France in pursuing it. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) Are you the moderator?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> (Via interpreter) Yes. First question, Virginie Robert from Les Echos on the French side.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> (Via interpreter) Good morning, Mr. Minister. You talked about the importance of the economic ties between France and the United States, which are very much troubled today by the impossibility of traveling to the United States. Could you please tell us when that will be possible again?</p>
<p>And Minister Le Drian, you talked about a more balanced relationship within NATO. Nonetheless, there are some stronger disagreements as to this organization. How – and China – how can you deal with that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> With regard to travel, look, we are anxious to be able to restore travel as fully and as quickly as possible. We’re very much guided by the science, by our medical experts. That has to be the foundational principle on which we’re looking at this. We have a working group established with the European Union on this question, and all I can tell you – I can’t put a date on it. I can tell you we’re working very actively on this right now, and we are – like France, like our other partners in Europe – both anxious and looking forward to restoring travel. But we have to be guided by the science. We have to be guided by medical expertise.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) What was the question? (Inaudible) “Chinese-ation” of NATO? I was not aware of your concept because I can’t see the connection between the Atlantic Ocean and China. Is there a border? It is something very new today.</p>
<p>There were no disagreement between us as to the future of NATO, quite to the contrary, and I believe that this summit gives some – is a new start for NATO. It clearly identifies its purpose, putting back at the forefront our community of values, which are very much at the heart or the foundation of our Alliance, and saying as well – and that when we have a community of values, if there are some disagreements within the Alliance, they are to be dealt with based on the concept we agree upon. These values – you see who I am referring to – and we also agreed, as President Biden has said very strongly, that the European Union was a central element in the new relationship that we want to put in place within the Alliance when it comes to giving some new momentum to the Alliance. And we also agreed regarding the relationship with Russia.</p>
<p>As to China, I believe as well that things are clear between us. That was not the issue. Like I said earlier, we have a very close analysis with the three pillars I mentioned. We have both partners. China has partners, and we have to be partners when it comes to a number of issues, which are relevant to the entire planet. Given the importance of this country that – on climate, biodiversity, health, we are partners, but we’re also competitors because (inaudible) to a number of major economic, technological issues or innovation. We are competitors, so we had to make sure that we – our own interests are being respected and make sure that the same standards are applied on both sides so that it is fair.</p>
<p>And then we are rivals because on a number of topics, we (inaudible) to different models, ours and theirs. And in this respect, we stand very firm as to our demands, and I have in mind in particular the situation in the Xinjiang. This is it. So the three pillars will have to be combined depending on the particular point in time. The emergency or the focus might be more on one or another at different point in times, but we agreed to strike the right balance and – given that we share the same views on China. This is what I can tell you about China and NATO.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Let me just add if I can, I think I wouldn’t have changed a word of what Jean-Yves just said. I think what we have seen, especially over the last few weeks, both at the G7, at NATO, and at the EU is a convergence of views on how to deal together with the challenges posed by China. And to the foreign minister’s point, we see it the same way. It’s, for all of us, a complicated relationship that has adversarial aspects, competitive ones, and cooperative ones. But the common denominator is that we’re going to be much more effective in engaging across these different aspects of the relationship if we do it together, and that’s what I think you saw come out of the three summits that we had, as well as the meeting between President Macron and President Biden.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b> Our first question goes to Shaun Tandon of the AFP.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you very much. Mr. Secretary, if I may begin, Afghanistan. President Ghani is in the United States today. There is an intelligence report warning that Kabul could fall as soon as six months after the U.S. withdrawal. How concerned are you about this? Is this motivating you to expedite contingency plans, particularly to protect the embassy and other U.S. interests?</p>
<p>If I may, can I ask both of you about Russia?</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Mr. Minister, what is your message to European countries that are responding to the issue of a meeting with President Putin?</p>
<p>(In English.) And on the same question on Russia, President Macron has talked about having a seat at the table in arms talks with – to the United States and Russia. Does the United States support that? And would you support France and Germany moving along with Putin? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> I’m happy to start. Let me just quickly start with the last question you asked. When it comes to strategic stability talks, arms control talks, there’s a very basic and simple principle, which is – for our friends and partners, which is nothing about you without you. So of course, European interests are implicated in any discussions we may have with Russia about strategic stability, and we will be in close coordination with France, with our partners if and as these talks move forward.</p>
<p>With regard to Afghanistan, a few things. I just want to reiterate an important point that sometimes gets lost, which is that even as we are withdrawing our forces from Afghanistan, we are not disengaging from Afghanistan; to the contrary. We’re working very hard to sustain a strong, diplomatic presence – not only our diplomatic presence, but with partners as well to sustain many of the programs that we’ve had in place to support Afghanistan economically: development assistance, humanitarian assistance, assistance to the Afghan security forces.</p>
<p>And President Ghani in Washington will be talking about all of that with President Biden, and I know the President will be reaffirming that ongoing support for Afghanistan, support that other countries will continue as well. At the same time, we’re watching the situation very, very closely, very carefully. We’re also working to make good on our obligations to those who helped us with the Special Immigrant Visa program, and I know the White House has discussed that in recent days.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) A few words on Russia given that you asked me about it. Two things, simply: First, we can only acknowledge the authoritarian trend in this country in various aspects, but in particular with something which is very much of a symbol, Mr. Navalny. We also see then there is a trend of intimidation by this country, and recently, we saw it in particular close to Ukraine. We can see also a trend of interference. So in each of these situations, we condemn, we adopt sanctions, and we stand extremely firm.</p>
<p>That being said, it is important to talk to Russia. Of course, it’s not about being naive about – talk to Russia. This is what President Macron did in August 2019 when he invited President Putin to come and talk. This is what President Biden just did because it is a great country. Because first it is our neighbor, and also because it is important that we have a stable relationship with this country, (inaudible). And it is in the name of these principles that we would like to maintain this dialogue. It does not prevent us from standing firm, like we said earlier.</p>
<p>But of course, Europe, as well, need to talk to Russia at a high level, and mainly because there is a major issue, which is arms control. And over the past few month, we witnessed the de-organization – deconstruction of the regulation system of weapons that – the system that was put in place in – at the end of the ’90s on the strategic armaments. And luckily, we have New START being extended, but we also have the issue of the intermediate nuclear forces. And all of these regulations are a matter of security to prevent any accident or incidence, to provide some relative transparency. All of that does not exist anymore, so this is what is at stake – the interest to rebuild, to begin to rebuild all of that. It was discussed by President Biden and President Putin, and this is what we will be working on together based on a common agenda.</p>
<p>So we need to talk to have a strategic stability, to have relational stability between the Europeans and the great neighbor. And all of the initiatives aiming at talking with a willingness of dialogue are there. And they’re not – the Americans, while they’re specialist in dialogue with Russia, and the Europeans are special experts in sanctions, we need both, and this is what we’re doing.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> And I’m sorry, I realized I didn’t get to the part of your question on Afghanistan. We are seeing elevated attacks on the Afghan security forces and in certain parts of the country compared to a year ago. No increase in attacks on our forces, on the NATO forces that remain. Had we not begun the process of drawing down our military forces, based on the agreement reached by the previous administration with the Taliban, our assessment is the status quo would not have held. The attacks that we’re seeing now and other attacks almost certainly would have commenced, including potentially attacks on provincial capitals.</p>
<p>So the status quo was not an option. But we’re looking very carefully at the situation on the ground in Afghanistan, and we’re also looking very hard at whether the Taliban is at all serious about a peaceful resolution to the conflict. We continue to be engaged on the diplomacy, but actions that would try to take the country by force are, of course, totally inconsistent with finding a peaceful resolution.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> (Via interpreter) Question from Alexandra Brangeon, RFI.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> (Via interpreter) Mr. Minister, good morning, Secretary of State. You both mentioned the fight against terrorism in the Sahel. Since the inception of the G5 Sahel, France has been asking for this force to be under a mandate of the United Nations. Secretary of State, given the reduction of the staff or the transformation of Barkhane, is that a game-changer? Could it have an impact on the American policy? And like an American colleague of mine was asking, what’s the “can”?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, I think I will – if it’s all right, I will – we’ll stick with English, but let me just say a few things here. As I said earlier, we are strong partners in the Sahel, and I actually had an opportunity very early on in my tenure as Secretary of State to take part in the G5 Sahel summit. That was back in February. We are continuing to strengthen our own approach to the region, but we have been the closest of partners together, and that partnership will continue. We very much understand the work that France is doing to recalibrate the approach, and I think we share the view that working to build the capacity of local partners to take on counterterrorism is the right approach. It makes a good deal of sense. But we’ll also very much continue to support the ongoing efforts that France is leading in the region.</p>
<p>As to structurally how this goes forward, that’s something that we’re talking about. But I can tell you that in terms of our support for the ongoing efforts in the Sahel that France will be making, that, that we’ll be making the other – that support will very much continue. We’ll continue to coordinate very closely, and to support one another in pursuit of our shared regional interests.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b> Our final question, we’ll go to Karen DeYoung of <i>The Washington Post</i>.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Via interpreter) If I may, a few words on this topic, which I know somehow. First of all, I can only rejoice about the fact that our decisions are properly understood, and – about the American willingness to continue to cooperate with us in the Sahel. The good understanding of our decision means that we continue to consider counterterrorism as a priority, in particular in the Sahel. So this fight will continue, but in a different military format. And it is not the first time we’ll adapt to the new deal of the threat.</p>
<p>And like I was telling Tony Blinken earlier, when I was at the time minister of defense, when we launched the Serval Operation in the Sahel and then we launched the Barkhane operation, and now we’re launching a new operation. It doesn’t have a name yet, but it is about adapting to the situation, it is about having a new model, probably with a less of a presence, of a footprint, but a stronger determination to cooperate with greater Sahel involvement, more of an international element, and more involvement of the special forces specialized in counter operations – counterterrorism in particular with – thanks to the Europeans and in particular in the Takuba Operation. France will remain the key element in it. We will have other opportunities to talk about this in Rome early next week.</p>
<p>I believe there was one last question. We agreed to take four questions, and then we’ll have to get &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you. I’d like to ask a question about the Iran talks to both of you. Actually, it’s a question that has three parts. The State Department said yesterday that the talks cannot go on indefinitely and that at some point, if an agreement is not reached, the United States and its partners would have to regroup. Is there a point at which Iran’s qualitative gains in advancing its nuclear program would go too far and it becomes impossible to return to the JCPOA as written?</p>
<p>Also, there’s been no announcement as of yet of an agreement between Iran and the IAEA to extend the temporary monitoring agreement that expired yesterday, and I wonder how much of a concern that is to you.</p>
<p>And finally Iranian President-elect Raisi has been accused by numerous human rights groups of serious rights abuses dating back to the 1980s. Can the United States in all consciousness – conscientiousness, lift its sanctions against him without a proper international probe into those allegations? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Thank you, Karen. A few things here. We still have serious differences with Iran with regard to returning to mutual compliance with the JCPOA. Our teams are going back for a seventh round of indirect negotiations in the coming days. We’ll see if we can bridge the differences, but they’re real, and we have to – we have to be able to bridge them. I would tell you that with regard to the IAEA this remains a serious concern, a concern that we’ve communicated to Iran, and it needs to be – needs to be resolved.</p>
<p>At some point – you’re right – if Iran continues to spin ever more sophisticated centrifuges at higher degrees, if it pursues other aspects of its program that were prohibited by the JCPOA, there will come a point, yes, where it will be very hard to return back to the standards set by the JCPOA of ensuring extensive breakout – breakout time – that is, the amount of time it would take Iran produce fissile materials for a nuclear weapon if it makes that decision, which I think adds some urgency to this effort. But we haven’t reached that point. I can’t put a date on it, but it’s something that we are conscious of. Having said that, we are only going to reach an agreement with Iran if it makes good on its obligations under the JCPOA. And again, we’re just not there yet, so we’ll see.</p>
<p>In terms of the last question, look, this is about pursuing our fundamental interests. And an Iran with a nuclear weapon or with a capacity to produce one on very short order is an Iran that is even more dangerous than it already is – an Iran can act with even greater impunity when it comes to supporting terrorism, destabilizing the region, engaging in proliferation. So we have a national interest in trying to put the nuclear problem back in the box that it was in under the JCPOA that unfortunately it is now out of. And at the same time in doing that, we will retain all of the necessary tools to deal with Iran’s actions in other areas that are profoundly dangerous and destabilizing.</p>
<p>In fact, I think we’ll be in a better position to do that, particularly since we’ll be united with our allies and partners on this. So our focus – irrespective of individuals, irrespective of leaders – is in pursuing the national interest, and we believe that if we can get back to compliance with the JCPOA, an agreement that was working that had put the nuclear program in a box, it would be in the national interest.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LE DRIAN:</b> (Inaudible) have to add to the Iranian issue further to what Tony just said. Except maybe, but he knows that well that the United Kingdom, France, and Germany held on good for the sake of our house for a number of years, which means that today we can revive the JCPOA. Without the determined vigilance on our part to keep the Vienna Accord alive, today we would not be renegotiating. And I must say that the coordination between the teams of the three European states and with the negotiators of the United States, all of that is happening and going well.</p>
<p>It’s been six weeks since the negotiations started again. Some progress was achieved, and we will now be entering the most difficult times. It will require some strong and courageous decisions on behalf of the new Iranian authorities, but now is the time. We are at the end of the process in the hard time, but there is some spirit, a mindset which I hope will remain and will enable an agreement, because, of course, it would be pointless to continue for too long. At some point in time, we’ll have to be back to the JCPOA, the 2015 accord.</p>
<p>It’s important even though we are not there yet, even though there were some major gestures, including on behalf of the United States of America. But then that will not be the end of it, like Tony was saying, because beyond the JCPOA there will be the issue of the sustainability of preserving the military nuclear element beyond the dates of the JCPOA.</p>
<p>We will also have to include in the regional dimension – make sure there is a forum in order to stabilize the region. And we will also need to take onboard the old issue of arms transfers, of the missiles coming from Iran. And we will have to articulate so the end of – we will have to articulate the JCPOA with all of these issues, and we are being optimistic – moderately optimistic, but nonetheless optimistic. Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> It is the end of it. I’m sorry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Releases 2021 Fiscal Transparency Report</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-releases-2021-fiscal-transparency-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 15:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 25, 2021, the United States Department of State released the 2021 Fiscal Transparency Report, which found that 74 of the 141 governments reviewed by the Department met minimum requirements of fiscal transparency.  Seventeen of the 67 governments that did not meet minimum requirements made significant progress during the review period.</p>
<p>Fiscal transparency is a critical element of effective public financial management, helps build private market confidence, and underpins economic sustainability.  It fosters greater government accountability by providing a window into government budgets for citizens, helping citizens hold their leadership accountable, and facilitating better-informed public debate.  These Congressionally-mandated annual fiscal transparency reviews provide opportunities to engage in dialogue with governments on the importance of fiscal transparency, particularly important given the need for significant economic, health, and social spending to offset the shocks of COVID-19.</p>
<p>The report describes the minimum requirements of fiscal transparency, reviews 141 governments, most of which were identified as recipients of U.S. assistance in the 2014 Fiscal Transparency Report, and further assesses governments that did not meet the minimum fiscal transparency requirements during the review period of January 1 – December 31, 2020.  The report also indicates whether governments that did not meet those requirements made significant progress to publicly disclose national budget documentation, contracts, and licenses during the review period.  The Department of State evaluated the public availability, substantial completeness, and reliability of budget documents, as well as the transparency of processes for awarding government contracts and licenses.  Beginning with this review period, if a government has a sovereign wealth fund, it must disclose its source of funding and general approach to withdrawals from the fund.  Additionally, debt of all major state-owned enterprises must now be disclosed, and the government must have a supreme audit institution that meets international standards of independence and has verified the government’s annual financial statements.</p>
<p>The report can be found on the Department’s website at <a href="https://www.state.gov/fiscal-transparency-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MjUuNDI0MTEwNzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvZmlzY2FsLXRyYW5zcGFyZW5jeS1yZXBvcnQifQ.WK5ImjVnKy50J-ygHuQUAyr0k6OkiiPwhFiB1hee-2Q/s/1039202793/br/108439705831-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1624719354905000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFfkAcLw6QqnBCf_KUiSrR7jjjLiw">https://www.state.gov/fiscal-<wbr />transparency-report</a>.  For further information, please contact the Bureau of Economic and Business Affairs’ Fiscal Transparency team at <a href="mailto:fiscaltransparency@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fiscaltransparency@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 25, 2021, the United States Department of State released the 2021 Fiscal Transparency Report, which found that 74 of the 141 governments reviewed by the Department met minimum requirements of fiscal transparency.  Seventeen of the 67 governments that did not meet minimum requirements made significant progress during the review period.</p>
<p>Fiscal transparency is a critical element of effective public financial management, helps build private market confidence, and underpins economic sustainability.  It fosters greater government accountability by providing a window into government budgets for citizens, helping citizens hold their leadership accountable, and facilitating better-informed public debate.  These Congressionally-mandated annual fiscal transparency reviews provide opportunities to engage in dialogue with governments on the importance of fiscal transparency, particularly important given the need for significant economic, health, and social spending to offset the shocks of COVID-19.</p>
<p>The report describes the minimum requirements of fiscal transparency, reviews 141 governments, most of which were identified as recipients of U.S. assistance in the 2014 Fiscal Transparency Report, and further assesses governments that did not meet the minimum fiscal transparency requirements during the review period of January 1 – December 31, 2020.  The report also indicates whether governments that did not meet those requirements made significant progress to publicly disclose national budget documentation, contracts, and licenses during the review period.  The Department of State evaluated the public availability, substantial completeness, and reliability of budget documents, as well as the transparency of processes for awarding government contracts and licenses.  Beginning with this review period, if a government has a sovereign wealth fund, it must disclose its source of funding and general approach to withdrawals from the fund.  Additionally, debt of all major state-owned enterprises must now be disclosed, and the government must have a supreme audit institution that meets international standards of independence and has verified the government’s annual financial statements.</p>
<p>The report can be found on the Department’s website at <a href="https://www.state.gov/fiscal-transparency-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MjUuNDI0MTEwNzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvZmlzY2FsLXRyYW5zcGFyZW5jeS1yZXBvcnQifQ.WK5ImjVnKy50J-ygHuQUAyr0k6OkiiPwhFiB1hee-2Q/s/1039202793/br/108439705831-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1624719354905000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFfkAcLw6QqnBCf_KUiSrR7jjjLiw">https://www.state.gov/fiscal-<wbr />transparency-report</a>.  For further information, please contact the Bureau of Economic and Business Affairs’ Fiscal Transparency team at <a href="mailto:fiscaltransparency@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fiscaltransparency@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Building a Stronger Democracy in Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/building-a-stronger-democracy-in-ethiopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 14:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Democracy flourishes when institutions of governance are inclusive, transparent, accountable, and responsive to its people. With that immutable fact in mind, the United States commends those Ethiopians who exercised their right to vote on June 21.</p>
<p>Elections, however, are not in and of themselves a sufficient marker of democracy or genuine political reform. The June 21 elections in Ethiopia took place against a backdrop of grave instability, including increasing inter-ethnic and inter-communal conflicts, and an electoral process that was not free or fair for all Ethiopians. The boycott of the elections by opposition parties, the detention of vocal political leaders, and the ongoing violence in multiple parts of the country underscore the need to launch an inclusive effort to build a national consensus on the governance of Ethiopia that preserves the sovereignty and unity of the state and strengthens the constitutional order.</p>
<p>In this period following the election, it is critical that Ethiopians come together to confront growing divisions. We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and refrain from inciting others to violence. The United States stands ready to assist Ethiopians to advance post-election dialogue, resolution of conflicts, and national reconciliation in Ethiopia. The ongoing conflict, violence, and likely famine declaration in Tigray demand urgent action, including a ceasefire, the withdrawal of Eritrean forces from Ethiopian territory, the transparent investigation of atrocities, and unhindered humanitarian access to populations in need.</p>
<p>We look forward to a continued partnership with the Ethiopian people and to supporting efforts to promote inclusive political participation that moves the country forward on a path to democracy and national unity.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Democracy flourishes when institutions of governance are inclusive, transparent, accountable, and responsive to its people. With that immutable fact in mind, the United States commends those Ethiopians who exercised their right to vote on June 21.</p>
<p>Elections, however, are not in and of themselves a sufficient marker of democracy or genuine political reform. The June 21 elections in Ethiopia took place against a backdrop of grave instability, including increasing inter-ethnic and inter-communal conflicts, and an electoral process that was not free or fair for all Ethiopians. The boycott of the elections by opposition parties, the detention of vocal political leaders, and the ongoing violence in multiple parts of the country underscore the need to launch an inclusive effort to build a national consensus on the governance of Ethiopia that preserves the sovereignty and unity of the state and strengthens the constitutional order.</p>
<p>In this period following the election, it is critical that Ethiopians come together to confront growing divisions. We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and refrain from inciting others to violence. The United States stands ready to assist Ethiopians to advance post-election dialogue, resolution of conflicts, and national reconciliation in Ethiopia. The ongoing conflict, violence, and likely famine declaration in Tigray demand urgent action, including a ceasefire, the withdrawal of Eritrean forces from Ethiopian territory, the transparent investigation of atrocities, and unhindered humanitarian access to populations in need.</p>
<p>We look forward to a continued partnership with the Ethiopian people and to supporting efforts to promote inclusive political participation that moves the country forward on a path to democracy and national unity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development Secretary General Cormann</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-organization-for-economic-cooperation-and-development-secretary-general-cormann/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 14:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Secretary General Mathias Cormann in Paris. Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Cormann emphasized the enduring importance of the OECD as a body of like-minded countries committed to shared values and the pursuit of a greener and more sustainable and inclusive world, especially as the organization celebrates its 60th anniversary this year. In light of the service of the United States as Chair of this year’s Ministerial Council Meeting (MCM), they discussed priorities for the second part of the MCM, scheduled for October 7-8 in Paris. The MCM will focus on addressing shared priorities such as tackling climate change; supporting working families, international taxation, inclusive growth; and championing high standards in the digital economy.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Secretary General Mathias Cormann in Paris. Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Cormann emphasized the enduring importance of the OECD as a body of like-minded countries committed to shared values and the pursuit of a greener and more sustainable and inclusive world, especially as the organization celebrates its 60th anniversary this year. In light of the service of the United States as Chair of this year’s Ministerial Council Meeting (MCM), they discussed priorities for the second part of the MCM, scheduled for October 7-8 in Paris. The MCM will focus on addressing shared priorities such as tackling climate change; supporting working families, international taxation, inclusive growth; and championing high standards in the digital economy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mozambique National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/mozambique-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 13:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I wish to extend best wishes to the people of the Republic of Mozambique as you mark the 46th anniversary of your country’s independence.</p>
<p>The United States values our strategic partnership with Mozambique, including our work together to help ensure all Mozambicans have the opportunity to prosper in a secure and peaceful environment.  We look forward to expanding trade and investment to create new opportunities for both our nations, while confronting a spectrum of challenges, from terrorism and violent extremism to climate change and global pandemics.</p>
<p>On your national day, we reflect on our growing friendship and look ahead to forging even stronger ties in the years to come.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I wish to extend best wishes to the people of the Republic of Mozambique as you mark the 46th anniversary of your country’s independence.</p>
<p>The United States values our strategic partnership with Mozambique, including our work together to help ensure all Mozambicans have the opportunity to prosper in a secure and peaceful environment.  We look forward to expanding trade and investment to create new opportunities for both our nations, while confronting a spectrum of challenges, from terrorism and violent extremism to climate change and global pandemics.</p>
<p>On your national day, we reflect on our growing friendship and look ahead to forging even stronger ties in the years to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Agreement to Prevent Unregulated High Seas Fisheries in the Central Arctic Ocean Enters into Force</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-agreement-to-prevent-unregulated-high-seas-fisheries-in-the-central-arctic-ocean-enters-into-force/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 12:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is pleased to highlight that the Agreement to Prevent Unregulated High Seas Fisheries in the Central Arctic Ocean will enter into force June 25, 2021.  This is the first multilateral agreement of its kind to take a legally binding, precautionary approach to protect an area from commercial fishing before such fishing has begun.</p>
<p>There are currently no commercial fisheries in the Arctic high seas, with most of the region covered by ice year-round.  However, with an ever-increasing ice-free area in the summer, commercial fishing may be possible in the foreseeable future.  The Agreement to Prevent Unregulated High Seas Fisheries in the Central Arctic Ocean aims to manage potential fishing in the high seas of this region.</p>
<p>The United States led the negotiation of the Agreement, which was signed in Greenland on October 3, 2018.  There were ten participants in the negotiation of and Signatories to the Agreement: Canada, the People’s Republic of China, the Kingdom of Denmark (in respect of the Faroe Islands and Greenland), the European Union, Iceland, Japan, the Kingdom of Norway, the Republic of Korea, the Russian Federation, and the United States of America.  The Agreement has two principal objectives: the prevention of unregulated fishing in the high seas portion of the central Arctic Ocean and the facilitation of joint scientific research and monitoring.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is pleased to highlight that the Agreement to Prevent Unregulated High Seas Fisheries in the Central Arctic Ocean will enter into force June 25, 2021.  This is the first multilateral agreement of its kind to take a legally binding, precautionary approach to protect an area from commercial fishing before such fishing has begun.</p>
<p>There are currently no commercial fisheries in the Arctic high seas, with most of the region covered by ice year-round.  However, with an ever-increasing ice-free area in the summer, commercial fishing may be possible in the foreseeable future.  The Agreement to Prevent Unregulated High Seas Fisheries in the Central Arctic Ocean aims to manage potential fishing in the high seas of this region.</p>
<p>The United States led the negotiation of the Agreement, which was signed in Greenland on October 3, 2018.  There were ten participants in the negotiation of and Signatories to the Agreement: Canada, the People’s Republic of China, the Kingdom of Denmark (in respect of the Faroe Islands and Greenland), the European Union, Iceland, Japan, the Kingdom of Norway, the Republic of Korea, the Russian Federation, and the United States of America.  The Agreement has two principal objectives: the prevention of unregulated fishing in the high seas portion of the central Arctic Ocean and the facilitation of joint scientific research and monitoring.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Rene Pfister of Der Spiegel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-rene-pfister-of-der-spiegel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 12:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Berlin, Germany</p>
<p>Berlin Marriott Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me start with a more general question about the German-American relations.  I think as much as European and German officials appreciate U.S. being back on the world stage and re-engaging in multilateralism, there is the fear that the Biden administration might be only a brief return to normal before Trump or a Trumpian figure will take over the White House in ’25.  And my question is:  Do you share the concern that the U.S. democracy is still in a fragile condition, and Europe should therefore try to stand on its own feet?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think we all have to deal with the here and now and the challenges that we’re facing together to try to deal with the – both the problems and opportunities that our citizens are facing around the world.  And what I’ve seen in just the last few months as we’ve been working closely with Germany, with other allies and partners, is that we’re producing meaningful results for our own people and for people around the world.  And ultimately, that’s what matters.  If we continue to do that, if we demonstrate that our democracies can deliver effectively for people, then I think the approach that we’re taking will be sustained.  So our obligation is to actually deliver results.</p>
<p>What we’ve seen, I think, working together – the G7, the NATO summit, the U.S.-EU summit – is exactly that.  Whether it was at the G7, our commitments together to deliver a billion doses of the COVID vaccine with more on top of that; the commitment to stop financing coal-fired plants so that we can really get at climate change – it’s the single biggest source of emissions; the program to, as we call it, Build Back Better for the World, investments we’re making together in infrastructure in low and mid-income countries with a race to the top in terms of the standards of investment; the work that we did at the U.S.-EU summit to end or at least put on pause trade disputes that had been lingering for years – in the case of Airbus and Boeing for 17 years – the steel tariffs.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Working together on trade and technology, setting standards, setting norms.  All of these things are concrete manifestations of the proposition that we not only can, we have to work together to deal with the challenges that are actually having an impact on the lives of our people.  And again, if we do that, if we show success, I think people will sustain that approach to policy and to international collaboration.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me ask you one question.  I mean, obviously, the most difficult issue at the moment between Washington and Berlin is the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.  You made it abundantly clear that President Biden opposes the project, and yet his administration waived sanction for the Nord Stream company and its CEO, Matthias Warnig.</p>
<p>And my question is:  Wasn’t that a huge mistake given the fact that Aleksey Navalny is still in prison, a court in Moscow banned Navalny’s anti-corruption organization, and just two weeks ago at an economic forum in Petersburg, Vladimir Putin made it perfectly clear that he is willing to use Nord Stream as a political weapon against Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  First, as you know, the pipeline began construction in 2018.  By the time we took office in January of this year, it was more than 90 percent complete – the physical construction of the pipeline – and as we went ahead and sanctioned more entities under our law than had ever been sanctioned before.  But the reality of the physical completion of the pipeline was such that we looked to see:  Can we make something out of a very bad hand that we inherited?  Because yes, President Biden has long said that the pipeline is a bad idea, that it will potentially be a tool of Russian economic coercion and strategic coercion, a tool that can be used not only against Ukraine but indeed Europe as a whole to the extent it increases dependence on Russian gas.</p>
<p>But the question before us is what to actually do about this to mitigate or prevent the damage that the pipeline could do if used in the wrong way by President Putin and by Russia, and that’s exactly the conversation we’re now engaged in with Germany.  And I think it’s going to be very important to show by concrete actions that we’ll agree on together and potentially with others that we can prevent or mitigate damage that could be done by the pipeline.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And I mean, obviously, you are paying a big political price for not imposing sanctions to Nord Stream 2.  I mean, you know the situation in Congress.  What do you expect from the German Government in return?  Could a moratorium be a compromise between Germany and the U.S. where the construction is finished but the pipeline would only be put into operation under certain circumstances – for example, the release of Aleksey Navalny?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re in very active discussions with the German Government right now looking at a series of possible steps, actions, measures that we can take to make sure that the pipeline is not used for negative purposes as a tool of coercion or blackmail and that the interests of countries like Ukraine are protected both economically and strategically.  So there are a series of very practical things that we’re looking at, that we’re talking about, and my expectation is that we’ll agree on important measures that, again, can mitigate the – any damage that could be done.</p>
<p>The sanctions that we’ve – that we waived, those waivers can be rescinded.  We have to report again to our Congress in about a month’s time.  So I hope and expect that we’ll show real results from these conversations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, and one more question about Ukraine.  When one looks at the Ukraine crisis, it is very clear that the Normandy format talks that started in 2014 and include France, Germany and Ukraine and Russia, brought little to no progress at all.  And my question is:  Was it a mistake on President Obama’s part to leave the conflict basically to the Europeans?  And isn’t it – and is it now time for the U.S. to play a more active role perhaps in joining the Normandy format talks?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We were very engaged – the United States was very engaged in Ukraine in 2015, 2016.  We respected the proposition that the Normandy format would be the central vehicle for trying to advance the Minsk process, the agreements that were reached, which unfortunately have largely not been implemented by Russia over many years, but that that was the best way forward.  But we were working as well to try to advance that process.</p>
<p>President Biden discussed this with President Putin, and of course, he’s discussed it with Chancellor Merkel, with President Macron and others.  And what we’ve said is, look, if Russia is serious about implementing Minsk and we can be helpful, we’re fully prepared to do that.  But it really starts with the basic question of whether Russia is serious about it or not, or whether it prefers this frozen conflict where it can turn up the heat whenever it feels like it, as it did recently by massing the largest number of troops on Ukraine’s border since 2014.  So the real test is whether Russia is serious or not.</p>
<p>Irrespective of that, we’re committed to Ukraine’s sovereignty, its territorial integrity, its independence, and making sure that it has the means to defend itself from Russian aggression as well as supporting its efforts to deal with the internal aggression posed by corruption and other democratic deficiencies.  So we’re there for Ukraine.  My hope would be that Russia would actually be serious about the Minsk process.  In that case, I think, Normandy can continue to play a central role, but we’re also prepared to be engaged and to try to move it forward, but the question is really with Moscow.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah.  Do you think about naming a special envoy for Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Look, we will look to see how we can best be helpful, if there is actual work to be done, and whether that’s through an envoy, whether that’s through the very experienced and very senior team that we’re putting together, including people who have deep experience with Ukraine.  For example, we – our Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs, one of our most senior officials, Victoria Nuland, is someone who has deep experience in Ukraine.  Our incoming Assistant Secretary of State for Europe when approved by Congress is also someone with deep experience.  So how we do it matters less than whether there’s an opportunity to really move – help move something forward and do it in very close collaboration with Germany, with France, with our partners.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Rene, we have time for a final question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Maybe one last question about the travel ban.  As a couple of days ago, American citizens are allowed to travel to Europe, but U.S. travel ban for citizens who want to travel to the U.S. is still in place.  Can you give us a timeline of when the ban will be lifted and what is the reason why European citizens who are vaccinated are not allowed to travel to the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We’re following the science and following the recommendations of our health authorities, principally the CDC, the Centers for Disease Control.  And that’s where we’re looking for guidance.  That’s where we’re looking for the best information possible upon which to make policy decisions.  We’re very anxious to have travel resume as robustly, as completely, as possible.  We have a working group with the European Union right now on this.  I can’t put a date on it.  I can tell you we’re working very, very actively on it, because we would like nothing better than to see travel pick up.  We have to all be deliberate about it and, again, make these decisions based on our best assessment of the science, our best assessment of health conditions.  That’s what we’re doing, but we’re doing it with the European Union.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Okay.  If you have time, one last question about China.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Go ahead.  One last one and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Just before the Biden administration took over in January 20th, the EU and China agreed on a trade deal that should create new investment opportunities for EU companies in China.  Did you consider that as an unfriendly gesture on part of the EU?  Do you now expect Germany and the EU to take a tougher stance on China?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, what we’re focused on is not trying to contain China or to hold China back.  We’re focused on trying to hold up the free and open, rules-based international system that the United States and Germany together have helped to build and we’ve invested so much in over so many decades.  And if different aspects of that free and open rules-based system are being challenged by anyone, whether it’s China or any other country, then we think it’s important to stand up and defend what we built, because it’s delivered very important results for all of our citizens and can continue to do so.  So that’s the basic approach.  We also recognize that we all have very complicated relationships with China that can’t be summed up in one word or, as we like to say, on a bumper sticker of a car.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>There are adversarial aspects, competitive ones, cooperative ones.  But whether it’s any of those three, our proposition is we’re much better off engaging China together.  We’re going to be much more effective in any of those areas if we’re doing it together.  So that’s what we’re looking towards.  We want to make sure that in any of our engagements with China that we’re upholding the basic norms and standards that bring us together, that we’re – if we’re in a race, it’s a race to the top, not a race to the bottom.  And that goes for the commercial relationship, that goes for the relationship on political and diplomatic issues, and so on.</p>
<p>So when it comes to something like the agreement that was reached, no, the question is not a hostile action.  We just want to make sure that we all have in mind some of the potential challenges that China poses, for example, when it comes to information technology that is so significant in all of our lives.  Unfortunately, if you’re doing business with a so-called private company from China, there is actually no distinction between private and the government.  The government has the ability to control and to elicit information from any of these companies.  And unfortunately, right now when it comes to norms and standards of human rights, of privacy, of intellectual property, the government in Beijing does not meet the standards that we’ve all set.  So I think we have to be careful.  So that’s all that we’re saying.</p>
<p>But what I think we’ve seen especially – just look at the last two weeks.  We’re seeing a convergence of views on the best ways to engage China.  The G7 summit – the last time the G7 leaders met in 2018, China was not even mentioned in the communique.  In this case, there were, I think, important things agreed to by the leaders when it comes to dealing with China.  Similarly at NATO just a couple of days later, the last time that NATO wrote a strategic concept back in 2010, China was not mentioned.  There’s focus on China in NATO as well.  And when we got to the U.S.-EU summit, we’ve agreed to establish between the United States and the EU a trade and technology council that’s going to make sure that when it comes to trade and technology, we’re working together on the norms, on the standards, on the rules in ways that reflect our values.  We re-established the U.S.-EU dialogue on China that had been dormant.</p>
<p>So what I’m seeing increasingly is a shared viewpoint but one that recognizes the complexity of the relationships, the fact that they’re consequential for all of us.  And we’re not asking people to choose between the United States and China.  We’re simply saying we have a common set of values and interests that have helped shape the international system for almost eight decades, and we need to continue to stand for freedom and for openness when it comes to that system and to do it together.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So thank you so much for your time, Mr. Secretary, and I hope I see you in Washington.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  See you Washington.  Thank you.  Good to be with you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Berlin, Germany</p>
<p>Berlin Marriott Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me start with a more general question about the German-American relations.  I think as much as European and German officials appreciate U.S. being back on the world stage and re-engaging in multilateralism, there is the fear that the Biden administration might be only a brief return to normal before Trump or a Trumpian figure will take over the White House in ’25.  And my question is:  Do you share the concern that the U.S. democracy is still in a fragile condition, and Europe should therefore try to stand on its own feet?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think we all have to deal with the here and now and the challenges that we’re facing together to try to deal with the – both the problems and opportunities that our citizens are facing around the world.  And what I’ve seen in just the last few months as we’ve been working closely with Germany, with other allies and partners, is that we’re producing meaningful results for our own people and for people around the world.  And ultimately, that’s what matters.  If we continue to do that, if we demonstrate that our democracies can deliver effectively for people, then I think the approach that we’re taking will be sustained.  So our obligation is to actually deliver results.</p>
<p>What we’ve seen, I think, working together – the G7, the NATO summit, the U.S.-EU summit – is exactly that.  Whether it was at the G7, our commitments together to deliver a billion doses of the COVID vaccine with more on top of that; the commitment to stop financing coal-fired plants so that we can really get at climate change – it’s the single biggest source of emissions; the program to, as we call it, Build Back Better for the World, investments we’re making together in infrastructure in low and mid-income countries with a race to the top in terms of the standards of investment; the work that we did at the U.S.-EU summit to end or at least put on pause trade disputes that had been lingering for years – in the case of Airbus and Boeing for 17 years – the steel tariffs.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Working together on trade and technology, setting standards, setting norms.  All of these things are concrete manifestations of the proposition that we not only can, we have to work together to deal with the challenges that are actually having an impact on the lives of our people.  And again, if we do that, if we show success, I think people will sustain that approach to policy and to international collaboration.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me ask you one question.  I mean, obviously, the most difficult issue at the moment between Washington and Berlin is the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.  You made it abundantly clear that President Biden opposes the project, and yet his administration waived sanction for the Nord Stream company and its CEO, Matthias Warnig.</p>
<p>And my question is:  Wasn’t that a huge mistake given the fact that Aleksey Navalny is still in prison, a court in Moscow banned Navalny’s anti-corruption organization, and just two weeks ago at an economic forum in Petersburg, Vladimir Putin made it perfectly clear that he is willing to use Nord Stream as a political weapon against Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  First, as you know, the pipeline began construction in 2018.  By the time we took office in January of this year, it was more than 90 percent complete – the physical construction of the pipeline – and as we went ahead and sanctioned more entities under our law than had ever been sanctioned before.  But the reality of the physical completion of the pipeline was such that we looked to see:  Can we make something out of a very bad hand that we inherited?  Because yes, President Biden has long said that the pipeline is a bad idea, that it will potentially be a tool of Russian economic coercion and strategic coercion, a tool that can be used not only against Ukraine but indeed Europe as a whole to the extent it increases dependence on Russian gas.</p>
<p>But the question before us is what to actually do about this to mitigate or prevent the damage that the pipeline could do if used in the wrong way by President Putin and by Russia, and that’s exactly the conversation we’re now engaged in with Germany.  And I think it’s going to be very important to show by concrete actions that we’ll agree on together and potentially with others that we can prevent or mitigate damage that could be done by the pipeline.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And I mean, obviously, you are paying a big political price for not imposing sanctions to Nord Stream 2.  I mean, you know the situation in Congress.  What do you expect from the German Government in return?  Could a moratorium be a compromise between Germany and the U.S. where the construction is finished but the pipeline would only be put into operation under certain circumstances – for example, the release of Aleksey Navalny?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re in very active discussions with the German Government right now looking at a series of possible steps, actions, measures that we can take to make sure that the pipeline is not used for negative purposes as a tool of coercion or blackmail and that the interests of countries like Ukraine are protected both economically and strategically.  So there are a series of very practical things that we’re looking at, that we’re talking about, and my expectation is that we’ll agree on important measures that, again, can mitigate the – any damage that could be done.</p>
<p>The sanctions that we’ve – that we waived, those waivers can be rescinded.  We have to report again to our Congress in about a month’s time.  So I hope and expect that we’ll show real results from these conversations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, and one more question about Ukraine.  When one looks at the Ukraine crisis, it is very clear that the Normandy format talks that started in 2014 and include France, Germany and Ukraine and Russia, brought little to no progress at all.  And my question is:  Was it a mistake on President Obama’s part to leave the conflict basically to the Europeans?  And isn’t it – and is it now time for the U.S. to play a more active role perhaps in joining the Normandy format talks?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We were very engaged – the United States was very engaged in Ukraine in 2015, 2016.  We respected the proposition that the Normandy format would be the central vehicle for trying to advance the Minsk process, the agreements that were reached, which unfortunately have largely not been implemented by Russia over many years, but that that was the best way forward.  But we were working as well to try to advance that process.</p>
<p>President Biden discussed this with President Putin, and of course, he’s discussed it with Chancellor Merkel, with President Macron and others.  And what we’ve said is, look, if Russia is serious about implementing Minsk and we can be helpful, we’re fully prepared to do that.  But it really starts with the basic question of whether Russia is serious about it or not, or whether it prefers this frozen conflict where it can turn up the heat whenever it feels like it, as it did recently by massing the largest number of troops on Ukraine’s border since 2014.  So the real test is whether Russia is serious or not.</p>
<p>Irrespective of that, we’re committed to Ukraine’s sovereignty, its territorial integrity, its independence, and making sure that it has the means to defend itself from Russian aggression as well as supporting its efforts to deal with the internal aggression posed by corruption and other democratic deficiencies.  So we’re there for Ukraine.  My hope would be that Russia would actually be serious about the Minsk process.  In that case, I think, Normandy can continue to play a central role, but we’re also prepared to be engaged and to try to move it forward, but the question is really with Moscow.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah.  Do you think about naming a special envoy for Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Look, we will look to see how we can best be helpful, if there is actual work to be done, and whether that’s through an envoy, whether that’s through the very experienced and very senior team that we’re putting together, including people who have deep experience with Ukraine.  For example, we – our Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs, one of our most senior officials, Victoria Nuland, is someone who has deep experience in Ukraine.  Our incoming Assistant Secretary of State for Europe when approved by Congress is also someone with deep experience.  So how we do it matters less than whether there’s an opportunity to really move – help move something forward and do it in very close collaboration with Germany, with France, with our partners.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Rene, we have time for a final question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Maybe one last question about the travel ban.  As a couple of days ago, American citizens are allowed to travel to Europe, but U.S. travel ban for citizens who want to travel to the U.S. is still in place.  Can you give us a timeline of when the ban will be lifted and what is the reason why European citizens who are vaccinated are not allowed to travel to the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We’re following the science and following the recommendations of our health authorities, principally the CDC, the Centers for Disease Control.  And that’s where we’re looking for guidance.  That’s where we’re looking for the best information possible upon which to make policy decisions.  We’re very anxious to have travel resume as robustly, as completely, as possible.  We have a working group with the European Union right now on this.  I can’t put a date on it.  I can tell you we’re working very, very actively on it, because we would like nothing better than to see travel pick up.  We have to all be deliberate about it and, again, make these decisions based on our best assessment of the science, our best assessment of health conditions.  That’s what we’re doing, but we’re doing it with the European Union.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Okay.  If you have time, one last question about China.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Go ahead.  One last one and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Just before the Biden administration took over in January 20th, the EU and China agreed on a trade deal that should create new investment opportunities for EU companies in China.  Did you consider that as an unfriendly gesture on part of the EU?  Do you now expect Germany and the EU to take a tougher stance on China?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, what we’re focused on is not trying to contain China or to hold China back.  We’re focused on trying to hold up the free and open, rules-based international system that the United States and Germany together have helped to build and we’ve invested so much in over so many decades.  And if different aspects of that free and open rules-based system are being challenged by anyone, whether it’s China or any other country, then we think it’s important to stand up and defend what we built, because it’s delivered very important results for all of our citizens and can continue to do so.  So that’s the basic approach.  We also recognize that we all have very complicated relationships with China that can’t be summed up in one word or, as we like to say, on a bumper sticker of a car.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>There are adversarial aspects, competitive ones, cooperative ones.  But whether it’s any of those three, our proposition is we’re much better off engaging China together.  We’re going to be much more effective in any of those areas if we’re doing it together.  So that’s what we’re looking towards.  We want to make sure that in any of our engagements with China that we’re upholding the basic norms and standards that bring us together, that we’re – if we’re in a race, it’s a race to the top, not a race to the bottom.  And that goes for the commercial relationship, that goes for the relationship on political and diplomatic issues, and so on.</p>
<p>So when it comes to something like the agreement that was reached, no, the question is not a hostile action.  We just want to make sure that we all have in mind some of the potential challenges that China poses, for example, when it comes to information technology that is so significant in all of our lives.  Unfortunately, if you’re doing business with a so-called private company from China, there is actually no distinction between private and the government.  The government has the ability to control and to elicit information from any of these companies.  And unfortunately, right now when it comes to norms and standards of human rights, of privacy, of intellectual property, the government in Beijing does not meet the standards that we’ve all set.  So I think we have to be careful.  So that’s all that we’re saying.</p>
<p>But what I think we’ve seen especially – just look at the last two weeks.  We’re seeing a convergence of views on the best ways to engage China.  The G7 summit – the last time the G7 leaders met in 2018, China was not even mentioned in the communique.  In this case, there were, I think, important things agreed to by the leaders when it comes to dealing with China.  Similarly at NATO just a couple of days later, the last time that NATO wrote a strategic concept back in 2010, China was not mentioned.  There’s focus on China in NATO as well.  And when we got to the U.S.-EU summit, we’ve agreed to establish between the United States and the EU a trade and technology council that’s going to make sure that when it comes to trade and technology, we’re working together on the norms, on the standards, on the rules in ways that reflect our values.  We re-established the U.S.-EU dialogue on China that had been dormant.</p>
<p>So what I’m seeing increasingly is a shared viewpoint but one that recognizes the complexity of the relationships, the fact that they’re consequential for all of us.  And we’re not asking people to choose between the United States and China.  We’re simply saying we have a common set of values and interests that have helped shape the international system for almost eight decades, and we need to continue to stand for freedom and for openness when it comes to that system and to do it together.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So thank you so much for your time, Mr. Secretary, and I hope I see you in Washington.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  See you Washington.  Thank you.  Good to be with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; June 24, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-24-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 22:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=254916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Good afternoon, and thank you for joining today’s daily press briefing.  I have three updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>As you know, the Secretary arrived in Berlin yesterday for a multi-leg European trip that would also take him to Paris, Rome, Bari and Matera.  This trip gives the Secretary a chance to follow up on the President’s successful trip to the region last week and continued discussions with key partners to underscore the U.S. commitment to a strong transatlantic partnership.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary met with Chancellor Merkel and Foreign Minister Maas to discuss how we can further strengthen the U.S.-Germany relationship to address common challenges, including recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, as well as China and Russia.  The Secretary also participated in the second Berlin conference on Libya which was an opportunity for the international community to support the progress made by the Libyan people and underscore our support for the full implementation of the relevant UN Security Council resolutions and the October 2020 nationwide ceasefire agreement.</p>
<p>Today, the Secretary and Foreign Minister Maas launched the initial meeting of the U.S.-Germany Dialogue on the Holocaust to highlight our shared commitment to combating anti-Semitism and Holocaust denial and distortion and to find innovative new ways to enhance Holocaust education.  The leaders used this opportunity to emphasize how anti-Semitism is rising around the world and such hatred and prejudice are inimical to U.S. and transatlantic interests and values.</p>
<p>The Secretary departs this evening for Paris where he will continue his discussion with European leaders.</p>
<p>Next, I am pleased to announce that 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine will arrive in Campinas, Brazil tomorrow morning.</p>
<p>This donation is a part of 80 million doses that President Biden announced on May 17th and is the result of close collaboration between the governments of the United States and Brazil toward putting an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>As President Biden has said, the United States is committed to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts as we have demonstrated right here at home.</p>
<p>We are sharing these vaccines to save lives and to lead the world into bringing an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>We’re working to get as many safe and effective vaccine doses to as many people around the world as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>Thanks to the innovation of U.S. companies and the resilience of and commitment of American people, we&#8217;re in a position to help others.</p>
<p>The United States congratulates law professor Gay McDougall on her election as an independent expert on the Committee on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination or CERD.  Given her extensive legal and international human rights experience, including two previous terms on the Committee, the United States considers Professor McDougall a highly qualified expert who has made and who will continue to make valuable contributions to the Committee.</p>
<p>Racial justice is at the forefront of our international engagements, as demonstrated by our engagement at the UN Human Rights Council (HRC) 46th session where we led a statement addressing systemic racism signed by 158 nations, our nomination of Professor McDougall to the CERD, and submitting overdue report on the CERD on June 2nd.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to engage the international community to find effective means to address systemic racism both at home and around the world.</p>
<p>And finally, leaders from 16 Southern African Development Community nations held a summit in Mozambique Wednesday June 23rd, 2021.  We applaud the Southern African Development Community’s focus on the threat of terrorism in Mozambique, as ISIS is not an isolated problem but rather a regional – a broader regional concern.</p>
<p>The United States is also committed to supporting the Government of Mozambique to counter terrorism and combat violent extremism with a holistic strategy that also includes socio-economic development, community resilience programs, and security assistance, as well as humanitarian aid.  We look forward to learning more of the South African Development Communities – Development Community, excuse me, plan coming out of the summit, and we will underscore the importance of keeping civilian protection and respect for human rights at the forefront of all security assistance.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Jiha, your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  I have a question related to Otto Warmbier, the University of Virginia student who was tortured by North Korea and later sent back home, but died in 2017.  New York City mayor Bill de Blasio and the council members of the city have been endorsing a bill that can change the name of their – one of their streets to Otto Warmbier Way to commemorate Otto Warmbier.  And the street that they want to rename is located right in front of the New York North Korean mission to the UN.  So I’m wondering if you support this idea or whether you have any concerns as the host country of the foreign missions to the UN.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Well, I’ll start off by saying that we certainly will continue to express our deepest condolences to the Warmbier family.  With respect to your question on the street naming and where specifically it is in New York City, I’d have to refer you back to the mayor of New York City and all the local officials in New York City for those specific decisions being made.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?  Yeah.  Thank you very kindly.  Very quickly, today Palestinian Authority security forces arrested a Palestinian activist and he died in custody.  I wonder if you have a position on this, because this really comes at the heels of many abuses by the Palestinian security forces against Palestinian activists.</p>
<p>And my second question is the fact that Senator Risch is holding $50 million in aid to the Palestinians that was approved by Congress.  Do you have – also have a comment on that?  Thank you, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Thank you for your question, Said.  So I’m going to start with your second question first.  For that, we simply won’t comment on the holds, and for that I’d have to send you back to Senator Risch’s office for any specific commentary.</p>
<p>To your first question, I’ll just say that we’re deeply disturbed by the death of Palestinian activist Nizar Banat and the information that has been reported regarding the circumstances surrounding his death.  We certainly also offer our sincere condolences not only to his family but as well as the community who’s been impacted by his death.  We urge the Palestinian Authority to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation and to also ensure full accountability in this case.  And we also strongly encourage the Palestinian Authority to respect the rights to free expression as well as the work of civil society.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jen Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Thanks for doing this.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you.  On the SIV issue, I was wondering whether you could tell us anything about the role the State Department is playing in the planning for a potential evacuation to a third country.  Which countries are under consideration for relocating the SIV applicants?  And then is anyone from the State Department meeting with anybody from the Afghan delegation that is in D.C. right now?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question, I don’t have anything to announce or report out.  But to your first question, we are identifying SIV applicants who have served as interpreters as well as translators to be relocated outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown by September, in order to safely complete the remainder of the Special Immigrant Visa application process.  These are individuals who are actually already in the SIV pipeline.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Abigail Williams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks so much, Jalina.  Following up on Jenny’s question regarding SIVs, I wanted to ask if you have any updated numbers on where you are in the process at looking at the 18,000 applicants.  I know that Secretary Blinken had spoken of 9,000 being towards the beginning process and another 9,000 waiting and face delays.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  No, I don’t have any specific updates in regards to numbers, but just will continue to underscore that we have said that we’re committed to supporting those who’ve helped the military as well as other government personnel with their duties, of course often at great personal risk, not only to themselves but to their family members.  And we’re continuing to work on every way possible to make sure we can help those who have helped us.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Oskar Gorzynski.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.  Did I say your name correctly?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.  Yeah, that’s pretty much right, as good as it gets.  So I wanted to ask about today’s meeting between German Minister of Economy Peter Altmaier and Secretary Kerry.  Do you have any information that – what are the topics?  And there have – relatedly, this week German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas said that he expects a deal with the U.S. on Nord Stream 2 by August.  Is that the State Department’s assessment as well, and what would such a deal include?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  I’ll take your second question first.  We have nothing to announce when it comes to any specific deadlines, but we’ll continue to underscore that the President has made rebuilding our relationship with our allies – and of course that would include Germany administration priority – the strength of these relationships will lay the foundation for many of our foreign policy priorities, such as economic recovery, recovery in combating COVID-19, as well as pushing back on the PRC and authoritarianism around the world.</p>
<p>To your first question, we don’t have anything to announce.  We’ll have to take that back and get back to you on the meeting you mentioned with Secretary Kerry.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thanks very much, Jalina.  Just to follow up on the Afghanistan question, do you have a sense for where you may send those folks who worked for the U.S. while they await processing their SIV visas?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So thank you for your question, Nick.  I don’t have anything to share about specific locations at this time, but I will say that we would take under any relocation in full compliance with all the applicable laws as well as in full coordination with Congress.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jose Luis Sanz.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  So Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, well a couple of questions about Central America.  First one is about Nicaragua.  The fact that the repression and the detention of opposition leaders or journalists has continued means that the sanctions and the international community and the United States strategy is not working, and how do you expect to continue trying to help to (inaudible) on transpiring election in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>And the second one is about the request to El Salvador for the extradition of MS-13 members.  Can you confirm how many of them has been – already been made by the United States?  I’m talking about the case that is being seen in New York.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question about MS-13 members and El Salvador, I’ll have to refer you to the Department of Justice.  And to your first question about Nicaragua, what I’ll say largely speaking is that, of course, the courage of the Nicaraguan people is admirable.  And we will continue to support them in the United States.  We’ll also continue to use all of our diplomatic and economic tools at our disposal to support Nicaraguans’ call for greater freedoms as well as accountability.  And of course, that would also include free and fair elections.</p>
<p>Thank you for your questions.  That’s all we have time for today, and I hope you have a great week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:24 p.m.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Good afternoon, and thank you for joining today’s daily press briefing.  I have three updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>As you know, the Secretary arrived in Berlin yesterday for a multi-leg European trip that would also take him to Paris, Rome, Bari and Matera.  This trip gives the Secretary a chance to follow up on the President’s successful trip to the region last week and continued discussions with key partners to underscore the U.S. commitment to a strong transatlantic partnership.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary met with Chancellor Merkel and Foreign Minister Maas to discuss how we can further strengthen the U.S.-Germany relationship to address common challenges, including recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, as well as China and Russia.  The Secretary also participated in the second Berlin conference on Libya which was an opportunity for the international community to support the progress made by the Libyan people and underscore our support for the full implementation of the relevant UN Security Council resolutions and the October 2020 nationwide ceasefire agreement.</p>
<p>Today, the Secretary and Foreign Minister Maas launched the initial meeting of the U.S.-Germany Dialogue on the Holocaust to highlight our shared commitment to combating anti-Semitism and Holocaust denial and distortion and to find innovative new ways to enhance Holocaust education.  The leaders used this opportunity to emphasize how anti-Semitism is rising around the world and such hatred and prejudice are inimical to U.S. and transatlantic interests and values.</p>
<p>The Secretary departs this evening for Paris where he will continue his discussion with European leaders.</p>
<p>Next, I am pleased to announce that 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine will arrive in Campinas, Brazil tomorrow morning.</p>
<p>This donation is a part of 80 million doses that President Biden announced on May 17th and is the result of close collaboration between the governments of the United States and Brazil toward putting an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>As President Biden has said, the United States is committed to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts as we have demonstrated right here at home.</p>
<p>We are sharing these vaccines to save lives and to lead the world into bringing an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>We’re working to get as many safe and effective vaccine doses to as many people around the world as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>Thanks to the innovation of U.S. companies and the resilience of and commitment of American people, we&#8217;re in a position to help others.</p>
<p>The United States congratulates law professor Gay McDougall on her election as an independent expert on the Committee on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination or CERD.  Given her extensive legal and international human rights experience, including two previous terms on the Committee, the United States considers Professor McDougall a highly qualified expert who has made and who will continue to make valuable contributions to the Committee.</p>
<p>Racial justice is at the forefront of our international engagements, as demonstrated by our engagement at the UN Human Rights Council (HRC) 46th session where we led a statement addressing systemic racism signed by 158 nations, our nomination of Professor McDougall to the CERD, and submitting overdue report on the CERD on June 2nd.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to engage the international community to find effective means to address systemic racism both at home and around the world.</p>
<p>And finally, leaders from 16 Southern African Development Community nations held a summit in Mozambique Wednesday June 23rd, 2021.  We applaud the Southern African Development Community’s focus on the threat of terrorism in Mozambique, as ISIS is not an isolated problem but rather a regional – a broader regional concern.</p>
<p>The United States is also committed to supporting the Government of Mozambique to counter terrorism and combat violent extremism with a holistic strategy that also includes socio-economic development, community resilience programs, and security assistance, as well as humanitarian aid.  We look forward to learning more of the South African Development Communities – Development Community, excuse me, plan coming out of the summit, and we will underscore the importance of keeping civilian protection and respect for human rights at the forefront of all security assistance.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Jiha, your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  I have a question related to Otto Warmbier, the University of Virginia student who was tortured by North Korea and later sent back home, but died in 2017.  New York City mayor Bill de Blasio and the council members of the city have been endorsing a bill that can change the name of their – one of their streets to Otto Warmbier Way to commemorate Otto Warmbier.  And the street that they want to rename is located right in front of the New York North Korean mission to the UN.  So I’m wondering if you support this idea or whether you have any concerns as the host country of the foreign missions to the UN.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Well, I’ll start off by saying that we certainly will continue to express our deepest condolences to the Warmbier family.  With respect to your question on the street naming and where specifically it is in New York City, I’d have to refer you back to the mayor of New York City and all the local officials in New York City for those specific decisions being made.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?  Yeah.  Thank you very kindly.  Very quickly, today Palestinian Authority security forces arrested a Palestinian activist and he died in custody.  I wonder if you have a position on this, because this really comes at the heels of many abuses by the Palestinian security forces against Palestinian activists.</p>
<p>And my second question is the fact that Senator Risch is holding $50 million in aid to the Palestinians that was approved by Congress.  Do you have – also have a comment on that?  Thank you, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Thank you for your question, Said.  So I’m going to start with your second question first.  For that, we simply won’t comment on the holds, and for that I’d have to send you back to Senator Risch’s office for any specific commentary.</p>
<p>To your first question, I’ll just say that we’re deeply disturbed by the death of Palestinian activist Nizar Banat and the information that has been reported regarding the circumstances surrounding his death.  We certainly also offer our sincere condolences not only to his family but as well as the community who’s been impacted by his death.  We urge the Palestinian Authority to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation and to also ensure full accountability in this case.  And we also strongly encourage the Palestinian Authority to respect the rights to free expression as well as the work of civil society.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jen Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Thanks for doing this.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you.  On the SIV issue, I was wondering whether you could tell us anything about the role the State Department is playing in the planning for a potential evacuation to a third country.  Which countries are under consideration for relocating the SIV applicants?  And then is anyone from the State Department meeting with anybody from the Afghan delegation that is in D.C. right now?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question, I don’t have anything to announce or report out.  But to your first question, we are identifying SIV applicants who have served as interpreters as well as translators to be relocated outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown by September, in order to safely complete the remainder of the Special Immigrant Visa application process.  These are individuals who are actually already in the SIV pipeline.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Abigail Williams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks so much, Jalina.  Following up on Jenny’s question regarding SIVs, I wanted to ask if you have any updated numbers on where you are in the process at looking at the 18,000 applicants.  I know that Secretary Blinken had spoken of 9,000 being towards the beginning process and another 9,000 waiting and face delays.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  No, I don’t have any specific updates in regards to numbers, but just will continue to underscore that we have said that we’re committed to supporting those who’ve helped the military as well as other government personnel with their duties, of course often at great personal risk, not only to themselves but to their family members.  And we’re continuing to work on every way possible to make sure we can help those who have helped us.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Oskar Gorzynski.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.  Did I say your name correctly?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.  Yeah, that’s pretty much right, as good as it gets.  So I wanted to ask about today’s meeting between German Minister of Economy Peter Altmaier and Secretary Kerry.  Do you have any information that – what are the topics?  And there have – relatedly, this week German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas said that he expects a deal with the U.S. on Nord Stream 2 by August.  Is that the State Department’s assessment as well, and what would such a deal include?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  I’ll take your second question first.  We have nothing to announce when it comes to any specific deadlines, but we’ll continue to underscore that the President has made rebuilding our relationship with our allies – and of course that would include Germany administration priority – the strength of these relationships will lay the foundation for many of our foreign policy priorities, such as economic recovery, recovery in combating COVID-19, as well as pushing back on the PRC and authoritarianism around the world.</p>
<p>To your first question, we don’t have anything to announce.  We’ll have to take that back and get back to you on the meeting you mentioned with Secretary Kerry.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thanks very much, Jalina.  Just to follow up on the Afghanistan question, do you have a sense for where you may send those folks who worked for the U.S. while they await processing their SIV visas?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So thank you for your question, Nick.  I don’t have anything to share about specific locations at this time, but I will say that we would take under any relocation in full compliance with all the applicable laws as well as in full coordination with Congress.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jose Luis Sanz.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  So Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, well a couple of questions about Central America.  First one is about Nicaragua.  The fact that the repression and the detention of opposition leaders or journalists has continued means that the sanctions and the international community and the United States strategy is not working, and how do you expect to continue trying to help to (inaudible) on transpiring election in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>And the second one is about the request to El Salvador for the extradition of MS-13 members.  Can you confirm how many of them has been – already been made by the United States?  I’m talking about the case that is being seen in New York.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question about MS-13 members and El Salvador, I’ll have to refer you to the Department of Justice.  And to your first question about Nicaragua, what I’ll say largely speaking is that, of course, the courage of the Nicaraguan people is admirable.  And we will continue to support them in the United States.  We’ll also continue to use all of our diplomatic and economic tools at our disposal to support Nicaraguans’ call for greater freedoms as well as accountability.  And of course, that would also include free and fair elections.</p>
<p>Thank you for your questions.  That’s all we have time for today, and I hope you have a great week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:24 p.m.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
