<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 20:53:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary McKeon Visits Harvard Business School for The Secretary’s Leadership Seminar Graduation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-mckeon-visits-harvard-business-school-for-the-secretarys-leadership-seminar-graduation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 20:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=322124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon will travel to Boston, Massachusetts on March 10 to speak at the graduation ceremony for the second cohort of The Secretary’s Leadership Seminar: A Harvard Business School Executive Education Program developed for the U.S. Department of State.  The graduation ceremony will take place on March 11, 2022.</p>
<p>The six-month seminar is designed to develop a diverse group of emerging leaders who will advance the Department’s mission by taking innovative approaches to enterprise-wide challenges in an inclusive and collaborative atmosphere.  Twenty-five mid-level Civil Service and twenty-five mid-level Foreign Service Department employees will complete the program in March.</p>
<p>In 2019, philanthropist and Harvard alumnus Howard Cox approached the Department to propose a relationship with Harvard Business School (HBS) aimed at enhancing workforce leadership training.  The seminar is the result of his engagement and ongoing collaboration between HBS and the Department.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon will travel to Boston, Massachusetts on March 10 to speak at the graduation ceremony for the second cohort of The Secretary’s Leadership Seminar: A Harvard Business School Executive Education Program developed for the U.S. Department of State.  The graduation ceremony will take place on March 11, 2022.</p>
<p>The six-month seminar is designed to develop a diverse group of emerging leaders who will advance the Department’s mission by taking innovative approaches to enterprise-wide challenges in an inclusive and collaborative atmosphere.  Twenty-five mid-level Civil Service and twenty-five mid-level Foreign Service Department employees will complete the program in March.</p>
<p>In 2019, philanthropist and Harvard alumnus Howard Cox approached the Department to propose a relationship with Harvard Business School (HBS) aimed at enhancing workforce leadership training.  The seminar is the result of his engagement and ongoing collaboration between HBS and the Department.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guatemala’s Public Ministry’s Continued Attacks Against Independent Judges and Prosecutors</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/guatemalas-public-ministrys-continued-attacks-against-independent-judges-and-prosecutors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 20:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=322116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned by Guatemalan Attorney General Consuelo Porras’ continued, brazen attacks on Guatemala’s justice system through politically motivated arrests and detentions of current and former public servants fighting corruption. The reports of repeated, uncommon delays in arraignment hearings, the withholding of information to defense counsels, refusals to hold hearings publicly, and leaks of sealed case details to online entities raise serious concerns regarding the fairness of these proceedings. In addition to the arrest of at least six former and current anti-corruption prosecutors, other prosecutors have been forced to flee the country and efforts continue to remove the immunity of additional anti-corruption judges and prosecutors. We are also alarmed that procedural delays often place public servants in the same facilities with those they have helped investigate or convict, leading to serious risks to their safety.</p>
<p>The United States calls on the Government of Guatemala to respect the human rights of all individuals, including by guaranteeing fair trials and ensuring the personal safety and fair and transparent treatment of all justice sector actors. The Attorney General’s efforts to target anticorruption and other prosecutors follow a disturbing trend of corruption and the weakening of democratic institutions and processes in Guatemala.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned by Guatemalan Attorney General Consuelo Porras’ continued, brazen attacks on Guatemala’s justice system through politically motivated arrests and detentions of current and former public servants fighting corruption. The reports of repeated, uncommon delays in arraignment hearings, the withholding of information to defense counsels, refusals to hold hearings publicly, and leaks of sealed case details to online entities raise serious concerns regarding the fairness of these proceedings. In addition to the arrest of at least six former and current anti-corruption prosecutors, other prosecutors have been forced to flee the country and efforts continue to remove the immunity of additional anti-corruption judges and prosecutors. We are also alarmed that procedural delays often place public servants in the same facilities with those they have helped investigate or convict, leading to serious risks to their safety.</p>
<p>The United States calls on the Government of Guatemala to respect the human rights of all individuals, including by guaranteeing fair trials and ensuring the personal safety and fair and transparent treatment of all justice sector actors. The Attorney General’s efforts to target anticorruption and other prosecutors follow a disturbing trend of corruption and the weakening of democratic institutions and processes in Guatemala.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with the United Arab Emirates Foreign Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-the-united-arab-emirates-foreign-minister-sheikh-abdullah-bin-zayed-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 20:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=322105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the UAE Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed cooperation to advance peace and security at the UN Security Council. Secretary Blinken reiterated the value of close coordination on Ukraine and the importance of building a strong international response to support Ukrainian democracy and sovereignty following Russia&#8217;s premeditated, unprovoked and unlawful invasion. The Secretary also underscored the U.S. commitment to help the UAE bolster its strong defensive capabilities against threats from Yemen and elsewhere in the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the UAE Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed cooperation to advance peace and security at the UN Security Council. Secretary Blinken reiterated the value of close coordination on Ukraine and the importance of building a strong international response to support Ukrainian democracy and sovereignty following Russia&#8217;s premeditated, unprovoked and unlawful invasion. The Secretary also underscored the U.S. commitment to help the UAE bolster its strong defensive capabilities against threats from Yemen and elsewhere in the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French President Macron</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-president-macron-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 19:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=322068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with French President Emmanuel Macron in Paris. Secretary Blinken and President Macron agreed on the need for continued strong U.S.-France cooperation in the face of the Russian government’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They discussed ongoing efforts to provide assistance for the government and people of Ukraine and reaffirmed their commitment to impose significant costs on President Putin and his associates for as long as they continue their war of choice in Ukraine. The Secretary and President compared notes on ongoing diplomacy to diminish the violence and bring the Kremlin’s war to a halt. They also agreed to continue close coordination on Iran and efforts to reach a deal in Vienna ensuring mutual return to full compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with French President Emmanuel Macron in Paris. Secretary Blinken and President Macron agreed on the need for continued strong U.S.-France cooperation in the face of the Russian government’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They discussed ongoing efforts to provide assistance for the government and people of Ukraine and reaffirmed their commitment to impose significant costs on President Putin and his associates for as long as they continue their war of choice in Ukraine. The Secretary and President compared notes on ongoing diplomacy to diminish the violence and bring the Kremlin’s war to a halt. They also agreed to continue close coordination on Iran and efforts to reach a deal in Vienna ensuring mutual return to full compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Meet and Greet with Embassy Tallinn Personnel and Families</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-meet-and-greet-with-embassy-tallinn-personnel-and-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 19:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=322053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Tallinn, Estonia</p>
<p>Swissotel</p>
<p><strong>MR ROAROFF:</strong>  Thank you for your patience.  It’s been a busy but wonderful morning welcoming Secretary Blinken to Tallinn.</p>
<p>Just a couple quick remarks of introduction and thanks, and then we’ll open it up for questions after some comments by the Secretary.  I just wanted to start by saying: Secretary Blinken, thank you for making this trilateral visit.  We know that you and your team, this is the last in a long trip – six or seven countries, we’ll call it seven so far with your foray into Ukraine with the foreign minister.  That was great.  So thank you for coming and reassuring our Estonian allies.</p>
<p>I think you know, and the foreign minister gave you an article, that this is the first bilateral trip of a Secretary of State to Estonia since 1991.  Do read that article; it is interesting.  That trip took place in September 1991, a month after the coup attempt when hardliners tried to overthrow Gorbachev in Moscow.  The message that Secretary Baker heard at that time from Estonia, from the Baltics, was:  The hardliners will come back, please help us; they’re going to come back and try to snuff out your independence.  So 30 years later, the region still faces a Russian threat.</p>
<p>Today, everybody in front of you is working hard with our Estonian partners to support Ukraine.  The brutal attack on Ukraine hits very close to a lot of us here.  We are working on security assistance.  We’re working on isolating Russia in traditional organizations.  We all have our heart in it, and we’re going to do our utmost to support Ukraine.</p>
<p>Finally, I’m just so proud to introduce you to the staff of Embassy Tallinn.  This is the best staff I have worked with in my 20 years in the State Department.  We’ve gone through COVID together, but we haven’t lost a step.  We have a number of policy victories we can point to, and we’ve also kept our people safe.</p>
<p>I would wrap it up just by saying we have not had an ambassador since 2018.  There is not one American in this room who has worked at this embassy who has worked under an ambassador.  This is a great tribute to our Estonian staff.  The fact that we are such a strong embassy, that we have not missed a beat, that we keep advancing policy forward is because of our Estonian colleagues, and we are forever grateful for them.</p>
<p>So with that, we welcome you to Estonia, and please, let me introduce you to the staff of Embassy Tallinn.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It is wonderful to see each and every one of you here today.  And let me say to the chargé, there’s another reason why this mission is performing so well, and that’s your leadership here.  I’m grateful for it, the partnership is grateful for it, and it’s, I think, important to be here at this particular time.</p>
<p>I was struck – I hadn’t realized that the last time a Secretary of State was here on a bilateral basis was Secretary Baker in 1991.  There’s something to me that’s very poignant about that, because I have tremendous reverence for Secretary Baker, someone I admire a great deal.  And the historic resonance, given what’s happening today, could not be more powerful.  So if even there’s any small way in which I can be following in his footsteps, with the extraordinary leadership he showed at that pivot point in history, that will be a good thing.</p>
<p>You know this because you’re living it every day – you’re living it with our Estonian friends, partners, allies, for the locally employed staff who are Estonian – you feel this.  You know what is at stake with this Russian aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We’re seeing the stakes on a very personal and individual level with the suffering of the Ukrainian people, the destruction that we’re seeing in Ukraine, the now more than 1.7 million people who had to flee the country for their safety, the hundreds of thousands more who are internally displaced, people living in besieged cities where they don’t have access to food and water, to medicine – nothing can come in, and they can’t get out safely.</p>
<p>So I know that you know and you feel the personal stakes and the lives that have been lost, the lives that have been changed.</p>
<p>I think friends here in Estonia and you also know why this is also about even more than Ukraine, and why it matters to the United States, why it matters to countries in Europe, why it matters to countries around the world.  And that’s because some of the foundational principles of the order that we tried to help establish over many years to keep peace and security, however imperfectly, that those principles are being challenged, that order is being challenged.  And if we allow that to stand with impunity, then we open a Pandora’s Box where this will not be the last conflict that we see – it will be the first of more to come.  So we have a profound interest in doing everything we can to end Russia’s war of aggression in Ukraine, and it’s an interest that is felt very profoundly here.</p>
<p>The President asked me to come here now to Estonia, but also to Lithuania and to Latvia, our Baltic partners and allies, to make one thing absolutely clear, and that’s his absolute commitment and absolute commitment of the United States to making good on our commitments to our NATO Allies and partners, to making sure that we’re prepared, and we will defend every inch of NATO territory if it comes under attack.  And it’s important that our friends in Estonia know that, know that they can count on that, because I know how concerned people are, how nervous they are about the implications for them of what’s happening in Ukraine.</p>
<p>But the bottom line is this:  Every country should have its sovereignty respected.  Every country deserves to be able to make its own choices about its future, policies, with whom it will associate.  And that’s what’s at stake when it comes to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>I really appreciate the fact that even as you’ve been grappling with this, even as you’ve been grappling with COVID – which I want to come back to – you’ve done remarkable work to continue to build, to strengthen the relationship between the United States and Estonia.  There are a couple of people that I just want to single out very quickly for the great work that they’ve done and they’ve led.  I don’t know if they’re actually here in the room today, but is Megan Naylor here anywhere?  Yep, Megan.</p>
<p>Thank you for five months of intensive diplomacy on something that people don’t fully necessarily grasp but that is of huge importance, and that’s the global minimum tax, and working with our Estonian partners to secure their support for that.  That’s going to have a powerful effect going forward in making sure we don’t have a race to the bottom around the world in search of low tax rates – giving countries a real resource base to actually provide for their people.  It’s one of the most important achievements I think we’ve had over the last year, and I thank you for your part in making it real.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>I know we have colleagues here from the Secret Service, from the FBI, who’ve done such incredible work with our Estonian partners on cyber security.  Again, one of the great challenges that we face – we have in Estonia one of the strongest partners anywhere in the world because of their remarkable facility with all things cyber, and I’m really grateful to our colleagues from the Secret Service, the FBI, for the great work they’ve done in working with our Estonian partners.</p>
<p>We’ve seen in this crisis new levels of collaboration and coordination.  To folks who are here with the defense attaché’s office, the Office of Defense Cooperation, what you’ve done working with the Estonians to facilitate the transfer of Javelins and other defense equipment to our Ukrainian friends has made a huge difference.  And we’re grateful for that.</p>
<p>And then to colleagues who are here from the consular section, going the extra mile, including working to support American citizens in Russia after the close of our consular section in Moscow.<a id="post-322053-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-322053-footnote-1"></a></p>
<p>All of these things are making a huge difference and they’re making a big difference in people’s lives.</p>
<p>As the chargé said, I know that here, as in embassies around the world, you’ve had to do your work over the last two years and deal with COVID at the same time.  That’s had a big impact on the professional part of your lives, and I know for many it’s had an impact on the personal part of your lives.  Some getting sick, some losing loved ones, but through all of this you kept going with tremendous resilience, with tremendous camaraderie, looking out for each other.  And I especially want to thank the management and MED units here for keeping the embassy safe and getting us through COVID.</p>
<p>Finally, I want to mention a couple of people by name.  And, again, I’m not sure if they’re here with us today but let me just say the locally employed staff here, as in every embassy, are the lifeblood of this mission, of this institution.  We can’t do what we do without you, without that partnership.  I’m so grateful for it, and I want to mention Taimi Veedla.  Is Taimi here?  Not here.  Well, LE Staff of the Year, and so I just wanted to recognize that.</p>
<p>And let me just mention a couple of other people as well.  Craig Shaffer, Tina Mills, Tõnu Jää – are any of you here today?  Thank you, thank you, thank you for everything you’ve done to keep people connected, for the exceptional IT services that you’ve helped provide.  I know there was a telephone upgrade for the entire mission.  Having had some telephone issues of my own back home, I know how challenging that is.  Thanks for getting that done.</p>
<p>And then finally to the community liaison officer Melissa Padgett – Melissa, are you here?  Melissa, thank you most of all for everything you’ve done to just keep people’s spirits high.  That makes all the difference in the world, especially in a challenging time, whether it’s COVID, whether it’s the challenge we’re dealing now with Ukraine.  I understand, and I’m actually extremely jealous that I’m not around to benefit from that, so I may have to come back – sauna trips to Estonian bogs – that sounds very good – cross country skiing, obviously great.  I’m not quite sure what to make of this – a ghost tour of old Tallinn.  That sounds like something I’d want to try to do, sounds like ghost stories in the old city.  Great.  All right, I’m coming back for that.</p>
<p>Finally, let me end with this.  As you all know better than anyone, we are in a particularly special year in this relationship, about to celebrate 100 years of diplomatic relations.  And I know you’ve got 100 days to 100 years, with events planned to lead up to that.  That, in and of itself, is a remarkable story.  It’s a story of many ups and downs in history, particularly for Estonia, but also something incredibly constant, and that is the relationship itself and our commitment to stick with our Ukrainian partners through thick and thin.  And it’s no more vital than it is today, so I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>Now, finally, there is someone who has served here for 30 years, since we reestablished this mission.  Evelyn Laasner, are you here?  (Applause.)  The very first employee when the embassy reopened, right there.  Thank you.  I was seeing applause over there.  Thank you.  Very first employee when the embassy reopened.  You’ve seen Estonia go from Soviet occupation to this incredibly flourishing democracy.  I understand that you’re retiring this year.  I didn’t want to let this day go by without saying thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.).</p>
<p>And finally, whether you are locally employed staff, whether you’re a Foreign Service officer, a civil servant, whether you’re a family member, because family members too are our frontline diplomats, and we know how much you do to build this relationship, how much you do representing your country, whether you’re from any of the other agencies that we’re privileged to work with, from the Defense Department, DHS, DOJ, AID – thank you, thank you, thank you for what you’re doing.  It makes a difference that many of our fellow citizens back home don’t necessarily see, but in ways big and small they’re actually going to feel in their lives.  I’m grateful to you.</p>
<p>And finally, to all of you who worked on putting this trip together on pretty short notice, I know how much goes into that, and all I can say is have a great wheels-up party.  (Laughter.)  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a href="#post-322053-footnote-ref-1"></a><a id="post-322053-footnote-1"></a>  <em>Due to the Russian government’s forced reduction of our consular workforce and the resulting staffing shortage, American Citizen Services are available only on an emergency basis in Moscow, but the consular section at Embassy Moscow remains open.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Tallinn, Estonia</p>
<p>Swissotel</p>
<p><strong>MR ROAROFF:</strong>  Thank you for your patience.  It’s been a busy but wonderful morning welcoming Secretary Blinken to Tallinn.</p>
<p>Just a couple quick remarks of introduction and thanks, and then we’ll open it up for questions after some comments by the Secretary.  I just wanted to start by saying: Secretary Blinken, thank you for making this trilateral visit.  We know that you and your team, this is the last in a long trip – six or seven countries, we’ll call it seven so far with your foray into Ukraine with the foreign minister.  That was great.  So thank you for coming and reassuring our Estonian allies.</p>
<p>I think you know, and the foreign minister gave you an article, that this is the first bilateral trip of a Secretary of State to Estonia since 1991.  Do read that article; it is interesting.  That trip took place in September 1991, a month after the coup attempt when hardliners tried to overthrow Gorbachev in Moscow.  The message that Secretary Baker heard at that time from Estonia, from the Baltics, was:  The hardliners will come back, please help us; they’re going to come back and try to snuff out your independence.  So 30 years later, the region still faces a Russian threat.</p>
<p>Today, everybody in front of you is working hard with our Estonian partners to support Ukraine.  The brutal attack on Ukraine hits very close to a lot of us here.  We are working on security assistance.  We’re working on isolating Russia in traditional organizations.  We all have our heart in it, and we’re going to do our utmost to support Ukraine.</p>
<p>Finally, I’m just so proud to introduce you to the staff of Embassy Tallinn.  This is the best staff I have worked with in my 20 years in the State Department.  We’ve gone through COVID together, but we haven’t lost a step.  We have a number of policy victories we can point to, and we’ve also kept our people safe.</p>
<p>I would wrap it up just by saying we have not had an ambassador since 2018.  There is not one American in this room who has worked at this embassy who has worked under an ambassador.  This is a great tribute to our Estonian staff.  The fact that we are such a strong embassy, that we have not missed a beat, that we keep advancing policy forward is because of our Estonian colleagues, and we are forever grateful for them.</p>
<p>So with that, we welcome you to Estonia, and please, let me introduce you to the staff of Embassy Tallinn.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It is wonderful to see each and every one of you here today.  And let me say to the chargé, there’s another reason why this mission is performing so well, and that’s your leadership here.  I’m grateful for it, the partnership is grateful for it, and it’s, I think, important to be here at this particular time.</p>
<p>I was struck – I hadn’t realized that the last time a Secretary of State was here on a bilateral basis was Secretary Baker in 1991.  There’s something to me that’s very poignant about that, because I have tremendous reverence for Secretary Baker, someone I admire a great deal.  And the historic resonance, given what’s happening today, could not be more powerful.  So if even there’s any small way in which I can be following in his footsteps, with the extraordinary leadership he showed at that pivot point in history, that will be a good thing.</p>
<p>You know this because you’re living it every day – you’re living it with our Estonian friends, partners, allies, for the locally employed staff who are Estonian – you feel this.  You know what is at stake with this Russian aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We’re seeing the stakes on a very personal and individual level with the suffering of the Ukrainian people, the destruction that we’re seeing in Ukraine, the now more than 1.7 million people who had to flee the country for their safety, the hundreds of thousands more who are internally displaced, people living in besieged cities where they don’t have access to food and water, to medicine – nothing can come in, and they can’t get out safely.</p>
<p>So I know that you know and you feel the personal stakes and the lives that have been lost, the lives that have been changed.</p>
<p>I think friends here in Estonia and you also know why this is also about even more than Ukraine, and why it matters to the United States, why it matters to countries in Europe, why it matters to countries around the world.  And that’s because some of the foundational principles of the order that we tried to help establish over many years to keep peace and security, however imperfectly, that those principles are being challenged, that order is being challenged.  And if we allow that to stand with impunity, then we open a Pandora’s Box where this will not be the last conflict that we see – it will be the first of more to come.  So we have a profound interest in doing everything we can to end Russia’s war of aggression in Ukraine, and it’s an interest that is felt very profoundly here.</p>
<p>The President asked me to come here now to Estonia, but also to Lithuania and to Latvia, our Baltic partners and allies, to make one thing absolutely clear, and that’s his absolute commitment and absolute commitment of the United States to making good on our commitments to our NATO Allies and partners, to making sure that we’re prepared, and we will defend every inch of NATO territory if it comes under attack.  And it’s important that our friends in Estonia know that, know that they can count on that, because I know how concerned people are, how nervous they are about the implications for them of what’s happening in Ukraine.</p>
<p>But the bottom line is this:  Every country should have its sovereignty respected.  Every country deserves to be able to make its own choices about its future, policies, with whom it will associate.  And that’s what’s at stake when it comes to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>I really appreciate the fact that even as you’ve been grappling with this, even as you’ve been grappling with COVID – which I want to come back to – you’ve done remarkable work to continue to build, to strengthen the relationship between the United States and Estonia.  There are a couple of people that I just want to single out very quickly for the great work that they’ve done and they’ve led.  I don’t know if they’re actually here in the room today, but is Megan Naylor here anywhere?  Yep, Megan.</p>
<p>Thank you for five months of intensive diplomacy on something that people don’t fully necessarily grasp but that is of huge importance, and that’s the global minimum tax, and working with our Estonian partners to secure their support for that.  That’s going to have a powerful effect going forward in making sure we don’t have a race to the bottom around the world in search of low tax rates – giving countries a real resource base to actually provide for their people.  It’s one of the most important achievements I think we’ve had over the last year, and I thank you for your part in making it real.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>I know we have colleagues here from the Secret Service, from the FBI, who’ve done such incredible work with our Estonian partners on cyber security.  Again, one of the great challenges that we face – we have in Estonia one of the strongest partners anywhere in the world because of their remarkable facility with all things cyber, and I’m really grateful to our colleagues from the Secret Service, the FBI, for the great work they’ve done in working with our Estonian partners.</p>
<p>We’ve seen in this crisis new levels of collaboration and coordination.  To folks who are here with the defense attaché’s office, the Office of Defense Cooperation, what you’ve done working with the Estonians to facilitate the transfer of Javelins and other defense equipment to our Ukrainian friends has made a huge difference.  And we’re grateful for that.</p>
<p>And then to colleagues who are here from the consular section, going the extra mile, including working to support American citizens in Russia after the close of our consular section in Moscow.<a id="post-322053-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-322053-footnote-1"></a></p>
<p>All of these things are making a huge difference and they’re making a big difference in people’s lives.</p>
<p>As the chargé said, I know that here, as in embassies around the world, you’ve had to do your work over the last two years and deal with COVID at the same time.  That’s had a big impact on the professional part of your lives, and I know for many it’s had an impact on the personal part of your lives.  Some getting sick, some losing loved ones, but through all of this you kept going with tremendous resilience, with tremendous camaraderie, looking out for each other.  And I especially want to thank the management and MED units here for keeping the embassy safe and getting us through COVID.</p>
<p>Finally, I want to mention a couple of people by name.  And, again, I’m not sure if they’re here with us today but let me just say the locally employed staff here, as in every embassy, are the lifeblood of this mission, of this institution.  We can’t do what we do without you, without that partnership.  I’m so grateful for it, and I want to mention Taimi Veedla.  Is Taimi here?  Not here.  Well, LE Staff of the Year, and so I just wanted to recognize that.</p>
<p>And let me just mention a couple of other people as well.  Craig Shaffer, Tina Mills, Tõnu Jää – are any of you here today?  Thank you, thank you, thank you for everything you’ve done to keep people connected, for the exceptional IT services that you’ve helped provide.  I know there was a telephone upgrade for the entire mission.  Having had some telephone issues of my own back home, I know how challenging that is.  Thanks for getting that done.</p>
<p>And then finally to the community liaison officer Melissa Padgett – Melissa, are you here?  Melissa, thank you most of all for everything you’ve done to just keep people’s spirits high.  That makes all the difference in the world, especially in a challenging time, whether it’s COVID, whether it’s the challenge we’re dealing now with Ukraine.  I understand, and I’m actually extremely jealous that I’m not around to benefit from that, so I may have to come back – sauna trips to Estonian bogs – that sounds very good – cross country skiing, obviously great.  I’m not quite sure what to make of this – a ghost tour of old Tallinn.  That sounds like something I’d want to try to do, sounds like ghost stories in the old city.  Great.  All right, I’m coming back for that.</p>
<p>Finally, let me end with this.  As you all know better than anyone, we are in a particularly special year in this relationship, about to celebrate 100 years of diplomatic relations.  And I know you’ve got 100 days to 100 years, with events planned to lead up to that.  That, in and of itself, is a remarkable story.  It’s a story of many ups and downs in history, particularly for Estonia, but also something incredibly constant, and that is the relationship itself and our commitment to stick with our Ukrainian partners through thick and thin.  And it’s no more vital than it is today, so I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>Now, finally, there is someone who has served here for 30 years, since we reestablished this mission.  Evelyn Laasner, are you here?  (Applause.)  The very first employee when the embassy reopened, right there.  Thank you.  I was seeing applause over there.  Thank you.  Very first employee when the embassy reopened.  You’ve seen Estonia go from Soviet occupation to this incredibly flourishing democracy.  I understand that you’re retiring this year.  I didn’t want to let this day go by without saying thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.).</p>
<p>And finally, whether you are locally employed staff, whether you’re a Foreign Service officer, a civil servant, whether you’re a family member, because family members too are our frontline diplomats, and we know how much you do to build this relationship, how much you do representing your country, whether you’re from any of the other agencies that we’re privileged to work with, from the Defense Department, DHS, DOJ, AID – thank you, thank you, thank you for what you’re doing.  It makes a difference that many of our fellow citizens back home don’t necessarily see, but in ways big and small they’re actually going to feel in their lives.  I’m grateful to you.</p>
<p>And finally, to all of you who worked on putting this trip together on pretty short notice, I know how much goes into that, and all I can say is have a great wheels-up party.  (Laughter.)  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a href="#post-322053-footnote-ref-1"></a><a id="post-322053-footnote-1"></a>  <em>Due to the Russian government’s forced reduction of our consular workforce and the resulting staffing shortage, American Citizen Services are available only on an emergency basis in Moscow, but the consular section at Embassy Moscow remains open.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks at International Women’s Day: Turning Toward the Future</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/remarks-at-international-womens-day-turning-toward-the-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 18:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=322030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Casablanca, Morocco</p>
<p>What a perfect way to celebrate International Women’s Day—to be with all of you. In the first instance, I just want to applaud all of you for what you are doing.</p>
<p>It is such a pleasure to be here with such a fabulous, accomplished group of women in celebration of International Women’s Day.</p>
<p>I want to begin by congratulating the Association of Moroccan Women Entrepreneurs, and particularly your President—and pardon me, as I will undoubtedly mispronounce someone’s name—but thank you, Leila , very much, for organizing such a wonderful program today.</p>
<p>I had the pleasure of meeting Leila’s mother Farida, as she was introduced, as well, earlier today—and thank you for doing this program in English for me this evening, I appreciate it. I know how proud Farida is of this amazing event and all Leila’s work advancing women’s entrepreneurship here in Morocco. I told her that I always think of my mother on this day because this was her birthday. And she was a woman entrepreneur in real estate.</p>
<p>So it is a pleasure to share the stage with Morocco’s Minister of Solidarity, Social Integration, and Family. Aawatif , it is wonderful to be with you. As I said to you, I would love to have the title of Minister of Social Solidarity. What a wonderful thing to bring everybody together. So thank you, very much.</p>
<p>Thank you as well to Casablanca Regional Wali Said—now I’m going to not get this right—Ahmidouch, Head of the Casablanca-Settat Regional Council Maazouz Abdellatif. I know that Casablanca’s first woman mayor wasn’t able to join us, but I know she has given her support to today’s event, and we are grateful for everything she does every day to empower Moroccan women every.</p>
<p>I want to echo something that Secretary Tony Blinken said earlier today in Estonia—which is for all of us, on this International Women’s Day, I for one, and I’m sure all of you, are giving a thought to the women of Ukraine.</p>
<p>More than 1.7 million Ukrainians, mostly women and children, have fled the war that Vladimir Putin unleashed on their country—often leaving their husbands behind to fight. Ukrainian women are giving birth in subway stations turned bomb shelters. They are caring for children with cancer in the basements of hospitals as they hide from missiles. They are taking up arms alongside Ukraine’s men to fight for their democracy and defend their homeland. The women of Ukraine, like all of you, embody the strength, resilience, and dauntless courage of women everywhere—and our hearts are with them today and every day.</p>
<p>International Women’s Day provides us with an annual opportunity to recognize the achievements of women and girls around the world—like all of you amazing entrepreneurs that are here today.</p>
<p>And it also gives us a chance to recommit to advancing the rights of women and girls—in our own countries, and around the world.</p>
<p>We have decades of evidence that when women and girls can participate fully and equally in education, in business, in government, in civil society—in every sphere of public life—then countries are more secure, more peaceful, and more prosperous.</p>
<p>When women are fully able to participate in their societies, we see stronger and more inclusive economic growth—the kind of growth that lifts up poor families and middle-class families alike. We see improvements in security, justice, and the rule of law.</p>
<p>And when women are at the table where decisions are made, we even see improvements in global peace and stability. When women participate in peace negotiations, the resulting peace deals are 35 percent more likely to last 15 years or longer. When the number of women in a national legislature increases by just five percent, that nation also becomes five times more likely to resort to peace to resolve international disputes.</p>
<p>That is why the United States is committed to advancing the rights of women and girls around the world, and to integrating gender equity and equality across all our foreign and domestic policy. We simply cannot build the world we want to see without the full and equal participation, rights, and dignity of women and girls everywhere.</p>
<p>Supporting women entrepreneurs is one of the best tools we have for advancing equality for women and girls. That’s because entrepreneurship equals financial empowerment and financial freedom. When women can start and grow their own businesses, they are less likely to be financially dependent on others in their lives—and that has all kinds of secondary effects.</p>
<p>Financial autonomy for women means less poverty for women and families. It means women have more power to influence decisions in their communities. It means greater recognition across society for women’s capabilities, our leadership, and our humanity.</p>
<p>Morocco has made important strides in recent decades to support women’s rights. In 2004, Morocco’s new family code made significant reforms to advance equality for women and girls. Thanks to the tireless work of women’s rights activists across Morocco, the 2011 revision to the Moroccan constitution recognized that men and women enjoy equal rights. And in 2018, Morocco adopted legislation criminalizing violence against women.</p>
<p>Despite this progress, however, the percentage of Moroccan women in the labor force remains quite low, one of the lowest in the world—and it’s actually lower than it was two decades ago.</p>
<p>Morocco’s New Development Model—a priority of King Mohammed VI—has put increasing women’s participation in the economy at the forefront of Morocco’s strategy for economic growth. The United States wants to support Morocco to reach its goal of increasing women’s participation in the workforce to 45 percent in 2035, up from 22 percent today. We are proud to be a partner to Morocco and Moroccan women in advancing women’s economic opportunity and supporting women entrepreneurs, including through the State Department’s POWER program.</p>
<p>POWER convenes women business leaders and entrepreneurs, in the United States and around the world, to help women develop their professional networks—as you all are doing here today—identify market opportunities, and break down barriers that hold women back economically. I am very glad that the State Department, led by our CDA David Greene, who is here with us today, and our mission here in Morocco were able to leverage the POWER program to support today’s event.</p>
<p>In spite of the progress we’ve made in advancing women’s rights—here in Morocco, at home in the United States, and elsewhere around the world—we have to be humble and acknowledge that there is more work to do. Not a single country has achieved gender equality—including the United States.</p>
<p>As you were told, I am the first woman to serve as Deputy Secretary of State. That took until 2021. I was the first woman to serve as the Undersecretary for Political Affairs. That took until 2011. It is, frankly, crazy that it took so long—but it did.</p>
<p>Now, there are some benefits to having this silver hair that I have. And one of the benefits is that I don’t have to worry quite so much about what people think about me. So if I walk into a meeting or a briefing and I’m the only woman in the room, which happens rather frequently, whether I’m visiting one of our embassies or meeting with a foreign delegation, I say something about it. Sometimes people take it on board, sometimes they dismiss it, often they’re sort of uncomfortable—but I always say something. Because if I don’t, who will?</p>
<p>When I served under President Obama, the top three positions on the National Security Council were all held by women. But men’s voices were still heard differently. In so many meetings, we’d go around the table, and a man would repeat a point one of the women had already made—without acknowledging it. You all have probably had that experience occasionally.</p>
<p>So my colleagues and I started speaking up when this happened. We’d say things like, “I’m so glad you agree with what Lisa just said.”</p>
<p>Now, I don’t know if the men always noticed. But it felt good to have each other’s back. We learned, in other words, that we women were all better off if we stuck together and reinforced and supported each other.</p>
<p>Throughout my career, I’ve benefited from having women mentors and colleagues who I could turn to if I needed to gut-check my reaction to something, to talk through a strategy, or sometimes just to vent, just to complain. Building a network of supportive colleagues is especially helpful when you’re in the minority in your field, in your organization, or in your field of study.</p>
<p>And building your support system is key for preventing burnout. That’s what you all are doing today. Helping each other out. Because let’s face it—it’s often just really hard to be the first, or one of the first, to do what you’re doing. If you can’t look around and see people who look like you in similar positions, it may be hard to imagine how you can get there yourself.</p>
<p>That’s why events like this one today are so important. By coming together as a community, you’re forging the kinds of networks, partnerships, and friendships that will help you achieve your goals and provide an example to younger women who wonder if they can do what you have already done.</p>
<p>We need each other to get through the hard times—to cheer each other’s accomplishments in the good times—and to make connections, suggest resources, and even just to offer a sympathetic ear during all the times in between.</p>
<p>The future is really bright for women entrepreneurs here in Morocco and around the world. So my appeal to you today, very much what this organization is all about, is: don’t stop chasing your goals, your ambitions, your dreams, and your power as leaders. And keep supporting each other. Because we have to stick together.</p>
<p>Thank you again for having me, and happy International Women’s Day.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1111110011" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Casablanca, Morocco</p>
<p>What a perfect way to celebrate International Women’s Day—to be with all of you. In the first instance, I just want to applaud all of you for what you are doing.</p>
<p>It is such a pleasure to be here with such a fabulous, accomplished group of women in celebration of International Women’s Day.</p>
<p>I want to begin by congratulating the Association of Moroccan Women Entrepreneurs, and particularly your President—and pardon me, as I will undoubtedly mispronounce someone’s name—but thank you, Leila , very much, for organizing such a wonderful program today.</p>
<p>I had the pleasure of meeting Leila’s mother Farida, as she was introduced, as well, earlier today—and thank you for doing this program in English for me this evening, I appreciate it. I know how proud Farida is of this amazing event and all Leila’s work advancing women’s entrepreneurship here in Morocco. I told her that I always think of my mother on this day because this was her birthday. And she was a woman entrepreneur in real estate.</p>
<p>So it is a pleasure to share the stage with Morocco’s Minister of Solidarity, Social Integration, and Family. Aawatif , it is wonderful to be with you. As I said to you, I would love to have the title of Minister of Social Solidarity. What a wonderful thing to bring everybody together. So thank you, very much.</p>
<p>Thank you as well to Casablanca Regional Wali Said—now I’m going to not get this right—Ahmidouch, Head of the Casablanca-Settat Regional Council Maazouz Abdellatif. I know that Casablanca’s first woman mayor wasn’t able to join us, but I know she has given her support to today’s event, and we are grateful for everything she does every day to empower Moroccan women every.</p>
<p>I want to echo something that Secretary Tony Blinken said earlier today in Estonia—which is for all of us, on this International Women’s Day, I for one, and I’m sure all of you, are giving a thought to the women of Ukraine.</p>
<p>More than 1.7 million Ukrainians, mostly women and children, have fled the war that Vladimir Putin unleashed on their country—often leaving their husbands behind to fight. Ukrainian women are giving birth in subway stations turned bomb shelters. They are caring for children with cancer in the basements of hospitals as they hide from missiles. They are taking up arms alongside Ukraine’s men to fight for their democracy and defend their homeland. The women of Ukraine, like all of you, embody the strength, resilience, and dauntless courage of women everywhere—and our hearts are with them today and every day.</p>
<p>International Women’s Day provides us with an annual opportunity to recognize the achievements of women and girls around the world—like all of you amazing entrepreneurs that are here today.</p>
<p>And it also gives us a chance to recommit to advancing the rights of women and girls—in our own countries, and around the world.</p>
<p>We have decades of evidence that when women and girls can participate fully and equally in education, in business, in government, in civil society—in every sphere of public life—then countries are more secure, more peaceful, and more prosperous.</p>
<p>When women are fully able to participate in their societies, we see stronger and more inclusive economic growth—the kind of growth that lifts up poor families and middle-class families alike. We see improvements in security, justice, and the rule of law.</p>
<p>And when women are at the table where decisions are made, we even see improvements in global peace and stability. When women participate in peace negotiations, the resulting peace deals are 35 percent more likely to last 15 years or longer. When the number of women in a national legislature increases by just five percent, that nation also becomes five times more likely to resort to peace to resolve international disputes.</p>
<p>That is why the United States is committed to advancing the rights of women and girls around the world, and to integrating gender equity and equality across all our foreign and domestic policy. We simply cannot build the world we want to see without the full and equal participation, rights, and dignity of women and girls everywhere.</p>
<p>Supporting women entrepreneurs is one of the best tools we have for advancing equality for women and girls. That’s because entrepreneurship equals financial empowerment and financial freedom. When women can start and grow their own businesses, they are less likely to be financially dependent on others in their lives—and that has all kinds of secondary effects.</p>
<p>Financial autonomy for women means less poverty for women and families. It means women have more power to influence decisions in their communities. It means greater recognition across society for women’s capabilities, our leadership, and our humanity.</p>
<p>Morocco has made important strides in recent decades to support women’s rights. In 2004, Morocco’s new family code made significant reforms to advance equality for women and girls. Thanks to the tireless work of women’s rights activists across Morocco, the 2011 revision to the Moroccan constitution recognized that men and women enjoy equal rights. And in 2018, Morocco adopted legislation criminalizing violence against women.</p>
<p>Despite this progress, however, the percentage of Moroccan women in the labor force remains quite low, one of the lowest in the world—and it’s actually lower than it was two decades ago.</p>
<p>Morocco’s New Development Model—a priority of King Mohammed VI—has put increasing women’s participation in the economy at the forefront of Morocco’s strategy for economic growth. The United States wants to support Morocco to reach its goal of increasing women’s participation in the workforce to 45 percent in 2035, up from 22 percent today. We are proud to be a partner to Morocco and Moroccan women in advancing women’s economic opportunity and supporting women entrepreneurs, including through the State Department’s POWER program.</p>
<p>POWER convenes women business leaders and entrepreneurs, in the United States and around the world, to help women develop their professional networks—as you all are doing here today—identify market opportunities, and break down barriers that hold women back economically. I am very glad that the State Department, led by our CDA David Greene, who is here with us today, and our mission here in Morocco were able to leverage the POWER program to support today’s event.</p>
<p>In spite of the progress we’ve made in advancing women’s rights—here in Morocco, at home in the United States, and elsewhere around the world—we have to be humble and acknowledge that there is more work to do. Not a single country has achieved gender equality—including the United States.</p>
<p>As you were told, I am the first woman to serve as Deputy Secretary of State. That took until 2021. I was the first woman to serve as the Undersecretary for Political Affairs. That took until 2011. It is, frankly, crazy that it took so long—but it did.</p>
<p>Now, there are some benefits to having this silver hair that I have. And one of the benefits is that I don’t have to worry quite so much about what people think about me. So if I walk into a meeting or a briefing and I’m the only woman in the room, which happens rather frequently, whether I’m visiting one of our embassies or meeting with a foreign delegation, I say something about it. Sometimes people take it on board, sometimes they dismiss it, often they’re sort of uncomfortable—but I always say something. Because if I don’t, who will?</p>
<p>When I served under President Obama, the top three positions on the National Security Council were all held by women. But men’s voices were still heard differently. In so many meetings, we’d go around the table, and a man would repeat a point one of the women had already made—without acknowledging it. You all have probably had that experience occasionally.</p>
<p>So my colleagues and I started speaking up when this happened. We’d say things like, “I’m so glad you agree with what Lisa just said.”</p>
<p>Now, I don’t know if the men always noticed. But it felt good to have each other’s back. We learned, in other words, that we women were all better off if we stuck together and reinforced and supported each other.</p>
<p>Throughout my career, I’ve benefited from having women mentors and colleagues who I could turn to if I needed to gut-check my reaction to something, to talk through a strategy, or sometimes just to vent, just to complain. Building a network of supportive colleagues is especially helpful when you’re in the minority in your field, in your organization, or in your field of study.</p>
<p>And building your support system is key for preventing burnout. That’s what you all are doing today. Helping each other out. Because let’s face it—it’s often just really hard to be the first, or one of the first, to do what you’re doing. If you can’t look around and see people who look like you in similar positions, it may be hard to imagine how you can get there yourself.</p>
<p>That’s why events like this one today are so important. By coming together as a community, you’re forging the kinds of networks, partnerships, and friendships that will help you achieve your goals and provide an example to younger women who wonder if they can do what you have already done.</p>
<p>We need each other to get through the hard times—to cheer each other’s accomplishments in the good times—and to make connections, suggest resources, and even just to offer a sympathetic ear during all the times in between.</p>
<p>The future is really bright for women entrepreneurs here in Morocco and around the world. So my appeal to you today, very much what this organization is all about, is: don’t stop chasing your goals, your ambitions, your dreams, and your power as leaders. And keep supporting each other. Because we have to stick together.</p>
<p>Thank you again for having me, and happy International Women’s Day.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1111110011" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with German Foreign Minister Baerbock</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-german-foreign-minister-baerbock/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 17:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock.  The Secretary reaffirmed the necessity for continued U.S.-German cooperation in the face of Putin’s unprovoked war against Ukraine.  He underscored the United States’ resolute support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and for Ukraine’s efforts to defend itself against continuing Russian aggression.  The Secretary highlighted our commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Russia accountable for its unlawful war of choice.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock.  The Secretary reaffirmed the necessity for continued U.S.-German cooperation in the face of Putin’s unprovoked war against Ukraine.  He underscored the United States’ resolute support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and for Ukraine’s efforts to defend itself against continuing Russian aggression.  The Secretary highlighted our commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Russia accountable for its unlawful war of choice.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Bourita of Morocco</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-foreign-minister-bourita-of-morocco/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 16:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Moroccan Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita in Rabat.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Bourita discussed ways to further enhance the long-standing bilateral relationship between the United States and Morocco, including shared interests in regional peace, security and prosperity.  The Deputy Secretary and Foreign Minister also discussed international developments, including Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked and unjustified war on Ukraine.  The Deputy Secretary and the Foreign Minister expressed strong support for the United Nations Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General Staffan de Mistura, who is seeking to reinvigorate the UN-led political process for Western Sahara.  The Deputy Secretary noted that we continue to view Morocco’s autonomy plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and a potential approach to satisfy the aspirations of the people of Western Sahara.  The Deputy Secretary and Foreign Minister also discussed the importance of protecting human rights, including freedom of expression, building on the productive September 2021 U.S.-Morocco dialogue on human rights.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Moroccan Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita in Rabat.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Bourita discussed ways to further enhance the long-standing bilateral relationship between the United States and Morocco, including shared interests in regional peace, security and prosperity.  The Deputy Secretary and Foreign Minister also discussed international developments, including Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked and unjustified war on Ukraine.  The Deputy Secretary and the Foreign Minister expressed strong support for the United Nations Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General Staffan de Mistura, who is seeking to reinvigorate the UN-led political process for Western Sahara.  The Deputy Secretary noted that we continue to view Morocco’s autonomy plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and a potential approach to satisfy the aspirations of the people of Western Sahara.  The Deputy Secretary and Foreign Minister also discussed the importance of protecting human rights, including freedom of expression, building on the productive September 2021 U.S.-Morocco dialogue on human rights.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Communiqué on the Morocco-U.S. Strategic Dialogue on Regional Political Issues</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-communique-on-the-morocco-u-s-strategic-dialogue-on-regional-political-issues/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 16:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of Morocco and the United States of America.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Minister of Foreign Affairs, African Cooperation, and Moroccan Expatriates, M. Nasser Bourita, and the Deputy Secretary of State of the United States of America, Ms. Wendy Sherman, held bilateral political consultations in Rabat today and co-chaired a session of the Morocco-U.S. Strategic Dialogue on Regional Political Issues.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Bourita and Deputy Secretary Sherman welcomed the celebration of International Women’s Day as a milestone in promoting and advancing women’s rights.  They underscored the need to advance efforts aiming at strengthening women’s rights and achieving equality.</p>
<p>The meeting was an opportunity to reiterate the commitment to the long-standing relations between Morocco and the United States that date to the Treaty of Peace and Friendship in 1787.  They emphasized that the strategic bilateral partnership between Morocco and the United States is rooted in shared interests in regional peace, security, and prosperity.  They also discussed areas for future U.S.-Moroccan cooperation.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Bourita and Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted King Mohammed VI’s leadership in advancing a far-reaching reform agenda.</p>
<p>They discussed the importance of promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms and building on the productive Morocco-U.S. dialogue on human rights held in September 2021, which serves as the main platform to discuss all human rights related issues.</p>
<p>The Minister and the Deputy Secretary expressed their intent to continue cooperation on issues of common interest such as regional peace and prosperity, and the development of Africa and regional security.  Deputy Secretary Sherman emphasized the crucial role played by the Kingdom of Morocco in maintaining regional security and stability as well as its contribution to peace and prosperity in the Middle East.</p>
<p>The Foreign Minister and Deputy Secretary recalled the Joint Declaration of December 22, 2020, signed by Morocco, United States, and Israel.  The Deputy Secretary welcomed the continued deepening of relations between Morocco and Israel.  They discussed ways and means to boost cooperation between the three countries.</p>
<p>The Foreign Minister and the Deputy Secretary expressed strong support for United Nations Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General Staffan de Mistura in leading the political process for Western Sahara, under the auspices of the United Nations.  The Deputy Secretary noted that the United States continues to view Morocco’s Autonomy Plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and one potential approach to meet the aspirations of the people of the region.</p>
<p>The Minister and the Deputy Secretary expressed their intent to continue strong cooperation to defeat terrorist groups, including AQIM and ISIS.  The Deputy Secretary thanked Morocco, a stable security-exporting partner, for its leadership of the Global Counterterrorism Forum and for its sustaining role in the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS, including by co-chairing the Africa Focus Group of the Coalition and hosting the upcoming Ministerial Meeting of the Coalition in May.  The Deputy Secretary expressed appreciation for Morocco’s continued support to the African Lion multilateral military exercises.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Bourita and Deputy Secretary Sherman also discussed a range of regional issues, including the Sahel, Libya, and Ukraine.  In this regard, the Minister and Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the importance of respecting the territorial integrity, sovereignty, and national unity of all the Member States of the United Nations.</p>
<p>Concerning Libya, the Deputy Secretary welcomed the positive role and important contribution of Morocco to support the UN’s efforts on the political process and hosting the intra-Libyan dialogue.  The Foreign Minister and Deputy Secretary reaffirmed their strong commitment to the sovereignty, independence, territorial integrity, and national unity of Libya and the priority for organizing national elections in the near term.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of Morocco and the United States of America.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Minister of Foreign Affairs, African Cooperation, and Moroccan Expatriates, M. Nasser Bourita, and the Deputy Secretary of State of the United States of America, Ms. Wendy Sherman, held bilateral political consultations in Rabat today and co-chaired a session of the Morocco-U.S. Strategic Dialogue on Regional Political Issues.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Bourita and Deputy Secretary Sherman welcomed the celebration of International Women’s Day as a milestone in promoting and advancing women’s rights.  They underscored the need to advance efforts aiming at strengthening women’s rights and achieving equality.</p>
<p>The meeting was an opportunity to reiterate the commitment to the long-standing relations between Morocco and the United States that date to the Treaty of Peace and Friendship in 1787.  They emphasized that the strategic bilateral partnership between Morocco and the United States is rooted in shared interests in regional peace, security, and prosperity.  They also discussed areas for future U.S.-Moroccan cooperation.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Bourita and Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted King Mohammed VI’s leadership in advancing a far-reaching reform agenda.</p>
<p>They discussed the importance of promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms and building on the productive Morocco-U.S. dialogue on human rights held in September 2021, which serves as the main platform to discuss all human rights related issues.</p>
<p>The Minister and the Deputy Secretary expressed their intent to continue cooperation on issues of common interest such as regional peace and prosperity, and the development of Africa and regional security.  Deputy Secretary Sherman emphasized the crucial role played by the Kingdom of Morocco in maintaining regional security and stability as well as its contribution to peace and prosperity in the Middle East.</p>
<p>The Foreign Minister and Deputy Secretary recalled the Joint Declaration of December 22, 2020, signed by Morocco, United States, and Israel.  The Deputy Secretary welcomed the continued deepening of relations between Morocco and Israel.  They discussed ways and means to boost cooperation between the three countries.</p>
<p>The Foreign Minister and the Deputy Secretary expressed strong support for United Nations Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General Staffan de Mistura in leading the political process for Western Sahara, under the auspices of the United Nations.  The Deputy Secretary noted that the United States continues to view Morocco’s Autonomy Plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and one potential approach to meet the aspirations of the people of the region.</p>
<p>The Minister and the Deputy Secretary expressed their intent to continue strong cooperation to defeat terrorist groups, including AQIM and ISIS.  The Deputy Secretary thanked Morocco, a stable security-exporting partner, for its leadership of the Global Counterterrorism Forum and for its sustaining role in the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS, including by co-chairing the Africa Focus Group of the Coalition and hosting the upcoming Ministerial Meeting of the Coalition in May.  The Deputy Secretary expressed appreciation for Morocco’s continued support to the African Lion multilateral military exercises.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Bourita and Deputy Secretary Sherman also discussed a range of regional issues, including the Sahel, Libya, and Ukraine.  In this regard, the Minister and Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the importance of respecting the territorial integrity, sovereignty, and national unity of all the Member States of the United Nations.</p>
<p>Concerning Libya, the Deputy Secretary welcomed the positive role and important contribution of Morocco to support the UN’s efforts on the political process and hosting the intra-Libyan dialogue.  The Foreign Minister and Deputy Secretary reaffirmed their strong commitment to the sovereignty, independence, territorial integrity, and national unity of Libya and the priority for organizing national elections in the near term.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The NagaWorld Strike and Detained Union Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-nagaworld-strike-and-detained-union-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 15:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On International Women’s Day, we recognize the courage of women union leaders in Cambodia who have bravely led their union at the NagaWorld casino and hotel complex in standing up for the rights of their fellow workers.</p>
<p>Cambodian authorities have detained seven of the women union leaders since December of last year, charging them with incitement for leading a peaceful strike to demand that terminated workers be reinstated.</p>
<p>The United States has serious concerns about the use of criminal charges against those peacefully exercising their rights to freedom of association and peaceful assembly.<strong>  </strong>We urge Cambodian authorities to release all detained unionists, drop the charges against them, and move to constructively resolve their dispute.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On International Women’s Day, we recognize the courage of women union leaders in Cambodia who have bravely led their union at the NagaWorld casino and hotel complex in standing up for the rights of their fellow workers.</p>
<p>Cambodian authorities have detained seven of the women union leaders since December of last year, charging them with incitement for leading a peaceful strike to demand that terminated workers be reinstated.</p>
<p>The United States has serious concerns about the use of criminal charges against those peacefully exercising their rights to freedom of association and peaceful assembly.<strong>  </strong>We urge Cambodian authorities to release all detained unionists, drop the charges against them, and move to constructively resolve their dispute.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
