<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:46:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Earth Day 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/earth-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As we celebrate the 52nd annual Earth Day, we are able to reflect on the past year as the period when we gained momentum in our global commitment to foster a healthier planet.</p>
<p>This Administration has made the climate crisis a foreign policy priority by working to scale up global ambition to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, infusing the climate dimension into our broader policy, and significantly increasing investments in climate adaptation and resilience. Thanks to U.S. leadership at COP26 in Glasgow, the world is much closer to keeping a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on global temperature rise within reach. We also released the United States Long-Term Strategy under the Paris Agreement, which outlines how we will achieve a net-zero economy by 2050, and, in partnership with the EU, we enlisted more than a hundred countries in the fight to reduce methane emissions — regarded as the single most effective near-term strategy to limit warming.  In addition, President Biden committed the United States to the ambitious goal of conserving at least 30 percent of U.S. lands and waters by 2030, and we hope other countries around the world will adopt similarly ambitious conservation efforts.</p>
<p>The United States is also proud to have played a significant role in reaching consensus at the UN Environment Assembly this year to launch an international negotiating process on a global agreement to end plastic pollution. This effort underscores the importance of addressing pollution while we tackle climate change and other environmental challenges. The Department is also working to support the Administration’s vision for sustainability in Federal Government operations, which puts agencies on the road to net-zero emissions.</p>
<p>As we take stock of our efforts, we remain clear-eyed about the reality that communities across the world are currently suffering due to environmental destruction and damage, including those in Ukraine who have experienced devastating loss of life due to Russia’s invasion. On this anniversary of Earth Day, we continue working towards environmental and diplomatic solutions that foster a healthier planet for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As we celebrate the 52nd annual Earth Day, we are able to reflect on the past year as the period when we gained momentum in our global commitment to foster a healthier planet.</p>
<p>This Administration has made the climate crisis a foreign policy priority by working to scale up global ambition to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, infusing the climate dimension into our broader policy, and significantly increasing investments in climate adaptation and resilience. Thanks to U.S. leadership at COP26 in Glasgow, the world is much closer to keeping a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on global temperature rise within reach. We also released the United States Long-Term Strategy under the Paris Agreement, which outlines how we will achieve a net-zero economy by 2050, and, in partnership with the EU, we enlisted more than a hundred countries in the fight to reduce methane emissions — regarded as the single most effective near-term strategy to limit warming.  In addition, President Biden committed the United States to the ambitious goal of conserving at least 30 percent of U.S. lands and waters by 2030, and we hope other countries around the world will adopt similarly ambitious conservation efforts.</p>
<p>The United States is also proud to have played a significant role in reaching consensus at the UN Environment Assembly this year to launch an international negotiating process on a global agreement to end plastic pollution. This effort underscores the importance of addressing pollution while we tackle climate change and other environmental challenges. The Department is also working to support the Administration’s vision for sustainability in Federal Government operations, which puts agencies on the road to net-zero emissions.</p>
<p>As we take stock of our efforts, we remain clear-eyed about the reality that communities across the world are currently suffering due to environmental destruction and damage, including those in Ukraine who have experienced devastating loss of life due to Russia’s invasion. On this anniversary of Earth Day, we continue working towards environmental and diplomatic solutions that foster a healthier planet for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-EU: Consultations between EEAS Secretary General Stefano Sannino and United States Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-eu-consultations-between-eeas-secretary-general-stefano-sannino-and-united-states-deputy-secretary-wendy-sherman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint press release by the U.S. Department of State and the European External Action Service.</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>On April 21 and 22, United States Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino in Brussels to once again underscore the unique strength of the U.S.-EU strategic partnership. They reaffirmed the joint transatlantic resolve in standing up for and defending freedom, democracy, and human rights, and to use all tools available in the Transatlantic relationship to take further coordinated action to tackle the current global challenges.</p>
<p>They commended the exceptional display of transatlantic unity and U.S.-EU coordination in response to Russia’s unprovoked military aggression against Ukraine, including on sanctions and export controls. They condemned in the strongest possible terms the reported atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in a number of now liberated Ukrainian towns, during the period when Russia had effective control of the area. Likewise, the U.S. and the EU condemned the continual shelling of civilians and civilian infrastructure by Russian armed forces. These horrific actions show the true face of the brutal war of aggression Russia is waging against Ukraine and its people. There can be no impunity for war crimes. They plan to coordinate their activities with the objective of ensuring the perpetrators are held to account.</p>
<p>They welcomed the inaugural meeting of the U.S.-EU High-Level Dialogue on Russia on March 30 and stressed the importance of continued coordination on the provision of security assistance to Ukraine and the implementation and enforcement of sanctions targeting Russia and Belarus, together with other like-minded partners. They discussed coordinating global outreach efforts to maintain a broad-based international coalition of support for Ukraine, in the face of Russia’s aggression. They discussed further efforts to increase humanitarian support and initiatives to provide coordinated political, financial, material and humanitarian support to the government and people of Ukraine. They also took stock of U.S. and EU efforts to counter the Kremlin and Beijing’s propaganda and disinformation program. They stressed continued U.S.-EU cooperation in favor of long-term sustainable peace, enhanced resilience, sovereignty, territorial integrity, and stability in the wider region, including in the South Caucasus and Central Asia. They also discussed the global economic disruptions caused by the Russia’s war of aggression, underlining that Russia bears full responsibility for the global negative impact of the war it is waging against Ukraine. In this context, they highlighted the need to address the negative impact of Russia’s invasion on global food security through a coordinated effort, in close cooperation with international bodies.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino held the third high-level meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China. Together, they exchanged views on their respective bilateral relations with China. In particular, they held an in-depth discussion on their recent engagement with China on Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. They underscored they will continue to urge China not to circumvent or undermine sanctions against Russia, and not to provide any form of support for Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, and reaffirmed that such support would have consequences for our respective relationships with China. They also expressed concern about China’s repeated information manipulation, including amplification of Russia’s disinformation regarding Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>On Taiwan, they underscored the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait to regional and global security and prosperity. They expressed their support for the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues, and discouraged any actions, which undermine the status quo.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino also discussed China’s stances and activities in multilateral fora, noting that U.S. and EU objectives will continue to focus squarely on upholding international law and principles, the maintenance of the centrality of the UN Charter, and respect for human rights. They expressed particular concern about, and opposition to, recent incidents of economic coercion by China, affirming their solidarity with those targeted and underscoring the importance of international cooperation in addressing growing instances of economic coercion. They also reviewed the outcome of senior officials’ and expert-level exchanges on multilateralism, human rights, and engagement with China. They condemned the situation in Xinjiang, notably the existence of a large network of “political reeducation” camps, widespread surveillance, systemic restrictions on freedom of religion or belief against Uyghurs and other persons belonging to minority groups, as well as the use of forced labor.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino held the second high-level Consultations on the Indo-Pacific, reiterating their resolve to engage with partners in the Indo-Pacific and reinforcing their shared interest in upholding the rules-based multilateral order in the region and advancing democracy and human rights. They exchanged views on their respective recent engagements with Indo-Pacific partners. They identified opportunities to tackle manipulation of the information space and counter disinformation, and ways to step up security and defense cooperation to enhance maritime awareness and build regional capacity to improve law enforcement and coordination in the maritime domain. They also recognized the importance of promoting due diligence and labor standards to fight child labor and address its root causes in the region. They reiterated their condemnation of the military takeover in Myanmar. They discussed synergies and cooperation between the U.S. Build Back Better World and the EU’s Global Gateway initiatives. They decided to continue close consultations with a view to coordinating the implementation of their respective Indo-Pacific strategies.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino also had the opportunity to discuss other key foreign policy issues of shared interest, including ongoing strong coordination and cooperation in the Western Balkans to advance its European integration and stability. They expressed their support for the formal opening of EU accession negotiations with North Macedonia and Albania and for the EU facilitated Belgrade Pristina Dialogue. They recognized the importance of the stabilization and security provided by EUFOR&#8217;s ALTHEA mission in Bosnia and Herzegovina, and coordination on fighting corruption, and promoting free and fair elections. On Afghanistan, they condemned the Taliban’s decision not to allow girls access to secondary schools, calling for the immediate reversal of this decision and pledged joint efforts to stabilize the economic and financial situation in the country, as well to push for an inclusive political process. They underlined the need to organize elections in Mali with the full support of ECOWAS’ mediation, while strongly condemning the reported abuses of human rights by the Malian armed forces and the Wagner group. They also acknowledged the need for the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali to conduct accurate investigations and release reports on all human rights abuses in Mali. The Sahel remains a region of priority interest where the U.S. and the EU are undertaking civilian, political, and security efforts as well as development and humanitarian aid. They remain particularly concerned about the humanitarian crisis in the Sahel, where over 20 million people could be in need of assistance this year. In this context and in line with the conclusions of the EU co-organized pledging event of April 6, 2022, they agreed on the need to continue to take concrete immediate and long-term actions to address the ongoing food and nutrition crises in the region.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino welcomed that the first meeting of the U.S.-EU dialogue on Security and Defense will be held with the participation of the U.S. Departments of State and Defense, the European External Action Service, as well as the European Commission and the European Defense Agency on 22 April 2022. The meeting represents an important milestone towards closer partnership between the U.S. and the EU in the area of security and defense.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino committed to continue their close consultations on foreign policy and security issues of shared concern and decided to hold the next high-level meetings under the Dialogue on China and the Consultations on the Indo-Pacific towards the end of 2022.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint press release by the U.S. Department of State and the European External Action Service.</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>On April 21 and 22, United States Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino in Brussels to once again underscore the unique strength of the U.S.-EU strategic partnership. They reaffirmed the joint transatlantic resolve in standing up for and defending freedom, democracy, and human rights, and to use all tools available in the Transatlantic relationship to take further coordinated action to tackle the current global challenges.</p>
<p>They commended the exceptional display of transatlantic unity and U.S.-EU coordination in response to Russia’s unprovoked military aggression against Ukraine, including on sanctions and export controls. They condemned in the strongest possible terms the reported atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in a number of now liberated Ukrainian towns, during the period when Russia had effective control of the area. Likewise, the U.S. and the EU condemned the continual shelling of civilians and civilian infrastructure by Russian armed forces. These horrific actions show the true face of the brutal war of aggression Russia is waging against Ukraine and its people. There can be no impunity for war crimes. They plan to coordinate their activities with the objective of ensuring the perpetrators are held to account.</p>
<p>They welcomed the inaugural meeting of the U.S.-EU High-Level Dialogue on Russia on March 30 and stressed the importance of continued coordination on the provision of security assistance to Ukraine and the implementation and enforcement of sanctions targeting Russia and Belarus, together with other like-minded partners. They discussed coordinating global outreach efforts to maintain a broad-based international coalition of support for Ukraine, in the face of Russia’s aggression. They discussed further efforts to increase humanitarian support and initiatives to provide coordinated political, financial, material and humanitarian support to the government and people of Ukraine. They also took stock of U.S. and EU efforts to counter the Kremlin and Beijing’s propaganda and disinformation program. They stressed continued U.S.-EU cooperation in favor of long-term sustainable peace, enhanced resilience, sovereignty, territorial integrity, and stability in the wider region, including in the South Caucasus and Central Asia. They also discussed the global economic disruptions caused by the Russia’s war of aggression, underlining that Russia bears full responsibility for the global negative impact of the war it is waging against Ukraine. In this context, they highlighted the need to address the negative impact of Russia’s invasion on global food security through a coordinated effort, in close cooperation with international bodies.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino held the third high-level meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China. Together, they exchanged views on their respective bilateral relations with China. In particular, they held an in-depth discussion on their recent engagement with China on Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. They underscored they will continue to urge China not to circumvent or undermine sanctions against Russia, and not to provide any form of support for Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, and reaffirmed that such support would have consequences for our respective relationships with China. They also expressed concern about China’s repeated information manipulation, including amplification of Russia’s disinformation regarding Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>On Taiwan, they underscored the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait to regional and global security and prosperity. They expressed their support for the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues, and discouraged any actions, which undermine the status quo.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino also discussed China’s stances and activities in multilateral fora, noting that U.S. and EU objectives will continue to focus squarely on upholding international law and principles, the maintenance of the centrality of the UN Charter, and respect for human rights. They expressed particular concern about, and opposition to, recent incidents of economic coercion by China, affirming their solidarity with those targeted and underscoring the importance of international cooperation in addressing growing instances of economic coercion. They also reviewed the outcome of senior officials’ and expert-level exchanges on multilateralism, human rights, and engagement with China. They condemned the situation in Xinjiang, notably the existence of a large network of “political reeducation” camps, widespread surveillance, systemic restrictions on freedom of religion or belief against Uyghurs and other persons belonging to minority groups, as well as the use of forced labor.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino held the second high-level Consultations on the Indo-Pacific, reiterating their resolve to engage with partners in the Indo-Pacific and reinforcing their shared interest in upholding the rules-based multilateral order in the region and advancing democracy and human rights. They exchanged views on their respective recent engagements with Indo-Pacific partners. They identified opportunities to tackle manipulation of the information space and counter disinformation, and ways to step up security and defense cooperation to enhance maritime awareness and build regional capacity to improve law enforcement and coordination in the maritime domain. They also recognized the importance of promoting due diligence and labor standards to fight child labor and address its root causes in the region. They reiterated their condemnation of the military takeover in Myanmar. They discussed synergies and cooperation between the U.S. Build Back Better World and the EU’s Global Gateway initiatives. They decided to continue close consultations with a view to coordinating the implementation of their respective Indo-Pacific strategies.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino also had the opportunity to discuss other key foreign policy issues of shared interest, including ongoing strong coordination and cooperation in the Western Balkans to advance its European integration and stability. They expressed their support for the formal opening of EU accession negotiations with North Macedonia and Albania and for the EU facilitated Belgrade Pristina Dialogue. They recognized the importance of the stabilization and security provided by EUFOR&#8217;s ALTHEA mission in Bosnia and Herzegovina, and coordination on fighting corruption, and promoting free and fair elections. On Afghanistan, they condemned the Taliban’s decision not to allow girls access to secondary schools, calling for the immediate reversal of this decision and pledged joint efforts to stabilize the economic and financial situation in the country, as well to push for an inclusive political process. They underlined the need to organize elections in Mali with the full support of ECOWAS’ mediation, while strongly condemning the reported abuses of human rights by the Malian armed forces and the Wagner group. They also acknowledged the need for the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali to conduct accurate investigations and release reports on all human rights abuses in Mali. The Sahel remains a region of priority interest where the U.S. and the EU are undertaking civilian, political, and security efforts as well as development and humanitarian aid. They remain particularly concerned about the humanitarian crisis in the Sahel, where over 20 million people could be in need of assistance this year. In this context and in line with the conclusions of the EU co-organized pledging event of April 6, 2022, they agreed on the need to continue to take concrete immediate and long-term actions to address the ongoing food and nutrition crises in the region.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino welcomed that the first meeting of the U.S.-EU dialogue on Security and Defense will be held with the participation of the U.S. Departments of State and Defense, the European External Action Service, as well as the European Commission and the European Defense Agency on 22 April 2022. The meeting represents an important milestone towards closer partnership between the U.S. and the EU in the area of security and defense.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino committed to continue their close consultations on foreign policy and security issues of shared concern and decided to hold the next high-level meetings under the Dialogue on China and the Consultations on the Indo-Pacific towards the end of 2022.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Timor-Leste Presidential Election</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/timor-leste-presidential-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We congratulate President-elect José Ramos-Horta on his election as Timor-Leste’s next president and look forward to working with President-elect Ramos-Horta to strengthen the enduring partnership between the United States and Timor-Leste.  Rooted in shared values and interests, our partnership has delivered opportunities to improve the livelihoods of the Timorese people through economic development, public health, security cooperation, and educational exchanges and training.</p>
<p>We commend Timorese authorities, including the Technical Secretariat for Electoral Administration and the National Elections Commission, for administering a free, fair, and transparent election and the hundreds of thousands of Timorese voters who cast their ballots peacefully.  Timor-Leste’s election serves as an inspiration for democracy in Southeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and the world.  This achievement represents another milestone in Timor-Leste’s tremendous work to build and strengthen its robust, vibrant democracy over its nearly 20-year history as an independent nation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We congratulate President-elect José Ramos-Horta on his election as Timor-Leste’s next president and look forward to working with President-elect Ramos-Horta to strengthen the enduring partnership between the United States and Timor-Leste.  Rooted in shared values and interests, our partnership has delivered opportunities to improve the livelihoods of the Timorese people through economic development, public health, security cooperation, and educational exchanges and training.</p>
<p>We commend Timorese authorities, including the Technical Secretariat for Electoral Administration and the National Elections Commission, for administering a free, fair, and transparent election and the hundreds of thousands of Timorese voters who cast their ballots peacefully.  Timor-Leste’s election serves as an inspiration for democracy in Southeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and the world.  This achievement represents another milestone in Timor-Leste’s tremendous work to build and strengthen its robust, vibrant democracy over its nearly 20-year history as an independent nation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Migration Talks with the Government of Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/migration-talks-with-the-government-of-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 21, U.S. and Cuban officials met in Washington, D.C. to discuss the implementation of the U.S.-Cuba Migration Accords. These bilateral discussions on migration are generally held semiannually, reflecting a commitment by both countries to regularly review the implementation of the Accords. Deputy Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Emily Mendrala led the U.S. interagency delegation, and Cuba’s Vice Foreign Minister Carlos Fernandez de Cossio led the Cuban delegation. These migration talks provide an opportunity for discussions on mutual implementation of the Migration Accords (comprised of a series of bilateral agreements between the United States and Cuba done in 1984, 1994, 1995, and 2017). The U.S. delegation highlighted areas of successful cooperation on migration, while also identifying issues that have been obstacles to fulfilling the goals of the Accords. Engaging in these talks underscores our commitment to pursuing constructive discussions with the Government of Cuba where appropriate to advance U.S. interests. These discussions represent the first Migration Accord talks between the United States and Cuba since 2018.</p>
<p>The United States also addressed consular services at U.S. Embassy Havana, to include resumption of immigrant visa services on a limited basis starting in May, current American citizen services, and current issuance of emergency non-immigrant visas. Enabling safe, legal, and orderly migration between Cuba and the United States remains a mutual interest between the United States and Cuba and is consistent with U.S. interests in fostering family reunification and promoting greater respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cuba.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 21, U.S. and Cuban officials met in Washington, D.C. to discuss the implementation of the U.S.-Cuba Migration Accords. These bilateral discussions on migration are generally held semiannually, reflecting a commitment by both countries to regularly review the implementation of the Accords. Deputy Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Emily Mendrala led the U.S. interagency delegation, and Cuba’s Vice Foreign Minister Carlos Fernandez de Cossio led the Cuban delegation. These migration talks provide an opportunity for discussions on mutual implementation of the Migration Accords (comprised of a series of bilateral agreements between the United States and Cuba done in 1984, 1994, 1995, and 2017). The U.S. delegation highlighted areas of successful cooperation on migration, while also identifying issues that have been obstacles to fulfilling the goals of the Accords. Engaging in these talks underscores our commitment to pursuing constructive discussions with the Government of Cuba where appropriate to advance U.S. interests. These discussions represent the first Migration Accord talks between the United States and Cuba since 2018.</p>
<p>The United States also addressed consular services at U.S. Embassy Havana, to include resumption of immigrant visa services on a limited basis starting in May, current American citizen services, and current issuance of emergency non-immigrant visas. Enabling safe, legal, and orderly migration between Cuba and the United States remains a mutual interest between the United States and Cuba and is consistent with U.S. interests in fostering family reunification and promoting greater respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cuba.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Suspension of Russia’s Permanent Observer Status at the Organization of American States</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/suspension-of-russias-permanent-observer-status-at-the-organization-of-american-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States welcomes the adoption of a resolution at the Organization of American States (OAS) suspending Russia as a Permanent Observer to that institution.  With the passage of this resolution, OAS member states demonstrated that we do not stand on the sidelines in the face of the Russian government’s violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses.  Our Hemisphere stands with Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s inhumanity in its premeditated, unprovoked, unjust war against Ukraine is horrifically clear.   Deaths and destruction mount daily.  More than 10 million Ukrainian citizens and others have been uprooted by the Kremlin’s coldblooded aggression.  On a global scale, Putin’s senseless war of choice has hurt economies and threatened the food security of the world’s most vulnerable.  As President Biden stated, “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security.”</p>
<p>The Russian government’s brutal attack against Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty demonstrates the Kremlin’s utter contempt for the values of democracy and respect for human rights, values that form the bedrock of the Inter American system.  We commend the governments of Antigua and Barbuda and Guatemala for leading the adoption of the resolution, and all the governments that supported it.</p>
<p>The OAS action today sends a clear message to the Kremlin.   The overwhelming number of countries in the Americas called upon the Kremlin to end its unconscionable war of choice, withdraw its forces, and comply with international law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States welcomes the adoption of a resolution at the Organization of American States (OAS) suspending Russia as a Permanent Observer to that institution.  With the passage of this resolution, OAS member states demonstrated that we do not stand on the sidelines in the face of the Russian government’s violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses.  Our Hemisphere stands with Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s inhumanity in its premeditated, unprovoked, unjust war against Ukraine is horrifically clear.   Deaths and destruction mount daily.  More than 10 million Ukrainian citizens and others have been uprooted by the Kremlin’s coldblooded aggression.  On a global scale, Putin’s senseless war of choice has hurt economies and threatened the food security of the world’s most vulnerable.  As President Biden stated, “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security.”</p>
<p>The Russian government’s brutal attack against Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty demonstrates the Kremlin’s utter contempt for the values of democracy and respect for human rights, values that form the bedrock of the Inter American system.  We commend the governments of Antigua and Barbuda and Guatemala for leading the adoption of the resolution, and all the governments that supported it.</p>
<p>The OAS action today sends a clear message to the Kremlin.   The overwhelming number of countries in the Americas called upon the Kremlin to end its unconscionable war of choice, withdraw its forces, and comply with international law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Fernandez’s Travel to Chile </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-fernandezs-travel-to-chile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Santiago, Chile, April 21-23 to engage with government officials, business leaders, and civil society, in support of regional trade and investment objectives, climate and environment programs, and pandemic response and preparedness.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Fernandez will meet with officials from the Chilean Ministries of Foreign Affairs, Health, and Mining, and with private sector representatives to discuss our joint COVID-19 pandemic response, regional economic recovery, and ways to deepen our bilateral economic ties to promote increased economic inclusion and prosperity for U.S. and Chilean citizens. The Under Secretary will also meet with the Chilean Minister of Environment and Chilean environmental organizations to discuss additional opportunities for U.S.-Chilean collaboration on combatting the climate crisis and supporting sustainable trade and development. On Earth Day, he will also meet with Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean Acting Executive Secretary Mario Cimoli.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Santiago, Chile, April 21-23 to engage with government officials, business leaders, and civil society, in support of regional trade and investment objectives, climate and environment programs, and pandemic response and preparedness.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Fernandez will meet with officials from the Chilean Ministries of Foreign Affairs, Health, and Mining, and with private sector representatives to discuss our joint COVID-19 pandemic response, regional economic recovery, and ways to deepen our bilateral economic ties to promote increased economic inclusion and prosperity for U.S. and Chilean citizens. The Under Secretary will also meet with the Chilean Minister of Environment and Chilean environmental organizations to discuss additional opportunities for U.S.-Chilean collaboration on combatting the climate crisis and supporting sustainable trade and development. On Earth Day, he will also meet with Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean Acting Executive Secretary Mario Cimoli.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Donfried’s Travel to the Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-donfrieds-travel-to-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried will travel to the Western Balkans from April 25 to 29, with stops in Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Serbia.</p>
<p>On April 25, she will thank Kosovo for providing refuge to Afghans and Ukrainians, encourage work on reforms for democratic consolidation and integration into European and Euro-Atlantic institutions, and review prospects for progress in the U.S.-supported, EU-facilitated Dialogue with Serbia toward an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>She will travel to Serbia on April 26 to urge Serbia to advance reforms for its European integration, enhance regional stability and prosperity, discuss opportunities for further energy diversification, and broaden our bilateral security and economic ties.  She will reiterate the need for Serbia and Kosovo to reengage in the EU-facilitated Dialogue.</p>
<p>On April 27, in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), Dr. Donfried will encourage officials to resume institutional participation at all levels of government to advance functionality and common-sense reforms for greater prosperity and for BiH to obtain EU candidate status.  She will urge BiH to hold fall elections on time and make progress in fighting endemic corruption.</p>
<p>In North Macedonia on April 28, she will meet with government leaders to signal our strong support for North Macedonia’s EU accession negotiations and thank them for their ongoing assistance to Ukraine. She will urge NATO’s newest member to continue close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and regional stability.</p>
<p>On April 28 she will commemorate 100 years of U.S.-Albanian diplomatic relations and thank Albania for our partnership on the United Nations Security Council and for its commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russian aggression.  She will also underscore our strong support for Albania&#8217;s EU accession and regional economic integration, as well as emphasize the need to fully implement justice reform and combat corruption.</p>
<p>Dr. Donfried will travel to Montenegro on April 29, where she will highlight U.S. support for and the need to accelerate work on Montenegro’s Euro-Atlantic path and EU accession, strengthening NATO membership, and on supporting shared values, including tackling corruption.  She will also thank Montenegro for joining EU sanctions on Russia in support of Ukraine, and for providing humanitarian and security assistance, as well as for closing its airspace to Russian aircraft.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried will travel to the Western Balkans from April 25 to 29, with stops in Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Serbia.</p>
<p>On April 25, she will thank Kosovo for providing refuge to Afghans and Ukrainians, encourage work on reforms for democratic consolidation and integration into European and Euro-Atlantic institutions, and review prospects for progress in the U.S.-supported, EU-facilitated Dialogue with Serbia toward an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>She will travel to Serbia on April 26 to urge Serbia to advance reforms for its European integration, enhance regional stability and prosperity, discuss opportunities for further energy diversification, and broaden our bilateral security and economic ties.  She will reiterate the need for Serbia and Kosovo to reengage in the EU-facilitated Dialogue.</p>
<p>On April 27, in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), Dr. Donfried will encourage officials to resume institutional participation at all levels of government to advance functionality and common-sense reforms for greater prosperity and for BiH to obtain EU candidate status.  She will urge BiH to hold fall elections on time and make progress in fighting endemic corruption.</p>
<p>In North Macedonia on April 28, she will meet with government leaders to signal our strong support for North Macedonia’s EU accession negotiations and thank them for their ongoing assistance to Ukraine. She will urge NATO’s newest member to continue close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and regional stability.</p>
<p>On April 28 she will commemorate 100 years of U.S.-Albanian diplomatic relations and thank Albania for our partnership on the United Nations Security Council and for its commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russian aggression.  She will also underscore our strong support for Albania&#8217;s EU accession and regional economic integration, as well as emphasize the need to fully implement justice reform and combat corruption.</p>
<p>Dr. Donfried will travel to Montenegro on April 29, where she will highlight U.S. support for and the need to accelerate work on Montenegro’s Euro-Atlantic path and EU accession, strengthening NATO membership, and on supporting shared values, including tackling corruption.  She will also thank Montenegro for joining EU sanctions on Russia in support of Ukraine, and for providing humanitarian and security assistance, as well as for closing its airspace to Russian aircraft.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Third Senior-Level International Partners Meeting on Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/third-senior-level-international-partners-meeting-on-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Brian A. Nichols, attended a senior-level international partners meeting on Haiti on April 21.  Hosted by France, this meeting convened international partner countries and international organizations for the third time in the past four months in support of progress on the challenges facing Haiti.  Participants encouraged political accord among Haitian actors so elections can take place as soon as conditions permit.</p>
<p>On April 1, the United States announced it would partner with Haiti through the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, which complements our existing programming in Haiti.  As the international community encourages Haitian political actors, civil society, and other stakeholders to find consensus and reach a political accord, this is an opportune time for coordinating future support for security, good governance, democratic institutions, and elections.</p>
<p>This meeting also reaffirms our efforts in providing advisory support, training, and other resources to the Haitian National Police (HNP).  In addition to deploying additional trainers and refurbishing HNP training facilities, the United States has delivered 60 new vehicles to the HNP.  The United States is working with HNP leadership to develop an elite unit capable of high-impact arrests and anti-gang operations, as well as expand its community policing efforts to regain the trust of citizens in gang-affected neighborhoods.</p>
<p>We commend our partners who have also contributed to building the operational capacity of the HNP.  We continue to work with international partners and organizations to support Haiti’s response to complex security challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Brian A. Nichols, attended a senior-level international partners meeting on Haiti on April 21.  Hosted by France, this meeting convened international partner countries and international organizations for the third time in the past four months in support of progress on the challenges facing Haiti.  Participants encouraged political accord among Haitian actors so elections can take place as soon as conditions permit.</p>
<p>On April 1, the United States announced it would partner with Haiti through the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, which complements our existing programming in Haiti.  As the international community encourages Haitian political actors, civil society, and other stakeholders to find consensus and reach a political accord, this is an opportune time for coordinating future support for security, good governance, democratic institutions, and elections.</p>
<p>This meeting also reaffirms our efforts in providing advisory support, training, and other resources to the Haitian National Police (HNP).  In addition to deploying additional trainers and refurbishing HNP training facilities, the United States has delivered 60 new vehicles to the HNP.  The United States is working with HNP leadership to develop an elite unit capable of high-impact arrests and anti-gang operations, as well as expand its community policing efforts to regain the trust of citizens in gang-affected neighborhoods.</p>
<p>We commend our partners who have also contributed to building the operational capacity of the HNP.  We continue to work with international partners and organizations to support Haiti’s response to complex security challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of choice against Ukraine and its brutal tactics, including egregious atrocities. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine and to assist the millions who have been forced to leave their homes. They also discussed the imposition of additional sanctions and other economic measures to hold the Russian Federation accountable. All expressed concern over food security due to Russia’s war and pledged to work together to find solutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of choice against Ukraine and its brutal tactics, including egregious atrocities. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine and to assist the millions who have been forced to leave their homes. They also discussed the imposition of additional sanctions and other economic measures to hold the Russian Federation accountable. All expressed concern over food security due to Russia’s war and pledged to work together to find solutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening of U.S.-Czech Republic Defense Cooperation Agreement Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-of-u-s-czech-republic-defense-cooperation-agreement-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes <wbr />Czech Defense Minister Jana Černochová’s announcement today to begin negotiating a bilateral Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>The agreement builds on the provisions of the NATO Status of Forces Agreement (SOFA) and is similar to other bilateral agreements the United States has concluded with other NATO Allies, including many of the Czech Republic’s neighbors along NATO’s Eastern Flank.  This agreement, when concluded, will help create an overarching framework to codify already existing cooperation between our two militaries, formalizing procedures, and providing a more transparent, predictable, and robust framework for both bilateral and enhanced NATO cooperation.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a tremendous source of American strength.  Since 1993, the United States and the Czech Republic have worked closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, the NATO Alliance, and the world.  Opening these consultations with the Czech Republic reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes <wbr />Czech Defense Minister Jana Černochová’s announcement today to begin negotiating a bilateral Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>The agreement builds on the provisions of the NATO Status of Forces Agreement (SOFA) and is similar to other bilateral agreements the United States has concluded with other NATO Allies, including many of the Czech Republic’s neighbors along NATO’s Eastern Flank.  This agreement, when concluded, will help create an overarching framework to codify already existing cooperation between our two militaries, formalizing procedures, and providing a more transparent, predictable, and robust framework for both bilateral and enhanced NATO cooperation.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a tremendous source of American strength.  Since 1993, the United States and the Czech Republic have worked closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, the NATO Alliance, and the world.  Opening these consultations with the Czech Republic reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
