<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:55:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Friends of Sudan Joint Statement on the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD Facilitated Political Process</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/friends-of-sudan-joint-statement-on-the-unitams-au-igad-facilitated-political-process/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Following is a joint statement on the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD Facilitated Political Process issued by Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan.</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan reiterate our strong support for the combined efforts of the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission to Sudan (UNITAMS), the African Union (AU), and the Intergovernmental Authority on Development (IGAD) to facilitate a Sudanese-led political process with the aim of restoring a civilian-led transition to democracy. We applaud these actors’ ongoing efforts to consult with a broad range of Sudanese stakeholders. We look forward to the imminent launch of the next phase of the talks with the aim of building consensus around the structure of credible, civilian-led institutions that will lead Sudan through a revived civilian-led transition period, culminating in free and fair democratic elections. The urgency cannot be overstated. We, therefore, urge constructive engagement of all stakeholders in this next phase and underscore the importance of ensuring women, as well as youth, and other historically marginalized groups enjoy full, effective, and meaningful participation and inclusion throughout every stage of the process.</p>
<p>We welcome the progress made so far through the cooperation of Sudanese stakeholders and the combined efforts of UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD. For this UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process to succeed, an enabling environment that allows all stakeholders to participate and freely express their views must be created, and Sudanese citizens must be protected from all kinds of violence. We welcome the commitments of the Sudanese authorities in this regard and encourage their implementation. Full respect for freedoms of association, expression, and peaceful assembly is vital, as is protection of property.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the immense economic pressures currently facing the Sudanese people and are committed to continuing to provide direct, humanitarian support to them during this difficult period. We look forward to the restoration of a credible transitional government agreed through the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process, which would pave the way to restore economic assistance and international debt relief.</p>
<p>As members of the Friends of Sudan, we continue to endorse the Sudanese-led political process facilitated by UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD as the best vehicle to realize the Sudanese people’s aspirations for freedom, peace, and justice and to restore Sudan’s democratic transition. We continue to pledge our full support to the Sudanese people and this process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Following is a joint statement on the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD Facilitated Political Process issued by Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan.</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan reiterate our strong support for the combined efforts of the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission to Sudan (UNITAMS), the African Union (AU), and the Intergovernmental Authority on Development (IGAD) to facilitate a Sudanese-led political process with the aim of restoring a civilian-led transition to democracy. We applaud these actors’ ongoing efforts to consult with a broad range of Sudanese stakeholders. We look forward to the imminent launch of the next phase of the talks with the aim of building consensus around the structure of credible, civilian-led institutions that will lead Sudan through a revived civilian-led transition period, culminating in free and fair democratic elections. The urgency cannot be overstated. We, therefore, urge constructive engagement of all stakeholders in this next phase and underscore the importance of ensuring women, as well as youth, and other historically marginalized groups enjoy full, effective, and meaningful participation and inclusion throughout every stage of the process.</p>
<p>We welcome the progress made so far through the cooperation of Sudanese stakeholders and the combined efforts of UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD. For this UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process to succeed, an enabling environment that allows all stakeholders to participate and freely express their views must be created, and Sudanese citizens must be protected from all kinds of violence. We welcome the commitments of the Sudanese authorities in this regard and encourage their implementation. Full respect for freedoms of association, expression, and peaceful assembly is vital, as is protection of property.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the immense economic pressures currently facing the Sudanese people and are committed to continuing to provide direct, humanitarian support to them during this difficult period. We look forward to the restoration of a credible transitional government agreed through the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process, which would pave the way to restore economic assistance and international debt relief.</p>
<p>As members of the Friends of Sudan, we continue to endorse the Sudanese-led political process facilitated by UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD as the best vehicle to realize the Sudanese people’s aspirations for freedom, peace, and justice and to restore Sudan’s democratic transition. We continue to pledge our full support to the Sudanese people and this process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman in Response to Russia at a UN Security Council Briefing on the Humanitarian Impact of Russia&#8217;s War Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/remarks-by-deputy-secretary-of-state-wendy-sherman-in-response-to-russia-at-a-un-security-council-briefing-on-the-humanitarian-impact-of-russias-war-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329311</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thank you very much and thank you for giving me this opportunity today. Much appreciated, Madam President. I feel that I must make four critical points.</p>
<p>First, I want to be clear that the conflict that is being suffered by the Ukrainian people is not about the Russian Federation versus the West. One hundred and forty countries, just last week, spoke in support of ending this conflict and the need to end this humanitarian crisis. A hundred and forty-one countries supported the initial resolution in the UN General Assembly, to say that this invasion by Russia should stop.</p>
<p>So, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, this is not about Russia versus the West. This is about the support of the UN Charter and the principles of sovereignty, territorial integrity, and the right of all countries – all countries – to choose their political orientation and their foreign policy.</p>
<p>Second, I myself was engaged directly with Russian counterparts to find a peaceful way forward to meet the concerns of the Russian Federation. I sat opposite Russian counterparts and put on the table many options to address the concerns. We provided, as does NATO, a paper of very specific ways in which we could address, reciprocally and mutually, security concerns. President Putin chose an invasion, not diplomacy.</p>
<p>Third, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, as a Jewish American, I cannot help but say this is not about Nazis in Ukraine. Last week, former U.S. Secretary of State, and former Permanent Representative to this Council, and one of my most cherished personal friends, Madeleine Albright died. She loved representing the United States here. She would have been outraged by the words of the Russian Federation today.</p>
<p>Later in her life, she learned that her parents raised her as Catholic to protect her from the Nazis because her family was Jewish. She learned that three of her grandparents died at the hands of the Nazis, while in concentration camps. She knew that the Jewish President of Ukraine was certainly not a Nazi. And that the citizens of Ukraine being slaughtered and starving, and without food and medicine, and the subject of this humanitarian dialogue today, are not and never were Nazis.</p>
<p>And finally, this dialogue today is about the humanitarian needs of Ukrainian civilians and humanitarian needs of people around the world, who as David Beasley said so eloquently, “feeding hungry children, to feeding starving children.” It&#8217;s about, as he said, “going from a breadbasket to a breadline.”</p>
<p>We must all do whatever we can, of course, to stop war. But there is an easy choice here. And it is a choice that can be made today in Istanbul, by President Putin, and that is to stop the war. So let us all, over 140 countries around the world, continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thank you very much and thank you for giving me this opportunity today. Much appreciated, Madam President. I feel that I must make four critical points.</p>
<p>First, I want to be clear that the conflict that is being suffered by the Ukrainian people is not about the Russian Federation versus the West. One hundred and forty countries, just last week, spoke in support of ending this conflict and the need to end this humanitarian crisis. A hundred and forty-one countries supported the initial resolution in the UN General Assembly, to say that this invasion by Russia should stop.</p>
<p>So, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, this is not about Russia versus the West. This is about the support of the UN Charter and the principles of sovereignty, territorial integrity, and the right of all countries – all countries – to choose their political orientation and their foreign policy.</p>
<p>Second, I myself was engaged directly with Russian counterparts to find a peaceful way forward to meet the concerns of the Russian Federation. I sat opposite Russian counterparts and put on the table many options to address the concerns. We provided, as does NATO, a paper of very specific ways in which we could address, reciprocally and mutually, security concerns. President Putin chose an invasion, not diplomacy.</p>
<p>Third, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, as a Jewish American, I cannot help but say this is not about Nazis in Ukraine. Last week, former U.S. Secretary of State, and former Permanent Representative to this Council, and one of my most cherished personal friends, Madeleine Albright died. She loved representing the United States here. She would have been outraged by the words of the Russian Federation today.</p>
<p>Later in her life, she learned that her parents raised her as Catholic to protect her from the Nazis because her family was Jewish. She learned that three of her grandparents died at the hands of the Nazis, while in concentration camps. She knew that the Jewish President of Ukraine was certainly not a Nazi. And that the citizens of Ukraine being slaughtered and starving, and without food and medicine, and the subject of this humanitarian dialogue today, are not and never were Nazis.</p>
<p>And finally, this dialogue today is about the humanitarian needs of Ukrainian civilians and humanitarian needs of people around the world, who as David Beasley said so eloquently, “feeding hungry children, to feeding starving children.” It&#8217;s about, as he said, “going from a breadbasket to a breadline.”</p>
<p>We must all do whatever we can, of course, to stop war. But there is an easy choice here. And it is a choice that can be made today in Istanbul, by President Putin, and that is to stop the war. So let us all, over 140 countries around the world, continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-crown-prince-of-abu-dhabi-sheikh-mohammed-bin-zayed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, in Rabat, Morocco.  The Secretary reaffirmed the countries’ close partnership and reviewed ways to broaden and deepen wide-ranging cooperation. The Secretary underscored that we remain committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats stemming from Yemen and elsewhere in the region.  He welcomed the UAE&#8217;s support for a truce leading to a ceasefire in Yemen and reiterated that the only path to a durable peace is through dialogue and diplomacy.  They also discussed President Putin&#8217;s unjustified war against the people of Ukraine as well as the conflict in Syria.  The Secretary again commended the UAE’s progress on normalization with Israel through the Abraham Accords and noted that he looks forward to working with the UAE and other partners on the initiatives conceived during the Negev Summit.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken thanked the Crown Prince for the UAE’s generous support in hosting and facilitating the safe transit of people from Afghanistan and commended the UAE for providing humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan as well as to Ukraine.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, in Rabat, Morocco.  The Secretary reaffirmed the countries’ close partnership and reviewed ways to broaden and deepen wide-ranging cooperation. The Secretary underscored that we remain committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats stemming from Yemen and elsewhere in the region.  He welcomed the UAE&#8217;s support for a truce leading to a ceasefire in Yemen and reiterated that the only path to a durable peace is through dialogue and diplomacy.  They also discussed President Putin&#8217;s unjustified war against the people of Ukraine as well as the conflict in Syria.  The Secretary again commended the UAE’s progress on normalization with Israel through the Abraham Accords and noted that he looks forward to working with the UAE and other partners on the initiatives conceived during the Negev Summit.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken thanked the Crown Prince for the UAE’s generous support in hosting and facilitating the safe transit of people from Afghanistan and commended the UAE for providing humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan as well as to Ukraine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Support of Partners Expelling Russian Intelligence Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/support-of-partners-expelling-russian-intelligence-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States applauds recent expulsions of Russian intelligence officers by our partners in Europe and around the world.  As our partners have outlined, these actions are in response to these individuals&#8217; activities, which are in contravention of their diplomatic status, and the Russian Federation’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>We stand unified with our partners in protecting their national security from the Russian Federation’s intelligence threats and against threats to democracy.  We continue our united support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to working with our Allies and partners to keep pressure on the Russian Federation and protect our common national interests from the Russian Federation’s actions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States applauds recent expulsions of Russian intelligence officers by our partners in Europe and around the world.  As our partners have outlined, these actions are in response to these individuals&#8217; activities, which are in contravention of their diplomatic status, and the Russian Federation’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>We stand unified with our partners in protecting their national security from the Russian Federation’s intelligence threats and against threats to democracy.  We continue our united support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to working with our Allies and partners to keep pressure on the Russian Federation and protect our common national interests from the Russian Federation’s actions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Moroccan Prime Minister Akhannouch   </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-moroccan-prime-minister-akhannouch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Moroccan Prime Minister Aziz Akhannouch in Rabat. The Secretary thanked the Prime Minister for his and his government&#8217;s hospitality, and they engaged in a wide-ranging discussion regarding bilateral, regional, and international priorities, including the effort to combat the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis. They also discussed King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda and the economic and social challenges Morocco faces. The Secretary remarked on the successes of the five-year, $460 million compact administered by the U.S. Millennium Challenge Corporation and focused on expanding opportunities for people across the Kingdom. They also reviewed our strong economic ties and discussed how we can deepen them. Across all of these efforts, the Secretary noted the importance of advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, including freedom of expression, in line with Morocco’s international commitments.</p>
<p>The Secretary emphasized the need for President Putin to end his war against the people of Ukraine, which is having tangible implications on the region, including higher food, commodity, and energy prices. The Secretary pledged the United States&#8217; continued support for the Kingdom and its people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Moroccan Prime Minister Aziz Akhannouch in Rabat. The Secretary thanked the Prime Minister for his and his government&#8217;s hospitality, and they engaged in a wide-ranging discussion regarding bilateral, regional, and international priorities, including the effort to combat the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis. They also discussed King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda and the economic and social challenges Morocco faces. The Secretary remarked on the successes of the five-year, $460 million compact administered by the U.S. Millennium Challenge Corporation and focused on expanding opportunities for people across the Kingdom. They also reviewed our strong economic ties and discussed how we can deepen them. Across all of these efforts, the Secretary noted the importance of advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, including freedom of expression, in line with Morocco’s international commitments.</p>
<p>The Secretary emphasized the need for President Putin to end his war against the people of Ukraine, which is having tangible implications on the region, including higher food, commodity, and energy prices. The Secretary pledged the United States&#8217; continued support for the Kingdom and its people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Concern About the Deteriorating Situation in South Sudan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-concern-about-the-deteriorating-situation-in-south-sudan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States notes with concern the growing tensions in South Sudan, including recent clashes between the South Sudan People’s Defense Force’s (SSPDF) and the Sudan People’s Liberation Army/Movement-In Opposition (SPLA/M-IO) in Upper Nile state.  We call for both sides to observe fully their obligations under the existing peace agreement and note that inflammatory rhetoric is counterproductive and should cease immediately. The SPLM-IO’s withdrawal from all peace agreement monitoring and verification mechanisms undermines the peace agreement and must be immediately reversed as ceasefire monitoring bodies investigate the recent violence and seek to hold perpetrators responsible.</p>
<p>The United States calls on President Salva Kiir and First Vice President Riek Machar to do their utmost to de-escalate tensions and to uphold their respective obligations under the 2018 peace agreement, including its ceasefire provisions.  We call on both leaders to resume implementation of key, long-delayed provisions of the revitalized peace agreement, including taking the necessary steps to establish an inclusive process to draft a new constitution, to establish necessary electoral legislation and mechanisms, and to respect the freedoms of expression, association, and peaceful assembly.  We urge regional states and institutions, namely the Intergovernmental Authority on Development, that are guarantors of the revitalized peace agreement to take swift action to lower tensions and put the peace process back on track prior to the expiration of the already extended transition period in February 2023.</p>
<p>All sides bear responsibility for the deteriorating situation.  Neither President Kiir nor First Vice President Machar have made good faith efforts to implement the provisions of the revitalized peace agreement, and both have resisted serious attempts to move South Sudan towards the peace, security, and prosperity the South Sudanese people continue to desire.  Furthermore, numerous other political leaders also fail to carry out their official responsibilities and many engage in political violence and otherwise violate the letter and spirit of the peace agreement. We call on all members of the Revitalized Transitional Government of National Unity to take the actions necessary to be seen as credible in the eyes of the South Sudanese people, starting with full adherence to and implementation of the 2018 peace agreement.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States notes with concern the growing tensions in South Sudan, including recent clashes between the South Sudan People’s Defense Force’s (SSPDF) and the Sudan People’s Liberation Army/Movement-In Opposition (SPLA/M-IO) in Upper Nile state.  We call for both sides to observe fully their obligations under the existing peace agreement and note that inflammatory rhetoric is counterproductive and should cease immediately. The SPLM-IO’s withdrawal from all peace agreement monitoring and verification mechanisms undermines the peace agreement and must be immediately reversed as ceasefire monitoring bodies investigate the recent violence and seek to hold perpetrators responsible.</p>
<p>The United States calls on President Salva Kiir and First Vice President Riek Machar to do their utmost to de-escalate tensions and to uphold their respective obligations under the 2018 peace agreement, including its ceasefire provisions.  We call on both leaders to resume implementation of key, long-delayed provisions of the revitalized peace agreement, including taking the necessary steps to establish an inclusive process to draft a new constitution, to establish necessary electoral legislation and mechanisms, and to respect the freedoms of expression, association, and peaceful assembly.  We urge regional states and institutions, namely the Intergovernmental Authority on Development, that are guarantors of the revitalized peace agreement to take swift action to lower tensions and put the peace process back on track prior to the expiration of the already extended transition period in February 2023.</p>
<p>All sides bear responsibility for the deteriorating situation.  Neither President Kiir nor First Vice President Machar have made good faith efforts to implement the provisions of the revitalized peace agreement, and both have resisted serious attempts to move South Sudan towards the peace, security, and prosperity the South Sudanese people continue to desire.  Furthermore, numerous other political leaders also fail to carry out their official responsibilities and many engage in political violence and otherwise violate the letter and spirit of the peace agreement. We call on all members of the Revitalized Transitional Government of National Unity to take the actions necessary to be seen as credible in the eyes of the South Sudanese people, starting with full adherence to and implementation of the 2018 peace agreement.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Announces Additional Humanitarian Assistance at the Launch of the 2022 Joint Response Plan for the Rohingya Humanitarian Crisis in Bangladesh</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-announces-additional-humanitarian-assistance-at-the-launch-of-the-2022-joint-response-plan-for-the-rohingya-humanitarian-crisis-in-bangladesh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the launch of the 2022 Joint Response Plan for the Rohingya Humanitarian Crisis in Bangladesh, U.S. Ambassador to Bangladesh Peter Haas announced more than $152 million in additional humanitarian assistance for those in Bangladesh, Burma, and elsewhere in the region affected by the Burmese military’s genocide, crimes against humanity, and ethnic cleansing against Rohingya.  With this new funding, our total assistance for this response reaches more than $1.7 billion since August 2017, when over 740,000 Rohingya were forced to flee to safety in Cox’s Bazar, Bangladesh.  This announcement demonstrates our solidarity with Rohingya and the generous communities hosting them as well as our ongoing commitment to strengthening the international response to the Rohingya crisis and the escalating violence in Burma.</p>
<p>The humanitarian assistance includes nearly $51 million from the State Department’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) and more than $101 million from the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID).  With more than $125 million for programs specifically in Bangladesh, this funding will enable our humanitarian partners to provide life-saving assistance to the over 920,000 Rohingya refugees in Bangladesh.  It also provides support to more than 540,000 affected members of the local host community in Bangladesh.  This assistance helps ensure children and young adults have access to education and vocational training, provides families with food, healthcare, access to clean water and sanitation to prevent the spread of disease, supports the protection of Rohingya refugees’ human rights and well-being, strengthens disaster preparedness, and helps combat the effects of climate change.  We commend our humanitarian partners for a strong and well-coordinated response as this crisis approaches its fifth year.</p>
<p>The United States recognizes that Bangladesh and its people have taken on an enormous responsibility in hosting refugees.  We are working with the Government of Bangladesh, Rohingya, and people within Burma toward finding solutions to this crisis, including the safe, voluntary, dignified, and sustainable return and reintegration of Rohingya refugees and internally displaced persons when conditions in Burma allow.  Secretary Blinken has determined that members of the Burmese military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya, and that many of those responsible for these atrocities are the same people who led the military coup in 2021 and ongoing violence across Burma.  We are relentlessly pressuring Burma’s military regime to stop its violence and return to the path of democracy.  At the same time, we also must expand education and livelihood opportunities, including cash-for-work programs and access to local markets, for Rohingya refugees in the region.  Education and income-generating activities are among the most effective methods to create safer refugee camps in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to delivering aid to Rohingya, and we welcome the generous pledges made by other donors at today’s event.  However, more support is desperately needed.  We urge other donors to come forward now with additional funds to sustain and increase support for the Rakhine State/Rohingya refugee crisis and those suffering from the escalating violence perpetrated by the genocidal military in Burma today.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the launch of the 2022 Joint Response Plan for the Rohingya Humanitarian Crisis in Bangladesh, U.S. Ambassador to Bangladesh Peter Haas announced more than $152 million in additional humanitarian assistance for those in Bangladesh, Burma, and elsewhere in the region affected by the Burmese military’s genocide, crimes against humanity, and ethnic cleansing against Rohingya.  With this new funding, our total assistance for this response reaches more than $1.7 billion since August 2017, when over 740,000 Rohingya were forced to flee to safety in Cox’s Bazar, Bangladesh.  This announcement demonstrates our solidarity with Rohingya and the generous communities hosting them as well as our ongoing commitment to strengthening the international response to the Rohingya crisis and the escalating violence in Burma.</p>
<p>The humanitarian assistance includes nearly $51 million from the State Department’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) and more than $101 million from the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID).  With more than $125 million for programs specifically in Bangladesh, this funding will enable our humanitarian partners to provide life-saving assistance to the over 920,000 Rohingya refugees in Bangladesh.  It also provides support to more than 540,000 affected members of the local host community in Bangladesh.  This assistance helps ensure children and young adults have access to education and vocational training, provides families with food, healthcare, access to clean water and sanitation to prevent the spread of disease, supports the protection of Rohingya refugees’ human rights and well-being, strengthens disaster preparedness, and helps combat the effects of climate change.  We commend our humanitarian partners for a strong and well-coordinated response as this crisis approaches its fifth year.</p>
<p>The United States recognizes that Bangladesh and its people have taken on an enormous responsibility in hosting refugees.  We are working with the Government of Bangladesh, Rohingya, and people within Burma toward finding solutions to this crisis, including the safe, voluntary, dignified, and sustainable return and reintegration of Rohingya refugees and internally displaced persons when conditions in Burma allow.  Secretary Blinken has determined that members of the Burmese military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya, and that many of those responsible for these atrocities are the same people who led the military coup in 2021 and ongoing violence across Burma.  We are relentlessly pressuring Burma’s military regime to stop its violence and return to the path of democracy.  At the same time, we also must expand education and livelihood opportunities, including cash-for-work programs and access to local markets, for Rohingya refugees in the region.  Education and income-generating activities are among the most effective methods to create safer refugee camps in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to delivering aid to Rohingya, and we welcome the generous pledges made by other donors at today’s event.  However, more support is desperately needed.  We urge other donors to come forward now with additional funds to sustain and increase support for the Rakhine State/Rohingya refugee crisis and those suffering from the escalating violence perpetrated by the genocidal military in Burma today.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-crown-prince-of-abu-dhabi-sheikh-mohammed-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Residence of the Crown Prince</p>
<p><strong>CROWN PRINCE BIN ZAYED:  </strong>(In progress)  This is a very important opportunity, and I’m sure we have a lot to talk about, especially between our bilateral relationship.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Your Highness, I’m grateful for the time today, and actually I’m grateful for the time every day because the partnership between our countries truly matters to the United States.  The UAE is a leader in the region, increasingly a leader in the world, and the many things that we are trying to do, including for our own people around the world, are going to be much more effective if they’re doing them together with you.</p>
<p>And we have a lot of challenges, but we also have some remarkable opportunities.  We were just, as you know, in the Negev, and that in and of itself was an extraordinary moment, and it’s the product in large part of the vision and courage you and other leaders in the UAE brought to it.  Sheikh Abdullah spoke very powerfully, and eloquently, and from the heart about what this could represent, and that had a real impact, I think.</p>
<p>At the same time, we have real challenges to confront together in the region and beyond – in the region, in Yemen, the aggression being committed by the Houthis, including terrorist attacks against the UAE, against Saudi Arabia.  We’re determined to do everything we can to help you defend yourselves effectively against that.  We will be consulting on Iran, another shared challenge, the status of the talks on the JCPOA, but also the work we can do together and need to do together to strengthen our collective security.</p>
<p>And finally, we have, unfortunately, Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, the impact it’s having not only in Europe but around the world, including here – food prices, energy prices, all of this.  But for all of this, I must tell you we are grateful for and committed to the partnership that we have with the UAE, and I am grateful for the time to be able to spend some time to talk to you about that today.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>CROWN PRINCE BIN ZAYED:  </strong>It’s my pleasure, sir.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Residence of the Crown Prince</p>
<p><strong>CROWN PRINCE BIN ZAYED:  </strong>(In progress)  This is a very important opportunity, and I’m sure we have a lot to talk about, especially between our bilateral relationship.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Your Highness, I’m grateful for the time today, and actually I’m grateful for the time every day because the partnership between our countries truly matters to the United States.  The UAE is a leader in the region, increasingly a leader in the world, and the many things that we are trying to do, including for our own people around the world, are going to be much more effective if they’re doing them together with you.</p>
<p>And we have a lot of challenges, but we also have some remarkable opportunities.  We were just, as you know, in the Negev, and that in and of itself was an extraordinary moment, and it’s the product in large part of the vision and courage you and other leaders in the UAE brought to it.  Sheikh Abdullah spoke very powerfully, and eloquently, and from the heart about what this could represent, and that had a real impact, I think.</p>
<p>At the same time, we have real challenges to confront together in the region and beyond – in the region, in Yemen, the aggression being committed by the Houthis, including terrorist attacks against the UAE, against Saudi Arabia.  We’re determined to do everything we can to help you defend yourselves effectively against that.  We will be consulting on Iran, another shared challenge, the status of the talks on the JCPOA, but also the work we can do together and need to do together to strengthen our collective security.</p>
<p>And finally, we have, unfortunately, Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, the impact it’s having not only in Europe but around the world, including here – food prices, energy prices, all of this.  But for all of this, I must tell you we are grateful for and committed to the partnership that we have with the UAE, and I am grateful for the time to be able to spend some time to talk to you about that today.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>CROWN PRINCE BIN ZAYED:  </strong>It’s my pleasure, sir.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Moroccan Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita at a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-moroccan-foreign-minister-nasser-bourita-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 18:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Dear Secretary of State the U.S., like to extend a warm welcome to him to Morocco.  We are all pleased and glad to meet him in our – in his – the first official state meeting of Secretary of State in the current administration to Morocco.  Welcome to you, sir.</p>
<p>As per the vision of His Majesty King Mohammed VI, the Moroccan-U.S. relations have always been longstanding and based on longstanding partnership that’s quite ambitious and developed, also grounded on personal relation between His Majesty King Mohammed VI and President Joe Biden since their meeting in Marrakesh back in 2016.</p>
<p>With Mr. Secretary of State we met yesterday in Negev, in Israel, to talk about how to support positive dynamics in the Middle East.  We are convening today also today as part of our endeavor to further strengthen our relations.  In May, we’ll convene again as part of the Global Alliance and Coalition Against ISIS and to support our joint endeavors to fight extremism and terrorism worldwide.  In June, Morocco and the U.S. will hold African Lion maneuvers.  That’s one of the major parts of our military cooperation.  In July, we will also host the Economic American-African Forum in Marrakesh.  All this testifies to the richness of our U.S. and Moroccan relations.</p>
<p>Thanks to their variety and diversity, this covers the political side, the security side, the military side, the economic side.  This is a partnership that goes back – our bilateral relations – to cover other areas like the Middle East, Africa, and other parts of the world.  Our relations are strong.  Our partnership is strong, grounded on mutual shared values, shared interests, grounded also on a shared vision around a number of international issues and regional issues.</p>
<p>His Majesty the King wants to make sure that these relations move forward as part of the tools and mechanisms that we all have.  The Strategic Dialogue and we held two weeks ago around with Lady Wendy Sherman.  Also dialogue on human rights, and we held two rounds earlier.  The FTA, that is the only U.S. agreement with an African country which has resulted in very positive outcomes in terms of developing and promoting our trade relations.  And we hope this will also play a key role in moving forward with the U.S. investments in Morocco.</p>
<p>As part of the MCC also, which has been a contribution, an important contribution to the endeavor of Morocco and also as part of tools for security and military cooperation.  This cooperation has always been strong and very productive, resulting in many initiatives between the U.S. and Morocco.  Today, we have talked around all these issues and how to further develop our mutual relation’s and bilateral relations so this partnership can be strong and modeled based on historical values, and also in line with the current ambitions and values.</p>
<p>We have talked about different challenges in Middle East, and we’d like to thank the U.S. as a party to the three-party agreement signed before His Majesty back in January – in December 2022, where Morocco has relaunched its relations with Israel.  This agreement has resulted in positive outcomes, and we can – this can also yield more fruits as part of concrete project that are beneficial to the Moroccan and Israeli peoples.  But the three-party agreement – Israel, U.S., and Morocco – is also a message and a sign for the need of a two-state solution, steady solution, in the Middle East by setting up free states which Jerusalem as a capital, living and coexisting with Israel.  And as part of the vision of His Majesty the King, Jerusalem can be a city for coexistence.</p>
<p>We have talked also about our partnership in Africa to face up to the different challenges and also to make profit of the many opportunities we have in Africa economically, in terms of trade, and also in terms of climate changes, and also in the area of trade and infrastructures, and also in terms of security and healthcare and military.  Africa is fertile land for U.S.-Moroccan cooperation.  And also the North Africa and Sahel, there are many challenge; there are many tensions that have to be addressed.  And also there are many security-related challenges that need to be addressed positively and constructively.</p>
<p>I think your visit, Tony, is very important and that has produced clear messages about this cooperation, the many possibilities we can actually profit from here to the benefit for our two countries, but also to the benefit of security and stability and development in areas that we consider to be very important to us and to you.  Once again, thank you for your visit, and you’re most welcome.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Foreign Minister, Nasser, thank you.  It’s really good to be with you once again.  It feels like it was only yesterday.</p>
<p>Indeed, we just came from the historic Negev Summit, and together with our partners from Bahrain, from Egypt, the United Arab Emirates, and Israel, we discussed, as Nasser said, a wide range of areas where we can seize on normalization to make a positive impact on the lives of our people.  It’s an effort that quite simply would not have been possible were it not for the courage and vision of leaders like His Majesty King Mohammed VI to break down longstanding barriers.  And I’m committed to working with the foreign minister and all our friends here and across the region to make this vision real, translating it into more opportunities for people and further widening the circle of friendship.</p>
<p>Now, while integration among some of these countries is new, the diplomatic relationship between Morocco and the United States dates back more than 240 years, and its depth and breadth are reflected in everything we discussed today, and Nasser touched on a lot of these issues.  For more than 15 years, our free trade agreement has benefited people and companies in both of our countries and beyond.  Today, we discussed how we can continue to grow our economic cooperation in particular to benefit underserved populations.</p>
<p>For example, we’re in the fifth and final year of what is a $460 million compact administrated by the U.S. Millennium Challenge Corporation.  That’s provided jobs and education opportunities for young people, boosted agricultural productivity, expanded land rights for women.  The compact includes a partnership with Morocco’s Ministry of Education that is piloting a model aimed at improving secondary education in 90 secondary schools across the country, training some 6,000 teachers and administrators, making investments in the schools’ infrastructure and in its technology.</p>
<p>Just last week, our officials came together and broke ground on a major expansion of the industrial zone in Bouznika, backed by a public-private partnership, and that is expected to generate some 4,000 jobs.</p>
<p>Partners show up for each other in difficult times, and as Morocco experiences one of the worst droughts in decades, we’re doing what we can to help.  Now, I tried to do what I could to help by bringing a little rain with me today – (laughter) – but that’s clearly not enough.  We have experts from the State Department and the Department of the Interior consulting directly with their Moroccan counterparts on immediate steps to diminish the drought’s impact and to increase water conversation.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, we’re hosting a conference in Casablanca that will bring together your top water management companies with some experts from the United States to focus on how this country can better produce, use, and conserve its water resources.  And going back long before this drought, we’d been working to build greater capacity in the country to try to predict, prepare for, and mitigate the worst impacts of droughts, and to train rising generations of Moroccan water management experts.  The drought’s already affected agricultural production, we know raising the cost of food.</p>
<p>Now, the natural disaster is being worsened by a manmade disaster, as the Russian Government and its brutal war in Ukraine has disrupted the supply of wheat and other commodities.  Here, across the region, we’re discussing concrete steps we can take and our partners can take to help reduce the impact of these shortages, particularly on the most vulnerable populations.  This disruption is another reason we’ll continue to urge our friends and partners to speak out with one voice in condemning the Russian Government’s aggression – the consequences of which are being felt around the world – and hold the Kremlin accountable for as long as this continues.</p>
<p>The increasing frequency and severity of droughts and other extreme weather here, in the United States, around the world also underscores the urgency of our collective efforts to address the climate crisis.  And in this, Morocco is a world leader, setting an ambitious target of achieving 63 percent renewable energy by 2035.  With 45 percent of the country’s electricity production already coming from renewables, Morocco is on track to meet this ambitious target and even exceed it.  Morocco also signed the Global Methane Pledge at COP26, and at COP22, the kingdom founded three African-wide commissions – the Congo Basin Commission, the Sahel Commission, the Small Island Nations Commission – and continues to lead climate finance and feasibility studies for all three of them.</p>
<p>We’ve also worked side by side in combating the COVID-19 pandemic.  We’ve been able to donate more than 2.5 million safe, effective vaccines to Morocco through the COVAX Initiative over the last several months alone.  And since the outset of the pandemic, we’ve been working closely with the Moroccan Ministry of Health and other partners to train health workers, provide PPE and essential lab equipment, and enhance Morocco’s vaccine cold chain, all of which has helped contribute to a very effective response, led by His Majesty, to COVID here in Morocco.  And Morocco is also now contributing to the efforts that other countries are making, something we greatly appreciated.</p>
<p>We launched a $3 million partnership with the Pasteur Institute of Morocco to strengthen global health security capacity so that we can prepare for, respond to, and deal with infectious disease in the future.  We support King Mohammed VI’s ambitious reform agenda to strengthen Morocco’s institutions and ensure government is responsive to the Moroccan people.  The United States is committed to working with Morocco to make concrete progress in key areas, advancing the right to freedom of expression and association, criminal justice reforms, women’s rights and gender equality, government transparency, which the foreign minister and I had an opportunity to discuss today.</p>
<p>We also discussed security.  The United States recognizes the important role that Morocco plays in maintaining regional security and stability, as well as its contribution to peace and prosperity in the region.  We’re collaborating closely on addressing regional issues like the Sahel and Libya, the fight against terrorism, where Morocco has demonstrated sustained leadership to the Global Counterterrorism Forum and the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS.  We very much support the work of the United Nations Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General Stefan de Mistura in leading the political process for Western Sahara, under the auspices of the United Nations, to promote a peaceful and prosperous future for the people of Western Sahara and the region.  And we appreciate Morocco’s support for this mission.  We continue to view Morocco’s Autonomy Plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and one potential approach to meet the aspirations of the people of Western Sahara.</p>
<p>Let me just conclude by wishing an early <i>Ramadan Kareem</i> to the people of Morocco and around the world who will celebrate the holy month starting in just a few days.  And I wish our Moroccan friends – I shouldn’t say this – I’m going to wish you good luck in the World Cup qualifying match.  That’s not fair to the other side.  If we wish both sides good luck, it will wind up in a tie, but that’s good for Morocco.</p>
<p>So Nasser, thank you for hosting us.  Thank you for your leadership.  Thank you for your friendship.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(In Arabic.)</p>
<p>Now, questions for the press.  We’ll take the first one from Fadwa Mrabti, Al Ghad TV.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Good afternoon.  Fadwa Mrabti from Al Ghad channel.  His Majesty Mohammed VI is president of Al-Quds Committee, and Morocco has been playing historical roles in terms of Palestinian cause today after resuming relations with Israel.  How does the U.S. administration see the role that Morocco can play in moving forward with the negotiations with regard to the Israeli-Palestinian issue, especially that Morocco hangs on to its position of two-state solution and the right of the Palestinians to have a free, independent state with Jerusalem as its capital?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
<p>First, I was just in Israel before the meeting that we had together in the Negev.  I was in Jerusalem and also in Ramallah.  And one of the points that I made in both Jerusalem with Israeli counterparts, in Ramallah with President Abbas, is of course the United States continued, ongoing support for a two-state solution, an outcome that would meet the aspirations of the Palestinian people and their entitlement to a state of their own, as well as, of course, ensuring the security of Israel and its strength as a Jewish and democratic state.</p>
<p>The normalization agreements and the work that Morocco and other countries are doing with Israel is not a substitute for this outcome, for two states.  But it can, I believe, reinforce it.  In our discussions yesterday in the Negev, all of the partners in this enterprise, including Morocco, including the United States, talked about the need to advance that prospect and that horizon, but in the meantime to do concrete things to help improve the lives of Palestinians.  And this is exactly one of the things that the work we’re doing through the partnership that now exists among the countries that participated in the Negev Summit, that’s exactly one of the things that we’re focused on.  And we were talking in very concrete ways about initiatives that we can undertake together to improve the lives of the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>At the same time, I think that Morocco’s growing relationship with Israel, as well as that of other countries, will further strengthen its voice, as well as their own voice, in trying to advance the prospect of two states and improving the lives of Palestinians day in, day out.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>   Our first question will go to Conor Finnegan, ABC News.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Mr. Foreign Minister, on the Abraham Accords, the previous U.S. administration had pledged to open a consulate in Western Sahara, and yet this administration has so far not taken any steps to follow through on that.  Are you concerned that the U.S. will not meet that commitment?  And when you reference the Negev Summit, can you be more specific?  What kinds of concrete steps is Morocco willing to take to deepen ties with Israel?</p>
<p>And Mr. Secretary, Russian and Ukrainian delegations met today in Turkey.  You have been skeptical of talks with Russia so far during this war, but both sides are now openly discussing the potential terms of an agreement.  So yes or no – do you believe that Russia is now engaging in genuine dialogue?  The Ukrainian side has also said that any agreement must involve security guarantees by third countries.  Will the U.S. get involved in talks, including by providing security guarantees?  And the Ukrainian foreign minister specifically warned today to his delegation before the meetings to not eat, drink, or touch anything during the talks.  Do you have any comment on the recent reports of a potential poisoning, and do you have any concern for the negotiators’ safety?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  (Via interpreter)  With regard to the first part of your question, obviously, the three-party agreement is definitely an important document that’s created dynamics in terms of relations with Israel but also in terms of promoting relations in different aspects with the U.S.  Morocco is definitely confident that Moroccan and U.S. relations are strong – tense, but moving forward in the right direction.  We are fully confident that all aspects pertaining to the three-party agreement signed in December 2020 can be applicable as part of agreements and also as part of the timing that different parties deem relevant and appropriate.</p>
<p>But the position of the U.S. with regard to the autonomy under Moroccan sovereignty is firm and stable under different administrations, and we have heard that again today.  Autonomy under Moroccan sovereignty is the only solution supported by the U.S. and by other countries, and you have also seen recently Spain and Germany joining and other African and Arab countries.  They all go along the same direction.  So we are all fully confident that their positions are moving forward, are continuing, and the implementation of that hedges on different constellations that we can perhaps talk about between us directly.</p>
<p>Now regarding the second part of your question, the Moroccan and Israel relations are very special.  From – based on the long and strong relations between the kings of Morocco and the Moroccan Jewish people that’s considered a big chunk of the Israeli population.  This is part that in – this is a part that enriches this relation.  Since the signing of the three-party agreement, a number of things have happened since then in terms of visits, agreements, direct airlines, and also different delegations coming in, and also visits of different officials.</p>
<p>The next step, as Antony said, should go directly to concrete projects that businesspeople can feel, that citizens can feel and see in both countries.  This – His Majesty talked about a choice based on conviction, its natural choice.  This natural choice based on conviction should also be strengthened and fortified by concrete projects, by projects visible to the citizens in agriculture, in use of water, in security, stability, and so on and so forth.  So this is what can actually give this relation more strength.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, we saw visit of Moroccan businesspeople to Israel where they had direct meetings with their counterparts, so how can we invest in this economic field so we can sign more agreements on the Qualified Industrial Zones?  This can be a three-party – three-party cooperation area for different parties to generate more opportunities and development for everybody.  So this relationship has been moving forward, has been moving forward with still a lot of opportunities in the future.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Conor, thank you.  First on the talks, I would leave it to our Ukrainian partners to characterize whether there is any genuine progress and whether Russia is engaging meaningfully.</p>
<p>What I can say is this:  There is what Russia says and there is what Russia does.  We’re focused on the latter, and what Russia is doing is the continued brutalization of Ukraine and its people, and that continues as we speak.  As a result of this aggression committed by Russia, as I mentioned the other day, fully half of the children in Ukraine have been displaced from their homes – half of the children.  And, of course, we’ve seen what is going on in Mariupol, among other places.</p>
<p>So we’re focused on what Russia does.  And what it should do is end the aggression now, stop firing, pull its forces back, and, of course, engage in talks.  The fact that the Ukrainians are – have the extraordinary courage and willingness and determination not only to stand up for their country and their futures, but to engage in these talks with a gun literally to their head, I think speaks volumes.  But I would look to them to characterize whether there’s any – anything meaningfully coming.</p>
<p>If there is some kind of outcome, and if our support for Ukraine can be part of that outcome –including our support in the future for its defense and security – of course that’s something we’ll want to pursue.  But again, from what I’ve – I have not seen anything that suggests that this is moving forward in an effective way, because Russia – at least we have not seen signs of real seriousness, but if Ukraine concludes that there is, that’s good and we support that.</p>
<p>As to the stories about the poisoning, I don’t have any details on that.  I’ve seen the reports. What I can say is that, of course, this raises concerns because Russia has a real track record, and you only have to go as far back as the poisonings in the UK, Navalny, and others to see why concerns would certainly be understandable.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Shakir Allaoui, 360.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Via interpreter)  My question is for the two ministers.  The United Kingdom is organizing in Marrakesh a summit for Africa.  How could Morocco become a platform to further develop this relationship with African countries?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:  </b>(Via interpreter)  As I said, our relations have regional ramifications.  What you are doing in our bilateral relations is productive and beneficial to our two countries, to our two peoples, our two economies.  But this also got other repercussions regionally.</p>
<p>In terms of the economic effects, you know how much His Majesty hands-on to Africa to achieve stability there and development.  Africa is not a burden now for the international community; it’s an opportunity for the international community.  There are many opportunities and big potentials in Africa.  Africa has proven even during COVID some kind of resilience before the economic effects of the pandemic.  Africa – its clout lies in its young population.  It is the only part of the world where you have 30 million individuals that on annual basis join the middle class.  This is unprecedented.  This is not seen in other parts of the world.  This by itself, in itself, an economic potential.</p>
<p>Africa has got a lot of potential of infrastructures, renewable resources, technologies, and so on and so forth.  Africa is an opportunity.  That’s why Morocco has developed its relations thank to the vision – with Africa thanks to the vision of His Majesty the king.  Morocco is heavily present in Africa.  It’s the second investor – African investor in Africa.  So how can we cooperate with our American partners?  We are the only ones having an FTA with the U.S. in Africa.  Africa now is creating (inaudible) free trade agreement in Africa.  So how can we use our bilateral FTA as a platform to get to Africa jointly?  We have a joint vision on development and stability and prosperity in Africa.  So how can the U.S. (inaudible) from Morocco or based on a partnership with Morocco can actually expand into Africa, especially in its western part and central part?</p>
<p>All these are potentials that we need to talk about within the (inaudible) to be held in July.</p>
<p>This is the vocation for Morocco, to be a bridge between partners and Africa.  That’s what we’re going to do in this economic forum in July.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  I think Nasser said it extremely well, and I would add simply that I think the – and we had a long conversation about this actually just today, about how we can work together more effectively in Africa, building on what we’re already doing.  We already have a strong security partnership when it comes to dealing with security challenges in Africa, but we want to make sure as well that we are dealing with some of the challenges that are also opportunities in building stronger global health, including in Africa, in addressing the climate challenge.</p>
<p>And again, Morocco is a leader on this, but we can bring some of that leadership and expertise together in Africa in pursuing infrastructure projects and in creating opportunities for young people throughout the continent.  These are all the kinds of things that we’ll be talking about in a couple of months, but we already talked about today.</p>
<p>But I think it’s evidence of something very powerful in this relationship.  We have a strong bilateral relationship.  We work on many things directly together in the interests of both our people.  We also have a strong regional partnership that you see translated in the work that we’re doing throughout the region.  But increasingly as well, it’s truly global, because when we’re working together on things like dealing with pandemics or dealing with climate change, these are of global consequence.</p>
<p>And as a result, Morocco is really and truly a partner on the global stage for us.  It’s a partnership we value deeply, and this is exactly why we’ve spent so much time today talking about how to deepen it, how to pursue it not only between ourselves, but in different parts of the world, and notably, Africa.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Our second question goes to Humeyra Pamuk of Reuters.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Hello, Mr. Secretary, Foreign Minister.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, just to quickly follow up on Ukraine, Russian deputy defense minister said Moscow has decided to fundamentally cut back military activity in the direction of Kyiv and Chernihiv.  Do you see this statement as a major shift in Russia’s invasion?  Has the United States over the last few days observed Russia shift its military focus from Kyiv to Donbas?</p>
<p>And separately, you will meet with Abu Dhabi crown prince later today.  It is no secret that the relationship with the UAE as well as Saudi Arabia is at a difficult place.  They snub America’s calls to increase oil production.  They’ve done little to help Ukraine.  What concrete ideas are you bringing to this meeting to put the relationship back on track, and are you hopeful that it will?</p>
<p>Mr. Foreign Minister, very quickly, earlier this month, Spain said it was backing Morocco’s autonomy proposals for Western Sahara.  Do you see any other EU states following suit?  And also, your country, along with several others in the Middle East, haven’t been very vocal for its support of Ukraine.  You haven’t showed up in the United Nations vote either.  Why aren’t you more critical of Russia?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, Humeyra.  Two things.  First, with regard to the statements that &#8212;</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m sorry, what did we miss?  No?</p>
<p>With regard to the statements on Russia’s aggression, I come back to what I said a few minutes ago, which is that we’re focused on what they do, not on what they say.  And so I can’t tell you whether these statements reflect some reorientation of the aggression to focus only on – “only,” in quotation marks, eastern and southern Ukraine, or whether this is a means by which Russia once again is trying to deflect and deceive people into thinking it’s doing – it’s not doing what it is doing, whether it’s simply trying to regroup, given the heavy losses that it’s suffered.  I don’t know.  So we’re focused on what they do.</p>
<p>I would add that if they somehow believe that an effort to subjugate “only,” in quotation marks, the eastern part of Ukraine or – and the southern part of Ukraine can succeed, then once again, they are profoundly fooling themselves.  They’re – we’ve seen the will and the determination of the Ukrainian people to determine their own future, not to have Russia or anyone else determine it for them.  And so I think that will would continue to be expressed one way or another in all parts of the country.</p>
<p>With regard to my meeting later today with the crown prince, it’s fortuitous that we have this opportunity to take advantage of our presence here to spend some time together.  I’m very much looking forward to it.  We’ll have an opportunity to have a truly strategic conversation about the full range of issues that we’re working on together, regionally, globally.</p>
<p>And I’ll have more to say, no doubt, about that tomorrow, but this is an important strategic relationship and partnership for the United States.  I’m really pleased to have the chance to sit down with him.  I was with the foreign minister for the last more than 24 hours in the Negev.  We had an opportunity to spend some time together, and of course we’re working very closely together not only in the context of the Negev Summit, but on so many other issues.</p>
<p>So more to say about that tomorrow, but I’m looking forward to it.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  On the first question on Spain, of course, the letter of the prime minister of Spain to His Majesty expressing support to the Moroccan Autonomy Plan as the basis for any solution to the Sahara issue is a very positive development.  And we reacted and we welcome that – this development, and we consider that it is – as His Majesty said, it will open a new chapter in our bilateral relations.</p>
<p>The position of Spain is not an isolated one.  There is a dynamic at the international level in support of the Moroccan Autonomy Plan as a serious, credible outcome for this regional dispute.  This is the position of the United States, this is the position of Germany, this is the position of France, this is the position of the Arab countries, this is the position of the African countries, and others.  So that’s why we think it’s time for Europe mainly – and I said that before – to get out of this comfort zone where we – people are just supporting the process.  And supporting a process doesn’t mean supporting a solution.  You can be comfortable in saying yes, we support a process, and this process could last for decades.  What is important now and why there is this dynamic – and de Mistura is also part of this dynamic – is how to shift into an outcome-oriented effort.</p>
<p>And in this regard, in different areas of the world, there is a consensus that this solution should be within Moroccan sovereignty and within the Moroccan Autonomy Plan.  And we hope that other countries will follow to get out of this comfort zone and to be actor in finding a solution instead of being passive in supporting the status quo.</p>
<p>On Ukraine, Moroccan position is very clear and it has been expressed many times.  We are in favor of territorial integrity and national unity of Ukraine, as of all the member states of the United Nations.  We are against the use or the recourse to force in settling disputes.  We are in favor of constructive neighborhood relations, and we are in favor of dialogue and negotiation to solve issues.  This has been our position.  It is clear and it is in line with the UN Charter.  It is in line with the principles of international law in which we believe.</p>
<p>So this position has been expressed, and we had today the opportunity to discuss more details about that.  Thank you.</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a id="footnote1"></a> References the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business Summit</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a id="footnote2"></a> December 2020</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Dear Secretary of State the U.S., like to extend a warm welcome to him to Morocco.  We are all pleased and glad to meet him in our – in his – the first official state meeting of Secretary of State in the current administration to Morocco.  Welcome to you, sir.</p>
<p>As per the vision of His Majesty King Mohammed VI, the Moroccan-U.S. relations have always been longstanding and based on longstanding partnership that’s quite ambitious and developed, also grounded on personal relation between His Majesty King Mohammed VI and President Joe Biden since their meeting in Marrakesh back in 2016.</p>
<p>With Mr. Secretary of State we met yesterday in Negev, in Israel, to talk about how to support positive dynamics in the Middle East.  We are convening today also today as part of our endeavor to further strengthen our relations.  In May, we’ll convene again as part of the Global Alliance and Coalition Against ISIS and to support our joint endeavors to fight extremism and terrorism worldwide.  In June, Morocco and the U.S. will hold African Lion maneuvers.  That’s one of the major parts of our military cooperation.  In July, we will also host the Economic American-African Forum in Marrakesh.  All this testifies to the richness of our U.S. and Moroccan relations.</p>
<p>Thanks to their variety and diversity, this covers the political side, the security side, the military side, the economic side.  This is a partnership that goes back – our bilateral relations – to cover other areas like the Middle East, Africa, and other parts of the world.  Our relations are strong.  Our partnership is strong, grounded on mutual shared values, shared interests, grounded also on a shared vision around a number of international issues and regional issues.</p>
<p>His Majesty the King wants to make sure that these relations move forward as part of the tools and mechanisms that we all have.  The Strategic Dialogue and we held two weeks ago around with Lady Wendy Sherman.  Also dialogue on human rights, and we held two rounds earlier.  The FTA, that is the only U.S. agreement with an African country which has resulted in very positive outcomes in terms of developing and promoting our trade relations.  And we hope this will also play a key role in moving forward with the U.S. investments in Morocco.</p>
<p>As part of the MCC also, which has been a contribution, an important contribution to the endeavor of Morocco and also as part of tools for security and military cooperation.  This cooperation has always been strong and very productive, resulting in many initiatives between the U.S. and Morocco.  Today, we have talked around all these issues and how to further develop our mutual relation’s and bilateral relations so this partnership can be strong and modeled based on historical values, and also in line with the current ambitions and values.</p>
<p>We have talked about different challenges in Middle East, and we’d like to thank the U.S. as a party to the three-party agreement signed before His Majesty back in January – in December 2022, where Morocco has relaunched its relations with Israel.  This agreement has resulted in positive outcomes, and we can – this can also yield more fruits as part of concrete project that are beneficial to the Moroccan and Israeli peoples.  But the three-party agreement – Israel, U.S., and Morocco – is also a message and a sign for the need of a two-state solution, steady solution, in the Middle East by setting up free states which Jerusalem as a capital, living and coexisting with Israel.  And as part of the vision of His Majesty the King, Jerusalem can be a city for coexistence.</p>
<p>We have talked also about our partnership in Africa to face up to the different challenges and also to make profit of the many opportunities we have in Africa economically, in terms of trade, and also in terms of climate changes, and also in the area of trade and infrastructures, and also in terms of security and healthcare and military.  Africa is fertile land for U.S.-Moroccan cooperation.  And also the North Africa and Sahel, there are many challenge; there are many tensions that have to be addressed.  And also there are many security-related challenges that need to be addressed positively and constructively.</p>
<p>I think your visit, Tony, is very important and that has produced clear messages about this cooperation, the many possibilities we can actually profit from here to the benefit for our two countries, but also to the benefit of security and stability and development in areas that we consider to be very important to us and to you.  Once again, thank you for your visit, and you’re most welcome.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Foreign Minister, Nasser, thank you.  It’s really good to be with you once again.  It feels like it was only yesterday.</p>
<p>Indeed, we just came from the historic Negev Summit, and together with our partners from Bahrain, from Egypt, the United Arab Emirates, and Israel, we discussed, as Nasser said, a wide range of areas where we can seize on normalization to make a positive impact on the lives of our people.  It’s an effort that quite simply would not have been possible were it not for the courage and vision of leaders like His Majesty King Mohammed VI to break down longstanding barriers.  And I’m committed to working with the foreign minister and all our friends here and across the region to make this vision real, translating it into more opportunities for people and further widening the circle of friendship.</p>
<p>Now, while integration among some of these countries is new, the diplomatic relationship between Morocco and the United States dates back more than 240 years, and its depth and breadth are reflected in everything we discussed today, and Nasser touched on a lot of these issues.  For more than 15 years, our free trade agreement has benefited people and companies in both of our countries and beyond.  Today, we discussed how we can continue to grow our economic cooperation in particular to benefit underserved populations.</p>
<p>For example, we’re in the fifth and final year of what is a $460 million compact administrated by the U.S. Millennium Challenge Corporation.  That’s provided jobs and education opportunities for young people, boosted agricultural productivity, expanded land rights for women.  The compact includes a partnership with Morocco’s Ministry of Education that is piloting a model aimed at improving secondary education in 90 secondary schools across the country, training some 6,000 teachers and administrators, making investments in the schools’ infrastructure and in its technology.</p>
<p>Just last week, our officials came together and broke ground on a major expansion of the industrial zone in Bouznika, backed by a public-private partnership, and that is expected to generate some 4,000 jobs.</p>
<p>Partners show up for each other in difficult times, and as Morocco experiences one of the worst droughts in decades, we’re doing what we can to help.  Now, I tried to do what I could to help by bringing a little rain with me today – (laughter) – but that’s clearly not enough.  We have experts from the State Department and the Department of the Interior consulting directly with their Moroccan counterparts on immediate steps to diminish the drought’s impact and to increase water conversation.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, we’re hosting a conference in Casablanca that will bring together your top water management companies with some experts from the United States to focus on how this country can better produce, use, and conserve its water resources.  And going back long before this drought, we’d been working to build greater capacity in the country to try to predict, prepare for, and mitigate the worst impacts of droughts, and to train rising generations of Moroccan water management experts.  The drought’s already affected agricultural production, we know raising the cost of food.</p>
<p>Now, the natural disaster is being worsened by a manmade disaster, as the Russian Government and its brutal war in Ukraine has disrupted the supply of wheat and other commodities.  Here, across the region, we’re discussing concrete steps we can take and our partners can take to help reduce the impact of these shortages, particularly on the most vulnerable populations.  This disruption is another reason we’ll continue to urge our friends and partners to speak out with one voice in condemning the Russian Government’s aggression – the consequences of which are being felt around the world – and hold the Kremlin accountable for as long as this continues.</p>
<p>The increasing frequency and severity of droughts and other extreme weather here, in the United States, around the world also underscores the urgency of our collective efforts to address the climate crisis.  And in this, Morocco is a world leader, setting an ambitious target of achieving 63 percent renewable energy by 2035.  With 45 percent of the country’s electricity production already coming from renewables, Morocco is on track to meet this ambitious target and even exceed it.  Morocco also signed the Global Methane Pledge at COP26, and at COP22, the kingdom founded three African-wide commissions – the Congo Basin Commission, the Sahel Commission, the Small Island Nations Commission – and continues to lead climate finance and feasibility studies for all three of them.</p>
<p>We’ve also worked side by side in combating the COVID-19 pandemic.  We’ve been able to donate more than 2.5 million safe, effective vaccines to Morocco through the COVAX Initiative over the last several months alone.  And since the outset of the pandemic, we’ve been working closely with the Moroccan Ministry of Health and other partners to train health workers, provide PPE and essential lab equipment, and enhance Morocco’s vaccine cold chain, all of which has helped contribute to a very effective response, led by His Majesty, to COVID here in Morocco.  And Morocco is also now contributing to the efforts that other countries are making, something we greatly appreciated.</p>
<p>We launched a $3 million partnership with the Pasteur Institute of Morocco to strengthen global health security capacity so that we can prepare for, respond to, and deal with infectious disease in the future.  We support King Mohammed VI’s ambitious reform agenda to strengthen Morocco’s institutions and ensure government is responsive to the Moroccan people.  The United States is committed to working with Morocco to make concrete progress in key areas, advancing the right to freedom of expression and association, criminal justice reforms, women’s rights and gender equality, government transparency, which the foreign minister and I had an opportunity to discuss today.</p>
<p>We also discussed security.  The United States recognizes the important role that Morocco plays in maintaining regional security and stability, as well as its contribution to peace and prosperity in the region.  We’re collaborating closely on addressing regional issues like the Sahel and Libya, the fight against terrorism, where Morocco has demonstrated sustained leadership to the Global Counterterrorism Forum and the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS.  We very much support the work of the United Nations Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General Stefan de Mistura in leading the political process for Western Sahara, under the auspices of the United Nations, to promote a peaceful and prosperous future for the people of Western Sahara and the region.  And we appreciate Morocco’s support for this mission.  We continue to view Morocco’s Autonomy Plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and one potential approach to meet the aspirations of the people of Western Sahara.</p>
<p>Let me just conclude by wishing an early <i>Ramadan Kareem</i> to the people of Morocco and around the world who will celebrate the holy month starting in just a few days.  And I wish our Moroccan friends – I shouldn’t say this – I’m going to wish you good luck in the World Cup qualifying match.  That’s not fair to the other side.  If we wish both sides good luck, it will wind up in a tie, but that’s good for Morocco.</p>
<p>So Nasser, thank you for hosting us.  Thank you for your leadership.  Thank you for your friendship.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(In Arabic.)</p>
<p>Now, questions for the press.  We’ll take the first one from Fadwa Mrabti, Al Ghad TV.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Good afternoon.  Fadwa Mrabti from Al Ghad channel.  His Majesty Mohammed VI is president of Al-Quds Committee, and Morocco has been playing historical roles in terms of Palestinian cause today after resuming relations with Israel.  How does the U.S. administration see the role that Morocco can play in moving forward with the negotiations with regard to the Israeli-Palestinian issue, especially that Morocco hangs on to its position of two-state solution and the right of the Palestinians to have a free, independent state with Jerusalem as its capital?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
<p>First, I was just in Israel before the meeting that we had together in the Negev.  I was in Jerusalem and also in Ramallah.  And one of the points that I made in both Jerusalem with Israeli counterparts, in Ramallah with President Abbas, is of course the United States continued, ongoing support for a two-state solution, an outcome that would meet the aspirations of the Palestinian people and their entitlement to a state of their own, as well as, of course, ensuring the security of Israel and its strength as a Jewish and democratic state.</p>
<p>The normalization agreements and the work that Morocco and other countries are doing with Israel is not a substitute for this outcome, for two states.  But it can, I believe, reinforce it.  In our discussions yesterday in the Negev, all of the partners in this enterprise, including Morocco, including the United States, talked about the need to advance that prospect and that horizon, but in the meantime to do concrete things to help improve the lives of Palestinians.  And this is exactly one of the things that the work we’re doing through the partnership that now exists among the countries that participated in the Negev Summit, that’s exactly one of the things that we’re focused on.  And we were talking in very concrete ways about initiatives that we can undertake together to improve the lives of the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>At the same time, I think that Morocco’s growing relationship with Israel, as well as that of other countries, will further strengthen its voice, as well as their own voice, in trying to advance the prospect of two states and improving the lives of Palestinians day in, day out.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>   Our first question will go to Conor Finnegan, ABC News.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Mr. Foreign Minister, on the Abraham Accords, the previous U.S. administration had pledged to open a consulate in Western Sahara, and yet this administration has so far not taken any steps to follow through on that.  Are you concerned that the U.S. will not meet that commitment?  And when you reference the Negev Summit, can you be more specific?  What kinds of concrete steps is Morocco willing to take to deepen ties with Israel?</p>
<p>And Mr. Secretary, Russian and Ukrainian delegations met today in Turkey.  You have been skeptical of talks with Russia so far during this war, but both sides are now openly discussing the potential terms of an agreement.  So yes or no – do you believe that Russia is now engaging in genuine dialogue?  The Ukrainian side has also said that any agreement must involve security guarantees by third countries.  Will the U.S. get involved in talks, including by providing security guarantees?  And the Ukrainian foreign minister specifically warned today to his delegation before the meetings to not eat, drink, or touch anything during the talks.  Do you have any comment on the recent reports of a potential poisoning, and do you have any concern for the negotiators’ safety?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  (Via interpreter)  With regard to the first part of your question, obviously, the three-party agreement is definitely an important document that’s created dynamics in terms of relations with Israel but also in terms of promoting relations in different aspects with the U.S.  Morocco is definitely confident that Moroccan and U.S. relations are strong – tense, but moving forward in the right direction.  We are fully confident that all aspects pertaining to the three-party agreement signed in December 2020 can be applicable as part of agreements and also as part of the timing that different parties deem relevant and appropriate.</p>
<p>But the position of the U.S. with regard to the autonomy under Moroccan sovereignty is firm and stable under different administrations, and we have heard that again today.  Autonomy under Moroccan sovereignty is the only solution supported by the U.S. and by other countries, and you have also seen recently Spain and Germany joining and other African and Arab countries.  They all go along the same direction.  So we are all fully confident that their positions are moving forward, are continuing, and the implementation of that hedges on different constellations that we can perhaps talk about between us directly.</p>
<p>Now regarding the second part of your question, the Moroccan and Israel relations are very special.  From – based on the long and strong relations between the kings of Morocco and the Moroccan Jewish people that’s considered a big chunk of the Israeli population.  This is part that in – this is a part that enriches this relation.  Since the signing of the three-party agreement, a number of things have happened since then in terms of visits, agreements, direct airlines, and also different delegations coming in, and also visits of different officials.</p>
<p>The next step, as Antony said, should go directly to concrete projects that businesspeople can feel, that citizens can feel and see in both countries.  This – His Majesty talked about a choice based on conviction, its natural choice.  This natural choice based on conviction should also be strengthened and fortified by concrete projects, by projects visible to the citizens in agriculture, in use of water, in security, stability, and so on and so forth.  So this is what can actually give this relation more strength.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, we saw visit of Moroccan businesspeople to Israel where they had direct meetings with their counterparts, so how can we invest in this economic field so we can sign more agreements on the Qualified Industrial Zones?  This can be a three-party – three-party cooperation area for different parties to generate more opportunities and development for everybody.  So this relationship has been moving forward, has been moving forward with still a lot of opportunities in the future.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Conor, thank you.  First on the talks, I would leave it to our Ukrainian partners to characterize whether there is any genuine progress and whether Russia is engaging meaningfully.</p>
<p>What I can say is this:  There is what Russia says and there is what Russia does.  We’re focused on the latter, and what Russia is doing is the continued brutalization of Ukraine and its people, and that continues as we speak.  As a result of this aggression committed by Russia, as I mentioned the other day, fully half of the children in Ukraine have been displaced from their homes – half of the children.  And, of course, we’ve seen what is going on in Mariupol, among other places.</p>
<p>So we’re focused on what Russia does.  And what it should do is end the aggression now, stop firing, pull its forces back, and, of course, engage in talks.  The fact that the Ukrainians are – have the extraordinary courage and willingness and determination not only to stand up for their country and their futures, but to engage in these talks with a gun literally to their head, I think speaks volumes.  But I would look to them to characterize whether there’s any – anything meaningfully coming.</p>
<p>If there is some kind of outcome, and if our support for Ukraine can be part of that outcome –including our support in the future for its defense and security – of course that’s something we’ll want to pursue.  But again, from what I’ve – I have not seen anything that suggests that this is moving forward in an effective way, because Russia – at least we have not seen signs of real seriousness, but if Ukraine concludes that there is, that’s good and we support that.</p>
<p>As to the stories about the poisoning, I don’t have any details on that.  I’ve seen the reports. What I can say is that, of course, this raises concerns because Russia has a real track record, and you only have to go as far back as the poisonings in the UK, Navalny, and others to see why concerns would certainly be understandable.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Shakir Allaoui, 360.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Via interpreter)  My question is for the two ministers.  The United Kingdom is organizing in Marrakesh a summit for Africa.  How could Morocco become a platform to further develop this relationship with African countries?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:  </b>(Via interpreter)  As I said, our relations have regional ramifications.  What you are doing in our bilateral relations is productive and beneficial to our two countries, to our two peoples, our two economies.  But this also got other repercussions regionally.</p>
<p>In terms of the economic effects, you know how much His Majesty hands-on to Africa to achieve stability there and development.  Africa is not a burden now for the international community; it’s an opportunity for the international community.  There are many opportunities and big potentials in Africa.  Africa has proven even during COVID some kind of resilience before the economic effects of the pandemic.  Africa – its clout lies in its young population.  It is the only part of the world where you have 30 million individuals that on annual basis join the middle class.  This is unprecedented.  This is not seen in other parts of the world.  This by itself, in itself, an economic potential.</p>
<p>Africa has got a lot of potential of infrastructures, renewable resources, technologies, and so on and so forth.  Africa is an opportunity.  That’s why Morocco has developed its relations thank to the vision – with Africa thanks to the vision of His Majesty the king.  Morocco is heavily present in Africa.  It’s the second investor – African investor in Africa.  So how can we cooperate with our American partners?  We are the only ones having an FTA with the U.S. in Africa.  Africa now is creating (inaudible) free trade agreement in Africa.  So how can we use our bilateral FTA as a platform to get to Africa jointly?  We have a joint vision on development and stability and prosperity in Africa.  So how can the U.S. (inaudible) from Morocco or based on a partnership with Morocco can actually expand into Africa, especially in its western part and central part?</p>
<p>All these are potentials that we need to talk about within the (inaudible) to be held in July.</p>
<p>This is the vocation for Morocco, to be a bridge between partners and Africa.  That’s what we’re going to do in this economic forum in July.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  I think Nasser said it extremely well, and I would add simply that I think the – and we had a long conversation about this actually just today, about how we can work together more effectively in Africa, building on what we’re already doing.  We already have a strong security partnership when it comes to dealing with security challenges in Africa, but we want to make sure as well that we are dealing with some of the challenges that are also opportunities in building stronger global health, including in Africa, in addressing the climate challenge.</p>
<p>And again, Morocco is a leader on this, but we can bring some of that leadership and expertise together in Africa in pursuing infrastructure projects and in creating opportunities for young people throughout the continent.  These are all the kinds of things that we’ll be talking about in a couple of months, but we already talked about today.</p>
<p>But I think it’s evidence of something very powerful in this relationship.  We have a strong bilateral relationship.  We work on many things directly together in the interests of both our people.  We also have a strong regional partnership that you see translated in the work that we’re doing throughout the region.  But increasingly as well, it’s truly global, because when we’re working together on things like dealing with pandemics or dealing with climate change, these are of global consequence.</p>
<p>And as a result, Morocco is really and truly a partner on the global stage for us.  It’s a partnership we value deeply, and this is exactly why we’ve spent so much time today talking about how to deepen it, how to pursue it not only between ourselves, but in different parts of the world, and notably, Africa.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Our second question goes to Humeyra Pamuk of Reuters.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Hello, Mr. Secretary, Foreign Minister.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, just to quickly follow up on Ukraine, Russian deputy defense minister said Moscow has decided to fundamentally cut back military activity in the direction of Kyiv and Chernihiv.  Do you see this statement as a major shift in Russia’s invasion?  Has the United States over the last few days observed Russia shift its military focus from Kyiv to Donbas?</p>
<p>And separately, you will meet with Abu Dhabi crown prince later today.  It is no secret that the relationship with the UAE as well as Saudi Arabia is at a difficult place.  They snub America’s calls to increase oil production.  They’ve done little to help Ukraine.  What concrete ideas are you bringing to this meeting to put the relationship back on track, and are you hopeful that it will?</p>
<p>Mr. Foreign Minister, very quickly, earlier this month, Spain said it was backing Morocco’s autonomy proposals for Western Sahara.  Do you see any other EU states following suit?  And also, your country, along with several others in the Middle East, haven’t been very vocal for its support of Ukraine.  You haven’t showed up in the United Nations vote either.  Why aren’t you more critical of Russia?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, Humeyra.  Two things.  First, with regard to the statements that &#8212;</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m sorry, what did we miss?  No?</p>
<p>With regard to the statements on Russia’s aggression, I come back to what I said a few minutes ago, which is that we’re focused on what they do, not on what they say.  And so I can’t tell you whether these statements reflect some reorientation of the aggression to focus only on – “only,” in quotation marks, eastern and southern Ukraine, or whether this is a means by which Russia once again is trying to deflect and deceive people into thinking it’s doing – it’s not doing what it is doing, whether it’s simply trying to regroup, given the heavy losses that it’s suffered.  I don’t know.  So we’re focused on what they do.</p>
<p>I would add that if they somehow believe that an effort to subjugate “only,” in quotation marks, the eastern part of Ukraine or – and the southern part of Ukraine can succeed, then once again, they are profoundly fooling themselves.  They’re – we’ve seen the will and the determination of the Ukrainian people to determine their own future, not to have Russia or anyone else determine it for them.  And so I think that will would continue to be expressed one way or another in all parts of the country.</p>
<p>With regard to my meeting later today with the crown prince, it’s fortuitous that we have this opportunity to take advantage of our presence here to spend some time together.  I’m very much looking forward to it.  We’ll have an opportunity to have a truly strategic conversation about the full range of issues that we’re working on together, regionally, globally.</p>
<p>And I’ll have more to say, no doubt, about that tomorrow, but this is an important strategic relationship and partnership for the United States.  I’m really pleased to have the chance to sit down with him.  I was with the foreign minister for the last more than 24 hours in the Negev.  We had an opportunity to spend some time together, and of course we’re working very closely together not only in the context of the Negev Summit, but on so many other issues.</p>
<p>So more to say about that tomorrow, but I’m looking forward to it.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  On the first question on Spain, of course, the letter of the prime minister of Spain to His Majesty expressing support to the Moroccan Autonomy Plan as the basis for any solution to the Sahara issue is a very positive development.  And we reacted and we welcome that – this development, and we consider that it is – as His Majesty said, it will open a new chapter in our bilateral relations.</p>
<p>The position of Spain is not an isolated one.  There is a dynamic at the international level in support of the Moroccan Autonomy Plan as a serious, credible outcome for this regional dispute.  This is the position of the United States, this is the position of Germany, this is the position of France, this is the position of the Arab countries, this is the position of the African countries, and others.  So that’s why we think it’s time for Europe mainly – and I said that before – to get out of this comfort zone where we – people are just supporting the process.  And supporting a process doesn’t mean supporting a solution.  You can be comfortable in saying yes, we support a process, and this process could last for decades.  What is important now and why there is this dynamic – and de Mistura is also part of this dynamic – is how to shift into an outcome-oriented effort.</p>
<p>And in this regard, in different areas of the world, there is a consensus that this solution should be within Moroccan sovereignty and within the Moroccan Autonomy Plan.  And we hope that other countries will follow to get out of this comfort zone and to be actor in finding a solution instead of being passive in supporting the status quo.</p>
<p>On Ukraine, Moroccan position is very clear and it has been expressed many times.  We are in favor of territorial integrity and national unity of Ukraine, as of all the member states of the United Nations.  We are against the use or the recourse to force in settling disputes.  We are in favor of constructive neighborhood relations, and we are in favor of dialogue and negotiation to solve issues.  This has been our position.  It is clear and it is in line with the UN Charter.  It is in line with the principles of international law in which we believe.</p>
<p>So this position has been expressed, and we had today the opportunity to discuss more details about that.  Thank you.</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a id="footnote1"></a> References the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business Summit</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a id="footnote2"></a> December 2020</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at Meeting with Moroccan Women in STEM</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-meeting-with-moroccan-women-in-stem/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 18:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Dar Kika Salam</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, Imane.  Thank you so much for bringing us all together and coordinating this, and also your work supporting STEM curriculums and work in general.  I’ve read a little bit about each of you.  This is a really outstanding group, and it’s just a pleasure and an honor to be with you today.  And I’m really anxious to hear from each of you, but what you have here is the present and future of STEM.  Whether it’s climate change, whether it’s global health, whether it’s agriculture, whether it’s aerospace engineering, you are already working on some of the most important issues of the day, and that’s a very powerful thing.</p>
<p>You’re starting pretty young in your careers, but I also know from what I’ve read – and I want to hear more about that – that you’re already also mentoring other people, and that’s extraordinary, because being able to pass on your experience, your knowledge, and also your support makes a big, big difference.  It has to be a continuous chain.  And somehow, apparently, you’re doing all of this on top of your schoolwork, so that’s remarkable.</p>
<p>Now, I’m not sure which one of you – one of you rescheduled an exam to be here?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Now, I don’t know if you can get credit for this or something, but – and I hope I’m not in trouble with the teacher, but thank you for doing that.  If it were up to me, you would get extra credit for being here, but we’ll see what we can do about that.</p>
<p>And then I think some of you are going to actually be studying at American universities in the fall.  So where are you headed?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  I’m going to (inaudible) in the fall.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s great.  Congratulations on that.  They’re lucky to have you, (inaudible).</p>
<p>The other thing that’s really striking to me is that you are all alumni of our exchange programs, and this is incredibly powerful evidence to me once again of the importance of those programs.  I think it’s one of the single best investments that the United States Government makes.  We’ve had a pretty good ability over the years to identify the most talented people in rising generations in different countries – you’re a wonderful example of that – and to develop relationships with people that hopefully will go on for generations.  And maybe even more important, besides whatever benefits you get, skills you learn, I suspect the connections among you, the networks that you develop through those programs and friends that you may have made either here from our embassy community, or in the United States, will last a lifetime.<b></b></p>
<p>But mostly I’m really eager to hear from you because, I think as powerful examples of women in STEM, you have a great story to tell others, to inspire others, but beyond that to really make a difference in the world on the issues that affect the lives of people everywhere, whether it’s here in Morocco, the United States, or anywhere else.</p>
<p>So I want to stop talking and get you to start talking because I want to hear from you.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Dar Kika Salam</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, Imane.  Thank you so much for bringing us all together and coordinating this, and also your work supporting STEM curriculums and work in general.  I’ve read a little bit about each of you.  This is a really outstanding group, and it’s just a pleasure and an honor to be with you today.  And I’m really anxious to hear from each of you, but what you have here is the present and future of STEM.  Whether it’s climate change, whether it’s global health, whether it’s agriculture, whether it’s aerospace engineering, you are already working on some of the most important issues of the day, and that’s a very powerful thing.</p>
<p>You’re starting pretty young in your careers, but I also know from what I’ve read – and I want to hear more about that – that you’re already also mentoring other people, and that’s extraordinary, because being able to pass on your experience, your knowledge, and also your support makes a big, big difference.  It has to be a continuous chain.  And somehow, apparently, you’re doing all of this on top of your schoolwork, so that’s remarkable.</p>
<p>Now, I’m not sure which one of you – one of you rescheduled an exam to be here?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Now, I don’t know if you can get credit for this or something, but – and I hope I’m not in trouble with the teacher, but thank you for doing that.  If it were up to me, you would get extra credit for being here, but we’ll see what we can do about that.</p>
<p>And then I think some of you are going to actually be studying at American universities in the fall.  So where are you headed?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  I’m going to (inaudible) in the fall.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s great.  Congratulations on that.  They’re lucky to have you, (inaudible).</p>
<p>The other thing that’s really striking to me is that you are all alumni of our exchange programs, and this is incredibly powerful evidence to me once again of the importance of those programs.  I think it’s one of the single best investments that the United States Government makes.  We’ve had a pretty good ability over the years to identify the most talented people in rising generations in different countries – you’re a wonderful example of that – and to develop relationships with people that hopefully will go on for generations.  And maybe even more important, besides whatever benefits you get, skills you learn, I suspect the connections among you, the networks that you develop through those programs and friends that you may have made either here from our embassy community, or in the United States, will last a lifetime.<b></b></p>
<p>But mostly I’m really eager to hear from you because, I think as powerful examples of women in STEM, you have a great story to tell others, to inspire others, but beyond that to really make a difference in the world on the issues that affect the lives of people everywhere, whether it’s here in Morocco, the United States, or anywhere else.</p>
<p>So I want to stop talking and get you to start talking because I want to hear from you.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
