<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:49:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations Announces Award for Worldwide Architectural and Engineering Support Services</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-bureau-of-overseas-buildings-operations-announces-award-for-worldwide-architectural-and-engineering-support-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State’s Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations (OBO) has selected 12 Architectural and Engineering (A/E) firms for the Worldwide Architectural and Engineering Support Services Indefinite Delivery / Indefinite Quantity (IDIQ). Selected from the distinguished stage one shortlist of 25 firms, these teams will provide program-level process- and procedure-improvement support, existing facilities surveys and analyses, and other project-specific support such as master plans, security mitigation studies, site expansion studies, project phasing analysis, and historic structures surveys.</p>
<p>The selected firms are:</p>
<p>AECOM Services, Inc.<br />
Buro Happold Engineering<br />
Davis Brody Bond<br />
Arthur Gensler, Jr. &amp; Associates, Inc. (dba Gensler)<br />
HDR KCCT JV<br />
Jacobs Government Services Company<br />
Lake Flato Architects<br />
The Mason &amp; Hanger Group, Inc.<br />
Moore Ruble Yudell Architects &amp; Planners<br />
ODA-Architecture, P.C.<br />
SmithGroup, Inc.<br />
WXY Architecture + Urban Design</p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 167 new diplomatic facilities. OBO currently has more than 50 active projects, either in design or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that positively represent the United States to other nations and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/bureau-of-overseas-buildings-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzAuNDM5MjY1ODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9vYm8ifQ.LOEdMtBF0oQQ6mPAT8RVgCg9maNhZ2I14i6lz34NKJ0/s/1039202793/br/110179718909-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627756386405000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEtE2_KdCZJ1GmElWnUkGTJPr8vQA">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State’s Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations (OBO) has selected 12 Architectural and Engineering (A/E) firms for the Worldwide Architectural and Engineering Support Services Indefinite Delivery / Indefinite Quantity (IDIQ). Selected from the distinguished stage one shortlist of 25 firms, these teams will provide program-level process- and procedure-improvement support, existing facilities surveys and analyses, and other project-specific support such as master plans, security mitigation studies, site expansion studies, project phasing analysis, and historic structures surveys.</p>
<p>The selected firms are:</p>
<p>AECOM Services, Inc.<br />
Buro Happold Engineering<br />
Davis Brody Bond<br />
Arthur Gensler, Jr. &amp; Associates, Inc. (dba Gensler)<br />
HDR KCCT JV<br />
Jacobs Government Services Company<br />
Lake Flato Architects<br />
The Mason &amp; Hanger Group, Inc.<br />
Moore Ruble Yudell Architects &amp; Planners<br />
ODA-Architecture, P.C.<br />
SmithGroup, Inc.<br />
WXY Architecture + Urban Design</p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 167 new diplomatic facilities. OBO currently has more than 50 active projects, either in design or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that positively represent the United States to other nations and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/bureau-of-overseas-buildings-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzAuNDM5MjY1ODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9vYm8ifQ.LOEdMtBF0oQQ6mPAT8RVgCg9maNhZ2I14i6lz34NKJ0/s/1039202793/br/110179718909-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627756386405000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEtE2_KdCZJ1GmElWnUkGTJPr8vQA">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Government Actions Impacting U.S. Mission Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/russian-government-actions-impacting-u-s-mission-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1">The United States is immensely grateful for the tireless dedication and commitment of our locally employed staff and contractors at U.S. Mission Russia. We thank them for their contributions to the overall operations and their work to improve relations between our two countries.  Their dedication, expertise and friendship have been a mainstay of Mission Russia for decades.</p>
<p class="p1">Starting in August, the Russian government is prohibiting the United States from retaining, hiring, or contracting Russian or third-country staff, except our guard force. We are deeply saddened that this action will force us to let go of 182 local employees and dozens of contractors at our diplomatic facilities in Moscow, Vladivostok, and Yekaterinburg.</p>
<p class="p1">These unfortunate measures will severely impact the U.S. mission to Russia’s operations, potentially including the safety of our personnel as well as our ability to engage in diplomacy with the Russian government.  Although we regret the actions of the Russian government forcing a reduction in our services and operations, the United States will follow through on our commitments while continuing to pursue a predictable and stable relationship with Russia.</p>
<p class="p1">We value our deep connection to the Russian people.  Our people-to-people relationships are the bedrock of our bilateral relations.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1">The United States is immensely grateful for the tireless dedication and commitment of our locally employed staff and contractors at U.S. Mission Russia. We thank them for their contributions to the overall operations and their work to improve relations between our two countries.  Their dedication, expertise and friendship have been a mainstay of Mission Russia for decades.</p>
<p class="p1">Starting in August, the Russian government is prohibiting the United States from retaining, hiring, or contracting Russian or third-country staff, except our guard force. We are deeply saddened that this action will force us to let go of 182 local employees and dozens of contractors at our diplomatic facilities in Moscow, Vladivostok, and Yekaterinburg.</p>
<p class="p1">These unfortunate measures will severely impact the U.S. mission to Russia’s operations, potentially including the safety of our personnel as well as our ability to engage in diplomacy with the Russian government.  Although we regret the actions of the Russian government forcing a reduction in our services and operations, the United States will follow through on our commitments while continuing to pursue a predictable and stable relationship with Russia.</p>
<p class="p1">We value our deep connection to the Russian people.  Our people-to-people relationships are the bedrock of our bilateral relations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harassment of Foreign Journalists in the People’s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/harassment-of-foreign-journalists-in-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 01:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned with the increasingly harsh surveillance, harassment, and intimidation of U.S. and other foreign journalists in the People’s Republic of China (PRC), including foreign journalists covering the devastation and loss of life caused by recent floods in Henan. The U.S. government reiterates the condolences of the American people to all those affected.</p>
<p>The PRC government claims to welcome foreign media and support their work, but its actions tell a different story. Its harsh rhetoric, promoted through official state media, toward any news it perceives to be critical of PRC policies, has provoked negative public sentiment leading to tense, in-person confrontations and harassment, including online verbal abuse and death threats of journalists simply doing their jobs. Foreign journalists are increasingly refused visas to enter or remain in the PRC, severely limiting the quantity and quality of independent reporting on important issues. We call on the PRC to act as a responsible nation hoping to welcome foreign media and the world for the upcoming Beijing 2022 Winter Olympic and Paralympic Games.</p>
<p>In her July 26 meetings with PRC officials in Tianjin, Deputy Secretary Sherman specifically raised the importance of media access, freedom from harassment, and press freedom. We call on PRC officials to ensure that journalists remain safe and able to report freely.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned with the increasingly harsh surveillance, harassment, and intimidation of U.S. and other foreign journalists in the People’s Republic of China (PRC), including foreign journalists covering the devastation and loss of life caused by recent floods in Henan. The U.S. government reiterates the condolences of the American people to all those affected.</p>
<p>The PRC government claims to welcome foreign media and support their work, but its actions tell a different story. Its harsh rhetoric, promoted through official state media, toward any news it perceives to be critical of PRC policies, has provoked negative public sentiment leading to tense, in-person confrontations and harassment, including online verbal abuse and death threats of journalists simply doing their jobs. Foreign journalists are increasingly refused visas to enter or remain in the PRC, severely limiting the quantity and quality of independent reporting on important issues. We call on the PRC to act as a responsible nation hoping to welcome foreign media and the world for the upcoming Beijing 2022 Winter Olympic and Paralympic Games.</p>
<p>In her July 26 meetings with PRC officials in Tianjin, Deputy Secretary Sherman specifically raised the importance of media access, freedom from harassment, and press freedom. We call on PRC officials to ensure that journalists remain safe and able to report freely.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Schedule &#8211; July 30, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-schedule-july-30-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                           ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN<br />
</u></strong>Secretary Blinken attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.<em> </em></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
Deputy Secretary Sherman attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON<br />
</u></strong>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</u></strong>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</u></strong><strong>2:00 p.m.</strong> Principal Deputy Spokesperson Jalina Porter holds a telephonic press briefing.<br />
<strong>(OPEN PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                           ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN<br />
</u></strong>Secretary Blinken attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.<em> </em></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
Deputy Secretary Sherman attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON<br />
</u></strong>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</u></strong>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</u></strong><strong>2:00 p.m.</strong> Principal Deputy Spokesperson Jalina Porter holds a telephonic press briefing.<br />
<strong>(OPEN PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights Uzra Zeya, Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga, Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth, and Senior Advisor to the USAID Administrator and Executive Director of the USAID Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri On the Collaborative Migration Management Strategy and Root Causes Strategy Toward Migration</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-for-civilian-security-democracy-and-human-rights-uzra-zeya-special-envoy-for-the-northern-triangle-ricardo-zuniga-bureau-of-population-refugees-and-migration-deputy-assistant-sec/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marta Costanzo Youth, Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration, Uzra Zeya, Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights, Ricardo Zúniga, Special Envoy for the Northern TriangleBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Senior Advisor to the USAID Administrator and Executive Director of the USAID Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Marta Costanzo Youth, Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration</p>
<p>Uzra Zeya, Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights</p>
<p>Ricardo Zúniga, Special Envoy for the Northern TriangleBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Senior Advisor to the USAID Administrator and Executive Director of the USAID Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining this on-the-record call to discuss the Root Causes and Collaborative Migration Management Strategies of the Biden-Harris administration.  Today, we are joined by Under Secretary of State for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights Uzra Zeya; Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga; Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Marta Youth; and  USAID Administrator and Executive Director of the USAID’s Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri to discuss these strategies.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Zeya will begin with introductory remarks, and then we’ll begin taking your questions.  With that, I’ll turn it over to the under secretary.</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</strong>  Thank you, Jalina, and good afternoon.  I am pleased to be here with my colleagues, Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Marta Youth, and Senior Advisor to the USAID Administrator and Executive Director of USAID’s Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri.</p>
<p>As you all know, this administration has prioritized migration policy reform since President Biden’s first day in office.  Today, the White House announced the launch of a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America and to humanely manage migration throughout North and Central America.  I am happy to speak with you all today to provide a bit more detail on these two plans and the role of the U.S. Department of State in supporting this key White House priority.</p>
<p>The Root Causes Strategy focuses on five areas that address the underlying factors that cause people to leave behind their homes, their families, and their countries:  first, addressing economic insecurity and inequality; second, combating corruption and supporting democratic governance; third, promoting respect for human rights, labor rights, and press freedom; fourth, countering and preventing violent crimes and human trafficking perpetrated by gangs and criminal networks; and fifth, combating sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence.</p>
<p>In tandem, the Collaborative Migration Management Strategy sets out eight concrete lines of action to build a regional framework for safe, orderly, and humane migration.  These include stabilizing populations with acute needs, expanding access to international protection, protection in home countries, and temporary labor programs in the region while improving worker protections, assisting and reintegrating returned people, fostering secure and humane management of borders, strengthening regional public messaging on migration, and finally, expanding access to lawful pathways for protection and opportunity in the United States.</p>
<p>These two strategies are unique in that they’re collaborative efforts rooted in partnership.  The Collaborative Migration Management Strategy is the first U.S. Government strategy to focus on strengthening cooperative efforts across North and Central America to humanely manage migration.  In close cooperation with governments in the region, the United States will promote expanded access to legal pathways to protection, family reunification, and temporary labor opportunities.</p>
<p>Similarly, on the Root Causes Strategy, we’re working with civil society, the private sector, labor unions, regional governments, and international partners to advance more democratic, prosperous, and safe societies where people thrive economically and live, work, and learn in safety and dignity.  We look forward to the support of local governments in the region on this strategy and the collaborative effort to ensure that the people of Central America enjoy opportunities to create the futures they desire for themselves and their families.</p>
<p>We all know this won’t be easy.  Some of the setbacks we’ve witnessed in the region, especially in terms of governance and transparency, are examples of why this work is so important and why we must press forward to make change.  Addressing these challenges is in the interest of the region and of the United States, and we will seek partners willing and committed to working with us to that end.</p>
<p>This is just a brief overview of some of the work we envision.  Now, I’d like to turn it over to my colleagues, Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth and Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga and Director of USAID’s Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri, who I’m sure will be happy to take your questions.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Jalina, over to you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:  </strong>Thank you. We’re going to give these – everyone a minute to fill in, and if the operator can remind people how to opt in the Q&amp;A, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Ladies and gentlemen, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone keypad.  You may withdraw your question at any time by repeating the same command.  If you’re using a speakerphone, we ask that you please pick up the handset before pressing the numbers.  Once again, if you have a question, please press 1 followed by 0 at this time.  Also, please wait until your line has been opened in order to hear the entirety of your question.</p>
<p>Once again, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Suzanne Monyak, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, this is Suzanne with <em>Roll Call</em>.  Thank you, guys, so much for having the call.  I had a question about some of the elements in the migration plan that were also emphasized on yesterday’s NSC call regarding creating pathways for protection in other countries outside of the U.S.  I know that was something the Trump administration did to an extent with the asylum cooperation agreements, which I know the Biden administration has moved to rescind.</p>
<p>But I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about the factors you guys are considering, with what countries who would be considered safe enough to be viable pathways for protection outside of the U.S., and sort of what has gone into those discussions when determining which countries to look at for that.</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH:  </strong>Thank you.  This is Marta Youth responding to your question.</p>
<p>So in terms of – let me just clarify in terms of expanding access to international protection.  When we talk about expanding access to protection in the region, what we’re really talking about is helping build and improve a national asylum systems.  And so, for example, one of the big success stories which really doesn’t get a lot of press is the success story of Mexico’s asylum system.  Mexico has a very – has a functioning asylum system.  They have had, I think, the last statistics I saw was at the – in the beginning of June.  They had over 40,000 people applying for application this year alone, and they have many offices throughout the country, and so forth.</p>
<p>And so this is – and Mexico is not alone in this.  Guatemala has a nascent asylum system that is functioning.  Costa Rica has been a generous host to refugees from Nicaragua and Venezuela and other countries.  So there is international protection in the region, and helping support countries in their efforts to build that protection is really what the focus of this.  It is not to be confused with the asylum cooperative agreements.  Those were also discussed in Executive Order 14010, and they were discussed in terms of suspending and terminating them, which is what Secretary Blinken did very soon after the President signed that executive order.  And so this is really part of the effort to make sure that people find protection closer to home.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:  </strong>Does anyone else want to take a stab at answering that question before we move on to the next person?</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Teresa Welsch.</p>
<p>Hi there.  Thanks for doing this call.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:  </strong>Yes, we can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Great.  This is Teresa Welsh with Devex.  I have a question about the USAID role in the strategy.  Could you talk a little bit more about the role that U.S. foreign assistance will play in this?  And thinking about development assistance as a migration deterrent, is that something that the missions in the Northern Triangle will really be focusing on?  And how does the administration see U.S. foreign assistance helping to carry out this strategy?  Thanks so much.</p>
<p><strong>MR CAMILLERI:</strong>  Sure.  This is Michael Camilleri.  I’m happy to take that.  Just a clarification – when you say the strategy, you’re referring to the root causes strategy or the collaborative migration management strategy?</p>
<p>Okay.  I’m not sure if we’re able to have a back-and-forth.  So I’m going to assume this is related to the root causes strategy.  Look, in terms of USAID’s role, we see it as absolutely integral to all five of the pillars that the under secretary outlined, whether it’s addressing economic insecurity and inequality, combating corruption and strengthening democratic governance, promoting respect for human rights, countering and preventing violence, as well as addressing sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence.  So we have existing programming across all five of those pillars, and we are already embarking on a process to align and optimize both our current and future programming to the specific lines of effort that you’ve seen in the strategy.</p>
<p>So in terms of the funding that the administration has requested from Congress, certainly for Fiscal Year ’22, the majority of that will flow through USAID.  So we see our role and the implementation of this as absolutely critical in collaboration with our State Department colleagues and those across the interagency.</p>
<p>In terms of the focus on addressing root causes of migration, I mean, clearly this is the – it’s the headline of the strategy.  It’s one we’re fully embracing of.  This – when we’re in Central America, this – what that means in practice is creating the conditions in collaboration with partners on the ground – whether it’s governments, or civil society, or faith-based groups, or the private sector – creating the conditions for Hondurans, Guatemalans, and Salvadorans to live a safe and stable and dignified life at home.  And so some of this can sound a little bit semantic I think, depending on which angle you’re coming at it from.  But ultimately, the endeavor to create the conditions where the citizens of these countries can envision a hopeful future for themselves in their home countries, which is what they want to do, is one that is entirely I think consistent, and of USAID’s mission, and one that we very much embrace.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Let’s go to Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi there.  Can you all here me?  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</strong>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Oh, okay.  So listen, I have a – kind of a pretty broad question, which has to do with:  How different is the approach that you guys are taking today, the approach that was announced this morning, compared to what the Obama administration was doing?  And how – what would you see are the main differences in this approach to what the previous administration was doing?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Michael, if you like, you can go ahead and take this question.</p>
<p><strong>MR CAMILLERI:</strong>  Sure.  Thanks, Ricardo.  And thank you for the question.</p>
<p>So certainly there are some parallels, and we’re dealing with the same region, so that’s natural.  But I would boil down the differences to three things – strategy, scale, and sustainability – and I’ll try to run through those fairly succinctly.  But from a strategic perspective, this new root causes strategy reflects a deep and comprehensive and updated analysis of the most pressing issues in the region.  We are learning from what’s worked well in the past and what’s worked not so well.  We’re using data increasingly to strategically target our programs to reach the people most likely to migrate and the places that they’re most likely to migrate from.</p>
<p>So while we’re continuing to focus on economic growth, on security and governance, particularly on anti-corruption, we’re also redoubling our efforts to combat gender-based violence and mitigate the impacts of climate change, which are both leading drivers of irregular migration.</p>
<p>As we move into implementation, we’re also thinking hard not just about what we do, but how we do it, and that includes with a view towards partnering more closely with local organizations in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, who know the needs of their communities the best.</p>
<p>In terms of scale, of course we are increasing the scale of these efforts.  President Biden and Vice President Harris have made addressing the root causes of irregular migration one of their top priorities.  This is certainly reflected in the President’s intention to request $4 billion for U.S. Government programs in Central America over the next four years.  So clearly the scale of this budgetary request reflects both the President’s commitment to Central America and his conviction in this new strategic framework that we’re launching today.</p>
<p>And then finally, we are focused on the long term.  We recognize that the chronic challenges in the region will take sustained commitment.  We’re dedicated to being a good partner for the people of Honduras, El Salvador, and Guatemala.  And at the same time, we recognize that development assistance is not a panacea.  We are, for this reason, seeking new partnerships – including with the private sector, with civil society, and with faith-based groups – to ensure that our work can have a lasting impact on those we seek to serve.</p>
<p>And this focus on sustainability also explains why governance is so central to our approach.  And I’m sure Ricardo will speak to this as well, but we recognize that effective democratic governance is necessary for long-term prosperity and stability.  Success ultimately in this region will require the leaders of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to govern in a transparent, accountable, and inclusive manner.</p>
<p>So our assistance can be catalytic; it can in some cases galvanize political will.  But it will not replace the responsibility that Central American governments have to their own people, and our focus on strengthening democratic governance, transparency, and accountability very much reflects this.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Let’s go to Rebecca Martin – or Morin, I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you so much for holding this call.  I have a question on the protests happening in Guatemala right now, after the top anti-corruption leader was dismissed last week.  How does this affect the Biden administration’s plan to address corruption in the region as part of the root causes strategy?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Thank you for that question.  This is Ricardo Zuniga at the Department of State.  So the protests today and the public response rejecting the removal of the special prosecutor against impunity is very much a reflection of the deep importance that the citizens of Central America place on having good governance, at having accountability, and ensuring that the problems around corruption are addressed.  Because it has an impact in the daily lives of Central Americans.  And our view, the reason that we’re so focused on issues around governance and corruption, is specifically because it undermines what we believe is the most important thing that we can do to address the problems that are driving irregular migration, and that’s absence of opportunity, the lack of opportunity.  What we hear from civil society, from public sector – people in the public sector, and from people in the private sector, is that, as was stated earlier, people prefer to remain at home, but the inability of people, families, and companies to make investments in Central America are often – those desires are thwarted by the lack of juridical certainty, by the lack of confidence that there is a level playing field for all the actors involved.</p>
<p>And so it is a very basic objective to support those in the region in – whether public sector employees, whether government officials, whether people in civil society, or whether people in the private sector – who are trying to achieve greater transparency and see the full realization of the rule of law in Central America as a base from which to grow.  So that’s why we backed the people who are working to combat corruption so strongly.  That prosecutor that you mentioned was cited by – was mentioned by the Secretary of State, Secretary Blinken, as a champion of anti-corruption earlier this year, and that is yet another reason why the United States came strongly to his defense when this action was taken last week.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Let’s go to Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi there.  Thanks for doing the call.  Can I follow up a little bit on Guatemala?  The president is out now saying that – Giammattei – saying that it’s counterproductive to suspend cooperation with the Public Ministry.  Could you talk a little bit about that, specifically about the balance between cooperation and sending a signal?  I mean, is there any risk of impeding cooperation if you do act because of this – these concerns on corruption?</p>
<p>And just a side issue as well:  I know that part of the strategy is working with the private sector.  Could you perhaps talk a little bit more about how you plan to do that?  Is that something that the government can have a role in in terms of encouraging it?  How do you expect to get more of the private sector interested in expanding economic opportunities there?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So thank you.  This is Ricardo Zuniga.  In that same statement, President Giammattei thanked the United States for the support they’d provided to the Public Ministry, and indeed, we provide that support because we believe that, number one, we have a number of shared law enforcement challenges, but the United States also made important investments in expanding access to justice in Guatemala, in expanding the work of the special prosecutor to deal not only with issues related to corruption and organized crime, but also issues like gender-based violence, which is an important driver of irregular migration but also a very – unfortunately, a serious social scourge in Guatemala.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Biden administration made clear that we are prepared to work with those who are prepared to work with us in combating corruption and promoting efforts to combat impunity.  And what we saw in this case was that we had to pause our cooperation with the Public Ministry while we reviewed that cooperation to ensure that it aligned with our objective of supporting those who are combating corruption.  We made very clear in our response that we had lost confidence in the attorney general as a partner in the effort to combat corruption.  The – there were serious questions about the decision to remove a person who was known for having taken a very strong stand against this.</p>
<p>So certainly we share with Guatemala and Guatemalan citizens and the Guatemalan people a very strong interest in ensuring that we are able to lead secure lives and that we’re dealing with shared security concerns.  And so we need to make sure that we are using our resources in a way that advances that effort, and we look forward to continuing to do that in Guatemala.</p>
<p>With regard to the private sector, what we find is that there is great eagerness to take advantage of the advantages in Central America.  Very often we talk about these challenges that we’re facing for a very good reason, but CAFTA-DR countries, of which Guatemala and the rest of Central America are a part, they are the third-largest U.S. market in the Americas, and that’s under very difficult conditions.  So we have an interest as the United States in increasing the ability of our trade partners to in fact provide for their citizens but also create opportunities and help drive opportunities in the United States.</p>
<p>So what we find is that our work with the private sector is very focused on what has been identified by the private sector as impediments to investment.  The first, I mentioned, which was constraints to growth related to governance and the need for judicial certainty, and the need for regulatory certainty, but also the need for investments in human resources, in human capital, where the United States is eager to assist; the need to work together to ensure that the United States, for example, as we pursue enhancements in our supply chains, are making the greatest advantage of markets and producers nearest the United States.</p>
<p>So there is – there are many reasons that we believe the private sector is an extremely important partner, not the least of which, as Michael mentioned – U.S. assistance is meant to enable, create – help create enabling conditions.  It’s not meant to substitute for the growth generated by the private sector.  We know that the best way to create opportunity is to allow citizens to be able to use their own potential and to allow the private sector, both national and international, to help generate the opportunities for people to lead successful lives at home.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  And we’ll take a final question from Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, thanks for doing this.  I just have a quick question on Title 42 policy.  Do you have an update on when the order could be lifted for families or in its entirety?</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH:</strong>  This is Marta Youth.  This is actually a DHS policy question, but as far as we’re aware, there is no change to DHS policy or operations related to their enforcement of the Title 42 order.  It is a public health authority of the CDC, so it’s not really an immigration authority.  Over.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  That concludes today’s call.  Thank you all for joining, and I hope you have a great rest of your week.</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</strong>  Thanks so much, everyone.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marta Costanzo Youth, Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration</p>
<p>Uzra Zeya, Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights</p>
<p>Ricardo Zúniga, Special Envoy for the Northern TriangleBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Senior Advisor to the USAID Administrator and Executive Director of the USAID Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining this on-the-record call to discuss the Root Causes and Collaborative Migration Management Strategies of the Biden-Harris administration.  Today, we are joined by Under Secretary of State for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights Uzra Zeya; Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga; Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Marta Youth; and  USAID Administrator and Executive Director of the USAID’s Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri to discuss these strategies.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Zeya will begin with introductory remarks, and then we’ll begin taking your questions.  With that, I’ll turn it over to the under secretary.</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</strong>  Thank you, Jalina, and good afternoon.  I am pleased to be here with my colleagues, Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Marta Youth, and Senior Advisor to the USAID Administrator and Executive Director of USAID’s Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri.</p>
<p>As you all know, this administration has prioritized migration policy reform since President Biden’s first day in office.  Today, the White House announced the launch of a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America and to humanely manage migration throughout North and Central America.  I am happy to speak with you all today to provide a bit more detail on these two plans and the role of the U.S. Department of State in supporting this key White House priority.</p>
<p>The Root Causes Strategy focuses on five areas that address the underlying factors that cause people to leave behind their homes, their families, and their countries:  first, addressing economic insecurity and inequality; second, combating corruption and supporting democratic governance; third, promoting respect for human rights, labor rights, and press freedom; fourth, countering and preventing violent crimes and human trafficking perpetrated by gangs and criminal networks; and fifth, combating sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence.</p>
<p>In tandem, the Collaborative Migration Management Strategy sets out eight concrete lines of action to build a regional framework for safe, orderly, and humane migration.  These include stabilizing populations with acute needs, expanding access to international protection, protection in home countries, and temporary labor programs in the region while improving worker protections, assisting and reintegrating returned people, fostering secure and humane management of borders, strengthening regional public messaging on migration, and finally, expanding access to lawful pathways for protection and opportunity in the United States.</p>
<p>These two strategies are unique in that they’re collaborative efforts rooted in partnership.  The Collaborative Migration Management Strategy is the first U.S. Government strategy to focus on strengthening cooperative efforts across North and Central America to humanely manage migration.  In close cooperation with governments in the region, the United States will promote expanded access to legal pathways to protection, family reunification, and temporary labor opportunities.</p>
<p>Similarly, on the Root Causes Strategy, we’re working with civil society, the private sector, labor unions, regional governments, and international partners to advance more democratic, prosperous, and safe societies where people thrive economically and live, work, and learn in safety and dignity.  We look forward to the support of local governments in the region on this strategy and the collaborative effort to ensure that the people of Central America enjoy opportunities to create the futures they desire for themselves and their families.</p>
<p>We all know this won’t be easy.  Some of the setbacks we’ve witnessed in the region, especially in terms of governance and transparency, are examples of why this work is so important and why we must press forward to make change.  Addressing these challenges is in the interest of the region and of the United States, and we will seek partners willing and committed to working with us to that end.</p>
<p>This is just a brief overview of some of the work we envision.  Now, I’d like to turn it over to my colleagues, Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth and Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga and Director of USAID’s Northern Triangle Task Force Michael Camilleri, who I’m sure will be happy to take your questions.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Jalina, over to you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:  </strong>Thank you. We’re going to give these – everyone a minute to fill in, and if the operator can remind people how to opt in the Q&amp;A, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Ladies and gentlemen, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone keypad.  You may withdraw your question at any time by repeating the same command.  If you’re using a speakerphone, we ask that you please pick up the handset before pressing the numbers.  Once again, if you have a question, please press 1 followed by 0 at this time.  Also, please wait until your line has been opened in order to hear the entirety of your question.</p>
<p>Once again, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Suzanne Monyak, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, this is Suzanne with <em>Roll Call</em>.  Thank you, guys, so much for having the call.  I had a question about some of the elements in the migration plan that were also emphasized on yesterday’s NSC call regarding creating pathways for protection in other countries outside of the U.S.  I know that was something the Trump administration did to an extent with the asylum cooperation agreements, which I know the Biden administration has moved to rescind.</p>
<p>But I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about the factors you guys are considering, with what countries who would be considered safe enough to be viable pathways for protection outside of the U.S., and sort of what has gone into those discussions when determining which countries to look at for that.</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH:  </strong>Thank you.  This is Marta Youth responding to your question.</p>
<p>So in terms of – let me just clarify in terms of expanding access to international protection.  When we talk about expanding access to protection in the region, what we’re really talking about is helping build and improve a national asylum systems.  And so, for example, one of the big success stories which really doesn’t get a lot of press is the success story of Mexico’s asylum system.  Mexico has a very – has a functioning asylum system.  They have had, I think, the last statistics I saw was at the – in the beginning of June.  They had over 40,000 people applying for application this year alone, and they have many offices throughout the country, and so forth.</p>
<p>And so this is – and Mexico is not alone in this.  Guatemala has a nascent asylum system that is functioning.  Costa Rica has been a generous host to refugees from Nicaragua and Venezuela and other countries.  So there is international protection in the region, and helping support countries in their efforts to build that protection is really what the focus of this.  It is not to be confused with the asylum cooperative agreements.  Those were also discussed in Executive Order 14010, and they were discussed in terms of suspending and terminating them, which is what Secretary Blinken did very soon after the President signed that executive order.  And so this is really part of the effort to make sure that people find protection closer to home.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:  </strong>Does anyone else want to take a stab at answering that question before we move on to the next person?</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Teresa Welsch.</p>
<p>Hi there.  Thanks for doing this call.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:  </strong>Yes, we can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Great.  This is Teresa Welsh with Devex.  I have a question about the USAID role in the strategy.  Could you talk a little bit more about the role that U.S. foreign assistance will play in this?  And thinking about development assistance as a migration deterrent, is that something that the missions in the Northern Triangle will really be focusing on?  And how does the administration see U.S. foreign assistance helping to carry out this strategy?  Thanks so much.</p>
<p><strong>MR CAMILLERI:</strong>  Sure.  This is Michael Camilleri.  I’m happy to take that.  Just a clarification – when you say the strategy, you’re referring to the root causes strategy or the collaborative migration management strategy?</p>
<p>Okay.  I’m not sure if we’re able to have a back-and-forth.  So I’m going to assume this is related to the root causes strategy.  Look, in terms of USAID’s role, we see it as absolutely integral to all five of the pillars that the under secretary outlined, whether it’s addressing economic insecurity and inequality, combating corruption and strengthening democratic governance, promoting respect for human rights, countering and preventing violence, as well as addressing sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence.  So we have existing programming across all five of those pillars, and we are already embarking on a process to align and optimize both our current and future programming to the specific lines of effort that you’ve seen in the strategy.</p>
<p>So in terms of the funding that the administration has requested from Congress, certainly for Fiscal Year ’22, the majority of that will flow through USAID.  So we see our role and the implementation of this as absolutely critical in collaboration with our State Department colleagues and those across the interagency.</p>
<p>In terms of the focus on addressing root causes of migration, I mean, clearly this is the – it’s the headline of the strategy.  It’s one we’re fully embracing of.  This – when we’re in Central America, this – what that means in practice is creating the conditions in collaboration with partners on the ground – whether it’s governments, or civil society, or faith-based groups, or the private sector – creating the conditions for Hondurans, Guatemalans, and Salvadorans to live a safe and stable and dignified life at home.  And so some of this can sound a little bit semantic I think, depending on which angle you’re coming at it from.  But ultimately, the endeavor to create the conditions where the citizens of these countries can envision a hopeful future for themselves in their home countries, which is what they want to do, is one that is entirely I think consistent, and of USAID’s mission, and one that we very much embrace.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Let’s go to Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi there.  Can you all here me?  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</strong>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Oh, okay.  So listen, I have a – kind of a pretty broad question, which has to do with:  How different is the approach that you guys are taking today, the approach that was announced this morning, compared to what the Obama administration was doing?  And how – what would you see are the main differences in this approach to what the previous administration was doing?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Michael, if you like, you can go ahead and take this question.</p>
<p><strong>MR CAMILLERI:</strong>  Sure.  Thanks, Ricardo.  And thank you for the question.</p>
<p>So certainly there are some parallels, and we’re dealing with the same region, so that’s natural.  But I would boil down the differences to three things – strategy, scale, and sustainability – and I’ll try to run through those fairly succinctly.  But from a strategic perspective, this new root causes strategy reflects a deep and comprehensive and updated analysis of the most pressing issues in the region.  We are learning from what’s worked well in the past and what’s worked not so well.  We’re using data increasingly to strategically target our programs to reach the people most likely to migrate and the places that they’re most likely to migrate from.</p>
<p>So while we’re continuing to focus on economic growth, on security and governance, particularly on anti-corruption, we’re also redoubling our efforts to combat gender-based violence and mitigate the impacts of climate change, which are both leading drivers of irregular migration.</p>
<p>As we move into implementation, we’re also thinking hard not just about what we do, but how we do it, and that includes with a view towards partnering more closely with local organizations in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, who know the needs of their communities the best.</p>
<p>In terms of scale, of course we are increasing the scale of these efforts.  President Biden and Vice President Harris have made addressing the root causes of irregular migration one of their top priorities.  This is certainly reflected in the President’s intention to request $4 billion for U.S. Government programs in Central America over the next four years.  So clearly the scale of this budgetary request reflects both the President’s commitment to Central America and his conviction in this new strategic framework that we’re launching today.</p>
<p>And then finally, we are focused on the long term.  We recognize that the chronic challenges in the region will take sustained commitment.  We’re dedicated to being a good partner for the people of Honduras, El Salvador, and Guatemala.  And at the same time, we recognize that development assistance is not a panacea.  We are, for this reason, seeking new partnerships – including with the private sector, with civil society, and with faith-based groups – to ensure that our work can have a lasting impact on those we seek to serve.</p>
<p>And this focus on sustainability also explains why governance is so central to our approach.  And I’m sure Ricardo will speak to this as well, but we recognize that effective democratic governance is necessary for long-term prosperity and stability.  Success ultimately in this region will require the leaders of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to govern in a transparent, accountable, and inclusive manner.</p>
<p>So our assistance can be catalytic; it can in some cases galvanize political will.  But it will not replace the responsibility that Central American governments have to their own people, and our focus on strengthening democratic governance, transparency, and accountability very much reflects this.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Let’s go to Rebecca Martin – or Morin, I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you so much for holding this call.  I have a question on the protests happening in Guatemala right now, after the top anti-corruption leader was dismissed last week.  How does this affect the Biden administration’s plan to address corruption in the region as part of the root causes strategy?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Thank you for that question.  This is Ricardo Zuniga at the Department of State.  So the protests today and the public response rejecting the removal of the special prosecutor against impunity is very much a reflection of the deep importance that the citizens of Central America place on having good governance, at having accountability, and ensuring that the problems around corruption are addressed.  Because it has an impact in the daily lives of Central Americans.  And our view, the reason that we’re so focused on issues around governance and corruption, is specifically because it undermines what we believe is the most important thing that we can do to address the problems that are driving irregular migration, and that’s absence of opportunity, the lack of opportunity.  What we hear from civil society, from public sector – people in the public sector, and from people in the private sector, is that, as was stated earlier, people prefer to remain at home, but the inability of people, families, and companies to make investments in Central America are often – those desires are thwarted by the lack of juridical certainty, by the lack of confidence that there is a level playing field for all the actors involved.</p>
<p>And so it is a very basic objective to support those in the region in – whether public sector employees, whether government officials, whether people in civil society, or whether people in the private sector – who are trying to achieve greater transparency and see the full realization of the rule of law in Central America as a base from which to grow.  So that’s why we backed the people who are working to combat corruption so strongly.  That prosecutor that you mentioned was cited by – was mentioned by the Secretary of State, Secretary Blinken, as a champion of anti-corruption earlier this year, and that is yet another reason why the United States came strongly to his defense when this action was taken last week.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Let’s go to Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi there.  Thanks for doing the call.  Can I follow up a little bit on Guatemala?  The president is out now saying that – Giammattei – saying that it’s counterproductive to suspend cooperation with the Public Ministry.  Could you talk a little bit about that, specifically about the balance between cooperation and sending a signal?  I mean, is there any risk of impeding cooperation if you do act because of this – these concerns on corruption?</p>
<p>And just a side issue as well:  I know that part of the strategy is working with the private sector.  Could you perhaps talk a little bit more about how you plan to do that?  Is that something that the government can have a role in in terms of encouraging it?  How do you expect to get more of the private sector interested in expanding economic opportunities there?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So thank you.  This is Ricardo Zuniga.  In that same statement, President Giammattei thanked the United States for the support they’d provided to the Public Ministry, and indeed, we provide that support because we believe that, number one, we have a number of shared law enforcement challenges, but the United States also made important investments in expanding access to justice in Guatemala, in expanding the work of the special prosecutor to deal not only with issues related to corruption and organized crime, but also issues like gender-based violence, which is an important driver of irregular migration but also a very – unfortunately, a serious social scourge in Guatemala.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Biden administration made clear that we are prepared to work with those who are prepared to work with us in combating corruption and promoting efforts to combat impunity.  And what we saw in this case was that we had to pause our cooperation with the Public Ministry while we reviewed that cooperation to ensure that it aligned with our objective of supporting those who are combating corruption.  We made very clear in our response that we had lost confidence in the attorney general as a partner in the effort to combat corruption.  The – there were serious questions about the decision to remove a person who was known for having taken a very strong stand against this.</p>
<p>So certainly we share with Guatemala and Guatemalan citizens and the Guatemalan people a very strong interest in ensuring that we are able to lead secure lives and that we’re dealing with shared security concerns.  And so we need to make sure that we are using our resources in a way that advances that effort, and we look forward to continuing to do that in Guatemala.</p>
<p>With regard to the private sector, what we find is that there is great eagerness to take advantage of the advantages in Central America.  Very often we talk about these challenges that we’re facing for a very good reason, but CAFTA-DR countries, of which Guatemala and the rest of Central America are a part, they are the third-largest U.S. market in the Americas, and that’s under very difficult conditions.  So we have an interest as the United States in increasing the ability of our trade partners to in fact provide for their citizens but also create opportunities and help drive opportunities in the United States.</p>
<p>So what we find is that our work with the private sector is very focused on what has been identified by the private sector as impediments to investment.  The first, I mentioned, which was constraints to growth related to governance and the need for judicial certainty, and the need for regulatory certainty, but also the need for investments in human resources, in human capital, where the United States is eager to assist; the need to work together to ensure that the United States, for example, as we pursue enhancements in our supply chains, are making the greatest advantage of markets and producers nearest the United States.</p>
<p>So there is – there are many reasons that we believe the private sector is an extremely important partner, not the least of which, as Michael mentioned – U.S. assistance is meant to enable, create – help create enabling conditions.  It’s not meant to substitute for the growth generated by the private sector.  We know that the best way to create opportunity is to allow citizens to be able to use their own potential and to allow the private sector, both national and international, to help generate the opportunities for people to lead successful lives at home.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  And we’ll take a final question from Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, thanks for doing this.  I just have a quick question on Title 42 policy.  Do you have an update on when the order could be lifted for families or in its entirety?</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH:</strong>  This is Marta Youth.  This is actually a DHS policy question, but as far as we’re aware, there is no change to DHS policy or operations related to their enforcement of the Title 42 order.  It is a public health authority of the CDC, so it’s not really an immigration authority.  Over.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  That concludes today’s call.  Thank you all for joining, and I hope you have a great rest of your week.</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</strong>  Thanks so much, everyone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Kuwaiti Foreign Minister Sheikh Dr. Ahmed Nasser Al-Mohammed Al-Sabah At a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-kuwaiti-foreign-minister-sheikh-dr-ahmed-nasser-al-mohammed-al-sabah-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 21:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  To start, I would like to welcome my friend, Mr. State Secretary Antony Blinken, in his visit, first visit to Kuwait, while I am a minister of – foreign affairs minister.  We were honored today in the morning to meet his highness the amir of the country, Sheikh Jaber (inaudible) Al-Jaber Al-Sabah, and also his highness the prime – the crown prince, Sheikh Mishal Al-Sabah, and also the prime – his highness the prime minister, Sheikh Sabah Al-Khaled Al-Hamad Al-Sabah, may God protect them.</p>
<p>We heard during the visit with his highness the amir the instructions to give support to the relations with the U.S., all – all what can be – and care.  And we should remember that this year, we celebrate the 60th anniversary of our diplomatic relations, and also 30th anniversary of liberation of Kuwait.  And the visit of my friend, Secretary of State Antony Blinken to Kuwait, comes quite – few days from the anniversary of the Iraqi invasion to Kuwait, which – where there was a very strong stand by USA in liberating Kuwait and having legitimacy back to Kuwait.  So we thank you, your excellency, my friend, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p>The bloods of the Kuwaitis and the U.S., the Americans, were together and mixed together in the liberation of Kuwait, and we remember through the coalition of 39 countries around the world to liberate Kuwait, headed and led by USA.  This will remain in the hearts of all Kuwaitis, all in appreciation for that.  And we will remain appreciative for the USA and the administration, the U.S. administration, and his excellency, his highness, the – or the President of USA and also State Secretary Mr. Blinken.</p>
<p>We remember also in this occasion the many relations we have between our both countries in all fields.  We talked about the importance of lending care of strategic discussions and dialogue and what is important for both countries and give extra push to the bilateral relation.  We look forward to the fifth dialogue session between Kuwait and USA.</p>
<p>And we believe that both countries and the whole world are going through the corona pandemic.  Maybe it is important to exchange expertise with respect to fighting this pandemic and all the other issues of development and enhancement of how to distribute the vaccine in both countries and all the world, actually, because both countries believe that we are not immune unless we are all vaccinated.  And we believe there’s another side that comes from corona, which is the aftermath of this pandemic with respect to the food security, and there’s a lot of collaboration in that respect with USA.  We thank USA for this part of the food security in the whole region and in the whole world.</p>
<p>We are also proud on the level of collaboration in education between USA and Kuwait, and there are several students who are studying in the USA, and many of Kuwaitis have benefited throughout the decades, the past decades of the unique education enjoyed in the U.S. by the USA.</p>
<p>And during the pandemic there were some aspects that we had to – we should learn from it and share expertise, and also the collaboration in this field itself, the pandemic.  Also those with respect to the information technology, cyber crime, cybersecurity, because none of the countries are really secure completely unless we join efforts together.  And we thank our friends in the USA for all the efforts they make with Kuwait to ensure cybersecurity in Kuwait.</p>
<p>This is – these are the bilateral issues that we will continue at the end of this year in the strategic discussion, and we also discussed several issues, regional and international.  And thank God we – there are so many, so many similarity in viewpoints regarding these issues on the regional and international level because we both believe as countries that – the elements in the international law and mentioned in the charter of establishing the United Nations itself.</p>
<p>I welcome you, my friend, State Secretary Antony Blinken, to Kuwait.  Welcome, and we wish for you a nice visit and successful one.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Good afternoon again.</p>
<p>It’s a real pleasure to be back in Kuwait to be able to spend time in person with my friend, the foreign minister.  We’ve had the opportunities to talk and work on issues, but nothing substitutes for being able to be in the same room, the same place, and have very good and detailed conversations.</p>
<p>So, Ahmed, I really want to thank you for your hospitality today and, of course, his highness the amir, the crown prince, the prime minister, the speaker of the parliament for their very, very warm reception and the very good conversations that we’ve had.</p>
<p>I’m here because of the strong ties of friendship and partnership between the United States and Kuwait.  And as the foreign minister has already noted, 60 years ago when Kuwait became an independent nation, our two nations quickly established diplomatic relations.  And 30 years ago, the United States was proud to lead a coalition of nations to help liberate Kuwait from the occupation of Saddam Hussein.  We were at the parliament and saw a video of President George H.W. Bush when he was here after the liberation, being received at the parliament, and it was quite, I must say, moving to see those images again of our president, of Secretary Baker, our Kuwaiti colleagues in that remarkable moment.  And as President Bush put it, by standing with a peaceful Kuwait against an invasion by a violent dictator, we were standing up for our principles, including the principle that America stands by her friends.</p>
<p>In the years since, the partnership between Kuwait and the United States has grown even stronger.  And today, as the foreign minister alluded to, we’re working together on a wide variety of issues.  We’re working together to end the COVID-19 pandemic, to advance regional security, to bridge divides, to address the needs of people across the Middle East and beyond.  And I really want to thank Kuwait for stepping up to provide very generous support to COVAX, the facility that helps provide vaccines around the world.  It’s leading the global effort to procure and equitably distribute safe and effective vaccines with strong support from both of our countries.</p>
<p>Kuwait has demonstrated and Ahmed, you’ve demonstrated personally remarkable statesmanship in healing the Gulf rift earlier this year, bringing a close to a political crisis that’s divided Gulf nations since 2017.  Kuwait’s a critical partner in the effort to end the war in Yemen and to advance the cause of a two-state solution between Israelis and Palestinians.  As Iraq works to strengthen its relations with its Arab neighbors, Kuwait and the United States are working together to increase its stability, its security, its integration with the region, including through Kuwait’s efforts to connect Iraq to the GCC electricity grid.  And we’re working together to help the Afghan people and support regional stability as coalition forces withdraw from Afghanistan.</p>
<p>This partnership is made possible by our deepening ties.  Kuwait is a major non-NATO ally of ours.  It’s a gracious host to American troops based here, and that allows us to continue our mission of helping to defend our partners in the region.  The bilateral trade relationship continues to grow.  In 2019, it accounted for about $4.5 billion.  We’re determined to raise that number substantially by putting forward a positive vision for how to get business done.</p>
<p>We know that allies and partners in the region have their own complex relationships around the world, including with China, and the question for us is not an either/or choice, but we believe that by promoting a level business playing field and relying on innovation and openness, the United States will remain a strong partner of choice throughout the region.</p>
<p>Earlier today, as I mentioned, I had a chance to tour Kuwait’s National Assembly, an institution vital to democratic governance.  I appreciate the work that our countries do together, both bilaterally and in international institutions, to advance respect for freedom of religion and belief.  Perhaps most significantly, our people-to-people ties are enduring.  Nearly 10,000 Kuwaitis studied in American universities and English-language institutions in the 2019-2020 academic year.  That’s the third-highest number of any country in the region.  It’s even more significant when we remember that Kuwait has one of the smaller populations in the region.  We’re grateful that so many Kuwaiti students have chosen to study in the United States.  We’re working hard to welcome as many of you back as possible, and we hope even more of you will study in the United States because strong bilateral partnerships like ours ultimately are founded on these people-to-people ties.</p>
<p>At a time of immense global challenge, it’s more important than ever to have friends that you can work with to solve problems, to advance shared interests and shared goals.  Kuwait is one of those friends.  The United States is proud of our partnership and I’m grateful for the good work that we’re getting done today and that we’ll get done in the future.</p>
<p>As noted, this is a time of in some ways looking back in celebration at the establishment of diplomatic relations, at the liberation of Kuwait, but much more important even than that is a moment for looking forward, to building on all that we’ve done together in recent years, to grow the partnership, to make it even stronger, to make it even broader, and to work together to tackle the challenges that we face and that the world faces.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Samira.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, Your Excellency, and welcome to your guest.  Samira from <em>Anhaar</em> – Kuwait <em>Anhaar </em>magazine, a question to both ministers.</p>
<p>It is regarding your excellency – what Blinken said to follow Afghanistan, and <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> had published that Kuwait will receive number of translators coming from Afghanistan and mentioned that it will receive them at an American base called Buehring, I think she said.  Did you discuss this issue?  And what’s the stand of Kuwait and the number of different individuals that Kuwait will receive and host?</p>
<p>The other question is regarding reducing the number of soldiers of – American soldiers – sorry, number of Patriot platforms.  Why did you reduce this in the region?  And you say – or this administration say that they are to enhance security in the region and protect the Gulf countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks very much for the question.  With regard to Afghanistan and the question of special immigrant visas, the United States is committed to helping those who helped us during our time in Afghanistan over the last 20 years.  And indeed, we’ve had very brave Afghans who have stood with us, with our soldiers, with our diplomats, mostly as translators and interpreters, and as a result of that service, benefit from the possibility of securing a visa to come live in the United States.  We’re actively engaged in that process, notably in relocation planning for those brave Afghans and their families.  That is a subject that came up today, as it’s come up in conversations with a number of other allies and partners.</p>
<p>With regard to the Patriots and other issues, I would refer you to the Department of Defense on those questions.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Mr. Secretary, I would like to follow up on the question on Afghan interpreters.  So there were expectation that you would reach an agreement here with Kuwait, but you’re not announcing it.  At this pace, how are you going to be able to relocate all those people before the U.S. forces leave in one month, if that’s the administration intention, of course?  And can you confirm that the first group will arrive in the U.S. today to be transferred to Fort Lee?</p>
<p>And Mr. Foreign Minister, has the Biden administration asked Kuwait to join the Abraham Accords with Israel, and is that something that you are considering?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  I’m happy to start.</p>
<p>So as you know, earlier this month, President Biden announced what we call Operation Allies Refuge to support the relocation for Afghan nationals and their families who are eligible for Special Immigrant Visas.  And that process is actively underway.  And indeed, we expect the first beneficiaries of the program to begin arriving very, very soon.</p>
<p>At the State Department, we’ve activated an Afghanistan Coordination Task Force that is working on this.  It’s led by a three-time ambassador, Tracey Jacobson, and has experts from across the relevant departments in government.  And that task force is coordinating our efforts to take SIV applicants out of harm’s way and, if qualified, bring them to the United States once their vetting is complete.  So we’re very actively engaged in that.  We put significant resources into this effort.  We are talking to a number of countries about the possibility of temporarily relocating these applicants as the process is complete.  It takes some time to work through the process.  And as I said, that was a product – one of the issues that came up in our conversations today, as it is with a number of other friends and allies, but we are very much focused on making good on our obligations to those who stood with us in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Regarding the Abraham Accords, all of the signatories, as far as Kuwait is concerned, it’s a sovereign issue for all of the signatories on the Abraham Accord.</p>
<p>But as far as Kuwait, it is the whole struggle of the Palestinians, now over 73 years of ordeal.  The most important aspect is not to go into the desperation.  We thank the U.S. administration for its commitment with the peace process, with the reviving of the political process.  We were in dire times end of May during all of the escalation of violence on Gaza.  And we truly do think that the only viable solution is a two-state solution.  And if we lose focus on that, then it might be put into ordeal and/or to jeopardy.</p>
<p>Therefore, continuous focus of the whole international community on reviving the spirit of peace as it was 30 years ago during Madrid or during Oslo is very important as far as Kuwait is concerned, and not to lose this momentum because the aspect of it, the ramification affect is very dire for the Palestinians and for the region.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  My name is Shahad Al-Matrouk from Al Arabiya’s channel.  I would like to talk about the Houthi behavior that is backed by Iran recently.  We saw new attempts to attack Saudi Arabia with ballistic missiles and drones.  Will Washington condemn only without taking any measures to stop these behaviors that target civilians?  Also, the U.S. military presence in the Gulf region, will it shrink in the coming period of time?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry.  Could you repeat the second part of the question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The U.S. military presence in the region, will it shrink in the coming period of time?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  With regard to Yemen, we are very, very focused on the diplomacy and efforts to bring the war to an end and to bring the resulting human suffering to an end.  As you know, at the very – toward the very beginning of the administration, we appointed a senior special envoy to lead our diplomacy for ending the war in Yemen, Tim Lenderking.  He’s been very actively engaged, as have I and other officials in the administration.  And it is incumbent on the Houthis to engage meaningfully and in good faith in an effort to end the war.  We appreciate the steps that Saudi Arabia has taken to move in that direction, and we’re also committed to the defense of Saudi Arabia, including when it comes to attacks against Saudi territory coming from Yemen, coming from the Houthis.  That’s – that remains vital.</p>
<p>So right now, I think the Houthis have failed to demonstrate a willingness to engage meaningfully in the peace process.  I think that every – virtually every country in the region as well as the United States are trying to move in that direction, and we would like to see the Houthis engage meaningfully in that effort as opposed to launching missiles at Saudi Arabia or continuing an offensive in Yemen itself.</p>
<p>With regard to our force posture, as every administration does upon taking office, we’re engaged in a global review of our force posture.  Again, I’ll leave that to the Pentagon to talk about, but we are very much committed to our presence in the region, in the Middle East, and here in Kuwait.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Since you’ve come to the region, Secretary Blinken, I wonder if I could ask about Iran.  The supreme leader said yesterday that Iran is not going to accept what he called Washington’s stubborn demands to revive the nuclear deal, as you won’t remove any of the sanctions imposed by the previous U.S. administration.  With trying to get them back into the nuclear deal, haven’t you failed to give them a good reason to get them back to the negotiating table?</p>
<p>And further, I wanted to ask, why has it taken nearly two weeks for the administration to speak out about protests that have been going on in Iran over – against the government in the last couple of weeks?</p>
<p>And to the foreign minister, I wonder, is Kuwait concerned about the U.S. recent agreement with Iraq to end its combat mission there?  This comes at a time when Iranian-backed militias appear to be in the ascendancy in Iraq.  The country’s politics is looking towards a more nationalist direction.  Does this give you concerns that what happened here 30 years ago is closer to happening again with the situation in Iraq?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we’ve engaged in multiple rounds of conversations and negotiations in Vienna – indirect, as you know.  The Iranians have refused to talk directly, but with our European partners, with Russia and China, we’ve been engaged in – as I said, in multiple rounds.  I think we have clearly demonstrated our good faith and desire to return to mutual compliance with the nuclear agreement, with the JCPOA.  And the fact of the matter is it is Iran that has decisions to make, fundamental decisions to make about whether it too wants to return to compliance.  And there is no amount of deflection that can change that basic fact.  The ball remains in Iran’s court and we will see if they are prepared to make the decisions necessary to come back into compliance.</p>
<p>We are committed to diplomacy, but this process cannot go on indefinitely.  At some point, the gains achieved by the JCPOA cannot be fully recovered by a return to the JCPOA if Iran continues the activities that it’s undertaken with regard to its nuclear program – activities that, of course, have broken through the constraints imposed by the JCPOA.  So we look to see what Iran is ready to do or not ready to do.  We remain fully prepared to return to Vienna to continue negotiations, but as I said, this process cannot and will not go on indefinitely.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Regarding the – your second question, the United States has proven time and time again of its commitment to the security of Kuwait and the region, and I think that throughout the six decades, there are lots of times and aspect that really, the United States showed in action its total commitment.</p>
<p>As well, we have an agreement treaty with the United States for the security and stability of Kuwait, and both of us are members under the leadership of United States in combating Daesh.  In Kuwait, we are hosting lots of allied country in combating Daesh, so this is an ongoing, as well, a commitment – an international commitment, a multilateral commitment in combating terrorism as well.</p>
<p>So no, we are not concerned about this matter.  We think that it is based on the sovereign decision of United – the United States, and the time has showed time and time again the fervent stance of United States with the security and stability of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Thank you so much, ladies and gentlemen.  Thank you so much, and see you soon.  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  To start, I would like to welcome my friend, Mr. State Secretary Antony Blinken, in his visit, first visit to Kuwait, while I am a minister of – foreign affairs minister.  We were honored today in the morning to meet his highness the amir of the country, Sheikh Jaber (inaudible) Al-Jaber Al-Sabah, and also his highness the prime – the crown prince, Sheikh Mishal Al-Sabah, and also the prime – his highness the prime minister, Sheikh Sabah Al-Khaled Al-Hamad Al-Sabah, may God protect them.</p>
<p>We heard during the visit with his highness the amir the instructions to give support to the relations with the U.S., all – all what can be – and care.  And we should remember that this year, we celebrate the 60th anniversary of our diplomatic relations, and also 30th anniversary of liberation of Kuwait.  And the visit of my friend, Secretary of State Antony Blinken to Kuwait, comes quite – few days from the anniversary of the Iraqi invasion to Kuwait, which – where there was a very strong stand by USA in liberating Kuwait and having legitimacy back to Kuwait.  So we thank you, your excellency, my friend, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p>The bloods of the Kuwaitis and the U.S., the Americans, were together and mixed together in the liberation of Kuwait, and we remember through the coalition of 39 countries around the world to liberate Kuwait, headed and led by USA.  This will remain in the hearts of all Kuwaitis, all in appreciation for that.  And we will remain appreciative for the USA and the administration, the U.S. administration, and his excellency, his highness, the – or the President of USA and also State Secretary Mr. Blinken.</p>
<p>We remember also in this occasion the many relations we have between our both countries in all fields.  We talked about the importance of lending care of strategic discussions and dialogue and what is important for both countries and give extra push to the bilateral relation.  We look forward to the fifth dialogue session between Kuwait and USA.</p>
<p>And we believe that both countries and the whole world are going through the corona pandemic.  Maybe it is important to exchange expertise with respect to fighting this pandemic and all the other issues of development and enhancement of how to distribute the vaccine in both countries and all the world, actually, because both countries believe that we are not immune unless we are all vaccinated.  And we believe there’s another side that comes from corona, which is the aftermath of this pandemic with respect to the food security, and there’s a lot of collaboration in that respect with USA.  We thank USA for this part of the food security in the whole region and in the whole world.</p>
<p>We are also proud on the level of collaboration in education between USA and Kuwait, and there are several students who are studying in the USA, and many of Kuwaitis have benefited throughout the decades, the past decades of the unique education enjoyed in the U.S. by the USA.</p>
<p>And during the pandemic there were some aspects that we had to – we should learn from it and share expertise, and also the collaboration in this field itself, the pandemic.  Also those with respect to the information technology, cyber crime, cybersecurity, because none of the countries are really secure completely unless we join efforts together.  And we thank our friends in the USA for all the efforts they make with Kuwait to ensure cybersecurity in Kuwait.</p>
<p>This is – these are the bilateral issues that we will continue at the end of this year in the strategic discussion, and we also discussed several issues, regional and international.  And thank God we – there are so many, so many similarity in viewpoints regarding these issues on the regional and international level because we both believe as countries that – the elements in the international law and mentioned in the charter of establishing the United Nations itself.</p>
<p>I welcome you, my friend, State Secretary Antony Blinken, to Kuwait.  Welcome, and we wish for you a nice visit and successful one.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Good afternoon again.</p>
<p>It’s a real pleasure to be back in Kuwait to be able to spend time in person with my friend, the foreign minister.  We’ve had the opportunities to talk and work on issues, but nothing substitutes for being able to be in the same room, the same place, and have very good and detailed conversations.</p>
<p>So, Ahmed, I really want to thank you for your hospitality today and, of course, his highness the amir, the crown prince, the prime minister, the speaker of the parliament for their very, very warm reception and the very good conversations that we’ve had.</p>
<p>I’m here because of the strong ties of friendship and partnership between the United States and Kuwait.  And as the foreign minister has already noted, 60 years ago when Kuwait became an independent nation, our two nations quickly established diplomatic relations.  And 30 years ago, the United States was proud to lead a coalition of nations to help liberate Kuwait from the occupation of Saddam Hussein.  We were at the parliament and saw a video of President George H.W. Bush when he was here after the liberation, being received at the parliament, and it was quite, I must say, moving to see those images again of our president, of Secretary Baker, our Kuwaiti colleagues in that remarkable moment.  And as President Bush put it, by standing with a peaceful Kuwait against an invasion by a violent dictator, we were standing up for our principles, including the principle that America stands by her friends.</p>
<p>In the years since, the partnership between Kuwait and the United States has grown even stronger.  And today, as the foreign minister alluded to, we’re working together on a wide variety of issues.  We’re working together to end the COVID-19 pandemic, to advance regional security, to bridge divides, to address the needs of people across the Middle East and beyond.  And I really want to thank Kuwait for stepping up to provide very generous support to COVAX, the facility that helps provide vaccines around the world.  It’s leading the global effort to procure and equitably distribute safe and effective vaccines with strong support from both of our countries.</p>
<p>Kuwait has demonstrated and Ahmed, you’ve demonstrated personally remarkable statesmanship in healing the Gulf rift earlier this year, bringing a close to a political crisis that’s divided Gulf nations since 2017.  Kuwait’s a critical partner in the effort to end the war in Yemen and to advance the cause of a two-state solution between Israelis and Palestinians.  As Iraq works to strengthen its relations with its Arab neighbors, Kuwait and the United States are working together to increase its stability, its security, its integration with the region, including through Kuwait’s efforts to connect Iraq to the GCC electricity grid.  And we’re working together to help the Afghan people and support regional stability as coalition forces withdraw from Afghanistan.</p>
<p>This partnership is made possible by our deepening ties.  Kuwait is a major non-NATO ally of ours.  It’s a gracious host to American troops based here, and that allows us to continue our mission of helping to defend our partners in the region.  The bilateral trade relationship continues to grow.  In 2019, it accounted for about $4.5 billion.  We’re determined to raise that number substantially by putting forward a positive vision for how to get business done.</p>
<p>We know that allies and partners in the region have their own complex relationships around the world, including with China, and the question for us is not an either/or choice, but we believe that by promoting a level business playing field and relying on innovation and openness, the United States will remain a strong partner of choice throughout the region.</p>
<p>Earlier today, as I mentioned, I had a chance to tour Kuwait’s National Assembly, an institution vital to democratic governance.  I appreciate the work that our countries do together, both bilaterally and in international institutions, to advance respect for freedom of religion and belief.  Perhaps most significantly, our people-to-people ties are enduring.  Nearly 10,000 Kuwaitis studied in American universities and English-language institutions in the 2019-2020 academic year.  That’s the third-highest number of any country in the region.  It’s even more significant when we remember that Kuwait has one of the smaller populations in the region.  We’re grateful that so many Kuwaiti students have chosen to study in the United States.  We’re working hard to welcome as many of you back as possible, and we hope even more of you will study in the United States because strong bilateral partnerships like ours ultimately are founded on these people-to-people ties.</p>
<p>At a time of immense global challenge, it’s more important than ever to have friends that you can work with to solve problems, to advance shared interests and shared goals.  Kuwait is one of those friends.  The United States is proud of our partnership and I’m grateful for the good work that we’re getting done today and that we’ll get done in the future.</p>
<p>As noted, this is a time of in some ways looking back in celebration at the establishment of diplomatic relations, at the liberation of Kuwait, but much more important even than that is a moment for looking forward, to building on all that we’ve done together in recent years, to grow the partnership, to make it even stronger, to make it even broader, and to work together to tackle the challenges that we face and that the world faces.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Samira.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, Your Excellency, and welcome to your guest.  Samira from <em>Anhaar</em> – Kuwait <em>Anhaar </em>magazine, a question to both ministers.</p>
<p>It is regarding your excellency – what Blinken said to follow Afghanistan, and <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> had published that Kuwait will receive number of translators coming from Afghanistan and mentioned that it will receive them at an American base called Buehring, I think she said.  Did you discuss this issue?  And what’s the stand of Kuwait and the number of different individuals that Kuwait will receive and host?</p>
<p>The other question is regarding reducing the number of soldiers of – American soldiers – sorry, number of Patriot platforms.  Why did you reduce this in the region?  And you say – or this administration say that they are to enhance security in the region and protect the Gulf countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks very much for the question.  With regard to Afghanistan and the question of special immigrant visas, the United States is committed to helping those who helped us during our time in Afghanistan over the last 20 years.  And indeed, we’ve had very brave Afghans who have stood with us, with our soldiers, with our diplomats, mostly as translators and interpreters, and as a result of that service, benefit from the possibility of securing a visa to come live in the United States.  We’re actively engaged in that process, notably in relocation planning for those brave Afghans and their families.  That is a subject that came up today, as it’s come up in conversations with a number of other allies and partners.</p>
<p>With regard to the Patriots and other issues, I would refer you to the Department of Defense on those questions.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Mr. Secretary, I would like to follow up on the question on Afghan interpreters.  So there were expectation that you would reach an agreement here with Kuwait, but you’re not announcing it.  At this pace, how are you going to be able to relocate all those people before the U.S. forces leave in one month, if that’s the administration intention, of course?  And can you confirm that the first group will arrive in the U.S. today to be transferred to Fort Lee?</p>
<p>And Mr. Foreign Minister, has the Biden administration asked Kuwait to join the Abraham Accords with Israel, and is that something that you are considering?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  I’m happy to start.</p>
<p>So as you know, earlier this month, President Biden announced what we call Operation Allies Refuge to support the relocation for Afghan nationals and their families who are eligible for Special Immigrant Visas.  And that process is actively underway.  And indeed, we expect the first beneficiaries of the program to begin arriving very, very soon.</p>
<p>At the State Department, we’ve activated an Afghanistan Coordination Task Force that is working on this.  It’s led by a three-time ambassador, Tracey Jacobson, and has experts from across the relevant departments in government.  And that task force is coordinating our efforts to take SIV applicants out of harm’s way and, if qualified, bring them to the United States once their vetting is complete.  So we’re very actively engaged in that.  We put significant resources into this effort.  We are talking to a number of countries about the possibility of temporarily relocating these applicants as the process is complete.  It takes some time to work through the process.  And as I said, that was a product – one of the issues that came up in our conversations today, as it is with a number of other friends and allies, but we are very much focused on making good on our obligations to those who stood with us in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Regarding the Abraham Accords, all of the signatories, as far as Kuwait is concerned, it’s a sovereign issue for all of the signatories on the Abraham Accord.</p>
<p>But as far as Kuwait, it is the whole struggle of the Palestinians, now over 73 years of ordeal.  The most important aspect is not to go into the desperation.  We thank the U.S. administration for its commitment with the peace process, with the reviving of the political process.  We were in dire times end of May during all of the escalation of violence on Gaza.  And we truly do think that the only viable solution is a two-state solution.  And if we lose focus on that, then it might be put into ordeal and/or to jeopardy.</p>
<p>Therefore, continuous focus of the whole international community on reviving the spirit of peace as it was 30 years ago during Madrid or during Oslo is very important as far as Kuwait is concerned, and not to lose this momentum because the aspect of it, the ramification affect is very dire for the Palestinians and for the region.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  My name is Shahad Al-Matrouk from Al Arabiya’s channel.  I would like to talk about the Houthi behavior that is backed by Iran recently.  We saw new attempts to attack Saudi Arabia with ballistic missiles and drones.  Will Washington condemn only without taking any measures to stop these behaviors that target civilians?  Also, the U.S. military presence in the Gulf region, will it shrink in the coming period of time?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry.  Could you repeat the second part of the question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The U.S. military presence in the region, will it shrink in the coming period of time?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  With regard to Yemen, we are very, very focused on the diplomacy and efforts to bring the war to an end and to bring the resulting human suffering to an end.  As you know, at the very – toward the very beginning of the administration, we appointed a senior special envoy to lead our diplomacy for ending the war in Yemen, Tim Lenderking.  He’s been very actively engaged, as have I and other officials in the administration.  And it is incumbent on the Houthis to engage meaningfully and in good faith in an effort to end the war.  We appreciate the steps that Saudi Arabia has taken to move in that direction, and we’re also committed to the defense of Saudi Arabia, including when it comes to attacks against Saudi territory coming from Yemen, coming from the Houthis.  That’s – that remains vital.</p>
<p>So right now, I think the Houthis have failed to demonstrate a willingness to engage meaningfully in the peace process.  I think that every – virtually every country in the region as well as the United States are trying to move in that direction, and we would like to see the Houthis engage meaningfully in that effort as opposed to launching missiles at Saudi Arabia or continuing an offensive in Yemen itself.</p>
<p>With regard to our force posture, as every administration does upon taking office, we’re engaged in a global review of our force posture.  Again, I’ll leave that to the Pentagon to talk about, but we are very much committed to our presence in the region, in the Middle East, and here in Kuwait.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Since you’ve come to the region, Secretary Blinken, I wonder if I could ask about Iran.  The supreme leader said yesterday that Iran is not going to accept what he called Washington’s stubborn demands to revive the nuclear deal, as you won’t remove any of the sanctions imposed by the previous U.S. administration.  With trying to get them back into the nuclear deal, haven’t you failed to give them a good reason to get them back to the negotiating table?</p>
<p>And further, I wanted to ask, why has it taken nearly two weeks for the administration to speak out about protests that have been going on in Iran over – against the government in the last couple of weeks?</p>
<p>And to the foreign minister, I wonder, is Kuwait concerned about the U.S. recent agreement with Iraq to end its combat mission there?  This comes at a time when Iranian-backed militias appear to be in the ascendancy in Iraq.  The country’s politics is looking towards a more nationalist direction.  Does this give you concerns that what happened here 30 years ago is closer to happening again with the situation in Iraq?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we’ve engaged in multiple rounds of conversations and negotiations in Vienna – indirect, as you know.  The Iranians have refused to talk directly, but with our European partners, with Russia and China, we’ve been engaged in – as I said, in multiple rounds.  I think we have clearly demonstrated our good faith and desire to return to mutual compliance with the nuclear agreement, with the JCPOA.  And the fact of the matter is it is Iran that has decisions to make, fundamental decisions to make about whether it too wants to return to compliance.  And there is no amount of deflection that can change that basic fact.  The ball remains in Iran’s court and we will see if they are prepared to make the decisions necessary to come back into compliance.</p>
<p>We are committed to diplomacy, but this process cannot go on indefinitely.  At some point, the gains achieved by the JCPOA cannot be fully recovered by a return to the JCPOA if Iran continues the activities that it’s undertaken with regard to its nuclear program – activities that, of course, have broken through the constraints imposed by the JCPOA.  So we look to see what Iran is ready to do or not ready to do.  We remain fully prepared to return to Vienna to continue negotiations, but as I said, this process cannot and will not go on indefinitely.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER AL-SABAH:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Regarding the – your second question, the United States has proven time and time again of its commitment to the security of Kuwait and the region, and I think that throughout the six decades, there are lots of times and aspect that really, the United States showed in action its total commitment.</p>
<p>As well, we have an agreement treaty with the United States for the security and stability of Kuwait, and both of us are members under the leadership of United States in combating Daesh.  In Kuwait, we are hosting lots of allied country in combating Daesh, so this is an ongoing, as well, a commitment – an international commitment, a multilateral commitment in combating terrorism as well.</p>
<p>So no, we are not concerned about this matter.  We think that it is based on the sovereign decision of United – the United States, and the time has showed time and time again the fervent stance of United States with the security and stability of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Thank you so much, ladies and gentlemen.  Thank you so much, and see you soon.  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Bid to Host Expo 2027</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-bid-to-host-expo-2027/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the U.S. Chargé d’affaires in Paris delivered a letter of candidature from Secretary Blinken to the Bureau International des Expositions (BIE) confirming that a proposal from Minnesota USA Expo is the United States’ national bid to host Expo 2027.  The proposed specialized Expo, commonly known as a World’s Fair, will focus on global health and sustainability under the theme “Healthy People, Healthy Planet: Wellness and Well-Being for All,” and will invite the world’s nations to showcase innovative and collaborative solutions to our shared challenges.</p>
<p>The Department of State, in collaboration with the Department of Commerce, will work with the Minnesota organizing committee, U.S. businesses and industry, cultural leaders and organizations, and civil society to develop an Expo that promotes American prosperity, strengthens global alliances, and connects our global community.  The United States looks forward to securing support from member states of the BIE ahead of the expected vote in November 2022 to select the host city for Expo 2027.</p>
<p>For more information on Minnesota USA Expo 2027, visit <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjkuNDM4NzQyNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3Lm1pbm5lc290YXVzYWV4cG8uY29tIn0.uNz7-mUzvC49DO7gNOKEd1D92FueQEoG3amTNNW7Vfg/s/1292923726/br/110126028586-l">www.MinnesotaUSAExpo.com</a> and follow @USAExpo2027 on Twitter.  Hosting Expo 2027 in Minnesota will continue our nation’s long tradition of hosting World’s Fairs and would be the first in the United States since 1984.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the U.S. Chargé d’affaires in Paris delivered a letter of candidature from Secretary Blinken to the Bureau International des Expositions (BIE) confirming that a proposal from Minnesota USA Expo is the United States’ national bid to host Expo 2027.  The proposed specialized Expo, commonly known as a World’s Fair, will focus on global health and sustainability under the theme “Healthy People, Healthy Planet: Wellness and Well-Being for All,” and will invite the world’s nations to showcase innovative and collaborative solutions to our shared challenges.</p>
<p>The Department of State, in collaboration with the Department of Commerce, will work with the Minnesota organizing committee, U.S. businesses and industry, cultural leaders and organizations, and civil society to develop an Expo that promotes American prosperity, strengthens global alliances, and connects our global community.  The United States looks forward to securing support from member states of the BIE ahead of the expected vote in November 2022 to select the host city for Expo 2027.</p>
<p>For more information on Minnesota USA Expo 2027, visit <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjkuNDM4NzQyNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3Lm1pbm5lc290YXVzYWV4cG8uY29tIn0.uNz7-mUzvC49DO7gNOKEd1D92FueQEoG3amTNNW7Vfg/s/1292923726/br/110126028586-l">www.MinnesotaUSAExpo.com</a> and follow @USAExpo2027 on Twitter.  Hosting Expo 2027 in Minnesota will continue our nation’s long tradition of hosting World’s Fairs and would be the first in the United States since 1984.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Kuwait Television</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-kuwait-television/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So Mr. <span class="il">Secretary</span>, if you could please tell us about your impression about your visit in <span class="il">Kuwait</span>?</p>
<p><b><span class="il">SECRETARY</span> <span class="il">BLINKEN</span>:</b>  Well, it’s wonderful to be back in <span class="il">Kuwait</span>.  It’s I think an auspicious time to be here.  It’s the 60th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and <span class="il">Kuwait</span> and, of course, the 30th anniversary of the liberation of <span class="il">Kuwait</span>.  So we’re rightly focused on those very important points in history, but mostly we’re looking forward to building on the very strong partnership that we already have.  And <span class="il">Kuwait</span> is a vital partner to the United States, both on a bilateral basis but also working together for stability in the region, for progress, for peace, bringing countries together.  <span class="il">Kuwait</span>’s played a leading role in ending the Gulf rift and bringing countries together.  We’re grateful that it hosts our own forces here.  And we’re working increasingly in different areas.</p>
<p>But I think what’s also interesting from my conversations here today – and it was a privilege to be able to see the amir, the crown prince, as well as my friend and colleague the Foreign Minster al-Sabah, the prime minister, the leader of the parliament – is we’re also focused on so many issues that affect the wellbeing of our citizens, and working more closely together on health security, on food security, on emerging technologies, and as well as the diplomatic work that we do together.  So we had a long agenda.  I think we had very strong conversations about our cooperation.  And I very much look forward to pursuing those in the months ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So Mr. <span class="il">Secretary</span>, if you could please tell us about your impression about your visit in <span class="il">Kuwait</span>?</p>
<p><b><span class="il">SECRETARY</span> <span class="il">BLINKEN</span>:</b>  Well, it’s wonderful to be back in <span class="il">Kuwait</span>.  It’s I think an auspicious time to be here.  It’s the 60th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and <span class="il">Kuwait</span> and, of course, the 30th anniversary of the liberation of <span class="il">Kuwait</span>.  So we’re rightly focused on those very important points in history, but mostly we’re looking forward to building on the very strong partnership that we already have.  And <span class="il">Kuwait</span> is a vital partner to the United States, both on a bilateral basis but also working together for stability in the region, for progress, for peace, bringing countries together.  <span class="il">Kuwait</span>’s played a leading role in ending the Gulf rift and bringing countries together.  We’re grateful that it hosts our own forces here.  And we’re working increasingly in different areas.</p>
<p>But I think what’s also interesting from my conversations here today – and it was a privilege to be able to see the amir, the crown prince, as well as my friend and colleague the Foreign Minster al-Sabah, the prime minister, the leader of the parliament – is we’re also focused on so many issues that affect the wellbeing of our citizens, and working more closely together on health security, on food security, on emerging technologies, and as well as the diplomatic work that we do together.  So we had a long agenda.  I think we had very strong conversations about our cooperation.  And I very much look forward to pursuing those in the months ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Spanish Foreign Minister Albares</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-spanish-foreign-minister-albares/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Spanish Foreign Minister José Manuel Albares and congratulated him on his new position.  The Secretary thanked Spain for the enduring alliance and deep friendship between our two countries.  Recognizing the strong ties between the United States and Spain, the Secretary and the Foreign Minister committed to further developing the Transatlantic relationship and jointly confronting shared challenges.  The Secretary outlined U.S. support for Cuban citizens’ rights to peaceful assembly, free speech, and democracy.  He advocated for comprehensive negotiations leading to free and fair elections in Venezuela, outlined concerns regarding Nicaragua, and affirmed our focus on promoting safe, orderly, and humane migration. The two ministers also discussed our shared interest in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Spanish Foreign Minister José Manuel Albares and congratulated him on his new position.  The Secretary thanked Spain for the enduring alliance and deep friendship between our two countries.  Recognizing the strong ties between the United States and Spain, the Secretary and the Foreign Minister committed to further developing the Transatlantic relationship and jointly confronting shared challenges.  The Secretary outlined U.S. support for Cuban citizens’ rights to peaceful assembly, free speech, and democracy.  He advocated for comprehensive negotiations leading to free and fair elections in Venezuela, outlined concerns regarding Nicaragua, and affirmed our focus on promoting safe, orderly, and humane migration. The two ministers also discussed our shared interest in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Saad Al-Enezi of Sky News Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-saad-al-enezi-of-sky-news-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 17:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  I would like to thank Mr. Antony Blinken, U.S. Secretary of State, and thank you for joining us this brief interview.  Hopefully it will shed a light on some major issues.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Pleasure to be with you.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  First, let’s talk about – start with Tunisia.  It’s like, been political development and it’s – things are moving in different directions.  What’s your take on this?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, Tunisia’s been a strong, remarkable example of democracy in recent years, and I think it sends a strong message to see a strong democracy in Tunisia that represents the will and the interests of the people.  So we’ve been concerned by the steps taken to move out of the constitutional order, and that’s a real concern.  I spoke to the president just a few days ago to express those concerns.  We know the devastation that’s occurred in Tunisia through COVID-19, the economy.  We know that the government needs to be responsive to those challenges and to those problems.  But we – we’re urging our friends in Tunisia to move forward in a way that’s consistent with the constitution, that gets back on the democratic path, follows the democratic order, and including unfreezing the parliament and, of course, establishing a government.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.  Another very important issue for at least people in the Gulf area is the nuclear Iraqi – I mean, Iranian nuclear deal.  You just talked in the press conference about diplomacy will not be forever.  What are other options if these talks fail?  I mean, is the military option on the table?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals other than to say that we are determined that Iran not acquire a nuclear weapon.  And that has been and remains resolutely our policy.  We believe that it’s in our interest and Iran’s interest to come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the JCPOA.  But that really depends on Iran making the decision to do so.  It’s not yet made that decision.  Meanwhile, it continues to advance its nuclear program in very dangerous ways, and at some point those advances will be such that returning to compliance with the nuclear agreement won’t solve the problem.  So that’s why I say this can’t go on indefinitely.</p>
<p class="p1">Meanwhile, of course, we’ve seen protests in Iran that started outside of Tehran; they’ve now come to Tehran.  In the first instance they were really about people’s deep frustration with the failure of government to meet their basic needs, including water, mismanagement of the economy.  And now we’ve seen them move to people expressing their larger aspirations for freedom and for a government that respects them and respects their rights.  And, of course, we stand with the people of Iran in the desire to have their voices heard, and we urge – strongly urge the government not to use violence and repression to silence those voices.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do you think if the talks succeed, and Iran will actually agree to not only the nuclear deal but also the broader picture of the missile problem and the other issues of its behavior in the area, do you think this would open the door, and do you envision seeing normal relation with Iran or even – in the foreseeable future, or maybe Iran become an ally in distant future?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we’re focused right now on determining whether Iran is willing to come back into compliance with the nuclear deal, and doing what the nuclear deal did, which is to put its nuclear program in a box and to remove the danger that Iran would be in a position to acquire a nuclear weapon very, very quickly.</p>
<p class="p1">At the same time, we’re determined to address the other challenges posed by Iran to us and to other countries in the region, including its destabilizing actions, its support for proxies and other militia that are engaged in violent action, its support for terrorism.  And that requires Iran’s engagement as well.</p>
<p class="p1">So our hope would be that we can return to the nuclear agreement and use that as a foundation for engaging Iran on these other issues where its actions are of real concern to us and to partners in the region.  Beyond that, it’s very hard to imagine the future.  We need to be focused on what we can do in the time ahead.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  When people in the region now, they are – some people or some allies maybe, they’re concerned about what they see.  I mean, they see – some people are interpreting what’s happening as U.S. pulling away, they’re questioning the commitment of the U.S. to their security, especially after withdrawing from Afghanistan in the manner it’s happened, and also the pact with Iraq which is rebranding the – your operation to an advisory position or an advisory phase and then reducing some of the defensive assets here in the Gulf.  People are a bit worried, even some of them might say they’re not, but that the United States is moving now to confront China, maybe at their own security – at the expense it.  What do – how do you answer such concerns?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, I think you have to look at each situation in its own right, which I’ll come to in a second.  But I also think it’s a mistake to equate engagement to the extent of our military presence in any one place.  We remain and we will remain very much present in the region and committed to the defense of our allies and partners.  That’s not going to change.  But my definition of engagement is much broader than the number of forces we may have in any one place.  It’s our economic engagement, our diplomatic engagement, our political engagement, and that is only increasing, including here in the Middle East.  And deepening, strengthening partnerships with countries throughout the region, to include Kuwait where I am today, is very much part of the agenda.</p>
<p class="p1">Now, the individual cases, it’s important to look at them, as I say, in their own right.  Afghanistan – we – why did we go to Afghanistan in the first place?  It was because we were attacked on 9/11.  We went there to bring to justice those who attacked us and to try to make sure that that could not happen again from Afghanistan soil.  And we largely succeeded in achieving those objectives.  Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and al-Qaida as a threat from Afghanistan to us and to others has been vastly diminished.  And we’ll keep an eye on things to make sure it doesn’t reemerge, and if it does, we would take action to deal with that.</p>
<p class="p1">And, of course, again, it’s 20 years later, $1 trillion.  Even as we are removing our forces, we’re remaining very much engaged in Afghanistan, supporting Afghanistan economically, development assistance, humanitarian assistance, support for its security forces, and diplomatic engagement to try to bring the parties to the table – the Taliban, the Afghan Government – to negotiate an end to the conflict.  So I think that’s the story on Afghanistan.</p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to Iraq, the success of Iraqi security forces is such that we are able to transition the mission that we have in Iraq so that our focus there is on supporting those forces with training and advice to deal with Daesh and any prospect that might reemerge.  Meanwhile, we have a very broad relationship with Iraq economically, diplomatically, politically.  We just had a Strategic Dialogue in Washington with senior Iraqi leadership that is evidence of that partnership.  So again, I think you have to be very careful with equating our engagement in any particular place just by looking at the numbers of American forces there.  I think we’re much more effective when that engagement is broad-based across the board, and on that basis, our engagement has only deepened.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>The last question, Mr. Secretary.  China is coming with a – very strongly in this area with the Silk Road initiative.  Do you have a competing vision from the U.S. to compete now with China for the future in the next decade and other decades?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, a few things are important here.  First, this is not a question of having to choose between China and the United States.  We know that people have relationships, economic relationships with a variety of countries, including China, and that includes investments from China.  But I think what’s very important is this:  We all have to look very carefully at the investments that are being made.  First, if they’re in sensitive areas involving sensitive technologies, that’s something people have to look at very carefully.  Unfortunately, when it comes to China, there’s really no difference between its so-called private companies and the state.  The state can order the companies to do anything at any time.  And we know that when it comes to human rights, when it comes to privacy, when it comes to protecting intellectual property, China has a different view of those issues than we do and others do.  So there’s that.</p>
<p class="p1">Second, in terms of investments, and as countries receive them and are in – doing business, they have to look very carefully at what that might involve.  And if it involves, for example, taking on a tremendous amount of debt that you can’t repay, if it involves workers coming in from another country to do the work – in this case, China – as opposed to having local workers do it, if it involves corruption, if it involves a lack of transparency, if it involves building things to bad standards without care for the environment, well, all of those things have to be factored in.  We do, I think, have an alternative vision, and that is to make investments that are, as we would say, a race to the top, not a race to the bottom, with a focus on making sure that countries don’t take on debt that they can’t manage, with a focus on the rights of workers, being attentive to the environment, making sure that we’re building things to high standards.  So, people can decide and make a choice about what makes the most sense for them.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Well, thank you very much.  I really appreciate it.  Would love to have more time with you, but our time is out.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Appreciate you being with us.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  I would like to thank Mr. Antony Blinken, U.S. Secretary of State, and thank you for joining us this brief interview.  Hopefully it will shed a light on some major issues.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Pleasure to be with you.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  First, let’s talk about – start with Tunisia.  It’s like, been political development and it’s – things are moving in different directions.  What’s your take on this?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, Tunisia’s been a strong, remarkable example of democracy in recent years, and I think it sends a strong message to see a strong democracy in Tunisia that represents the will and the interests of the people.  So we’ve been concerned by the steps taken to move out of the constitutional order, and that’s a real concern.  I spoke to the president just a few days ago to express those concerns.  We know the devastation that’s occurred in Tunisia through COVID-19, the economy.  We know that the government needs to be responsive to those challenges and to those problems.  But we – we’re urging our friends in Tunisia to move forward in a way that’s consistent with the constitution, that gets back on the democratic path, follows the democratic order, and including unfreezing the parliament and, of course, establishing a government.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.  Another very important issue for at least people in the Gulf area is the nuclear Iraqi – I mean, Iranian nuclear deal.  You just talked in the press conference about diplomacy will not be forever.  What are other options if these talks fail?  I mean, is the military option on the table?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals other than to say that we are determined that Iran not acquire a nuclear weapon.  And that has been and remains resolutely our policy.  We believe that it’s in our interest and Iran’s interest to come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the JCPOA.  But that really depends on Iran making the decision to do so.  It’s not yet made that decision.  Meanwhile, it continues to advance its nuclear program in very dangerous ways, and at some point those advances will be such that returning to compliance with the nuclear agreement won’t solve the problem.  So that’s why I say this can’t go on indefinitely.</p>
<p class="p1">Meanwhile, of course, we’ve seen protests in Iran that started outside of Tehran; they’ve now come to Tehran.  In the first instance they were really about people’s deep frustration with the failure of government to meet their basic needs, including water, mismanagement of the economy.  And now we’ve seen them move to people expressing their larger aspirations for freedom and for a government that respects them and respects their rights.  And, of course, we stand with the people of Iran in the desire to have their voices heard, and we urge – strongly urge the government not to use violence and repression to silence those voices.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do you think if the talks succeed, and Iran will actually agree to not only the nuclear deal but also the broader picture of the missile problem and the other issues of its behavior in the area, do you think this would open the door, and do you envision seeing normal relation with Iran or even – in the foreseeable future, or maybe Iran become an ally in distant future?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we’re focused right now on determining whether Iran is willing to come back into compliance with the nuclear deal, and doing what the nuclear deal did, which is to put its nuclear program in a box and to remove the danger that Iran would be in a position to acquire a nuclear weapon very, very quickly.</p>
<p class="p1">At the same time, we’re determined to address the other challenges posed by Iran to us and to other countries in the region, including its destabilizing actions, its support for proxies and other militia that are engaged in violent action, its support for terrorism.  And that requires Iran’s engagement as well.</p>
<p class="p1">So our hope would be that we can return to the nuclear agreement and use that as a foundation for engaging Iran on these other issues where its actions are of real concern to us and to partners in the region.  Beyond that, it’s very hard to imagine the future.  We need to be focused on what we can do in the time ahead.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  When people in the region now, they are – some people or some allies maybe, they’re concerned about what they see.  I mean, they see – some people are interpreting what’s happening as U.S. pulling away, they’re questioning the commitment of the U.S. to their security, especially after withdrawing from Afghanistan in the manner it’s happened, and also the pact with Iraq which is rebranding the – your operation to an advisory position or an advisory phase and then reducing some of the defensive assets here in the Gulf.  People are a bit worried, even some of them might say they’re not, but that the United States is moving now to confront China, maybe at their own security – at the expense it.  What do – how do you answer such concerns?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, I think you have to look at each situation in its own right, which I’ll come to in a second.  But I also think it’s a mistake to equate engagement to the extent of our military presence in any one place.  We remain and we will remain very much present in the region and committed to the defense of our allies and partners.  That’s not going to change.  But my definition of engagement is much broader than the number of forces we may have in any one place.  It’s our economic engagement, our diplomatic engagement, our political engagement, and that is only increasing, including here in the Middle East.  And deepening, strengthening partnerships with countries throughout the region, to include Kuwait where I am today, is very much part of the agenda.</p>
<p class="p1">Now, the individual cases, it’s important to look at them, as I say, in their own right.  Afghanistan – we – why did we go to Afghanistan in the first place?  It was because we were attacked on 9/11.  We went there to bring to justice those who attacked us and to try to make sure that that could not happen again from Afghanistan soil.  And we largely succeeded in achieving those objectives.  Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and al-Qaida as a threat from Afghanistan to us and to others has been vastly diminished.  And we’ll keep an eye on things to make sure it doesn’t reemerge, and if it does, we would take action to deal with that.</p>
<p class="p1">And, of course, again, it’s 20 years later, $1 trillion.  Even as we are removing our forces, we’re remaining very much engaged in Afghanistan, supporting Afghanistan economically, development assistance, humanitarian assistance, support for its security forces, and diplomatic engagement to try to bring the parties to the table – the Taliban, the Afghan Government – to negotiate an end to the conflict.  So I think that’s the story on Afghanistan.</p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to Iraq, the success of Iraqi security forces is such that we are able to transition the mission that we have in Iraq so that our focus there is on supporting those forces with training and advice to deal with Daesh and any prospect that might reemerge.  Meanwhile, we have a very broad relationship with Iraq economically, diplomatically, politically.  We just had a Strategic Dialogue in Washington with senior Iraqi leadership that is evidence of that partnership.  So again, I think you have to be very careful with equating our engagement in any particular place just by looking at the numbers of American forces there.  I think we’re much more effective when that engagement is broad-based across the board, and on that basis, our engagement has only deepened.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>The last question, Mr. Secretary.  China is coming with a – very strongly in this area with the Silk Road initiative.  Do you have a competing vision from the U.S. to compete now with China for the future in the next decade and other decades?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, a few things are important here.  First, this is not a question of having to choose between China and the United States.  We know that people have relationships, economic relationships with a variety of countries, including China, and that includes investments from China.  But I think what’s very important is this:  We all have to look very carefully at the investments that are being made.  First, if they’re in sensitive areas involving sensitive technologies, that’s something people have to look at very carefully.  Unfortunately, when it comes to China, there’s really no difference between its so-called private companies and the state.  The state can order the companies to do anything at any time.  And we know that when it comes to human rights, when it comes to privacy, when it comes to protecting intellectual property, China has a different view of those issues than we do and others do.  So there’s that.</p>
<p class="p1">Second, in terms of investments, and as countries receive them and are in – doing business, they have to look very carefully at what that might involve.  And if it involves, for example, taking on a tremendous amount of debt that you can’t repay, if it involves workers coming in from another country to do the work – in this case, China – as opposed to having local workers do it, if it involves corruption, if it involves a lack of transparency, if it involves building things to bad standards without care for the environment, well, all of those things have to be factored in.  We do, I think, have an alternative vision, and that is to make investments that are, as we would say, a race to the top, not a race to the bottom, with a focus on making sure that countries don’t take on debt that they can’t manage, with a focus on the rights of workers, being attentive to the environment, making sure that we’re building things to high standards.  So, people can decide and make a choice about what makes the most sense for them.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Well, thank you very much.  I really appreciate it.  Would love to have more time with you, but our time is out.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Appreciate you being with us.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
