<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 23:54:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence’s (NSCAI) Global Emerging Technology Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-national-security-commission-on-artificial-intelligences-nscai-global-emerging-technology-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 23:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Mayflower Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you all very, very much.  It is actually wonderful to be in a room with real people – (laughter) – with friends, with colleagues and without masks too.  So in and of itself, that’s a very positive thing.</p>
<p>But there is a lot to be positive about today, and it starts with the remarkable work of the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence, especially the work of my friend Eric Schmidt, another friend and close colleague Bob Work, who I haven’t seen yet but hopefully is here, and – Bob, there you are – and the executive director Ylli Bajraktari.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for this remarkable effort.  I am in your debt, and quite frankly the country is going to be in your debt for the work that you’ve done.  I’m going to put this down.</p>
<p>And I really want to thank the members of Congress who have come together across party lines to launch this enterprise at what is a pivotal moment for our country, and I think for the world at large.</p>
<p>Today, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Defense, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Commerce, the National Security Advisor, the director of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy.</p>
<p>In and of itself, that is testament to how seriously the administration takes these issues.  And again, that’s in no small part due to the work of this commission.</p>
<p>You have helped clarify the links among AI, the broader set of emerging technologies, strategic competition, and our national security and prosperity.</p>
<p>And you have made crystal clear that our country needs to play catch-up and to do it fast.  And not just our country.  Countries around the world.  And I’ll come to that.</p>
<p>We’re moving quickly, because we want to ensure that as AI and related technologies transform how we live, how we work, how we compete, how we defend ourselves, that we’re staying ahead of change, indeed that we are shaping change and, critically, making sure it delivers for our people.</p>
<p>My colleagues, I think, have very capably covered the administration’s work on these issues as it relates to our domestic renewal, our economy, and our defense.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do today is to focus on the State Department’s distinct role, because diplomacy will be critical.</p>
<p>Working with partners and allies to develop and deploy technology is going to help us tackle the most urgent challenges we face, from pandemics to the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Diplomacy will also be essential to mitigating risks, from preventing cyber attacks that target our businesses, to regulating technology that threatens our privacy, to defending our democratic values and way of life.</p>
<p>And let me just pause for a second on that last point, because I think it deserves emphasis.  It’s fundamentally what’s at stake here.</p>
<p>More than anything else, our task is to put forth and carry out a compelling vision for how to use technology in a way that serves our people, protects our interests and upholds our democratic values.  It’s not enough to highlight the horrors of techno-authoritarianism, to point to what countries like China and Russia are doing, and say that it’s wrong and dangerous, even as it is.  We’ve also got to make the positive case for our own approach, and then we’ve got to deliver.  That is the challenge before us.</p>
<p>We need the United States and we need its partners to remain the world’s innovative leaders and standard setters, to ensure that universal rights and democratic values remain at the center of all the innovation that’s to come, and that it delivers real benefits in people’s lives.  That fundamentally is the test that we have to pass, and it’s a test I think you’ve heard President Biden allude to.</p>
<p>In short, democracies have to pass the tech test together.  And diplomacy, I believe, has a big role to play in that.</p>
<p>Now, any time you hear someone from the State Department talking, we’re likely to throw in pillars and frameworks and tranches, so I can’t be any different today.  We have to have our pillars, so let me walk you through six of them – (laughter) – that cover the approach to these issues.  I know you’d be disappointed without it.</p>
<p>The first is reducing the national security risks posed by malicious cyber activities and emerging technologies.</p>
<p>This is the most basic thing our diplomacy has to do: protect our people, protect our networks, prevent conflict, and establish standards of responsible conduct in cyberspace.</p>
<p>Already, we’ve brought countries together around an approach that recognizes international law to make it clear that countries are governed in cyberspace just like they are offline and that defines norms that apply not only in wartime but in peacetime too, because we’re now dealing with significant cyber incidents outside the context of war.</p>
<p>We’ve also called for practical confidence-building measures; for example, steps as simple as establishing points of contact, so that in the event of a major cyber incident we actually know who to call.  Under American leadership, UN member-states have come together repeatedly to reaffirm this basic framework.</p>
<p>Now we’re working to bring allies and partners along to respond collectively when others engage in malicious cyber activity.  That’s what happened after the SolarWinds intrusion.  We attributed it to Russia; 22 countries, the European Union, NATO quickly supported that conclusion.  And that’s important, because when we speak with one voice, we can more effectively deter future bad acts.</p>
<p>Last month, as some of you will have noted, at the NATO summit, NATO reaffirmed that a cyber attack could trigger Article V – “an attack on one is an attack on all” – and that’s an important step too in deterring those attacks and protecting our national security in the cyber age.</p>
<p>We’re also treating ransomware not only as a law enforcement issue but also as a national security issue.  Ransomware and other cyber crimes affect all of us – our businesses, local governments; our most critical infrastructure, from power grids to hospitals.  As you know, one in four Americans has been the victim of a cyber crime, at a cost of more than $4 billion every single year.  That’s a direct threat to the safety, to the well-being of our people, and so it’s at the top of our diplomatic agenda.</p>
<p>And it’s also why we’re elevating ransomware in our engagements with Russia.  Our message is clear:  Countries that harbor cyber criminals have a responsibility to take action.  If they don’t, we will.  We’re strengthening our diplomatic and foreign assistance tools to fight transnational cyber criminals, and we’re working to expand membership in the global cyber crime treaty known as the Budapest Convention.</p>
<p>We’ll launch similar efforts on AI and other emerging technologies.  If they’re going to be used as part of our national defense, we want the world to have a shared understanding of how to do that responsibly, in the same way that we’ve hammered out rules for how to use conventional and nuclear weapons.  That’s how we reduce the risk of proliferation.  It’s how we prevent escalation or unintended incidents.</p>
<p>The second pillar is ensuring that our leadership in the fierce strategic technology competition that’s now underway not only continues but grows and strengthens.</p>
<p>We know China is determined to become the world’s technology leader.  And they have a well-resourced and comprehensive plan to achieve those ambitions.</p>
<p>We must preserve our competitive and comparative advantages.</p>
<p>That means building resilient, diverse, and secure supply chains for critical technologies.  Our proposed investments in semiconductor manufacturing here at home is an important part of that.  And again, I really want to underscore the very important work that was done on a bipartisan basis in Congress to help allow us to do that.</p>
<p>But I think you know this too:  We can’t onshore everything.  We don’t need to.  We’ll work with partners to “friend-shore” and “near-shore” our supply chains, and that will make all of us more resilient.</p>
<p>We’ll protect information communications technologies.  The Biden-Harris administration is committed to 5G security.  And we’re promoting the use of trusted and diverse vendors, including American companies, and advocating in multilateral settings for high standards for security and for trust.</p>
<p>We’re taking a fresh look at tools like export controls, investment screening, visa screening, to make sure our strategic competitors are not exploiting our own innovative ecosystems to gain military or national security advantage.</p>
<p>Today we also know that it’s harder to ensure that American innovations are used for commercial purposes only.  Countries like China don’t differentiate between civilian and military in the same way, and emerging technologies, including AI applications, blur that line too.  So we’ve got to think differently about how to protect our innovation and industries against that kind of misuse.</p>
<p>And of course, we need to do this at the same time that we’re growing our talent pipelines.  Perhaps more than any other factor, having the right people will determine whether we win the competition for the future.  We’ve got to recruit, we’ve got to retain the top talent, including talent from around the world, so that the best and the brightest study here, stay here, feel welcome here.</p>
<p>The third pillar: defending an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet.</p>
<p>We’ve been fighting for this vision of the internet for a long, long time.  Many of you in this room have been engaged in that effort.  These principles created the conditions that allowed the internet to grow into the transformative force that it’s become: an extraordinary resource for learning, for connection, for economic growth.</p>
<p>But the hard truth is that the internet is also growing more closed, more insecure, more fractured every single day.</p>
<p>We see country after country putting up firewalls, controlling speech, targeting activists, shutting down the internet to squelch dissent.  And while authoritarian regimes deny access to their networks, they actively reach into others and into ours, taking advantage and meddling in more open societies.  It’s no wonder that some countries are asking whether the principles around which we’ve organized the internet are still relevant, are still tenable.</p>
<p>In many ways, we are at an inflection point, some would say even a tipping point.  And our choice is between giving up on our vision for the internet or stepping up the fight.  We will step up the fight.</p>
<p>We’ll defend the principles of an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet across the full spectrum of our engagement – from trade agreements to governance to hardware.  We’ll use our diplomacy to unite governments and the private sector more firmly behind these efforts.  The work we do today will determine what the internet looks like just a few years from now.  That’s a responsibility we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>The fourth pillar I want to talk about is setting technical standards and creating norms for emerging technologies.</p>
<p>Technical standards help ensure quality, protect consumer health and safety, facilitate global interoperability.  They also help overcome trade barriers and expand market access.</p>
<p>We believe in a transparent, consensus-based, and private sector-led approach to developing standards for emerging technologies.  That’s how we’ll arrive at standards that are technologically sound, have earned people’s trust, reflect our values, and help American companies compete on a level playing field.</p>
<p>And norms, of course, are standards of another kind.  We’ll work with partners to ensure that technologies are developed and deployed in ethical ways that respect people’s rights.</p>
<p>That’s what we did at the UN International Telecommunications Union just a few months ago.  Some countries proposed norms that would allow the use, for example, of facial recognition technology in ways that could threaten human rights.  We brought governments and businesses together to stop it.</p>
<p>Whenever rules and norms that affect American lives are being debated and decided, American diplomats won’t be just – won’t just be in the room; we will be leading the charge.</p>
<p>The fifth pillar is this:  It’s making technology work for democracy.</p>
<p>Some of the leading threats to democracies today are playing out, as you all know, in cyberspace. We have to be leading the world’s efforts, and particularly the world’s democracies, in responding to those threats – fighting back against disinformation, standing up for internet freedom, reducing the misuse of surveillance technology.</p>
<p>We’ve got to make sure that our companies are not inadvertently fueling authoritarian practices, whether it’s in China or anywhere else.</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve released “surveillance due diligence guidance” to try to help American companies prevent their products from being misused.</p>
<p>Technology is also disrupting democracies from within – challenging the ways we think about privacy, free speech, the power of government, and corporations.  President Biden will take on these issues here at home.  For example, his new executive order on promoting competition in the U.S. economy asks the FTC to establish rules for companies on surveillance and how to treat personal data.</p>
<p>But democracies have to work together on these issues as well.  We need to close the gaps in regulatory and legal frameworks so that democracies can collaborate more easily on issues like privacy, content moderation, data sharing, and on digital trade.</p>
<p>You all know very well these are incredibly complicated issues.  The world’s democracies are not all on the same page on every single one of them.  But at heart we do share the same principles, and I have confidence that we can work together through the differences that we have.  I can tell you this:  It is a diplomatic priority for the United States to do that.</p>
<p>So is advancing trustworthy AI.  We need be able to reassure our citizens that AI is secure, that it does not have bias embedded in it, that it can be used safely.  And here, we’re grateful for a lot of good work happening in some critical organizations, including at the OECD and the Global Partnership on AI.  This is very important, too.</p>
<p>We’re interested in increasing access to shared public data sets for AI training and testing, while still preserving privacy – especially in sectors like health, climate, and energy, where AI could create transformational breakthroughs.</p>
<p>Finally, the sixth pillar is promoting cooperation.</p>
<p>Yes, our work in this space is about protecting ourselves and our allies from threats.  And yes, it’s about competition.  But more than anything, we want and we need to bring a spirit of cooperation to tech diplomacy.  Because the bottom-line truth is this:  The United States cannot deliver on these pillars on our own.  We need partners.</p>
<p>And this may be in some ways, I think, the most fundamental imperative of our time.  And it, of course, extends beyond technology.  If you think about virtually any challenge that we have to face as a country, as a society, challenges that have a direct impact on the lives of our citizens, whether it’s dealing with this pandemic, whether it’s climate change, whether it is emerging technologies, we know that not a single one can be fully and effectively addressed by any one country acting alone, even the United States.  Now, more than ever before in my lifetime, there is an imperative for cooperation.</p>
<p>So we are building technology into nearly all of our diplomatic engagements – tech by tech, issue by issue, bilaterally, multilaterally, always looking to assemble the right configurations of allies and partners to get things done.</p>
<p>And as we see it, this agenda has to start with our democratic partners.</p>
<p>And I think we’ve already gotten some good work under our belts.  We’ve been developing shared principles at the G7.  I think you saw some of that emerge just a few weeks ago with President Biden.  We’ve created a new U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council that’s going to be an important vehicle for advancing this agenda.  We’re starting a new science and technology partnership with the UK.  We’re launching cooperative agreements with Korea and Japan on emerging technologies.  We created a Critical and Emerging Tech Working Group with the Quad countries – with Japan, Australia, India.  We’re working with G7 partners through Build Back Better World to mobilize private capital and government finance to build digital infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries.</p>
<p>Our goal is strong networks – plural – of countries, companies, universities connected by shared values and a shared commitment to design and deploy technology for the benefit of all people, to strengthen open and interoperable systems, to encourage freedom of thought and expression, which are the heart of innovation, to defend each other against those who are intent on taking technologies that could be used for good and using them for harm.</p>
<p>To deliver on all of this, we need a State Department and a diplomatic corps that treats cyber and technology like the central issues that they are.</p>
<p>I’ve asked the two deputy secretaries of state, Wendy Sherman and Brian McKeon, to take the lead on delivering recommendations for how to elevate and institutionalize cyber and tech diplomacy across the department.  And I am committed to driving this forward in full partnership with Congress.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure the State Department is organized for the task at hand because the issues before us really bear little relationship to borders on a map or the current organizational chart of the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll build more expertise among our workforce in science, in technology, in innovation.  And here’s a request:  Help us spread the word.  We’re looking for outstanding people, for talent who want to make the leap to government, spend some time in government.  Now is a great time to put those skills to use, leveraging tech for the good of our country and for the good of the world.</p>
<p>In the coming weeks, the State Department will be releasing our first ever data strategy to help us use data more effectively and more creatively for diplomacy.  If Netflix can predict what TV show my wife and I might choose to watch next, I think data can also help us and help the department predict maybe the next civil conflict, the next famine, the next economic crisis, and how we can respond more effectively.</p>
<p>I intend to leave my successor at the State Department with strong capabilities in cyber and tech diplomacy, with clear leadership, lines of authority, organizational homes, and talent at every level.  We need to become much better at anticipating the foreign policy implications of the next wave of innovation, and the wave after that.  I want to shape the strategic tech landscape, not just react to it.</p>
<p>And at the same time, we have to find ways to put tech and innovation to the task of solving the concrete problems that we’re facing, whether that’s verifying an arms control agreement or preventing the next pandemic.  I’ve been in and out of government for the better part of 25 years, and the last time I was serving with Bob and others, we’d be in that Situation Room in the White House looking at one of the many challenges that would somehow wind up in our inbox, and I think it became clearer and clearer to all of us that for virtually every single one, there was some technological component to the solution.  Part of the problem is that many of us who are engaged in these issues are not brought up on these disciplines.  Bob is an exception to that, but many of us come from the humanities, from law.  It’s not our first knowledge.  It’s not our first instinct.</p>
<p>And I got to the point when I had the responsibility of chairing some of these meetings to thinking that I needed scientists and technologists in the room just to tell me whether I needed scientists and technologists in the room – (laughter) – to help identify the problems and help identify some of the solutions.  And I became more and more convinced that virtually everything on our agenda has some tech or science or innovative component to the solution.  So we need to do a better job bringing that knowledge, that expertise, that focus into the department and to everything we do.</p>
<p>We started to do that a few years ago when I was last here.  We actually set up our first-ever office in Silicon Valley.  Some of the other agencies of government were ahead of us.  We developed partnerships with leading institutions.  One of my very strong and positive memories was spending some time out at Stanford, we had started working with a class called Hacking for Diplomacy where 20 bureaus of the State Department sent this class problems that we were trying to solve.  And these remarkable students over the course of a semester or even a year worked to solve them.  And bringing that approach, bringing that perspective brought forward answers that I don’t think we would have come to doing it on our own in Washington.  So we need to make this shift too, and the changes we’re making at State I think will help us to do that.</p>
<p>If there’s one thing I want to leave you with today, it’s this:  For the Biden-Harris administration, this is not a standalone diplomatic issue.  It’s not just another line of effort.  We’re weaving cyber and technology diplomacy into our work across the board.  Nothing is more consequential to our competitiveness, to our security, and ultimately, to our democracy.</p>
<p>We’re in the early days of this endeavor.  All of us in the national security community have a tremendous amount to learn and even more to do.  We intend to secure American leadership.  We intend to get results for the American people.  And as we do, we will build upon the work of this commission and continue to work in partnership with you.</p>
<p>Thank you so much for listening.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Mayflower Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you all very, very much.  It is actually wonderful to be in a room with real people – (laughter) – with friends, with colleagues and without masks too.  So in and of itself, that’s a very positive thing.</p>
<p>But there is a lot to be positive about today, and it starts with the remarkable work of the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence, especially the work of my friend Eric Schmidt, another friend and close colleague Bob Work, who I haven’t seen yet but hopefully is here, and – Bob, there you are – and the executive director Ylli Bajraktari.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for this remarkable effort.  I am in your debt, and quite frankly the country is going to be in your debt for the work that you’ve done.  I’m going to put this down.</p>
<p>And I really want to thank the members of Congress who have come together across party lines to launch this enterprise at what is a pivotal moment for our country, and I think for the world at large.</p>
<p>Today, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Defense, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Commerce, the National Security Advisor, the director of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy.</p>
<p>In and of itself, that is testament to how seriously the administration takes these issues.  And again, that’s in no small part due to the work of this commission.</p>
<p>You have helped clarify the links among AI, the broader set of emerging technologies, strategic competition, and our national security and prosperity.</p>
<p>And you have made crystal clear that our country needs to play catch-up and to do it fast.  And not just our country.  Countries around the world.  And I’ll come to that.</p>
<p>We’re moving quickly, because we want to ensure that as AI and related technologies transform how we live, how we work, how we compete, how we defend ourselves, that we’re staying ahead of change, indeed that we are shaping change and, critically, making sure it delivers for our people.</p>
<p>My colleagues, I think, have very capably covered the administration’s work on these issues as it relates to our domestic renewal, our economy, and our defense.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do today is to focus on the State Department’s distinct role, because diplomacy will be critical.</p>
<p>Working with partners and allies to develop and deploy technology is going to help us tackle the most urgent challenges we face, from pandemics to the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Diplomacy will also be essential to mitigating risks, from preventing cyber attacks that target our businesses, to regulating technology that threatens our privacy, to defending our democratic values and way of life.</p>
<p>And let me just pause for a second on that last point, because I think it deserves emphasis.  It’s fundamentally what’s at stake here.</p>
<p>More than anything else, our task is to put forth and carry out a compelling vision for how to use technology in a way that serves our people, protects our interests and upholds our democratic values.  It’s not enough to highlight the horrors of techno-authoritarianism, to point to what countries like China and Russia are doing, and say that it’s wrong and dangerous, even as it is.  We’ve also got to make the positive case for our own approach, and then we’ve got to deliver.  That is the challenge before us.</p>
<p>We need the United States and we need its partners to remain the world’s innovative leaders and standard setters, to ensure that universal rights and democratic values remain at the center of all the innovation that’s to come, and that it delivers real benefits in people’s lives.  That fundamentally is the test that we have to pass, and it’s a test I think you’ve heard President Biden allude to.</p>
<p>In short, democracies have to pass the tech test together.  And diplomacy, I believe, has a big role to play in that.</p>
<p>Now, any time you hear someone from the State Department talking, we’re likely to throw in pillars and frameworks and tranches, so I can’t be any different today.  We have to have our pillars, so let me walk you through six of them – (laughter) – that cover the approach to these issues.  I know you’d be disappointed without it.</p>
<p>The first is reducing the national security risks posed by malicious cyber activities and emerging technologies.</p>
<p>This is the most basic thing our diplomacy has to do: protect our people, protect our networks, prevent conflict, and establish standards of responsible conduct in cyberspace.</p>
<p>Already, we’ve brought countries together around an approach that recognizes international law to make it clear that countries are governed in cyberspace just like they are offline and that defines norms that apply not only in wartime but in peacetime too, because we’re now dealing with significant cyber incidents outside the context of war.</p>
<p>We’ve also called for practical confidence-building measures; for example, steps as simple as establishing points of contact, so that in the event of a major cyber incident we actually know who to call.  Under American leadership, UN member-states have come together repeatedly to reaffirm this basic framework.</p>
<p>Now we’re working to bring allies and partners along to respond collectively when others engage in malicious cyber activity.  That’s what happened after the SolarWinds intrusion.  We attributed it to Russia; 22 countries, the European Union, NATO quickly supported that conclusion.  And that’s important, because when we speak with one voice, we can more effectively deter future bad acts.</p>
<p>Last month, as some of you will have noted, at the NATO summit, NATO reaffirmed that a cyber attack could trigger Article V – “an attack on one is an attack on all” – and that’s an important step too in deterring those attacks and protecting our national security in the cyber age.</p>
<p>We’re also treating ransomware not only as a law enforcement issue but also as a national security issue.  Ransomware and other cyber crimes affect all of us – our businesses, local governments; our most critical infrastructure, from power grids to hospitals.  As you know, one in four Americans has been the victim of a cyber crime, at a cost of more than $4 billion every single year.  That’s a direct threat to the safety, to the well-being of our people, and so it’s at the top of our diplomatic agenda.</p>
<p>And it’s also why we’re elevating ransomware in our engagements with Russia.  Our message is clear:  Countries that harbor cyber criminals have a responsibility to take action.  If they don’t, we will.  We’re strengthening our diplomatic and foreign assistance tools to fight transnational cyber criminals, and we’re working to expand membership in the global cyber crime treaty known as the Budapest Convention.</p>
<p>We’ll launch similar efforts on AI and other emerging technologies.  If they’re going to be used as part of our national defense, we want the world to have a shared understanding of how to do that responsibly, in the same way that we’ve hammered out rules for how to use conventional and nuclear weapons.  That’s how we reduce the risk of proliferation.  It’s how we prevent escalation or unintended incidents.</p>
<p>The second pillar is ensuring that our leadership in the fierce strategic technology competition that’s now underway not only continues but grows and strengthens.</p>
<p>We know China is determined to become the world’s technology leader.  And they have a well-resourced and comprehensive plan to achieve those ambitions.</p>
<p>We must preserve our competitive and comparative advantages.</p>
<p>That means building resilient, diverse, and secure supply chains for critical technologies.  Our proposed investments in semiconductor manufacturing here at home is an important part of that.  And again, I really want to underscore the very important work that was done on a bipartisan basis in Congress to help allow us to do that.</p>
<p>But I think you know this too:  We can’t onshore everything.  We don’t need to.  We’ll work with partners to “friend-shore” and “near-shore” our supply chains, and that will make all of us more resilient.</p>
<p>We’ll protect information communications technologies.  The Biden-Harris administration is committed to 5G security.  And we’re promoting the use of trusted and diverse vendors, including American companies, and advocating in multilateral settings for high standards for security and for trust.</p>
<p>We’re taking a fresh look at tools like export controls, investment screening, visa screening, to make sure our strategic competitors are not exploiting our own innovative ecosystems to gain military or national security advantage.</p>
<p>Today we also know that it’s harder to ensure that American innovations are used for commercial purposes only.  Countries like China don’t differentiate between civilian and military in the same way, and emerging technologies, including AI applications, blur that line too.  So we’ve got to think differently about how to protect our innovation and industries against that kind of misuse.</p>
<p>And of course, we need to do this at the same time that we’re growing our talent pipelines.  Perhaps more than any other factor, having the right people will determine whether we win the competition for the future.  We’ve got to recruit, we’ve got to retain the top talent, including talent from around the world, so that the best and the brightest study here, stay here, feel welcome here.</p>
<p>The third pillar: defending an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet.</p>
<p>We’ve been fighting for this vision of the internet for a long, long time.  Many of you in this room have been engaged in that effort.  These principles created the conditions that allowed the internet to grow into the transformative force that it’s become: an extraordinary resource for learning, for connection, for economic growth.</p>
<p>But the hard truth is that the internet is also growing more closed, more insecure, more fractured every single day.</p>
<p>We see country after country putting up firewalls, controlling speech, targeting activists, shutting down the internet to squelch dissent.  And while authoritarian regimes deny access to their networks, they actively reach into others and into ours, taking advantage and meddling in more open societies.  It’s no wonder that some countries are asking whether the principles around which we’ve organized the internet are still relevant, are still tenable.</p>
<p>In many ways, we are at an inflection point, some would say even a tipping point.  And our choice is between giving up on our vision for the internet or stepping up the fight.  We will step up the fight.</p>
<p>We’ll defend the principles of an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet across the full spectrum of our engagement – from trade agreements to governance to hardware.  We’ll use our diplomacy to unite governments and the private sector more firmly behind these efforts.  The work we do today will determine what the internet looks like just a few years from now.  That’s a responsibility we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>The fourth pillar I want to talk about is setting technical standards and creating norms for emerging technologies.</p>
<p>Technical standards help ensure quality, protect consumer health and safety, facilitate global interoperability.  They also help overcome trade barriers and expand market access.</p>
<p>We believe in a transparent, consensus-based, and private sector-led approach to developing standards for emerging technologies.  That’s how we’ll arrive at standards that are technologically sound, have earned people’s trust, reflect our values, and help American companies compete on a level playing field.</p>
<p>And norms, of course, are standards of another kind.  We’ll work with partners to ensure that technologies are developed and deployed in ethical ways that respect people’s rights.</p>
<p>That’s what we did at the UN International Telecommunications Union just a few months ago.  Some countries proposed norms that would allow the use, for example, of facial recognition technology in ways that could threaten human rights.  We brought governments and businesses together to stop it.</p>
<p>Whenever rules and norms that affect American lives are being debated and decided, American diplomats won’t be just – won’t just be in the room; we will be leading the charge.</p>
<p>The fifth pillar is this:  It’s making technology work for democracy.</p>
<p>Some of the leading threats to democracies today are playing out, as you all know, in cyberspace. We have to be leading the world’s efforts, and particularly the world’s democracies, in responding to those threats – fighting back against disinformation, standing up for internet freedom, reducing the misuse of surveillance technology.</p>
<p>We’ve got to make sure that our companies are not inadvertently fueling authoritarian practices, whether it’s in China or anywhere else.</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve released “surveillance due diligence guidance” to try to help American companies prevent their products from being misused.</p>
<p>Technology is also disrupting democracies from within – challenging the ways we think about privacy, free speech, the power of government, and corporations.  President Biden will take on these issues here at home.  For example, his new executive order on promoting competition in the U.S. economy asks the FTC to establish rules for companies on surveillance and how to treat personal data.</p>
<p>But democracies have to work together on these issues as well.  We need to close the gaps in regulatory and legal frameworks so that democracies can collaborate more easily on issues like privacy, content moderation, data sharing, and on digital trade.</p>
<p>You all know very well these are incredibly complicated issues.  The world’s democracies are not all on the same page on every single one of them.  But at heart we do share the same principles, and I have confidence that we can work together through the differences that we have.  I can tell you this:  It is a diplomatic priority for the United States to do that.</p>
<p>So is advancing trustworthy AI.  We need be able to reassure our citizens that AI is secure, that it does not have bias embedded in it, that it can be used safely.  And here, we’re grateful for a lot of good work happening in some critical organizations, including at the OECD and the Global Partnership on AI.  This is very important, too.</p>
<p>We’re interested in increasing access to shared public data sets for AI training and testing, while still preserving privacy – especially in sectors like health, climate, and energy, where AI could create transformational breakthroughs.</p>
<p>Finally, the sixth pillar is promoting cooperation.</p>
<p>Yes, our work in this space is about protecting ourselves and our allies from threats.  And yes, it’s about competition.  But more than anything, we want and we need to bring a spirit of cooperation to tech diplomacy.  Because the bottom-line truth is this:  The United States cannot deliver on these pillars on our own.  We need partners.</p>
<p>And this may be in some ways, I think, the most fundamental imperative of our time.  And it, of course, extends beyond technology.  If you think about virtually any challenge that we have to face as a country, as a society, challenges that have a direct impact on the lives of our citizens, whether it’s dealing with this pandemic, whether it’s climate change, whether it is emerging technologies, we know that not a single one can be fully and effectively addressed by any one country acting alone, even the United States.  Now, more than ever before in my lifetime, there is an imperative for cooperation.</p>
<p>So we are building technology into nearly all of our diplomatic engagements – tech by tech, issue by issue, bilaterally, multilaterally, always looking to assemble the right configurations of allies and partners to get things done.</p>
<p>And as we see it, this agenda has to start with our democratic partners.</p>
<p>And I think we’ve already gotten some good work under our belts.  We’ve been developing shared principles at the G7.  I think you saw some of that emerge just a few weeks ago with President Biden.  We’ve created a new U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council that’s going to be an important vehicle for advancing this agenda.  We’re starting a new science and technology partnership with the UK.  We’re launching cooperative agreements with Korea and Japan on emerging technologies.  We created a Critical and Emerging Tech Working Group with the Quad countries – with Japan, Australia, India.  We’re working with G7 partners through Build Back Better World to mobilize private capital and government finance to build digital infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries.</p>
<p>Our goal is strong networks – plural – of countries, companies, universities connected by shared values and a shared commitment to design and deploy technology for the benefit of all people, to strengthen open and interoperable systems, to encourage freedom of thought and expression, which are the heart of innovation, to defend each other against those who are intent on taking technologies that could be used for good and using them for harm.</p>
<p>To deliver on all of this, we need a State Department and a diplomatic corps that treats cyber and technology like the central issues that they are.</p>
<p>I’ve asked the two deputy secretaries of state, Wendy Sherman and Brian McKeon, to take the lead on delivering recommendations for how to elevate and institutionalize cyber and tech diplomacy across the department.  And I am committed to driving this forward in full partnership with Congress.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure the State Department is organized for the task at hand because the issues before us really bear little relationship to borders on a map or the current organizational chart of the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll build more expertise among our workforce in science, in technology, in innovation.  And here’s a request:  Help us spread the word.  We’re looking for outstanding people, for talent who want to make the leap to government, spend some time in government.  Now is a great time to put those skills to use, leveraging tech for the good of our country and for the good of the world.</p>
<p>In the coming weeks, the State Department will be releasing our first ever data strategy to help us use data more effectively and more creatively for diplomacy.  If Netflix can predict what TV show my wife and I might choose to watch next, I think data can also help us and help the department predict maybe the next civil conflict, the next famine, the next economic crisis, and how we can respond more effectively.</p>
<p>I intend to leave my successor at the State Department with strong capabilities in cyber and tech diplomacy, with clear leadership, lines of authority, organizational homes, and talent at every level.  We need to become much better at anticipating the foreign policy implications of the next wave of innovation, and the wave after that.  I want to shape the strategic tech landscape, not just react to it.</p>
<p>And at the same time, we have to find ways to put tech and innovation to the task of solving the concrete problems that we’re facing, whether that’s verifying an arms control agreement or preventing the next pandemic.  I’ve been in and out of government for the better part of 25 years, and the last time I was serving with Bob and others, we’d be in that Situation Room in the White House looking at one of the many challenges that would somehow wind up in our inbox, and I think it became clearer and clearer to all of us that for virtually every single one, there was some technological component to the solution.  Part of the problem is that many of us who are engaged in these issues are not brought up on these disciplines.  Bob is an exception to that, but many of us come from the humanities, from law.  It’s not our first knowledge.  It’s not our first instinct.</p>
<p>And I got to the point when I had the responsibility of chairing some of these meetings to thinking that I needed scientists and technologists in the room just to tell me whether I needed scientists and technologists in the room – (laughter) – to help identify the problems and help identify some of the solutions.  And I became more and more convinced that virtually everything on our agenda has some tech or science or innovative component to the solution.  So we need to do a better job bringing that knowledge, that expertise, that focus into the department and to everything we do.</p>
<p>We started to do that a few years ago when I was last here.  We actually set up our first-ever office in Silicon Valley.  Some of the other agencies of government were ahead of us.  We developed partnerships with leading institutions.  One of my very strong and positive memories was spending some time out at Stanford, we had started working with a class called Hacking for Diplomacy where 20 bureaus of the State Department sent this class problems that we were trying to solve.  And these remarkable students over the course of a semester or even a year worked to solve them.  And bringing that approach, bringing that perspective brought forward answers that I don’t think we would have come to doing it on our own in Washington.  So we need to make this shift too, and the changes we’re making at State I think will help us to do that.</p>
<p>If there’s one thing I want to leave you with today, it’s this:  For the Biden-Harris administration, this is not a standalone diplomatic issue.  It’s not just another line of effort.  We’re weaving cyber and technology diplomacy into our work across the board.  Nothing is more consequential to our competitiveness, to our security, and ultimately, to our democracy.</p>
<p>We’re in the early days of this endeavor.  All of us in the national security community have a tremendous amount to learn and even more to do.  We intend to secure American leadership.  We intend to get results for the American people.  And as we do, we will build upon the work of this commission and continue to work in partnership with you.</p>
<p>Thank you so much for listening.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>State Department Helps Launch New IIJ Guide to Counter Racially or Ethnically Motivated Violent Extremism</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/state-department-helps-launch-new-iij-guide-to-counter-racially-or-ethnically-motivated-violent-extremism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The International Institute for Justice and the Rule of Law (IIJ) today released an <em>IIJ Criminal Justice Practitioner’s Guide for Addressing Racially or Ethnically Motivated Violent Extremism (REMVE)</em> developed under the IIJ REMVE initiative, supported by the United States and the United Kingdom. This Guide will assist in educating policy makers and criminal justice practitioners on how criminal judicial tools can best be deployed to counter transnational REMVE networks and actors.</p>
<p>The<em> IIJ Criminal Justice Practitioner’s Guide</em> was developed through a series of expert meetings, drawing on the first-hand professional experiences of more than 60 recognized subject-matter experts and experienced practitioners from 20 countries and international organizations across North America, Europe, and beyond. The State Department’s Bureau of Counterterrorism worked closely with the Department of Justice, FBI, and the Department of the Treasury to ensure the Guide reflects the U.S. Government’s considerable experience in this area.</p>
<p>The Guide affords policymakers and practitioners a compendium of the tools at their disposal. It builds on existing tools and approaches, including good practices developed by the Global Counterterrorism Forum (GCTF), and outlines where new strategies and national authorities may be needed. The Guide also equips practitioners with a set of Good Practices for effectively addressing REMVE that encompasses trends, legislation and regulation, investigation and disruption, prosecution, prison rehabilitation and post-release monitoring, and community engagement and public outreach.</p>
<p>The Guide is available for download here: <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MTMuNDMxNjg1OTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RoZWlpai5vcmcvd3AtY29udGVudC91cGxvYWRzL0oxMDQzNC1JSUotUkVNVkUtUHJhY3RpdGlvbmVycy1HdWlkZV9FTkctV0VCLXYwMy5wZGYifQ.UtB_k6-aGn0MzuqwWI1DfQiBqA6tBJs9T7eLRp-EGUE/s/1250718950/br/109263465840-l">https://theiij.org/wp-content/uploads/J10434-IIJ-REMVE-Practitioners-Guide_ENG-WEB-v03.pdf</a></p>
<p>For more information about this initiative or the State Department’s work to counter REMVE, please contact the Bureau of Counterterrorism at <a href="mailto:CTPublicAffairs@state.gov">CTPublicAffairs@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The International Institute for Justice and the Rule of Law (IIJ) today released an <em>IIJ Criminal Justice Practitioner’s Guide for Addressing Racially or Ethnically Motivated Violent Extremism (REMVE)</em> developed under the IIJ REMVE initiative, supported by the United States and the United Kingdom. This Guide will assist in educating policy makers and criminal justice practitioners on how criminal judicial tools can best be deployed to counter transnational REMVE networks and actors.</p>
<p>The<em> IIJ Criminal Justice Practitioner’s Guide</em> was developed through a series of expert meetings, drawing on the first-hand professional experiences of more than 60 recognized subject-matter experts and experienced practitioners from 20 countries and international organizations across North America, Europe, and beyond. The State Department’s Bureau of Counterterrorism worked closely with the Department of Justice, FBI, and the Department of the Treasury to ensure the Guide reflects the U.S. Government’s considerable experience in this area.</p>
<p>The Guide affords policymakers and practitioners a compendium of the tools at their disposal. It builds on existing tools and approaches, including good practices developed by the Global Counterterrorism Forum (GCTF), and outlines where new strategies and national authorities may be needed. The Guide also equips practitioners with a set of Good Practices for effectively addressing REMVE that encompasses trends, legislation and regulation, investigation and disruption, prosecution, prison rehabilitation and post-release monitoring, and community engagement and public outreach.</p>
<p>The Guide is available for download here: <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MTMuNDMxNjg1OTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RoZWlpai5vcmcvd3AtY29udGVudC91cGxvYWRzL0oxMDQzNC1JSUotUkVNVkUtUHJhY3RpdGlvbmVycy1HdWlkZV9FTkctV0VCLXYwMy5wZGYifQ.UtB_k6-aGn0MzuqwWI1DfQiBqA6tBJs9T7eLRp-EGUE/s/1250718950/br/109263465840-l">https://theiij.org/wp-content/uploads/J10434-IIJ-REMVE-Practitioners-Guide_ENG-WEB-v03.pdf</a></p>
<p>For more information about this initiative or the State Department’s work to counter REMVE, please contact the Bureau of Counterterrorism at <a href="mailto:CTPublicAffairs@state.gov">CTPublicAffairs@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 13, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-13-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=258775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2:11 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> All right. Happy Tuesday, everyone. Just a couple things here at the top. I wanted to start with developments in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>As you know, President Biden and Secretary Blinken have made human rights central to our foreign policy, and I would like to address two important issues, as I said before, in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>We continue to follow widespread, peaceful protests throughout Cuba as Cubans are calling for freedom and human rights.</p>
<p>They are standing up to Cuba&#8217;s authoritarian regime.</p>
<p>Their basic needs are not being met and they are understandably exhausted.</p>
<p>We commend the people of Cuba for showing great bravery, the strength of their will, and the power of their voice.</p>
<p>In response, the Cuban Government has attempted to silence their voices and communications through internet shutdowns, violence, and arbitrary detentions of dozens of protesters, journalists, activists, and other repressive tactics.</p>
<p>We remain deeply concerned by the Cuban Government’s, quote, “call to combat” and by the images of violence that we have seen over the past two days. We call for calm and we condemn any violence against those protesting peacefully, and we equally call on the Cuban Government to release anyone detained for peaceful protest.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-venezuela"></a> Turning to Venezuela, the United States strongly condemns the unjust detention of 2015 National Assembly representative Freddy Guevara and harassment of Interim President Juan Guaido in Venezuela.</p>
<p>These reprehensible acts are incompatible with efforts to create conditions for comprehensive negotiations between the Venezuelan opposition and the Nicolas Maduro regime to resolve Venezuela’s crisis.</p>
<p>We call for the immediate release of Congressman Guevara and urge the international community to join us in condemning his detention in the strongest terms.</p>
<p>Venezuelans have suffered for far too long under a regime that engages in widespread repression and human rights abuses, targeting those who are attempting to build a democratic country with leaders and institutions that are accountable to the people.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-china"></a> Next, as part of the whole-of-government effort, multiple U.S. agencies issued an updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory today that describes the heightened risks for businesses that have supply chains and investment links to Xinjiang, China, due to the People’s Republic of China’s ongoing human rights abuses in the region. These include but are not limited to forced labor.</p>
<p>This business advisory was jointly issued by six U.S. Government agencies, and that includes us, the Department of State, the Department of Commerce, Homeland Security, Labor, and Treasury, along with the Office of the United States Trade Representative.</p>
<p>The advisory notes that – the Department of State’s determination that the PRC government is perpetrating genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang. It cautions that given the severity and extent of these and other abuses, businesses and individuals that do not exit supply chains, ventures, and investments connected to Xinjiang could run a high risk of violating U.S. law. You can find the advisory and a fact sheet on the State Department’s website at state.gov.</p>
<p>The release of the updated advisory today underscores the Biden-Harris administration’s commitment to promoting responsible business practices as well as accountability for the PRC government’s abuses in Xinjiang. I note the European Commission and the European External Action Service today published global forced labor guidance to help EU companies address the risk of forced labor and supply chains based on international due diligence guidelines. The United States and the European Union, we share concerns on the use of forced labor in global supply chains and we’re committed to working together to address this issue. We’ll continue to work with our interagency partners, the private sector, and our allies and partners around the world to promote reliable supply chains free from forced labor and call attention to human rights abuses.</p>
<p>So with that, Matt, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. Just logistically, if you’re – before I go to Cuba, if you’re not able to preview the ASEAN meeting that the Secretary is going to participate in tonight, can you just say if you expect that the Burmese foreign minister will be a part of this discussion?</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-asean"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I would need to refer to ASEAN to discuss their participation in tonight’s meeting with Secretary Blinken – virtual meeting, that is. Of course, this will be an important opportunity, and the latest in a series of opportunities the Secretary has had, to reaffirm the centrality of ASEAN and to underscore its essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture.</p>
<p>As you know, we’ve had a number of opportunities to engage with our ASEAN partners. We met with the chair of ASEAN in a recent trip to London several weeks ago now. Deputy Secretary Sherman has been in the region for in-person meetings herself. The Secretary has spoken bilaterally on a number of occasions to his ASEAN counterparts. But I know the Secretary is very much looking forward to this, his first meeting with his fellow ASEAN ministers.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. On Cuba, there are quite a few critics of the previous administration’s Cuba policy who are now, because you haven’t changed that policy at all, by extension, critics of this administration’s Cuba policy who have pointed out or made the argument that the very sharp reduction in remittances that Cuban Americans are allowed to send back to the island is one, not the – not – surely not the only, but is one reason why the basic needs of Cuban people are not being met, as – in your words.</p>
<p>Do you accept – do you see any validity to that argument? And whether you do or not, are remittances or – and allowing them or allowing them to go back up to the level that they were under the Obama administration, is that part of the review?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would say our review is taking a broad look at what we can do to support the core principles at the center of our policy, and that is democracy and human rights. To your point, Matt, we are always considering options available to us that would allow us to support the Cuban people, to support their humanitarian needs, which are indeed profound, and they are profound because of not anything the United States has done, but from the actions and inactions, mismanagement, corruption of the Cuban regime.</p>
<p>Look, the other point I would make is that current U.S. policy, the so-called embargo, it allows humanitarian goods to reach Cuba, and we do expedite any request to export humanitarian or medical supplies to the island. We regularly authorize the export of agricultural products, medicine, medical equipment, and humanitarian goods to Cuba. And we’ve authorized billions of dollars’ worth of goods over the past couple decades, since the latest iteration of this has been in effect. But just in 2020 alone, we exported more than $175 million worth of goods to Cuba, including food and medicine, to help the Cuban people. In the first six months of 2021 alone, Cuba imported $123 million worth of, in this case, chicken from the United States.</p>
<p>Now, the pandemic has added an extra layer of pain and suffering onto the Cuban people as it has around the world, and we share the concern that the Cuban people have as they have faced an exponential rise in COVID cases across the island. Now, Cuba has made a sovereign decision regarding how it will address the pandemic, and that includes, in this case, the use of its own indigenously produced vaccine. Cuba, as you know, has not joined COVAX. The Cuban Government could always decide to receive outside vaccine donations, but the Cuban Government has decided not to do so yet.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, okay, but – so does that mean you do or do not agree with the argument that a sharp reduction in remittances has contributed to the lack of basic needs for &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I have not seen a comprehensive study of it, so I’m not prepared to comment on that from here. What I would say, again, is that we are always looking for ways that we can support the Cuban people. We are consistent – we are constantly reviewing what policy measures might bring that about, and by “bring that about” I mean support of democracy, support for human rights on the island. That policy review is ongoing. We are engaging a wide range of stakeholders. We’re taking a close look not only what our immediate predecessor did but, of course, the actions of the Obama-Biden administration, administrations before that. Across any number of policy areas, we are seeking to learn from and to take into account the lessons of previous administrations – what they’ve done well, where there’s room to do something better or to do something different – and so that’s what we’re doing here. This is no different.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. And then just the last one: You mentioned that the current U.S. policy – you called it the “so-called embargo.” What exactly would you call it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The embargo. I’m not arguing with that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I follow up on that regarding remittances?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because my understanding is that the wire transfers are part of the late November, post-election additional sanctions by the Trump administration and that that is what many Cuban Americans are complaining about, where they can no longer send – from Miami, who support the overall embargo. So I was wondering today if there was any running room, any flexibility that the administration would be considering. Then I asked that question of Senator Menendez within the last hour or two and he said absolutely not, because the Cuban Government takes 20 percent off the top on the remittances and then transfers the money to pesos, the dollars to pesos, and so the people there are getting a fraction of what their relatives are sending home.</p>
<p>That said, I understand he’s been in touch with the White House at the highest levels on this very issue today. Is there anything that the White House would do that would go against the chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee who wrote section two Helms-Burton?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Far be it from me to speak for our – speak for the White House. I will &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, as an administration official, how likely – especially one where nominations go through that committee and are being held by a singular – single Republican.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I will say is that – and I think there is widespread support; we recognize this in the administration; there is widespread support for this idea in Congress – is that the idea that Americans, and especially Cuban Americans, have the potential to be, and oftentimes are, the best – our best ambassadors for what we hope to see on the island nation of Cuba. That is also central to our policy review. We have absolutely been in touch with senior members of Congress. I won’t be in a position to confirm those discussions or to read them out, but as part of our dialogue when it comes to our review of the Cuba policy, we have engaged with Congress. In the aftermath – well, I shouldn’t say the aftermath, of course; they’re still ongoing – in the midst of the protests on Cuba, we have been engaged with senior members of Congress as well.</p>
<p>We do recognize that for our policies to have the most effect, to have broad legitimacy and support, it’s important that they have, to the maximum extent possible, support of Congress, and, of course, Cuba is no different. So those consultations are ongoing. Our policy review is ongoing. Even in the midst of that review, we’re going to be looking for ways we can support the Cuban people.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, when you said that our Cuban Americans are the best advocates, the best ambassadors for democracy versus authoritarianism, let’s say – I’m paraphrasing, but that seems to be the import of what you’re saying – is there some flexibility, as you said you’re discussing with members of Congress, to some of the travel restrictions, COVID permitting?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I’m not in a position to preview what we might do going forward from the podium. What I can say is that even before these protests started, we are looking for ways in the midst of COVID, in the midst of the other hardships that the Cuban people have endured because of, again, the corruption, the mismanagement of their own government – perhaps the indifference of their own government – we are looking for ways that we might support the Cuban people in a way that’s consistent with our interests, that’s consistent with our values.</p>
<p>We are, of course, doing that in the midst of these protests. These protests are about many things, but certainly the suffering of the Cuban people that is – has been made all the more acute during the pandemic. It’s top of mind. Of course, their quest for additional freedom, for human rights, central to it as well, and what we can do in a way that is responsible and effective to support those aims, including their humanitarian needs, we’ll continue to consider and move forward as appropriate.</p>
<p>Lara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Yesterday Jen Psaki said at the White House podium that the United States has spent something like $20 million to support democracy assistance programs in Cuba since 2009. Can you give us some granular detail on how that money was spent? Was it mostly for broadcast channels? Was there nothing else? And if it was mostly for broadcast, was that normal operating costs, or was that above and beyond what had already been budgeted in previous years?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, what Jen was referring to yesterday was the fact that we do provide economic support funds for democracy promotion programs to Cuba on an annual basis, and that amount has been $20 million per year for several years now. And now these U.S.-funded programs, they are – they do go to broadcast funding. They inform the Cuban public through support for independent media. They support Cubans to promote free expression in their communities. They increase access to information on democracy, participatory government, human rights, and market economics. They provide emergency and humanitarian assistance to human rights defenders and to political prisoners, and they prepare those who seek, who aspire, to have a voice in a free and democratic Cuba. All of this funding, all of these programs, they do adhere to the laws and the guidelines laid out in the Helms-Burton Act of 1996 and the Cuban Liberty and Solidarity Act.</p>
<p>We’ve made no secret of the fact that support for democracy, support for human rights, is really at the core of our approach to Cuba. They are going to be anchors of our – not only our policy review, but where we net out on that policy.</p>
<p>I would make one other point, that as these protests have taken place, we have seen the Cuban Government respond with internet shutdowns, with blackouts. These are government-imposed internet shutdowns. And so just as we’ve been doing with this funding, we call on Cuba’s leaders to demonstrate restraint, to urge respect for the voice of the people by opening all means of communication, both online and offline. Shutting down technology, shutting down information pathways – that does nothing to address the legitimate needs and aspirations of the Cuban people. And so we’ve been very clear on that from the start.</p>
<p>Lara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So just to drill down a tiny bit on a technical detail, is it fair to assume that that money has come out of this building and/or USAID? And did it go strictly through NGOs?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course, we’re not providing any funding directly to the Cuban Government. Oftentimes, as you know, we work through partners on the ground. For additional details you may want to reach out USAID for how they may administer it.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-georgia"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. A couple questions about Georgia. I watched your briefing a week ago, where you talked about organized violence on Tbilisi’s streets when Georgian law enforcement, as many allege, intentionally did not stop the violent mob’s attacks on journalists and members of the LGBTQI community. After your briefing, two days ago precisely, a cameraman of TV Pirveli, my colleague, Alexander Lashkarava – this is actually him – he was beaten up by this mob and he died two days ago.</p>
<p>And so my question would be: In light of these events and the recent past events in Georgia, there are serious concerns that Georgia is diverting towards illiberalism. So is the Secretary Blinken comfortable with that development? And also what do you have to say to those people on the street right now who are demanding the resignation of the Prime Minister Irakli Garibashvili? I might have a few follow-ups on that. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Well, first, of course, we extend our deepest condolences to your former colleague Lekso Lashkarava, to his family, loved ones, and of course to his colleagues, yourself included. We’re closely following the reports concerning his death. We do call for calm and an end to the violence that has already caused one tragic loss of life, in this case the death of your colleague. The safety of every Georgian journalist and the credibility of democracy in Georgia, in fact, require that every individual who attacked peaceful protesters and journalists on July 5th and 6th or those who incited violence – they must be identified; they should be arrested and prosecuted to the full extent of the law. We remind Georgia’s leaders and its law enforcement of their responsibility to protect all of those exercising their constitutional rights. We remind them of their responsibility to protect journalists exercising the freedom of press – of the press. And we encourage all Georgians, including Georgian officials, to publicly condemn this type of violence that has no place in a democracy.</p>
<p>We proudly advance efforts around the globe to protect LGBTQI populations from violence and abuse, criminalization, discrimination, and stigma, and we seek to empower local LGBTQI+ movements and persons. We firmly oppose abuses against the LGBTQI+ community and, of course, in this case, the brutal violence against your former colleague, your now deceased colleague. When it comes to the prime minister and his future, that, of course, is a decision for the Georgian people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. My sources on the Capitol Hill are telling me that there are talks on imposing personal sanctions against those officials in the Georgian Government who were directly responsible for the violence we all saw on July 5th. Is this an idea the State Department is also entertaining? How realistic that could be? And very lastly, I would like to know what you think about the responsibility of the opposition political parties in Georgia who are leading those people on the streets. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we have a number of tools to hold accountable those responsible in some way for human rights abuses, for violence around the world. Sanctions are indeed one of those tools. As you know, we don’t preview sanctions before we enact them. But we are following the situation very closely, and we are committed to seeing to it that those responsible for this are held accountable.</p>
<p>When it comes to all political actors in Georgia, again, we urge them to very publicly condemn this violence. When it comes to the Georgian Government, I would reiterate our calls for a thorough investigation of this that leads to the perpetrators of this horrific crime being brought to justice.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-burma"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I wanted to ask about Myanmar. The situation in the country at the moment is that there’s a huge COVID spike and people are calling – people are sort of reporting oxygen shortages, there’s very little medical care, there seems to be very little supply of vaccines. It’s not – Myanmar has not come up, Burma has not come up in – Burma in discussion about vaccine diplomacy or vaccines for other countries. I’m wondering: Is it a possibility to send COVID vaccines or assistance to a country like Myanmar, where you’re currently not in a good relationship with the government? Is that something that you are considering? Is there any way you can give assistance to the people of the country in the current political climate there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, to be very clear, our assistance in the form of vaccines has nothing to do with politics. And again, our goal is to put shots in arms, not to twist arms, knowing that if we are to end this pandemic here in this country and around the world, we have to be in a position to support the distribution of a safe and effective vaccine around the world. And that is precisely what we’ve been doing.</p>
<p>As you know, the President has authorized 80 million from our own domestic stockpile to be distributed. We have announced the allocation of millions of those doses to countries around the world. We have announced the purchase of 500 million Pfizer doses that will start going out next month and into 2022 as well. Working together with the international community in the context of the G7 summit earlier – it was last month now, I suppose – committed to some 1 billion vaccines for the world.</p>
<p>So just because we may not have the best of relations with a particular regime or government does not mean that that diminishes the need for that country’s people. And as you know, it’s – we have bilateral mechanisms to provide vaccines but also COVAX. COVAX is supporting the safe and effective distribution of vaccines around the world. We are working diligently through COVAX, and, in fact, three quarters of our vaccine allotment is going through COVAX. And that’s part and parcel of the $2 billion commitment we made early on to COVAX and the $4 billion total that the United States will vector towards COVAX over time. So the people of Burma are equally deserving of medical care as people around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, follow-up. So far there aren’t – there isn’t any donations of vaccines or other stuff to the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have not made any announcements, but as you know, we continue to work with COVAX. And if we do have a Burma-specific announcement, we’ll be happy to let you know.</p>
<p>Lalit.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. A follow-up on COVAX, but the country is India I wanted to ask me about. Do you know how much – figures of India receiving the COVID-19 vaccines from the U.S. so far? Has India started receiving COVID-19 vaccines from the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as I just said to Simon, as you know, the United States will share 80 million doses from our domestic stockpile with countries around the world. Before we can ship those doses, however, each country must complete its own domestic set of operational, of regulatory, and legal processes that are specific to each country. Now, India has determined that it needs further time to review legal provisions related to accepting vaccine donations. Once India works through its legal processes, our donations of vaccines to India will proceed expeditiously. We would need to refer you to the Government of India on the status of its discussions with COVAX, which, in this case, is helping to facilitate that delivery.</p>
<p>More broadly in the region, throughout South Asia, we’re donating millions of vaccines to Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Nepal, the Maldives, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka. Roughly 40 million doses have been delivered worldwide so far.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the delay in shipping COVID-19 vaccines to India is because of some regulations that India has to clear that, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I would need to refer you to the Indian Government for their processes and where they are internally. But we are ready to ship those vaccines expeditiously when we have a greenlight from the Government of India.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But have you determined how many vaccines you are planning to ship to India?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ve announced that. I – we can get that for you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And can you also give us a sense of cooperation between India and U.S. on COVID-19 vaccines development and production and also to the third-world countries?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And – what was the last part of your question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And also the third-world countries.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Absolutely. So cooperation between our two countries, it is not the product of something – of only something that was built in the context of COVID. It actually builds on decades of successful partnership between our two countries in health, in biomedical research. We are partnering to strengthen the global response to COVID-19 on issues ranging from addressing infectious disease outbreaks to strengthening health systems to securing global supply chains.</p>
<p>We recently welcomed an initiative to collaborate through the International Center of Excellence in Research focused on infectious diseases, and in this case that includes COVID-19 and other emerging threats. And we look forward to an overarching MOU, a memorandum of understanding, to enhance health cooperation beyond that.</p>
<p>We are further working on diagnostics, therapeutics, vaccines to combat the disease and to recognize the importance of manufacturing critical drugs during this time and to making them accessible globally. And we’re able to do that because India’s pharmaceutical sector is strong, it’s well-established, it has played a central role in manufacturing vaccines for global use over some time. And we’re pleased that U.S. pharmaceutical companies in turn are coordinating with their Indian counterparts since the beginning of the pandemic. As you know, beyond this partnership, in the context of the Quad leader’s summit, there was an agreement to work with India to boost manufacturing of COVID vaccines that would support a safe and effective and eventually universal distribution of vaccines around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One final one. The situation – the pandemic situation in India has improved quite considerably in the last few weeks. The U.S. had imposed some travel restrictions on people coming from India. Now the situation is improving. Are you reviewing it and when do you think this will be lifted?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would say there are a couple of things at play here. When it comes to the travel restrictions, as you know, that is something that we are taking a close look at – the U.S. Government, I should say, is taking a close look at. There are expert groups that have been formed. And “experts” in this case refers primarily to medical professionals, because for us this is not a decision about politics; this is a decision about public health and the safety of the American people but also the safety of the global traveling public. And we want to make sure that this decision is adjudicated with that central principle in mind.</p>
<p>The State Department, for our part, we also routinely issue travel advisories and we routinely update them for all countries based on a comprehensive review of available safety information and ongoing developments. We review those regularly and we make updates as warranted.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned, very much. I have a follow-up on Cuba, but first I want to ask two questions on Brazil.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-brazil"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Brazilian president wants to change next election process back to a paper vote. He has alleged that fraud in previous election, without giving evidence, and last week he threatened to cancel next election next year if there is not a clean one. So what is the administration reaction, response to these claims? And does the U.S. have confidence that the previous past elections in Brazil were fair, and the next one will also be fair?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What we call for – and this is not unique to Brazil, but it’s what we call for around the world – are free and fair elections, the ability of the people to exercise their will freely and fairly. And so the mechanics of an election are typically not of consequence to us. What is of consequence is the character of an election, and so we will be looking to see to it that elections around the world – but including in Brazil – are free and fair.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you being patient to these claims that the president is making? He is following Trump’s playbook when it comes to election fraud.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would not want to characterize what the Brazilian president is saying, but I will characterize where we stand on the exercise of democracy, the ability of peoples around the world to exercise their free will, and that’s free and fair elections in our view are important. They are important in democracies; they are important in aspiring democracies. They are a key metric as we determine the health of democracies and the health of participatory electoral systems around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And another one, because harassment against journalists also in Brazil has increased since President Bolsonaro took office. Last week the organization Reporters Without Borders included Bolsonaro on a list of press predators, alongside 37 authoritarian leaders like Bashar al-Assad and Vladimir Putin. And also last week president’s lawyer sent a message to a female reporter saying that in China, she would be – she would disappear and her body would not be found. So what is – is this kind of threat is something that worries this administration, coming from Bolsonaro’s government?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, generally the department is always concerned when journalists face threats of harassment, face threats of intimidation, and especially when there are threats of violence. We already spoke of one especially tragic case during the course of this briefing. Freedom of the press, freedom of expression more broadly, is something we support around the world. In order to have freedom of the press, freedom of expression, you have to stand up for the safety and security of journalists and reporters around the world. So I haven’t taken a close look at the study you mentioned, but we certainly have seen, broadly speaking, an uptick in threats of intimidation, threats of violence of reporters globally.</p>
<p>As you know, the Secretary, just in advance of World Press Freedom Day, in May of this year, hosted a group of journalists, many of whom have faced intimidation, threats of violence in their own work. And we did that very purposefully, to put a spotlight on this challenge. And it’s a challenge that not only comes from governments; sometimes nongovernmental organizations and actors, terrorist groups, and others take part in this. But journalists should never face threats, face danger in the course of their work for what it is they may report, for what it is they may uncover.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Would these violations of human rights impact the bilateral relationship between Brazil and the U.S., since you are saying this administration put human rights at the center of foreign policy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, that’s exactly the point. And it’s not unique to Brazil; it’s not unique to any one country. But in every relationship we have – this includes with our closest partners; it includes those with whom we may have profound disagreements – we are always going to be taking a close look at a country’s human rights record to seek improvement where we can, but ultimately to see to it that people around the world are protected in exercising their universal rights, their universal freedoms. The United States will always be a voice for that. Oftentimes we do make that point publicly, but in private conversations as well we don’t shy away, and we do what we can in our assessment as – in the means most effective for us to protect and to safeguard human rights around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just – can I do a very quick follow-up on Cuba?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because during the campaign, President Biden said that Trump’s reversals on Cuba policy have inflicted harm to the Cuban people and done nothing to advance democracy and human rights. So does President Biden still want to change Trump’s policy on Cuba? And when would be a good time, if not now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are undertaking a review of our – of a Cuba policy precisely to determine how best we can support the human rights of Cubans, how best we can support the prospect for democracy on the island. Now, of course, successive administrations have sought in some ways to do that, and so as I said before, we are going to be taking a close look at what has and has not worked in the past, and unfortunately, in the case of Cuba there may be more that has not worked than what has worked. And so we are going to be, as we’ve done in other cases as well, studying that very closely to determine what we can do most effectively, consistent with our values, consistent with our interests, to move the ball forward, especially when it comes to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Will Cuba become a priority now, after the events on the ground?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course, you heard from the President directly, you heard from the Secretary directly standing right here. We have not been shy about speaking to what is going on. Of course, it’s always a priority for us when citizens are taking to the streets peacefully to express their aspirations for democracy and human rights. We’ll continue to watch this very closely.</p>
<p>Yes, Rich.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I want to stay in the hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’ll – in the hemisphere? Were you staying in the hemisphere?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I was going to go to a different hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, let’s stay in the hemisphere. I’ll come right back to you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-haiti"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So in Haiti – is the U.S. team in Haiti assisting the assassination investigation part of a U.S. foreign emergency support team? Do you know who from this building was part of the U.S. delegation went to Haiti on Sunday? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right. So there was an interagency delegation that was in Haiti on Sunday. DAS Lochman from our Western Hemisphere Affairs Bureau represented the department in discussions on Sunday. The team was deployed in order to take part in an assessment of how best the United States can support the Haitian people as they respond to this. Right now we’re focusing on that investigation, what we might be able to do to support the Haitian investigation into the assassination of President Moise.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is anyone from the FEST, the foreign emergency support team, there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we’ll get back to you on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Uh-huh. And what is the U.S. message to Haitian people standing outside of U.S. embassy, asking for political asylum?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I understand that the situation in front of our Embassy in Port-au-Prince is now calm. The groups that were gathered there, I understand, have dissipated. As we do around the world, we encourage Haitians, in this case, not to gather in front of our embassy. For their own safety, for their own security, we continue to urge calm across the – across Haiti. We have heard Acting Prime Minister Joseph make very similar calls, other political actors make similar calls, calling for calm. We reiterate those. That is precisely what Haiti needs, as Haiti’s political actors, we hope, will work together in the interests of the Haitian people to make meaningful progress in efforts to form a consensus government that can lead to free and fair elections.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So have the Haitians made any requests that you guys have said no to?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right now we are evaluating a number of requests. We are evaluating how best we can support the needs of the Haitian Government at the moment. As I said right now, much of that focuses on the ongoing investigation into the killing of President Moise. In addition to the interagency team, the FBI and DHS have been engaged on the ground as well to determine the investigative assets, investigative support that Haiti may need on its investigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So does that mean the answer is no, you haven’t denied any requests, at least yet?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re still evaluating. I don’t believe we &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, fine. But have you said no to anything?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah. I don’t believe we have denied any requests right yet, but we’re still evaluating quite a bit.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one follow-up &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But as you said yesterday, the focus is on the investigation rather than security assistance, which was a request. So is there a response to that request?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as I think you’ve heard from the Pentagon and from the White House, we are evaluating requests for assistance, just as we would requests from assistance in other contexts. We know in this case that there may be needs for protection in the context of critical infrastructure. We’re taking a close look at that as well. FBI and DHS, as I said before, have been engaging with their Haitian counterparts, but all of these requests we’re evaluating in line with our assessment of how we can best assist the Haitian people and the Haitian Government.</p>
<p>Rich.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-olympics"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. The European Parliament has voted for a diplomatic boycott of the upcoming Winter Olympics. Does the U.S. support that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Do we support their &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> They’re boycotting. Would – is the U.S. considering or will the U.S. follow suit and do the same?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are – what is true is that we are closely consulting with allies and partners, as well as other actors, including the business community, to identify common concerns and, ideally, to establish a common approach regarding the 2022 Winter Olympics and Paralympic Games. We’ll continue to speak out consistently in the meantime, and again, jointly with allies and partners when it comes to what we’re seeing from PRC officials. And we’ll continue to impose costs and sanctions on those responsible for human rights abuses, including the state sponsorship of forced labor. And just today, as I said at the outset of the briefing, you saw the updated business advisory that came from the Department of State and several of our interagency partners. But right now, we are engaged in discussions to establish those common concerns, and I don’t have anything for you beyond that.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-china2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the U.S. – as you – as the U.S. engages with its allies on this decision-making process, did the European Union or those countries engage? Was that – their decision the result of consultations with the United States?</p>
<p>And then sort of separately on your talking about the business community and today’s advisory, can you confirm that we can expect one on Hong Kong? And the Xinjiang advisory is about three dozen pages. Succinctly, what is the message to the business community? That this type of activity, knowingly having forced labor in your supply chains, is immoral – which it is, clearly, in the statement – or is it illegal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think what we said in – at the outset is that companies that engage with entities and who are enmeshed in supply chains in Xinjiang do face potential legal exposure. And the business advisory was quite clear on that.</p>
<p>When it comes to the EU and how they arrived at this decision, I’m not going to speak for the EU. I will let them speak for themselves. I will say that the EU, of course, is an important partner when it comes to any number of issues, and that in part is predicated on our shared values. And I would make the broader point that you have seen a great deal of convergence between the United States and our European allies on – based on those values in the context of the PRC and Xinjiang in particular. Let me give you just a few examples.</p>
<p>At the G7 summit, President Biden and Chancellor Merkel outlined our shared positions on China. The President had an opportunity to meet with a number of his other counterparts, including British Prime Minister Johnson and others, to discuss the importance of coordinating and responding to China’s non-market practices and the need to speak out on human rights abuses, including in Xinjiang and Hong Kong. The communique that resulted from the G7 summit also addressed the need for action against forced labor practices in the agricultural, solar, and garment sectors. There was an entire paragraph – paragraph 49, I belive it was – dedicated to this issue and showcasing the convergence.</p>
<p>At the NATO summit, the communique for the first time ever addressed the security challenges from China. And the United States and our NATO Allies, many of whom are European, of course, agreed to draft a new strategic concept, a framework that will guide the Alliance’s approach to the evolving strategic environment in the coming years – not only to address Russia’s aggressive actions, but also those posed by the PRC to our collective security.</p>
<p>And then, of course, at the U.S.-EU summit the leaders launched the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council, the goal – whose goal is to write the rules of the road for the economy of the 21st century in areas like emerging technology and competition policy. And we’ve also put forward a series of affirmative ideas, Build Back Better World being at the center of this, offering and making clear that, one, democracies can deliver; and two, there is an alternative, attractive model to what other countries may be offering here.</p>
<p>When it comes to Hong Kong, we don’t have anything to announce at this time regarding future policy moves. You’ve heard from us on any number of occasions our concern regarding Beijing’s ongoing attempts to undermine Hong Kong’s autonomy, to dismantle its democratic institutions and processes. We’ll continue to call international attention to and to hold PRC and Hong Kong authorities accountable for the erosion of the rule of law in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>I would make one additional broader point here. We know that a healthy business community relies on the rule of law, which the national security law that applies to Hong Kong continues to undermine. As a general matter, we seek to ensure that businesses can operate in a stable, predictable, and fair regulatory environments around the world. And rule of law risks that were formerly limited to mainland China are now increasingly a concern in Hong Kong. That’s of great concern to us. It is of great concern to the American business community. It’s of great concern to the international business community.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-haiti2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Cuba – just because you’re on Cuba – my colleague asked about the urgency of this ongoing policy review. Is there a timeline for completion? I think we’ve continued to ask, and obviously the protests sort of lend a greater immediacy to the question.</p>
<p>And then on Haiti, are you – is the administration particularly concerned about instability in the country as a result of this dispute over control of the government? And is the State Department or the interagency going to continue to engage with all of the claimants to power?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we have engaged with a wide variety of stakeholders in Haiti. The interagency delegation that was there over the weekend met with Claude Joseph, Ariel Henry, Joseph Lambert, and others. And we have continued to urge these political actors to work together in the interests of the Haitian people.</p>
<p>We have called on Haitian political leaders, the Haitian private sector, civil society to come together to – importantly, to strengthen the democratic institutions and to reach an inclusive solution that will facilitate peace and stability and lead to presidential and legislative elections.</p>
<p>For us, this is about – the guiding principles are Haiti’s constitution, its institutions, and we have urged Haitian political actors to work together in the interests of their people to make meaningful progress in that effort to form a consensus government that ultimately can lead to free and fair elections. And of course, the Haitian constitution calls for those free and fair elections later this year.</p>
<p>Beyond this immediate political situation, Haiti’s political gridlock has long taken a great toll on the country, and it’s vital for Haiti’s leaders to finally come together to chart a united path for the country. The United States will continue to be a partner to the Haitian people. We will continue to engage constructively with Haiti’s political actors and its broader set of stakeholders to do what we can to help support Haiti’s political leaders finding this consensus solution.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba4"></a> On the Cuba policy review, of course, we are moving as expeditiously as appropriate in this case. We are making sure that we are consulting with, as I said before, a broad and wide variety of stakeholders. We are taking a close look at what the United States can best do to support the needs of the Cuban people, to support their legitimate and long-denied aspirations for democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-egypt"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I ask about Egypt?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There was a report yesterday in Politico that Mohamed Soltan, whose case I’m sure you’re familiar with, that there was an agreement by the State Department under the previous administration, at least something signed, to the effect that he would be again in custody of the United States and that Egypt’s intelligence chief has raised that again.</p>
<p>First of all, is there any truth to the – to that initial finding that there was some document there? Was this raised? And do you have any comment overall on his situation now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we’re aware of the document that was reported related to Mohamed Soltan, of course, a U.S. citizen. He was formerly imprisoned in Egypt. We don’t have a comment on its legal authority.</p>
<p>What I would remind you, though, is what we said at the time: The United States condemned the detention of Mr. Soltan and we called for his immediate release. It’s something that we worked for very assiduously.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could you say whether the Egyptians have raised this again?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position to detail that.</p>
<p>Lara.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-iran"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Staying in that region, if we could go to Iran. There is a report out of Tehran today that a government spokesman said that Iran and the United States are negotiating for prisoners exchanges.</p>
<p>First, I assume that was not a direct negotiation, but if it was, could you please comment?</p>
<p>And then secondly, this seems like a good opportunity to ask about the status of the talks and what effort is being made to break the current stalemate, or hold, or logjam, or whatever we want to call it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, first on the question of detainees, you are correct; it is indirect but active discussions taking place on this – to this end, seeing the release of the Americans who have been unjustly detained, deprived of their freedom for far too long now. We are treating the issue of detainees independently from discussions of the JCPOA, as you know. It&#8217;s really a matter of us to see to it that these detainees are released as soon as possible. We are working with the utmost urgency and we want it to be resolved immediately. We&#8217;re working night and day to bring these detainees, these American citizens home. We&#8217;re also working with our allies, many of whom also have citizens currently arbitrarily or wrongfully detained by the Iranian Government.</p>
<p>Look, the broader point is that Iran&#8217;s unjust imprisonment of U.S. citizens for use as political leverage, it&#8217;s abhorrent, it&#8217;s outrageous. Our priority is bringing these individuals home as possible and resolving the cases of missing and abducted U.S. citizens just as quickly as we can.</p>
<p>When it comes to the status of the talks, we&#8217;ve discussed this yesterday, but questions about when or whether Iran would be prepared to start a seventh round of talks or to reach an understanding on a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA, those questions have to be addressed to Tehran. They can&#8217;t be addressed to us. As we&#8217;ve made clear, we are prepared to continue engaging in the context of these indirect negotiations with Iran. We&#8217;re prepared to return to a seventh round of talks. We&#8217;ve been equally clear that there&#8217;s not a deadline, a firm deadline that we have in mind as of right now, but we&#8217;ve made no secret of the fact that we are considering the implications of Iran’s nuclear advances for a potential return to the JCPOA. So we&#8217;re watching very closely.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Great. Ned, just on the indirect, active – indirect but active discussions on the – is there anything new about this today other than the fact that an Iranian official said this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Anything new over the course of the last couple months? We&#8217;ve known about these talks for some time. They&#8217;ve been going on, yes, separately from the nuclear talks, but still they&#8217;ve been going on. And I think that senior officials who we all know has talked about it pretty openly.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I – correct me, Lara, if I&#8217;m wrong, but I think Lara asked a question just based on what an Iranian official said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no, no, I know. But I&#8217;m wondering, it&#8217;s – I’m not saying it&#8217;s not a valid question. I just wonder if there&#8217;s anything new today that was not new last week or the week before or the month – a month before or two months or three months.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, I think we have found in the cases – in the case of Americans who are held against their will unjustly around the world that these discussions are best undertaken quietly, and we often don&#8217;t speak to the details from the podium precisely because we are doing everything we can and working as urgently as we can to secure their release. I&#8217;m just not in a position to update on where these indirect discussions may be.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, yeah, but they&#8217;ve been going on for months, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, they&#8217;ve been going on before this administration took office. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>That’s – yes, I mean – okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-indopacificasean"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, thank you, Ned. Two questions, please. First, on the Secretary&#8217;s ASEAN foreign ministers meeting later this evening, last week Kurt Campbell spoke at an event where he said I think we have been “missing in action” in many respects in the Pacific. He said we recognize fully that for an effective Asia strategy you must do more in Southeast Asia. And he said we want in the next little while to step up our game substantially.</p>
<p>So first, would the State Department agree that the U.S. has been missing in action in the Pacific? And will the Secretary&#8217;s message today be about greater U.S. engagement in Southeast Asia? And then I have a follow-up on China.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So this is a region, the Indo-Pacific, that is vitally important to us for any number of interests, but also our values. I think what the Secretary will say tonight – and I expect we&#8217;ll have a readout after the session concludes – is a reaffirmation of our commitment to ASEAN’s centrality and a reaffirmation of ASEAN’s central and essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture. The Secretary will have the first opportunity tonight to speak to ASEAN – at least to the foreign ministers – as a whole, but as you know, we did meet with the Bruneian foreign minister in London, current chair of ASEAN; the Secretary has been in contact bilaterally with – over the phone and in person with a number of ASEAN members. Deputy Secretary Sherman was – traveled to the region several weeks ago, where she met with ASEAN counterparts.</p>
<p>So I think both in terms of word and deed, we have demonstrated our commitment to the centrality of ASEAN. We know of its indispensable and central role to the regional architecture. But I wouldn’t want to get ahead of the Secretary’s engagement tonight.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-china3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And then – excuse me – on China, China’s Foreign Ministry has responded to yesterday’s atrocities report, and they’ve said that the U.S. is no position to point fingers at other countries’ human rights situation. They gave examples of past treatment of Native Americans, I think they brought up George Floyd, and they called the report a waste of paper. Do you have any response to that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have a response to that. I will just say, without commenting on what sounds like the PRC playbook, that we have been very clear that as part of our commitment to human rights – our defense, our promotion of human rights around the world – that as a confident democracy, as a country that is comfortable and confident in its standing, we can be open, we can be transparent about where we have veered off course, where we have not met the ideals that – towards which we strive every day. After all, and as we often like to point out, this country was not born a perfect union. It is our essential mission every day to form a more perfect union.</p>
<p>Where that imperfection has been on display, at least speaking for this administration, we have not sought to sweep it under the rug, we’ve not sought to hide it from the rest of the world. We know that for the health, for the wellbeing of our own democracy, it’s important that we are open and transparent but also to be the model that we aspire to be for other democracies and aspiring democracies around the world. We set an important example by comporting ourselves in that.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, everyone. Very quick? Very – yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-russiaclimate"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Quickly, Special Envoy John Kerry’s meeting in Russia, because it was reported by media reports that the U.S. is trying to setting up some proposal to work with Russia on climate change. Do you have any readout on his meetings in Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have a readout at the moment. I do expect that the special envoy’s office will be in a position to provide additional details at the conclusion of his meetings there. Of course, it is not a secret that we have profound differences with the Russian Federation on any number of issues, and I need not go into them. But it’s also not a secret – and you saw this in the form of President Biden meeting with President Putin – that we believe there are going to be certain areas where our interests align. And you saw that in the context of an agreement last week announced to extend the Syrian humanitarian corridor by 12 months; you see that in – you saw that in the renewal of the New START agreement for five years in the first days of this administration; and Secretary Kerry at the moment is testing the proposition as to whether we can work together on the global and existential challenge of climate change. Russia is one of the world’s most prolific emitters, and so Russia has a responsibility, as does the United States, to be ambitious in its climate targets.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I – so do you expect Secretary Kerry to go to Brazil as well this year before the summit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have any forthcoming travel to announce. I would have to refer you to his office for that.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:13 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2:11 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> All right. Happy Tuesday, everyone. Just a couple things here at the top. I wanted to start with developments in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>As you know, President Biden and Secretary Blinken have made human rights central to our foreign policy, and I would like to address two important issues, as I said before, in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>We continue to follow widespread, peaceful protests throughout Cuba as Cubans are calling for freedom and human rights.</p>
<p>They are standing up to Cuba&#8217;s authoritarian regime.</p>
<p>Their basic needs are not being met and they are understandably exhausted.</p>
<p>We commend the people of Cuba for showing great bravery, the strength of their will, and the power of their voice.</p>
<p>In response, the Cuban Government has attempted to silence their voices and communications through internet shutdowns, violence, and arbitrary detentions of dozens of protesters, journalists, activists, and other repressive tactics.</p>
<p>We remain deeply concerned by the Cuban Government’s, quote, “call to combat” and by the images of violence that we have seen over the past two days. We call for calm and we condemn any violence against those protesting peacefully, and we equally call on the Cuban Government to release anyone detained for peaceful protest.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-venezuela"></a> Turning to Venezuela, the United States strongly condemns the unjust detention of 2015 National Assembly representative Freddy Guevara and harassment of Interim President Juan Guaido in Venezuela.</p>
<p>These reprehensible acts are incompatible with efforts to create conditions for comprehensive negotiations between the Venezuelan opposition and the Nicolas Maduro regime to resolve Venezuela’s crisis.</p>
<p>We call for the immediate release of Congressman Guevara and urge the international community to join us in condemning his detention in the strongest terms.</p>
<p>Venezuelans have suffered for far too long under a regime that engages in widespread repression and human rights abuses, targeting those who are attempting to build a democratic country with leaders and institutions that are accountable to the people.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-china"></a> Next, as part of the whole-of-government effort, multiple U.S. agencies issued an updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory today that describes the heightened risks for businesses that have supply chains and investment links to Xinjiang, China, due to the People’s Republic of China’s ongoing human rights abuses in the region. These include but are not limited to forced labor.</p>
<p>This business advisory was jointly issued by six U.S. Government agencies, and that includes us, the Department of State, the Department of Commerce, Homeland Security, Labor, and Treasury, along with the Office of the United States Trade Representative.</p>
<p>The advisory notes that – the Department of State’s determination that the PRC government is perpetrating genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang. It cautions that given the severity and extent of these and other abuses, businesses and individuals that do not exit supply chains, ventures, and investments connected to Xinjiang could run a high risk of violating U.S. law. You can find the advisory and a fact sheet on the State Department’s website at state.gov.</p>
<p>The release of the updated advisory today underscores the Biden-Harris administration’s commitment to promoting responsible business practices as well as accountability for the PRC government’s abuses in Xinjiang. I note the European Commission and the European External Action Service today published global forced labor guidance to help EU companies address the risk of forced labor and supply chains based on international due diligence guidelines. The United States and the European Union, we share concerns on the use of forced labor in global supply chains and we’re committed to working together to address this issue. We’ll continue to work with our interagency partners, the private sector, and our allies and partners around the world to promote reliable supply chains free from forced labor and call attention to human rights abuses.</p>
<p>So with that, Matt, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. Just logistically, if you’re – before I go to Cuba, if you’re not able to preview the ASEAN meeting that the Secretary is going to participate in tonight, can you just say if you expect that the Burmese foreign minister will be a part of this discussion?</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-asean"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I would need to refer to ASEAN to discuss their participation in tonight’s meeting with Secretary Blinken – virtual meeting, that is. Of course, this will be an important opportunity, and the latest in a series of opportunities the Secretary has had, to reaffirm the centrality of ASEAN and to underscore its essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture.</p>
<p>As you know, we’ve had a number of opportunities to engage with our ASEAN partners. We met with the chair of ASEAN in a recent trip to London several weeks ago now. Deputy Secretary Sherman has been in the region for in-person meetings herself. The Secretary has spoken bilaterally on a number of occasions to his ASEAN counterparts. But I know the Secretary is very much looking forward to this, his first meeting with his fellow ASEAN ministers.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. On Cuba, there are quite a few critics of the previous administration’s Cuba policy who are now, because you haven’t changed that policy at all, by extension, critics of this administration’s Cuba policy who have pointed out or made the argument that the very sharp reduction in remittances that Cuban Americans are allowed to send back to the island is one, not the – not – surely not the only, but is one reason why the basic needs of Cuban people are not being met, as – in your words.</p>
<p>Do you accept – do you see any validity to that argument? And whether you do or not, are remittances or – and allowing them or allowing them to go back up to the level that they were under the Obama administration, is that part of the review?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would say our review is taking a broad look at what we can do to support the core principles at the center of our policy, and that is democracy and human rights. To your point, Matt, we are always considering options available to us that would allow us to support the Cuban people, to support their humanitarian needs, which are indeed profound, and they are profound because of not anything the United States has done, but from the actions and inactions, mismanagement, corruption of the Cuban regime.</p>
<p>Look, the other point I would make is that current U.S. policy, the so-called embargo, it allows humanitarian goods to reach Cuba, and we do expedite any request to export humanitarian or medical supplies to the island. We regularly authorize the export of agricultural products, medicine, medical equipment, and humanitarian goods to Cuba. And we’ve authorized billions of dollars’ worth of goods over the past couple decades, since the latest iteration of this has been in effect. But just in 2020 alone, we exported more than $175 million worth of goods to Cuba, including food and medicine, to help the Cuban people. In the first six months of 2021 alone, Cuba imported $123 million worth of, in this case, chicken from the United States.</p>
<p>Now, the pandemic has added an extra layer of pain and suffering onto the Cuban people as it has around the world, and we share the concern that the Cuban people have as they have faced an exponential rise in COVID cases across the island. Now, Cuba has made a sovereign decision regarding how it will address the pandemic, and that includes, in this case, the use of its own indigenously produced vaccine. Cuba, as you know, has not joined COVAX. The Cuban Government could always decide to receive outside vaccine donations, but the Cuban Government has decided not to do so yet.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, okay, but – so does that mean you do or do not agree with the argument that a sharp reduction in remittances has contributed to the lack of basic needs for &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I have not seen a comprehensive study of it, so I’m not prepared to comment on that from here. What I would say, again, is that we are always looking for ways that we can support the Cuban people. We are consistent – we are constantly reviewing what policy measures might bring that about, and by “bring that about” I mean support of democracy, support for human rights on the island. That policy review is ongoing. We are engaging a wide range of stakeholders. We’re taking a close look not only what our immediate predecessor did but, of course, the actions of the Obama-Biden administration, administrations before that. Across any number of policy areas, we are seeking to learn from and to take into account the lessons of previous administrations – what they’ve done well, where there’s room to do something better or to do something different – and so that’s what we’re doing here. This is no different.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. And then just the last one: You mentioned that the current U.S. policy – you called it the “so-called embargo.” What exactly would you call it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The embargo. I’m not arguing with that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I follow up on that regarding remittances?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because my understanding is that the wire transfers are part of the late November, post-election additional sanctions by the Trump administration and that that is what many Cuban Americans are complaining about, where they can no longer send – from Miami, who support the overall embargo. So I was wondering today if there was any running room, any flexibility that the administration would be considering. Then I asked that question of Senator Menendez within the last hour or two and he said absolutely not, because the Cuban Government takes 20 percent off the top on the remittances and then transfers the money to pesos, the dollars to pesos, and so the people there are getting a fraction of what their relatives are sending home.</p>
<p>That said, I understand he’s been in touch with the White House at the highest levels on this very issue today. Is there anything that the White House would do that would go against the chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee who wrote section two Helms-Burton?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Far be it from me to speak for our – speak for the White House. I will &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, as an administration official, how likely – especially one where nominations go through that committee and are being held by a singular – single Republican.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I will say is that – and I think there is widespread support; we recognize this in the administration; there is widespread support for this idea in Congress – is that the idea that Americans, and especially Cuban Americans, have the potential to be, and oftentimes are, the best – our best ambassadors for what we hope to see on the island nation of Cuba. That is also central to our policy review. We have absolutely been in touch with senior members of Congress. I won’t be in a position to confirm those discussions or to read them out, but as part of our dialogue when it comes to our review of the Cuba policy, we have engaged with Congress. In the aftermath – well, I shouldn’t say the aftermath, of course; they’re still ongoing – in the midst of the protests on Cuba, we have been engaged with senior members of Congress as well.</p>
<p>We do recognize that for our policies to have the most effect, to have broad legitimacy and support, it’s important that they have, to the maximum extent possible, support of Congress, and, of course, Cuba is no different. So those consultations are ongoing. Our policy review is ongoing. Even in the midst of that review, we’re going to be looking for ways we can support the Cuban people.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, when you said that our Cuban Americans are the best advocates, the best ambassadors for democracy versus authoritarianism, let’s say – I’m paraphrasing, but that seems to be the import of what you’re saying – is there some flexibility, as you said you’re discussing with members of Congress, to some of the travel restrictions, COVID permitting?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I’m not in a position to preview what we might do going forward from the podium. What I can say is that even before these protests started, we are looking for ways in the midst of COVID, in the midst of the other hardships that the Cuban people have endured because of, again, the corruption, the mismanagement of their own government – perhaps the indifference of their own government – we are looking for ways that we might support the Cuban people in a way that’s consistent with our interests, that’s consistent with our values.</p>
<p>We are, of course, doing that in the midst of these protests. These protests are about many things, but certainly the suffering of the Cuban people that is – has been made all the more acute during the pandemic. It’s top of mind. Of course, their quest for additional freedom, for human rights, central to it as well, and what we can do in a way that is responsible and effective to support those aims, including their humanitarian needs, we’ll continue to consider and move forward as appropriate.</p>
<p>Lara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Yesterday Jen Psaki said at the White House podium that the United States has spent something like $20 million to support democracy assistance programs in Cuba since 2009. Can you give us some granular detail on how that money was spent? Was it mostly for broadcast channels? Was there nothing else? And if it was mostly for broadcast, was that normal operating costs, or was that above and beyond what had already been budgeted in previous years?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, what Jen was referring to yesterday was the fact that we do provide economic support funds for democracy promotion programs to Cuba on an annual basis, and that amount has been $20 million per year for several years now. And now these U.S.-funded programs, they are – they do go to broadcast funding. They inform the Cuban public through support for independent media. They support Cubans to promote free expression in their communities. They increase access to information on democracy, participatory government, human rights, and market economics. They provide emergency and humanitarian assistance to human rights defenders and to political prisoners, and they prepare those who seek, who aspire, to have a voice in a free and democratic Cuba. All of this funding, all of these programs, they do adhere to the laws and the guidelines laid out in the Helms-Burton Act of 1996 and the Cuban Liberty and Solidarity Act.</p>
<p>We’ve made no secret of the fact that support for democracy, support for human rights, is really at the core of our approach to Cuba. They are going to be anchors of our – not only our policy review, but where we net out on that policy.</p>
<p>I would make one other point, that as these protests have taken place, we have seen the Cuban Government respond with internet shutdowns, with blackouts. These are government-imposed internet shutdowns. And so just as we’ve been doing with this funding, we call on Cuba’s leaders to demonstrate restraint, to urge respect for the voice of the people by opening all means of communication, both online and offline. Shutting down technology, shutting down information pathways – that does nothing to address the legitimate needs and aspirations of the Cuban people. And so we’ve been very clear on that from the start.</p>
<p>Lara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So just to drill down a tiny bit on a technical detail, is it fair to assume that that money has come out of this building and/or USAID? And did it go strictly through NGOs?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course, we’re not providing any funding directly to the Cuban Government. Oftentimes, as you know, we work through partners on the ground. For additional details you may want to reach out USAID for how they may administer it.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-georgia"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. A couple questions about Georgia. I watched your briefing a week ago, where you talked about organized violence on Tbilisi’s streets when Georgian law enforcement, as many allege, intentionally did not stop the violent mob’s attacks on journalists and members of the LGBTQI community. After your briefing, two days ago precisely, a cameraman of TV Pirveli, my colleague, Alexander Lashkarava – this is actually him – he was beaten up by this mob and he died two days ago.</p>
<p>And so my question would be: In light of these events and the recent past events in Georgia, there are serious concerns that Georgia is diverting towards illiberalism. So is the Secretary Blinken comfortable with that development? And also what do you have to say to those people on the street right now who are demanding the resignation of the Prime Minister Irakli Garibashvili? I might have a few follow-ups on that. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Well, first, of course, we extend our deepest condolences to your former colleague Lekso Lashkarava, to his family, loved ones, and of course to his colleagues, yourself included. We’re closely following the reports concerning his death. We do call for calm and an end to the violence that has already caused one tragic loss of life, in this case the death of your colleague. The safety of every Georgian journalist and the credibility of democracy in Georgia, in fact, require that every individual who attacked peaceful protesters and journalists on July 5th and 6th or those who incited violence – they must be identified; they should be arrested and prosecuted to the full extent of the law. We remind Georgia’s leaders and its law enforcement of their responsibility to protect all of those exercising their constitutional rights. We remind them of their responsibility to protect journalists exercising the freedom of press – of the press. And we encourage all Georgians, including Georgian officials, to publicly condemn this type of violence that has no place in a democracy.</p>
<p>We proudly advance efforts around the globe to protect LGBTQI populations from violence and abuse, criminalization, discrimination, and stigma, and we seek to empower local LGBTQI+ movements and persons. We firmly oppose abuses against the LGBTQI+ community and, of course, in this case, the brutal violence against your former colleague, your now deceased colleague. When it comes to the prime minister and his future, that, of course, is a decision for the Georgian people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. My sources on the Capitol Hill are telling me that there are talks on imposing personal sanctions against those officials in the Georgian Government who were directly responsible for the violence we all saw on July 5th. Is this an idea the State Department is also entertaining? How realistic that could be? And very lastly, I would like to know what you think about the responsibility of the opposition political parties in Georgia who are leading those people on the streets. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we have a number of tools to hold accountable those responsible in some way for human rights abuses, for violence around the world. Sanctions are indeed one of those tools. As you know, we don’t preview sanctions before we enact them. But we are following the situation very closely, and we are committed to seeing to it that those responsible for this are held accountable.</p>
<p>When it comes to all political actors in Georgia, again, we urge them to very publicly condemn this violence. When it comes to the Georgian Government, I would reiterate our calls for a thorough investigation of this that leads to the perpetrators of this horrific crime being brought to justice.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-burma"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I wanted to ask about Myanmar. The situation in the country at the moment is that there’s a huge COVID spike and people are calling – people are sort of reporting oxygen shortages, there’s very little medical care, there seems to be very little supply of vaccines. It’s not – Myanmar has not come up, Burma has not come up in – Burma in discussion about vaccine diplomacy or vaccines for other countries. I’m wondering: Is it a possibility to send COVID vaccines or assistance to a country like Myanmar, where you’re currently not in a good relationship with the government? Is that something that you are considering? Is there any way you can give assistance to the people of the country in the current political climate there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, to be very clear, our assistance in the form of vaccines has nothing to do with politics. And again, our goal is to put shots in arms, not to twist arms, knowing that if we are to end this pandemic here in this country and around the world, we have to be in a position to support the distribution of a safe and effective vaccine around the world. And that is precisely what we’ve been doing.</p>
<p>As you know, the President has authorized 80 million from our own domestic stockpile to be distributed. We have announced the allocation of millions of those doses to countries around the world. We have announced the purchase of 500 million Pfizer doses that will start going out next month and into 2022 as well. Working together with the international community in the context of the G7 summit earlier – it was last month now, I suppose – committed to some 1 billion vaccines for the world.</p>
<p>So just because we may not have the best of relations with a particular regime or government does not mean that that diminishes the need for that country’s people. And as you know, it’s – we have bilateral mechanisms to provide vaccines but also COVAX. COVAX is supporting the safe and effective distribution of vaccines around the world. We are working diligently through COVAX, and, in fact, three quarters of our vaccine allotment is going through COVAX. And that’s part and parcel of the $2 billion commitment we made early on to COVAX and the $4 billion total that the United States will vector towards COVAX over time. So the people of Burma are equally deserving of medical care as people around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, follow-up. So far there aren’t – there isn’t any donations of vaccines or other stuff to the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have not made any announcements, but as you know, we continue to work with COVAX. And if we do have a Burma-specific announcement, we’ll be happy to let you know.</p>
<p>Lalit.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. A follow-up on COVAX, but the country is India I wanted to ask me about. Do you know how much – figures of India receiving the COVID-19 vaccines from the U.S. so far? Has India started receiving COVID-19 vaccines from the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as I just said to Simon, as you know, the United States will share 80 million doses from our domestic stockpile with countries around the world. Before we can ship those doses, however, each country must complete its own domestic set of operational, of regulatory, and legal processes that are specific to each country. Now, India has determined that it needs further time to review legal provisions related to accepting vaccine donations. Once India works through its legal processes, our donations of vaccines to India will proceed expeditiously. We would need to refer you to the Government of India on the status of its discussions with COVAX, which, in this case, is helping to facilitate that delivery.</p>
<p>More broadly in the region, throughout South Asia, we’re donating millions of vaccines to Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Nepal, the Maldives, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka. Roughly 40 million doses have been delivered worldwide so far.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the delay in shipping COVID-19 vaccines to India is because of some regulations that India has to clear that, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I would need to refer you to the Indian Government for their processes and where they are internally. But we are ready to ship those vaccines expeditiously when we have a greenlight from the Government of India.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But have you determined how many vaccines you are planning to ship to India?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ve announced that. I – we can get that for you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And can you also give us a sense of cooperation between India and U.S. on COVID-19 vaccines development and production and also to the third-world countries?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And – what was the last part of your question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And also the third-world countries.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Absolutely. So cooperation between our two countries, it is not the product of something – of only something that was built in the context of COVID. It actually builds on decades of successful partnership between our two countries in health, in biomedical research. We are partnering to strengthen the global response to COVID-19 on issues ranging from addressing infectious disease outbreaks to strengthening health systems to securing global supply chains.</p>
<p>We recently welcomed an initiative to collaborate through the International Center of Excellence in Research focused on infectious diseases, and in this case that includes COVID-19 and other emerging threats. And we look forward to an overarching MOU, a memorandum of understanding, to enhance health cooperation beyond that.</p>
<p>We are further working on diagnostics, therapeutics, vaccines to combat the disease and to recognize the importance of manufacturing critical drugs during this time and to making them accessible globally. And we’re able to do that because India’s pharmaceutical sector is strong, it’s well-established, it has played a central role in manufacturing vaccines for global use over some time. And we’re pleased that U.S. pharmaceutical companies in turn are coordinating with their Indian counterparts since the beginning of the pandemic. As you know, beyond this partnership, in the context of the Quad leader’s summit, there was an agreement to work with India to boost manufacturing of COVID vaccines that would support a safe and effective and eventually universal distribution of vaccines around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One final one. The situation – the pandemic situation in India has improved quite considerably in the last few weeks. The U.S. had imposed some travel restrictions on people coming from India. Now the situation is improving. Are you reviewing it and when do you think this will be lifted?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would say there are a couple of things at play here. When it comes to the travel restrictions, as you know, that is something that we are taking a close look at – the U.S. Government, I should say, is taking a close look at. There are expert groups that have been formed. And “experts” in this case refers primarily to medical professionals, because for us this is not a decision about politics; this is a decision about public health and the safety of the American people but also the safety of the global traveling public. And we want to make sure that this decision is adjudicated with that central principle in mind.</p>
<p>The State Department, for our part, we also routinely issue travel advisories and we routinely update them for all countries based on a comprehensive review of available safety information and ongoing developments. We review those regularly and we make updates as warranted.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned, very much. I have a follow-up on Cuba, but first I want to ask two questions on Brazil.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-brazil"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Brazilian president wants to change next election process back to a paper vote. He has alleged that fraud in previous election, without giving evidence, and last week he threatened to cancel next election next year if there is not a clean one. So what is the administration reaction, response to these claims? And does the U.S. have confidence that the previous past elections in Brazil were fair, and the next one will also be fair?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What we call for – and this is not unique to Brazil, but it’s what we call for around the world – are free and fair elections, the ability of the people to exercise their will freely and fairly. And so the mechanics of an election are typically not of consequence to us. What is of consequence is the character of an election, and so we will be looking to see to it that elections around the world – but including in Brazil – are free and fair.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you being patient to these claims that the president is making? He is following Trump’s playbook when it comes to election fraud.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would not want to characterize what the Brazilian president is saying, but I will characterize where we stand on the exercise of democracy, the ability of peoples around the world to exercise their free will, and that’s free and fair elections in our view are important. They are important in democracies; they are important in aspiring democracies. They are a key metric as we determine the health of democracies and the health of participatory electoral systems around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And another one, because harassment against journalists also in Brazil has increased since President Bolsonaro took office. Last week the organization Reporters Without Borders included Bolsonaro on a list of press predators, alongside 37 authoritarian leaders like Bashar al-Assad and Vladimir Putin. And also last week president’s lawyer sent a message to a female reporter saying that in China, she would be – she would disappear and her body would not be found. So what is – is this kind of threat is something that worries this administration, coming from Bolsonaro’s government?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, generally the department is always concerned when journalists face threats of harassment, face threats of intimidation, and especially when there are threats of violence. We already spoke of one especially tragic case during the course of this briefing. Freedom of the press, freedom of expression more broadly, is something we support around the world. In order to have freedom of the press, freedom of expression, you have to stand up for the safety and security of journalists and reporters around the world. So I haven’t taken a close look at the study you mentioned, but we certainly have seen, broadly speaking, an uptick in threats of intimidation, threats of violence of reporters globally.</p>
<p>As you know, the Secretary, just in advance of World Press Freedom Day, in May of this year, hosted a group of journalists, many of whom have faced intimidation, threats of violence in their own work. And we did that very purposefully, to put a spotlight on this challenge. And it’s a challenge that not only comes from governments; sometimes nongovernmental organizations and actors, terrorist groups, and others take part in this. But journalists should never face threats, face danger in the course of their work for what it is they may report, for what it is they may uncover.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Would these violations of human rights impact the bilateral relationship between Brazil and the U.S., since you are saying this administration put human rights at the center of foreign policy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, that’s exactly the point. And it’s not unique to Brazil; it’s not unique to any one country. But in every relationship we have – this includes with our closest partners; it includes those with whom we may have profound disagreements – we are always going to be taking a close look at a country’s human rights record to seek improvement where we can, but ultimately to see to it that people around the world are protected in exercising their universal rights, their universal freedoms. The United States will always be a voice for that. Oftentimes we do make that point publicly, but in private conversations as well we don’t shy away, and we do what we can in our assessment as – in the means most effective for us to protect and to safeguard human rights around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just – can I do a very quick follow-up on Cuba?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because during the campaign, President Biden said that Trump’s reversals on Cuba policy have inflicted harm to the Cuban people and done nothing to advance democracy and human rights. So does President Biden still want to change Trump’s policy on Cuba? And when would be a good time, if not now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are undertaking a review of our – of a Cuba policy precisely to determine how best we can support the human rights of Cubans, how best we can support the prospect for democracy on the island. Now, of course, successive administrations have sought in some ways to do that, and so as I said before, we are going to be taking a close look at what has and has not worked in the past, and unfortunately, in the case of Cuba there may be more that has not worked than what has worked. And so we are going to be, as we’ve done in other cases as well, studying that very closely to determine what we can do most effectively, consistent with our values, consistent with our interests, to move the ball forward, especially when it comes to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Will Cuba become a priority now, after the events on the ground?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course, you heard from the President directly, you heard from the Secretary directly standing right here. We have not been shy about speaking to what is going on. Of course, it’s always a priority for us when citizens are taking to the streets peacefully to express their aspirations for democracy and human rights. We’ll continue to watch this very closely.</p>
<p>Yes, Rich.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I want to stay in the hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’ll – in the hemisphere? Were you staying in the hemisphere?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I was going to go to a different hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, let’s stay in the hemisphere. I’ll come right back to you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-haiti"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So in Haiti – is the U.S. team in Haiti assisting the assassination investigation part of a U.S. foreign emergency support team? Do you know who from this building was part of the U.S. delegation went to Haiti on Sunday? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right. So there was an interagency delegation that was in Haiti on Sunday. DAS Lochman from our Western Hemisphere Affairs Bureau represented the department in discussions on Sunday. The team was deployed in order to take part in an assessment of how best the United States can support the Haitian people as they respond to this. Right now we’re focusing on that investigation, what we might be able to do to support the Haitian investigation into the assassination of President Moise.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is anyone from the FEST, the foreign emergency support team, there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we’ll get back to you on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Uh-huh. And what is the U.S. message to Haitian people standing outside of U.S. embassy, asking for political asylum?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I understand that the situation in front of our Embassy in Port-au-Prince is now calm. The groups that were gathered there, I understand, have dissipated. As we do around the world, we encourage Haitians, in this case, not to gather in front of our embassy. For their own safety, for their own security, we continue to urge calm across the – across Haiti. We have heard Acting Prime Minister Joseph make very similar calls, other political actors make similar calls, calling for calm. We reiterate those. That is precisely what Haiti needs, as Haiti’s political actors, we hope, will work together in the interests of the Haitian people to make meaningful progress in efforts to form a consensus government that can lead to free and fair elections.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So have the Haitians made any requests that you guys have said no to?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right now we are evaluating a number of requests. We are evaluating how best we can support the needs of the Haitian Government at the moment. As I said right now, much of that focuses on the ongoing investigation into the killing of President Moise. In addition to the interagency team, the FBI and DHS have been engaged on the ground as well to determine the investigative assets, investigative support that Haiti may need on its investigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So does that mean the answer is no, you haven’t denied any requests, at least yet?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re still evaluating. I don’t believe we &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, fine. But have you said no to anything?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah. I don’t believe we have denied any requests right yet, but we’re still evaluating quite a bit.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one follow-up &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But as you said yesterday, the focus is on the investigation rather than security assistance, which was a request. So is there a response to that request?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as I think you’ve heard from the Pentagon and from the White House, we are evaluating requests for assistance, just as we would requests from assistance in other contexts. We know in this case that there may be needs for protection in the context of critical infrastructure. We’re taking a close look at that as well. FBI and DHS, as I said before, have been engaging with their Haitian counterparts, but all of these requests we’re evaluating in line with our assessment of how we can best assist the Haitian people and the Haitian Government.</p>
<p>Rich.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-olympics"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. The European Parliament has voted for a diplomatic boycott of the upcoming Winter Olympics. Does the U.S. support that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Do we support their &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> They’re boycotting. Would – is the U.S. considering or will the U.S. follow suit and do the same?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are – what is true is that we are closely consulting with allies and partners, as well as other actors, including the business community, to identify common concerns and, ideally, to establish a common approach regarding the 2022 Winter Olympics and Paralympic Games. We’ll continue to speak out consistently in the meantime, and again, jointly with allies and partners when it comes to what we’re seeing from PRC officials. And we’ll continue to impose costs and sanctions on those responsible for human rights abuses, including the state sponsorship of forced labor. And just today, as I said at the outset of the briefing, you saw the updated business advisory that came from the Department of State and several of our interagency partners. But right now, we are engaged in discussions to establish those common concerns, and I don’t have anything for you beyond that.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-china2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the U.S. – as you – as the U.S. engages with its allies on this decision-making process, did the European Union or those countries engage? Was that – their decision the result of consultations with the United States?</p>
<p>And then sort of separately on your talking about the business community and today’s advisory, can you confirm that we can expect one on Hong Kong? And the Xinjiang advisory is about three dozen pages. Succinctly, what is the message to the business community? That this type of activity, knowingly having forced labor in your supply chains, is immoral – which it is, clearly, in the statement – or is it illegal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think what we said in – at the outset is that companies that engage with entities and who are enmeshed in supply chains in Xinjiang do face potential legal exposure. And the business advisory was quite clear on that.</p>
<p>When it comes to the EU and how they arrived at this decision, I’m not going to speak for the EU. I will let them speak for themselves. I will say that the EU, of course, is an important partner when it comes to any number of issues, and that in part is predicated on our shared values. And I would make the broader point that you have seen a great deal of convergence between the United States and our European allies on – based on those values in the context of the PRC and Xinjiang in particular. Let me give you just a few examples.</p>
<p>At the G7 summit, President Biden and Chancellor Merkel outlined our shared positions on China. The President had an opportunity to meet with a number of his other counterparts, including British Prime Minister Johnson and others, to discuss the importance of coordinating and responding to China’s non-market practices and the need to speak out on human rights abuses, including in Xinjiang and Hong Kong. The communique that resulted from the G7 summit also addressed the need for action against forced labor practices in the agricultural, solar, and garment sectors. There was an entire paragraph – paragraph 49, I belive it was – dedicated to this issue and showcasing the convergence.</p>
<p>At the NATO summit, the communique for the first time ever addressed the security challenges from China. And the United States and our NATO Allies, many of whom are European, of course, agreed to draft a new strategic concept, a framework that will guide the Alliance’s approach to the evolving strategic environment in the coming years – not only to address Russia’s aggressive actions, but also those posed by the PRC to our collective security.</p>
<p>And then, of course, at the U.S.-EU summit the leaders launched the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council, the goal – whose goal is to write the rules of the road for the economy of the 21st century in areas like emerging technology and competition policy. And we’ve also put forward a series of affirmative ideas, Build Back Better World being at the center of this, offering and making clear that, one, democracies can deliver; and two, there is an alternative, attractive model to what other countries may be offering here.</p>
<p>When it comes to Hong Kong, we don’t have anything to announce at this time regarding future policy moves. You’ve heard from us on any number of occasions our concern regarding Beijing’s ongoing attempts to undermine Hong Kong’s autonomy, to dismantle its democratic institutions and processes. We’ll continue to call international attention to and to hold PRC and Hong Kong authorities accountable for the erosion of the rule of law in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>I would make one additional broader point here. We know that a healthy business community relies on the rule of law, which the national security law that applies to Hong Kong continues to undermine. As a general matter, we seek to ensure that businesses can operate in a stable, predictable, and fair regulatory environments around the world. And rule of law risks that were formerly limited to mainland China are now increasingly a concern in Hong Kong. That’s of great concern to us. It is of great concern to the American business community. It’s of great concern to the international business community.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-haiti2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Cuba – just because you’re on Cuba – my colleague asked about the urgency of this ongoing policy review. Is there a timeline for completion? I think we’ve continued to ask, and obviously the protests sort of lend a greater immediacy to the question.</p>
<p>And then on Haiti, are you – is the administration particularly concerned about instability in the country as a result of this dispute over control of the government? And is the State Department or the interagency going to continue to engage with all of the claimants to power?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we have engaged with a wide variety of stakeholders in Haiti. The interagency delegation that was there over the weekend met with Claude Joseph, Ariel Henry, Joseph Lambert, and others. And we have continued to urge these political actors to work together in the interests of the Haitian people.</p>
<p>We have called on Haitian political leaders, the Haitian private sector, civil society to come together to – importantly, to strengthen the democratic institutions and to reach an inclusive solution that will facilitate peace and stability and lead to presidential and legislative elections.</p>
<p>For us, this is about – the guiding principles are Haiti’s constitution, its institutions, and we have urged Haitian political actors to work together in the interests of their people to make meaningful progress in that effort to form a consensus government that ultimately can lead to free and fair elections. And of course, the Haitian constitution calls for those free and fair elections later this year.</p>
<p>Beyond this immediate political situation, Haiti’s political gridlock has long taken a great toll on the country, and it’s vital for Haiti’s leaders to finally come together to chart a united path for the country. The United States will continue to be a partner to the Haitian people. We will continue to engage constructively with Haiti’s political actors and its broader set of stakeholders to do what we can to help support Haiti’s political leaders finding this consensus solution.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-cuba4"></a> On the Cuba policy review, of course, we are moving as expeditiously as appropriate in this case. We are making sure that we are consulting with, as I said before, a broad and wide variety of stakeholders. We are taking a close look at what the United States can best do to support the needs of the Cuban people, to support their legitimate and long-denied aspirations for democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-egypt"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I ask about Egypt?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There was a report yesterday in Politico that Mohamed Soltan, whose case I’m sure you’re familiar with, that there was an agreement by the State Department under the previous administration, at least something signed, to the effect that he would be again in custody of the United States and that Egypt’s intelligence chief has raised that again.</p>
<p>First of all, is there any truth to the – to that initial finding that there was some document there? Was this raised? And do you have any comment overall on his situation now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we’re aware of the document that was reported related to Mohamed Soltan, of course, a U.S. citizen. He was formerly imprisoned in Egypt. We don’t have a comment on its legal authority.</p>
<p>What I would remind you, though, is what we said at the time: The United States condemned the detention of Mr. Soltan and we called for his immediate release. It’s something that we worked for very assiduously.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could you say whether the Egyptians have raised this again?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position to detail that.</p>
<p>Lara.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-iran"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Staying in that region, if we could go to Iran. There is a report out of Tehran today that a government spokesman said that Iran and the United States are negotiating for prisoners exchanges.</p>
<p>First, I assume that was not a direct negotiation, but if it was, could you please comment?</p>
<p>And then secondly, this seems like a good opportunity to ask about the status of the talks and what effort is being made to break the current stalemate, or hold, or logjam, or whatever we want to call it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, first on the question of detainees, you are correct; it is indirect but active discussions taking place on this – to this end, seeing the release of the Americans who have been unjustly detained, deprived of their freedom for far too long now. We are treating the issue of detainees independently from discussions of the JCPOA, as you know. It&#8217;s really a matter of us to see to it that these detainees are released as soon as possible. We are working with the utmost urgency and we want it to be resolved immediately. We&#8217;re working night and day to bring these detainees, these American citizens home. We&#8217;re also working with our allies, many of whom also have citizens currently arbitrarily or wrongfully detained by the Iranian Government.</p>
<p>Look, the broader point is that Iran&#8217;s unjust imprisonment of U.S. citizens for use as political leverage, it&#8217;s abhorrent, it&#8217;s outrageous. Our priority is bringing these individuals home as possible and resolving the cases of missing and abducted U.S. citizens just as quickly as we can.</p>
<p>When it comes to the status of the talks, we&#8217;ve discussed this yesterday, but questions about when or whether Iran would be prepared to start a seventh round of talks or to reach an understanding on a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA, those questions have to be addressed to Tehran. They can&#8217;t be addressed to us. As we&#8217;ve made clear, we are prepared to continue engaging in the context of these indirect negotiations with Iran. We&#8217;re prepared to return to a seventh round of talks. We&#8217;ve been equally clear that there&#8217;s not a deadline, a firm deadline that we have in mind as of right now, but we&#8217;ve made no secret of the fact that we are considering the implications of Iran’s nuclear advances for a potential return to the JCPOA. So we&#8217;re watching very closely.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Great. Ned, just on the indirect, active – indirect but active discussions on the – is there anything new about this today other than the fact that an Iranian official said this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Anything new over the course of the last couple months? We&#8217;ve known about these talks for some time. They&#8217;ve been going on, yes, separately from the nuclear talks, but still they&#8217;ve been going on. And I think that senior officials who we all know has talked about it pretty openly.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I – correct me, Lara, if I&#8217;m wrong, but I think Lara asked a question just based on what an Iranian official said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no, no, I know. But I&#8217;m wondering, it&#8217;s – I’m not saying it&#8217;s not a valid question. I just wonder if there&#8217;s anything new today that was not new last week or the week before or the month – a month before or two months or three months.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, I think we have found in the cases – in the case of Americans who are held against their will unjustly around the world that these discussions are best undertaken quietly, and we often don&#8217;t speak to the details from the podium precisely because we are doing everything we can and working as urgently as we can to secure their release. I&#8217;m just not in a position to update on where these indirect discussions may be.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, yeah, but they&#8217;ve been going on for months, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, they&#8217;ve been going on before this administration took office. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>That’s – yes, I mean – okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-indopacificasean"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, thank you, Ned. Two questions, please. First, on the Secretary&#8217;s ASEAN foreign ministers meeting later this evening, last week Kurt Campbell spoke at an event where he said I think we have been “missing in action” in many respects in the Pacific. He said we recognize fully that for an effective Asia strategy you must do more in Southeast Asia. And he said we want in the next little while to step up our game substantially.</p>
<p>So first, would the State Department agree that the U.S. has been missing in action in the Pacific? And will the Secretary&#8217;s message today be about greater U.S. engagement in Southeast Asia? And then I have a follow-up on China.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So this is a region, the Indo-Pacific, that is vitally important to us for any number of interests, but also our values. I think what the Secretary will say tonight – and I expect we&#8217;ll have a readout after the session concludes – is a reaffirmation of our commitment to ASEAN’s centrality and a reaffirmation of ASEAN’s central and essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture. The Secretary will have the first opportunity tonight to speak to ASEAN – at least to the foreign ministers – as a whole, but as you know, we did meet with the Bruneian foreign minister in London, current chair of ASEAN; the Secretary has been in contact bilaterally with – over the phone and in person with a number of ASEAN members. Deputy Secretary Sherman was – traveled to the region several weeks ago, where she met with ASEAN counterparts.</p>
<p>So I think both in terms of word and deed, we have demonstrated our commitment to the centrality of ASEAN. We know of its indispensable and central role to the regional architecture. But I wouldn’t want to get ahead of the Secretary’s engagement tonight.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-china3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And then – excuse me – on China, China’s Foreign Ministry has responded to yesterday’s atrocities report, and they’ve said that the U.S. is no position to point fingers at other countries’ human rights situation. They gave examples of past treatment of Native Americans, I think they brought up George Floyd, and they called the report a waste of paper. Do you have any response to that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have a response to that. I will just say, without commenting on what sounds like the PRC playbook, that we have been very clear that as part of our commitment to human rights – our defense, our promotion of human rights around the world – that as a confident democracy, as a country that is comfortable and confident in its standing, we can be open, we can be transparent about where we have veered off course, where we have not met the ideals that – towards which we strive every day. After all, and as we often like to point out, this country was not born a perfect union. It is our essential mission every day to form a more perfect union.</p>
<p>Where that imperfection has been on display, at least speaking for this administration, we have not sought to sweep it under the rug, we’ve not sought to hide it from the rest of the world. We know that for the health, for the wellbeing of our own democracy, it’s important that we are open and transparent but also to be the model that we aspire to be for other democracies and aspiring democracies around the world. We set an important example by comporting ourselves in that.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, everyone. Very quick? Very – yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-258775-russiaclimate"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Quickly, Special Envoy John Kerry’s meeting in Russia, because it was reported by media reports that the U.S. is trying to setting up some proposal to work with Russia on climate change. Do you have any readout on his meetings in Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have a readout at the moment. I do expect that the special envoy’s office will be in a position to provide additional details at the conclusion of his meetings there. Of course, it is not a secret that we have profound differences with the Russian Federation on any number of issues, and I need not go into them. But it’s also not a secret – and you saw this in the form of President Biden meeting with President Putin – that we believe there are going to be certain areas where our interests align. And you saw that in the context of an agreement last week announced to extend the Syrian humanitarian corridor by 12 months; you see that in – you saw that in the renewal of the New START agreement for five years in the first days of this administration; and Secretary Kerry at the moment is testing the proposition as to whether we can work together on the global and existential challenge of climate change. Russia is one of the world’s most prolific emitters, and so Russia has a responsibility, as does the United States, to be ambitious in its climate targets.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I – so do you expect Secretary Kerry to go to Brazil as well this year before the summit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have any forthcoming travel to announce. I would have to refer you to his office for that.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:13 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken&#8217;s Call with OAS Secretary General Almagro</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-oas-secretary-general-almagro/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Secretary General of the Organization of American States (OAS) Luis Almagro to discuss the situation in Haiti following the assassination of President Jovenel Moïse. The Secretary expressed appreciation for the work of the OAS to support democracy in Haiti. The Secretary underscored the United States’ commitment to working with the OAS and our international partners to help Haitian institutions restore security and to pave the way for free and fair legislative and presidential elections in 2021. Secretary Blinken also expressed concern with the political and security situation the Haitian people are enduring and reiterated the United States’ support for democratic governance and stability in Haiti.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Secretary General of the Organization of American States (OAS) Luis Almagro to discuss the situation in Haiti following the assassination of President Jovenel Moïse. The Secretary expressed appreciation for the work of the OAS to support democracy in Haiti. The Secretary underscored the United States’ commitment to working with the OAS and our international partners to help Haitian institutions restore security and to pave the way for free and fair legislative and presidential elections in 2021. Secretary Blinken also expressed concern with the political and security situation the Haitian people are enduring and reiterated the United States’ support for democratic governance and stability in Haiti.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States of America and Republic of Ghana Sign a Memorandum of Understanding Concerning Strategic Civil Nuclear Cooperation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-of-america-and-republic-of-ghana-sign-a-memorandum-of-understanding-concerning-strategic-civil-nuclear-cooperation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 20:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the United States of America and Republic of Ghana signed a Memorandum of Understanding Concerning Strategic Civil Nuclear Cooperation (NCMOU), which improves our cooperation on nuclear energy and strengthens our diplomatic and economic relationship.</p>
<p>Dr. C.S. Eliot Kang, the Senior Official for Arms Control and International Security, signed for the United States, and Hon. Kwaku Ampratwum Sarpong, Deputy Minister for Foreign Affairs and Regional Integration, signed for Ghana.</p>
<p>The United States and Ghana have an enduring diplomatic relationship, which includes long-standing cooperation in the fields of security, energy and commerce.  Cooperation in nuclear energy, science and technology can lead to significant contributions to clean energy, agricultural improvements, clean water, advanced medical treatments, and more.</p>
<p>Nuclear Cooperation MOUs are diplomatic mechanisms that strengthen and expand strategic ties between the United States and a partner country by providing a framework for cooperation on civil nuclear issues and for engagement between experts from government, industry, national laboratories, and academic institutions.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the United States of America and Republic of Ghana signed a Memorandum of Understanding Concerning Strategic Civil Nuclear Cooperation (NCMOU), which improves our cooperation on nuclear energy and strengthens our diplomatic and economic relationship.</p>
<p>Dr. C.S. Eliot Kang, the Senior Official for Arms Control and International Security, signed for the United States, and Hon. Kwaku Ampratwum Sarpong, Deputy Minister for Foreign Affairs and Regional Integration, signed for Ghana.</p>
<p>The United States and Ghana have an enduring diplomatic relationship, which includes long-standing cooperation in the fields of security, energy and commerce.  Cooperation in nuclear energy, science and technology can lead to significant contributions to clean energy, agricultural improvements, clean water, advanced medical treatments, and more.</p>
<p>Nuclear Cooperation MOUs are diplomatic mechanisms that strengthen and expand strategic ties between the United States and a partner country by providing a framework for cooperation on civil nuclear issues and for engagement between experts from government, industry, national laboratories, and academic institutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Commission of the International Tracing Service Annual Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/international-commission-of-the-international-tracing-service-annual-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 20:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>I’m pleased to welcome you all to the 84<sup>th</sup> meeting of the International Commission of the International Tracing Service.</p>
<p>“Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it,” the philosopher George Santayana once wrote.</p>
<p>For decades, the International Tracing Service and now the Arolsen Archives have ensured that each generation remembers the history of the Holocaust and of Nazi persecution—and never, never repeats it.</p>
<p>From the earliest days after World War II, as the International Tracing Service brought families back together… to the rise of the internet, which has connected this “paper monument” with people all over the world… the Archives have grown and changed with the times.</p>
<p>Over the last year, the Arolsen Archives have faced unique challenges, as the COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted programs and made research even more difficult.</p>
<p>I want to recognize the leadership of Cherrie  Daniels, the Special Envoy for Holocaust Issues, and the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, in chairing the International Commission this year. And I want to thank every nation represented on the International Commission for your commitment to preserving and teaching this history.</p>
<p>You have found innovative ways to tell the stories of the Holocaust, even in the depths of the pandemic.</p>
<p>More than 18,000 volunteers—many of them young people from Germany, the United States, and other countries—have joined the “Every Name Counts” project. They have transcribed more than 3.6 million handwritten documents with the names of people victimized or murdered by the Nazis.</p>
<p>This crowdsourced initiative lets people “put their hands on history,” even from their own homes. It helps expand the reach of the Arolsen Archives. And it keeps each individual victim’s memory alive.</p>
<p>And as travel restrictions are lifted, the “Stolen Memory” project will once again travel to towns and cities across Germany, and also expand to Spain and Russia. This pop-up, interactive exhibit helps make the Holocaust tangible to people, by using personal items to tell the stories of concentration camp inmates and their surviving relatives.</p>
<p>Soon, the United States and Germany will be joining together to fund additional traveling exhibits, telling the stories of millions of Holocaust victims and forced laborers from Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>In recent years, we have seen a rise in anti-Semitic attacks in the United States, in Europe, and elsewhere.</p>
<p>We have seen anti-Semitic tropes and rhetoric spread unchecked via social media and the internet.</p>
<p>And we have seen concerted efforts to try to cast doubt on the very facts of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>All of these trends remind us that the work of the Arolsen Archives is as urgent and important as it has ever been.</p>
<p>And they also remind us that authoritarian actors always try to gain power by sowing division, bigotry, and hatred—and by spreading misinformation and lies.</p>
<p>It is up to all of us to resist those forces—including by preserving, understanding, and speaking the truth about the Holocaust and Nazi atrocities.</p>
<p>Thank you again for all the work that you do, and for your tireless efforts to connect the histories contained in the Arolsen Archives with people all around the world.</p>
<p>I send you my very best wishes for a successful annual meeting.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1111110011" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>I’m pleased to welcome you all to the 84<sup>th</sup> meeting of the International Commission of the International Tracing Service.</p>
<p>“Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it,” the philosopher George Santayana once wrote.</p>
<p>For decades, the International Tracing Service and now the Arolsen Archives have ensured that each generation remembers the history of the Holocaust and of Nazi persecution—and never, never repeats it.</p>
<p>From the earliest days after World War II, as the International Tracing Service brought families back together… to the rise of the internet, which has connected this “paper monument” with people all over the world… the Archives have grown and changed with the times.</p>
<p>Over the last year, the Arolsen Archives have faced unique challenges, as the COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted programs and made research even more difficult.</p>
<p>I want to recognize the leadership of Cherrie  Daniels, the Special Envoy for Holocaust Issues, and the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, in chairing the International Commission this year. And I want to thank every nation represented on the International Commission for your commitment to preserving and teaching this history.</p>
<p>You have found innovative ways to tell the stories of the Holocaust, even in the depths of the pandemic.</p>
<p>More than 18,000 volunteers—many of them young people from Germany, the United States, and other countries—have joined the “Every Name Counts” project. They have transcribed more than 3.6 million handwritten documents with the names of people victimized or murdered by the Nazis.</p>
<p>This crowdsourced initiative lets people “put their hands on history,” even from their own homes. It helps expand the reach of the Arolsen Archives. And it keeps each individual victim’s memory alive.</p>
<p>And as travel restrictions are lifted, the “Stolen Memory” project will once again travel to towns and cities across Germany, and also expand to Spain and Russia. This pop-up, interactive exhibit helps make the Holocaust tangible to people, by using personal items to tell the stories of concentration camp inmates and their surviving relatives.</p>
<p>Soon, the United States and Germany will be joining together to fund additional traveling exhibits, telling the stories of millions of Holocaust victims and forced laborers from Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>In recent years, we have seen a rise in anti-Semitic attacks in the United States, in Europe, and elsewhere.</p>
<p>We have seen anti-Semitic tropes and rhetoric spread unchecked via social media and the internet.</p>
<p>And we have seen concerted efforts to try to cast doubt on the very facts of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>All of these trends remind us that the work of the Arolsen Archives is as urgent and important as it has ever been.</p>
<p>And they also remind us that authoritarian actors always try to gain power by sowing division, bigotry, and hatred—and by spreading misinformation and lies.</p>
<p>It is up to all of us to resist those forces—including by preserving, understanding, and speaking the truth about the Holocaust and Nazi atrocities.</p>
<p>Thank you again for all the work that you do, and for your tireless efforts to connect the histories contained in the Arolsen Archives with people all around the world.</p>
<p>I send you my very best wishes for a successful annual meeting.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1111110011" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issuance of the Updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/issuance-of-the-updated-xinjiang-supply-chain-business-advisory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 14:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State, alongside the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Commerce, the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the U.S. Department of Labor, issued an <a href="https://www.state.gov/xinjiang-supply-chain-business-advisory/">updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory</a> in response to the government of the People’s Republic of China&#8217;s (PRC) ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and the growing evidence of its use of forced labor there. The updated Advisory highlights the heightened risks for businesses with supply chain and investment links to Xinjiang given the entities complicit in forced labor and other human rights abuses there and throughout China.</p>
<p>Among other elements, the updated Business Advisory:</p>
<ul>
<li>Includes information from the Department of Labor and the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, which are now co-signatories;</li>
<li>Notes that the PRC government is perpetrating genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang;</li>
<li>Provides specific information regarding risks related to investment in PRC companies linked to surveillance and forced labor in Xinjiang;</li>
<li>Strengthens recommendations for businesses regarding the risks and potential exposure related to supply chains and investment links to Xinjiang, including but not limited to surveillance;</li>
<li>Updates the list of U.S. government enforcement actions in and in connection to Xinjiang;</li>
<li>Adds information on silicon and polysilicon supply chains linked to Xinjiang; and</li>
<li>Provides a list of other countries’ relevant regulatory provisions and information on forced labor in supply chains.</li>
</ul>
<p>The United States will continue to promote accountability for the PRC’s atrocities and other abuses through a whole-of-government effort and in close coordination with the private sector and our allies and partners.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State, alongside the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Commerce, the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the U.S. Department of Labor, issued an <a href="https://www.state.gov/xinjiang-supply-chain-business-advisory/">updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory</a> in response to the government of the People’s Republic of China&#8217;s (PRC) ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and the growing evidence of its use of forced labor there. The updated Advisory highlights the heightened risks for businesses with supply chain and investment links to Xinjiang given the entities complicit in forced labor and other human rights abuses there and throughout China.</p>
<p>Among other elements, the updated Business Advisory:</p>
<ul>
<li>Includes information from the Department of Labor and the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, which are now co-signatories;</li>
<li>Notes that the PRC government is perpetrating genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang;</li>
<li>Provides specific information regarding risks related to investment in PRC companies linked to surveillance and forced labor in Xinjiang;</li>
<li>Strengthens recommendations for businesses regarding the risks and potential exposure related to supply chains and investment links to Xinjiang, including but not limited to surveillance;</li>
<li>Updates the list of U.S. government enforcement actions in and in connection to Xinjiang;</li>
<li>Adds information on silicon and polysilicon supply chains linked to Xinjiang; and</li>
<li>Provides a list of other countries’ relevant regulatory provisions and information on forced labor in supply chains.</li>
</ul>
<p>The United States will continue to promote accountability for the PRC’s atrocities and other abuses through a whole-of-government effort and in close coordination with the private sector and our allies and partners.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issuance of Updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/issuance-of-updated-xinjiang-supply-chain-business-advisory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 14:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today the U.S. Department of State, alongside the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Commerce, the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the U.S. Department of Labor issued an <a href="https://www.state.gov/xinjiang-supply-chain-business-advisory/">updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory</a> to highlight the heightened risks for businesses with supply chain and investment links to Xinjiang, given the entities complicit in forced labor and other human rights abuses there and throughout China. This updates the original Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory issued by U.S. government agencies on July 1, 2020.</p>
<p>The PRC government continues its horrific abuses in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (Xinjiang) and elsewhere in China, targeting Uyghurs, ethnic Kazakhs, and ethnic Kyrgyz who are predominantly Muslim, and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups. These abuses include widespread, state-sponsored forced labor and intrusive surveillance, forced population control measures and separation of children from families, mass detention, and other human rights abuses amidst ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity. Given the severity and extent of these abuses, businesses and individuals that do not exit supply chains, ventures, and/or investments connected to Xinjiang could run a high risk of violating U.S. law. The updated advisory highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>Information related to widespread, state-sponsored forced labor and intrusive surveillance in and related to Xinjiang;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information related to the various kinds of risks and potential exposure to state-sponsored forced labor and human rights abuses related to Xinjiang;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Department of State Guidance on Implementing the “UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights” for Transactions Linked to Foreign Government End-Users for Products or Services with Surveillance Capabilities;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information for investors in PRC companies linked to surveillance in Xinjiang;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information on due diligence related to banking, financial institutions and other investors;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information from the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative and the U.S. Department of Labor;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Updated information about U.S. government actions taken in response to human rights abuses in and in connection to Xinjiang, including but not limited to the issuance of Withhold Release Orders by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the addition of entities to the U.S. Department of Commerce Entity List, the imposition of economic sanctions by the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the imposition of visa restrictions by the U.S. Department of State, and the addition of goods to the U.S. Department of Labor’s <i>List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor </i>(Annex 1);</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information on forced labor in the Xinjiang silicon and polysilicon supply chain and the prevalence of inputs sourced from <wbr />Xinjiang (Annex 4); and</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>A list of other countries’ regulatory provisions and information on forced labor in supply chains (Annex 7).</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, contact <a href="mailto:DRL-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DRL-Press@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/key-topics-bureau-of-democracy-human-rights-and-labor/business-and-human-rights/">https://www.state.gov/key-topics-bureau-of-democracy-human-rights-and-labor/business-and-human-rights/</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today the U.S. Department of State, alongside the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Commerce, the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the U.S. Department of Labor issued an <a href="https://www.state.gov/xinjiang-supply-chain-business-advisory/">updated Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory</a> to highlight the heightened risks for businesses with supply chain and investment links to Xinjiang, given the entities complicit in forced labor and other human rights abuses there and throughout China. This updates the original Xinjiang Supply Chain Business Advisory issued by U.S. government agencies on July 1, 2020.</p>
<p>The PRC government continues its horrific abuses in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (Xinjiang) and elsewhere in China, targeting Uyghurs, ethnic Kazakhs, and ethnic Kyrgyz who are predominantly Muslim, and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups. These abuses include widespread, state-sponsored forced labor and intrusive surveillance, forced population control measures and separation of children from families, mass detention, and other human rights abuses amidst ongoing genocide and crimes against humanity. Given the severity and extent of these abuses, businesses and individuals that do not exit supply chains, ventures, and/or investments connected to Xinjiang could run a high risk of violating U.S. law. The updated advisory highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>Information related to widespread, state-sponsored forced labor and intrusive surveillance in and related to Xinjiang;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information related to the various kinds of risks and potential exposure to state-sponsored forced labor and human rights abuses related to Xinjiang;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Department of State Guidance on Implementing the “UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights” for Transactions Linked to Foreign Government End-Users for Products or Services with Surveillance Capabilities;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information for investors in PRC companies linked to surveillance in Xinjiang;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information on due diligence related to banking, financial institutions and other investors;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information from the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative and the U.S. Department of Labor;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Updated information about U.S. government actions taken in response to human rights abuses in and in connection to Xinjiang, including but not limited to the issuance of Withhold Release Orders by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the addition of entities to the U.S. Department of Commerce Entity List, the imposition of economic sanctions by the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the imposition of visa restrictions by the U.S. Department of State, and the addition of goods to the U.S. Department of Labor’s <i>List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor </i>(Annex 1);</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Information on forced labor in the Xinjiang silicon and polysilicon supply chain and the prevalence of inputs sourced from <wbr />Xinjiang (Annex 4); and</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>A list of other countries’ regulatory provisions and information on forced labor in supply chains (Annex 7).</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, contact <a href="mailto:DRL-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DRL-Press@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/key-topics-bureau-of-democracy-human-rights-and-labor/business-and-human-rights/">https://www.state.gov/key-topics-bureau-of-democracy-human-rights-and-labor/business-and-human-rights/</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Montenegro Statehood Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/montenegro-statehood-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 04:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Montenegro as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>This year, as we mark 15 years of robust bilateral relations and Montenegro’s fourth year as a NATO Ally, the United States stands with all those who are committed to pursuing the reforms needed to speed Montenegro’s EU accession.  A tolerant and inclusive Montenegro which is firmly rooted in the Euro-Atlantic community will lead to a more prosperous and secure future for all citizens of Montenegro.</p>
<p>I wish the people of Montenegro good health and happiness as we continue to deepen our bilateral ties, which are built upon a foundation of shared values and democratic principles.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Montenegro as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>This year, as we mark 15 years of robust bilateral relations and Montenegro’s fourth year as a NATO Ally, the United States stands with all those who are committed to pursuing the reforms needed to speed Montenegro’s EU accession.  A tolerant and inclusive Montenegro which is firmly rooted in the Euro-Atlantic community will lead to a more prosperous and secure future for all citizens of Montenegro.</p>
<p>I wish the people of Montenegro good health and happiness as we continue to deepen our bilateral ties, which are built upon a foundation of shared values and democratic principles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 12, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-12-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 23:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=258592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>3:15 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you, everyone, for bearing with us today. I’m sorry we got a late start. I just have a few things at the top before we take some questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MODOLVA"></a> First, today is an important day for Moldova. We are pleased to announce that the United States has donated 500,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to Moldova, the first shipment to arrive today, July 12th. This donation, which was announced Friday, July 9th, will increase the number of vaccinated Moldovans by more than 100 percent, and it comes in addition to over $7 million in U.S. aid provided to Moldova since the beginning of the pandemic last year.</p>
<p>Separately, the United States congratulates the people of Moldova on their July 11th early parliamentary elections. We echo the preliminary findings of the OSCE and ODIHR, which found that the elections were well administered, they were competitive, and that the fundamental freedoms were largely respected. We urge Moldovan authorities to address concerns raised by ODIHR in its report, including enhancing full impartiality of the Central Election Commission and effective campaign finance oversight, and addressing the insufficient legal framework to regulate electoral dispute resolution.</p>
<p>We are committed to strengthening our partnership with Moldova based on shared democratic values and we look forward to working with the new government to grow our bilateral relationship and our cooperation.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-PHILIPPINESCHINA"></a> Today marks the fifth anniversary of the landmark decision in the arbitration between the Philippines and China on the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Five years ago, the Arbitral Tribunal, constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention, delivered a unanimous and enduring decision firmly rejecting the PRC’s expansive South China Sea maritime claims as having no basis in international law.</p>
<p>Yesterday evening, as you probably saw, Secretary Blinken released an official statement supporting this important ruling.</p>
<p>Many of our partners and allies, including Australia, Canada, Denmark, France, Germany, Japan, New Zealand, the Philippines, and the EU, issued statements or took to social media to demonstrate global support for the rules-based maritime order.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken told senior PRC officials in Anchorage early this year, quote, “The alternative to a rules-based order is a world in which might makes right and winners take all, and that would be a far more violent and unstable world for all of us.”</p>
<p>We call on the PRC to abide by its obligations under international law, to cease its provocative behavior, and to demonstrate respect for the rights of all countries, those both big and small.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIATIGRAY"></a> Next, the United States is gravely concerned by reports of ongoing hostilities in western Tigray and evidence of escalating military conflict there. Escalating fighting will undermine critical ongoing efforts to deliver humanitarian relief to famine-affected populations in Tigray.</p>
<p>We again call on the Tigrayan Defense Forces, the Amhara regional forces, and Ethiopian National Defense Forces to move towards a negotiated ceasefire in the interests of civilians in the region and to preserve the unity of the Ethiopian state. We strongly condemn any retaliatory attacks that have been or may be directed against civilians in the Tigray region, whether by organized military or security forces or by rogue elements. The United States further calls on all armed actors to comply with their international humanitarian legal obligations, including regarding the protection of civilians. All those who are responsible for violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses must be held accountable.</p>
<p>As we have consistently said, any effort to change the internal boundaries of Ethiopia by force is unacceptable. Any issue of such national importance, like borders, would be an issue for the Ethiopian people to decide through consensual dialogue, not by the barrel of a gun.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MOROCCO"></a> The United States is disappointed by reports that a court in Morocco has sentenced journalist Soulaiman Raissouni to five years in prison. We note Mr. Raissouni has alleged there were violations of fair trial guarantees. We believe the judicial process that led to his verdict contradicts the Moroccan system’s fundamental promise of fair trials for individuals accused of crimes, and it is inconsistent with the promise of the 2011 constitution and His Majesty King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda.</p>
<p>We also have concerns about the case’s negative impact on freedom of expression and freedom of association in Morocco. Press freedom is foundational to prosperous and secure societies, and governments must ensure that journalists can safely perform their essential roles without fear of unjust detention, violence, or threats. We are following this case closely as well as those of other detained journalists in Morocco, including Omar Radi, and we have raised these concerns with the Moroccan Government and we will continue to do so.</p>
<p>With that, I am happy to move to your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. In addition – on Afghanistan, in addition to the change in command that happened earlier today, the embassy announced overnight that it’s going to resume immigrant visa processing. And I am just wondering, is this resumption going to make a dent in the backlog, or how much of a dent will it make in the backlog? Does it affect the relocation plans or the option for relocation, and is anything – has anything been decided on that front?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you are correct that the embassy has announced over Twitter that it will resume immigrant visa interviews this week, and that does include the SIV process. As you know, the SIV process is written into law. It was designed by Congress and involves more than a dozen steps, and that includes both a role for the Department of State as well as for the Department of Homeland Security. As we’ve said before, there are approximately 18,000 Afghan principal applicants at some stage of this process as of May of 2021.</p>
<p>Approximately half of those applicants are at some stage of the process pending applicant action, so in other words, approximately 9,000 or half of these applicants need to take action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case. About 30 percent of these applicants are awaiting a decision at the chief of mission stage and the final 20 percent were approved by the chief of mission stage and they’re moving through the application process, either in the petition or the visa processing stages.</p>
<p>You are also right in your question that we have mobilized significant resources to do all we can to make a dent in the applicants. As you know, we have been very clear and consistent that we have – the United States has – a special responsibility to those who have assisted us in different ways over the years, often at great risk to themselves, sometimes to their families as well. That is also why we have identified a group of SIV applicants – that is to say, individuals who were already somewhere in that SIV processing chain – whom at the right time before the military withdrawal is complete later this year relocate or at least offer to relocate to a third country as they go through their SIV application processing. We have been in conversations, diplomatic discussions with a number of countries around the world. These have – discussions have occurred at any number of levels, to include senior levels, but we don’t have any updates for you regarding that.</p>
<p>The other point I would make is that throughout this process, we have prioritized the safety and the security of those who, often at great risk to themselves, have helped the United States over the years. And so we will be in some cases constrained in terms of what we can say publicly about relocation, about numbers, about certain details. But as soon as we have more to share on that front, we will do so.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, but how much of a – once the interviews resume, how many can they do? How many can – how much of a dent do you think you can make in the backlog?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, we are moving just as quickly as we can. The &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You can’t say – just say that so I don’t keep – because I’m going to keep asking the question until you – if you don’t know, that’s fine. But I’m just – that’s my question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, we have already made significant progress in shortening the period it requires for an applicant to go from the start of the process to – through the visa provision stage. We have shortened that by a number of months and we have done that by surging individuals, by – through operations in Kabul, but the other important point is that much of this adjudication and processing that takes place at the chief of mission stage need not and does not take place in Kabul. This is a point that we have made in terms of our embassy staffing posture in Kabul. We are able to process individuals at the chief of mission stage from here in Washington.</p>
<p>And the other point I would make – again, this program is defined in statute. It was passed by Congress, designed by Congress. We will continue to work with Congress to find ways that we could potentially streamline these operations, knowing that there are to date more than 18,000 people who have – who are somewhere in that process. Again, our goal is to shorten that process as much as we can in a way that is pursuant to the safety and security needs of these individuals but also responsible in the way that we are processing the individuals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So since the President’s announcement that all troops would be gone by the end – by September 11th and now August 31st – but since the initial announcement back in May, how many SIV applicants – applications have been approved, and how many of those approved visa holders have been admitted to the United States? May, June, July – that’s three months.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We can see if we can provide a snapshot of that three-month period. I don’t have that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, is it more than zero? I don’t know. I’m &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll see if we can provide specific numbers.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Anything else on Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, sure. Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> If it’s on Afghanistan, yeah, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I’ve just got one on Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTANTURKEY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Turkish President Erdogan says Turkey and the U.S. have reached an agreement on security for HKIA. Is this true? Can we get details if it is? The 2020 Doha agreement says no U.S. military can remain in Afghanistan. Will any U.S. military personnel assigned to airport security be rebranded as diplomats and given diplomatic passports?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, what I can say is that we have had discussions with our Turkish partners in the context of broader cooperation in Afghanistan. Those discussions are ongoing. We don’t have anything to announce today. I know that last week the Department of Defense read out a couple of those conversations, but I don’t have any additional details to share for you now.</p>
<p>We certainly welcome Turkey’s constructive role when it comes to the withdrawal and the – and the broader safety and security situation in Afghanistan, also with support for the diplomatic process.</p>
<p>When it comes to U.S. personnel on the ground, I would need to refer you to DOD for details of that.</p>
<p>Connor.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on SIVs.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thinking of what you said about the limited commentary you can give us on numbers and everything, can you give us any sense of the scale of how many people are in this group that you’ve identified? Is it in the hundreds? As you’ve said, there are 18,000 applicants in total. How many of them would be expected to be relocated?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are making an assessment based on the needs, based on the safety and security of those applicants. We don’t have numbers to share. And again, we’re going to be limited in the details that we ultimately will be able to share. But as we do, we will do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You can’t give us any sense of like hundreds, thousands?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>At this point, I don’t have any specific numbers to share.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And then on Ambassador Khalilzad’s travel to the region, which was announced on Saturday, does he have a specific message he’s bringing to the Taliban? Is he going to offer incentives or give them a warning if they don’t cooperate in peace negotiations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think his message will be consistent with the message that we have reiterated all along, and that is that we continue to call for an end to ongoing violence. We know that violence has been driven largely by the Taliban. We know that a negotiated settlement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban is really the only way to end 40 years of violence and, importantly, to bring to Afghanistan’s people the safety and security and the peace that they seek.</p>
<p>And as so as Ambassador Khalilzad is there, he will urge the sides to engage in serious negotiations, to try to determine that political roadmap for a future for Afghanistan that leads to a just and durable settlement. Both of those are very important to us. A settlement cannot be durable if it is not just, and that has been a guiding principle of us all along – of ours all along.</p>
<p>We also know in the context of the recent uptick in violence – we’ve made this point before, but the world will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. Importantly, legitimacy and assistance and popular mandate within Afghanistan for any Afghan Government can only be possible if that government, again, has the support of the people, and for the United States and for the international community, if it has a fundamental and basic respect for human rights. For us that’s non-negotiable.</p>
<p>In the interim, we’ll continue, as you’ve heard, to support the ANDSF. That support will transition and form over time. But what won’t transition and form over time is the partnership, the partnership we will maintain with the Afghan people, with Afghanistan’s leaders, as we support this diplomacy seeking a just and durable political settlement.</p>
<p>Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just to add on Afghanistan, I don’t know if this is – if you all do this here, so hopefully this isn’t out of school. But would it be possible at some point to get someone to walk us through the process that the SIVs undergo just while all the details and the destinations are being worked out? Because then we can write about it with – from a place of greater understanding of what the challenges and the whole process and the parameters will be that apply to all these applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That is something we do here, and happy to take that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; and take that back. I think there would be some good utility. Again, it’s a process, and there would be good utility because it’s a process that is not uncomplicated. There are a number of steps that take place in country, that take place back here. And so we’ll take that back and let you know.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, can I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Anything else?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong> Ned, yeah, just one on Afghanistan.  I just can’t – what does it mean, “the world will not accept the imposition of a government by force?”  And you say that – for that – for us that’s non-negotiable.  But what does that mean?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The basic respect for human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But what does that mean &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; that it’s non-negotiable? What are you going to do if and when that happens, when there is the government imposed by force?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, I think this goes back to the two criteria that we’ve spoken to: it’s just and it’s durable.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In order for any government &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But you seem to – you seem to think that the Taliban care about being named and shamed.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And I don’t – I just don’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think – and more importantly, this department and our allies and partners around the world think – that any government that might come to power in Afghanistan will require not an insignificant degree of assistance from the international community. And the international community has been very clear that any government that doesn’t respect the basic and the fundamental rights of its people won’t be in a position to accrue that international support. That is what we’re calling for: a just settlement.</p>
<p>If a settlement is not just, it won’t be durable. And it may not be durable in large part because the international community won’t be there to offer it the backing that successive – well, certainly that in the past 20 years – central governments in Afghanistan have required.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ISPAL"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. Moving on to the Palestinian issue, today the special rapporteur for human rights for the Palestinian territories, Michael Lynk, called the occupation a war crime. Do you agree that the occupation is a war crime, I mean, in the spirit of this presentation today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’ve seen those comments. We aren’t going to evaluate or respond to every statement. To be clear, the State Department has never used such terminology. We are committed to promoting respect for human rights in Israel and the West Bank and the Gaza Strip. We have an enduring partnership with Israel, and we discuss a wide range of issues with the Israeli Government, and that includes human rights. We discuss them with Israel just as we do with other – every other partner around the world.</p>
<p>We continue to emphasize to both Israel and to the Palestinian Authority the need to refrain from unilateral action that exacerbates tension. This includes annexation of territory. It includes settlement activity. It includes demolitions. It includes incitement of violence. It includes support for terrorism, and that includes providing compensation to individual imprisoned for acts of terrorism.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, let me ask you about this specific case. There is a Palestinian feminist and leader and known leftist, Khalida Jarrar, who has been in and out of prison for the past 10 years. There are never any charges. She is a Palestinian legislator. She is guilty of being a leftie or maybe even a communist, and she is boisterous in her speech and so on, but that’s why she has been in prison.</p>
<p>Well, yesterday – she is prison now – she is supposed to be let out next October. Yesterday her daughter died. She is 30 years told. They are preventing her from going – joining in the funeral. Would you call on the Israelis to allow her to go and be in the funeral procession of her daughter?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, I am not in a position to weigh in on the merits of any particular case today. Again, what – the point I’ve made before is the operative one, that whether it is our Israeli partners, whether it’s a partner around the world, we consistently raise human rights. We also, importantly, remain committed to – in seeing to it that Palestinians are able to live equally in peace, in security, in dignity.</p>
<p>That is incredibly important to us. It is really at the foundation of our approach to this conflict – the idea that both Israelis and Palestinians deserve equal measures of these elements, of these very important elements. And it is why, as you’ve seen, we have already begun to re-establish that partnership with the Palestinian people. We are moving ahead with re-establishing our ties with the Palestinian Authority. Of course, Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity not only to speak with President Abbas but also to meet in person with him.</p>
<p>As you know, DAS, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State, Hady Amr is in the region right now. He is meeting with and will be meeting in the coming days with Israeli officials, with Palestinian officials, but also with elements of civil society. And his interaction and his upcoming, forthcoming meetings with elements of civil society are important to us because that is what we know needs to be empowered through all of this. And so Deputy Assistant Secretary Amr will have a series of meetings where he’ll be – will be able to push forward with some of this important work.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> We understand. But on this issue of administrative detention which is practiced by Israel time and time and time again without any charge. I mean, when people are charged with something, that is clear, but they keep arresting people and sometimes they go on for 20 years, 15 years, under administrative detention. Does that – doesn’t that bother you as a basic violation of a very basic human right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, we have spoken about administrative detention before. We have made clear that whether it’s our closest friends or other partners around the world we don’t shy away from raising issues of human rights. In the case of Israeli and Palestinians, again, our policy is predicated on the idea that Palestinians deserve equal measures of freedom, of safety, of security, and dignity. And this gets to your question.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for taking my question. So the Chinese Government came out strongly against Secretary Blinken’s statement regarding the fifth anniversary of the international tribunal’s ruling on the – China’s – at The Hague, China’s expansive claims in South China Sea. It was foreign ministry spokesman Zhao Lijian called it – called the ruling a waste of paper.</p>
<p>So my question is: Wouldn’t it be easier for the U.S. State Department to push its position on this ruling if the U.S. Government ratifies UNCLOS, the UN Convention on the Law of the Seas? And so – and with that – and further to that question, is there – is there an effort underway within the U.S. Government to ratify UNCLOS? Is it under consideration? Is it a priority for this administration to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the point I would make is that since UNCLOS was adopted, every U.S. administration has recognized its provisions on traditional uses of the ocean as reflecting customary international law and has recognized that the United States would abide by UNCLOS with respect to traditional uses of the sea. And that includes the assertion of rights in maritime spaces.</p>
<p>Now, for the PRC, the PRC is a state party to UNCLOS. The PRC has agreed to abide by compulsory dispute settlement with regard to arbitration. But by ignoring the 2016 arbitral tribunal ruling on the South China Sea and dismissing it, as you said, as a mere scrap of paper, Beijing is in clear violation of its obligations under UNCLOS.</p>
<p>Look, for us, this is not a question of the United States against the People’s Republic of China or any other country. For us, this is an affirmative policy of the free and open Indo-Pacific and beyond that, the rules-based international system that every country in the world, big and small, has an obligation to abide by.</p>
<p>So again, when it comes to territorial claims, for example, the United States doesn’t take a position on that. When it comes to these maritime claims, we do endorse the unanimous, decisive ruling that was put forward by the arbitral council. So if you want to ask about which country is being more faithful to the principles that undergird UNCLOS, I think you have a pretty clear answer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But it’s – it is or is not a commitment of this administration to get the Senate to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have an update for you on potential Senate ratification, but again, every administration since UNCLOS has gone into effect has abided by its core underlying principles.</p>
<p>Nadia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-DISIS"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And Nadia, while I’m thinking of it, you asked earlier about ISIS. I’m happy to offer some &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; context there and perhaps save my colleagues some response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Some emailing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The Secretary had an opportunity – I guess it was late last month – to travel to Italy and to join his Italian counterpart, Luigi Di Maio, as a co-host of the D-ISIS coalition ministerial. And that coalition remains critically important to our efforts, and the coalition, we heard in Italy, is united in its determination to see ISIS destroyed.</p>
<p>On that, the global coalition has destroyed 100 percent of ISIS’s fraudulent territorial so-called caliphate. The ISIS leader, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, of course, is no longer with us. We have heard a clear determination from the global coalition to see to it that ISIS won’t be allowed to reconstitute that territorial caliphate. Through our diplomatic efforts, this global coalition has continued to grow and now stands at, I believe, 83 members. There are 78 countries and five international organizations. And this includes a broad swath of regions: 26 members from Africa and Asia as well. And we continue to expand that partnership and cooperation against a common enemy.</p>
<p>Of course, that is not to say that ISIS does not continue to pose a threat, and we have continued to work through the coalition bilaterally, multilaterally, and in other forms to provide support to our partners in the Middle East, in Africa, who are facing these horrific attacks from the terrorist group.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you for that. I have two questions on Iran and Yemen. On Iran, Iran Foreign Minister Mr. Javad Zarif said that the talks in Vienna is nearing an end, and apparently he gave a very comprehensive report to the Shura Council talking about what he called illegal U.S. sanctions and the impact on the oil and on the banking sectors.</p>
<p>Does the administration share his view that, actually, the talks are about to be concluded and you’re going to reach an agreement? What is he basing his assessment on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I cannot speak to what he’s basing his assessment on. I can speak to our – where we stand on this, and that is that Special Envoy Malley and his team are prepared to return to Vienna for a seventh round of talks as soon as they are scheduled. Look, questions about when or whether Iran would be prepared to start a seventh round or reach an understanding on a mutual return to the JCPOA, those can only be addressed by Tehran. They can’t be routed here. We’ve made very clear that we are prepared to return to a seventh round. Again, we’re not imposing a deadline on these talks, but Secretary Blinken has made the point, I’ve made the point from here as well, that we are conscious that as time proceeds, Iran’s nuclear advances will have a bearing on our view of ultimately returning to the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So again, we stand ready to resume negotiations. We continue to believe that diplomacy is the most effective means at our disposal to achieve what we seek, and that is verifiably and – verifiably and permanently ensuring that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And on Yemen quickly, can you brief us on what’s the latest the administration is doing to encourage the Houthis to come back to the negotiation table? There was a time when Mr. Lenderking will go to the region very often, and there were some encouraging signs, but now it seems to be silent. So are – these talks are kind of hitting a dead end? Would you say that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m sorry, what was the final part of your question?</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-YEMEN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The talks, are they hitting a dead end? Are we not going anywhere, in any direction?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, absolutely not. And Special Envoy Lenderking and his team continue to work very closely with the UN special envoy, continue to work very closely with our partners in the region. Of course, you know last week Special Envoy Lenderking met with the Saudi deputy minister of defense. He has recently undertaken a series of meetings to continue this diplomatic push. There is a serious proposal on the table. The Houthis are the ones who – despite these constructive ideas that have been put forward, the Houthis are the ones who continue to perpetrate these horrifying attacks, including on Yemeni civilians. Just in Marib on – late last month, June 29th, the horrific attack that took the life of a child.</p>
<p>We also know that the Houthi offensive only exacerbates the humanitarian crisis that Yemen is in right now. We are supporting this diplomacy as a means to bring about an end to this long-running conflict, but also knowing that this diplomacy is the most effective means to mitigate and to ease the humanitarian burden on the Yemeni people. And so we are working urgently. Special Envoy Lenderking is working urgently. We know that our partners in the UN are doing the same, and we’ll continue to do that with a combination of both carrots and sticks.</p>
<p>And as you know, we continue to apply pressure to the Houthis in the context of both domestic and international sanctions. Just on June 10th we sanctioned 12 individuals and entities and a vessel related to an international network used to facilitate the provision of – I believe it is millions of dollars to Houthis in cooperation with the Qods Force. This was in addition to the designation in May of two Houthi leaders, both of whom have played a significant role in this offensive against Marib.</p>
<p>So our message is very clear. The Houthis need to show us that they are serious about diplomacy, and they can do that by ceasing this offensive and by easing the humanitarian plight on their own people. And this is something we have been working very concertedly with our partners and allies towards.</p>
<p>Yes, Tracy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-HAITI"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can I ask a Haiti question, please?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary again reiterated the importance of elections before the end of the year. Elections have never solved Haiti’s problems, ever, so I’m just wondering if you could explain to me the thinking behind this imperative that there be elections to settle Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I would start with the proposition that for us, this is about institutions. It’s about Haiti’s institutions. We continue to support the Haitian people and their constitution, knowing that the constitution needs to be an enduring framework for what happens next. And so yes, in our view there need to be free and fair elections. They need to happen this year – legislative elections, presidential elections – pursuant to the Haitian constitution. And that is precisely why we have continued to support them.</p>
<p>We have continued even in recent hours. And as you know, there was an interagency delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday. It included representation from the Department of State. And the delegation continued to encourage Haiti’s political actors and its stakeholders to build an inclusive Haitian consensus to peacefully navigate and overcome this crisis. And to do that, we continue to believe that what needs to govern this is the Haitian constitution and Haiti’s institutions, and ultimately, in an effort to bolster Haiti’s democracy.</p>
<p>Yes, Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Quick follow-up on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Haiti still? Or – Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Conor, go for it, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I just ask about the security assistance aspect of that? That’s something that apparently was discussed yesterday. Is there any timeframe for the administration to make a decision on potential security assistance? What, if anything, could be in the cards?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So our immediate focus – and this was a focus of the delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday – is determining the assistance that Haiti may need with this investigation. And after close consultation with Haitian officials in recent days and again on Sunday, we believe our focus should be assisting the Haitian Government with navigating the investigation into the assassination of President Moise, determining who is culpable, and supporting the Haitian Government as it seeks justice in this case. And FBI and DHS officials have also traveled to Port-au-Prince. They’re working to determine what assistance the United States can provide to the Haitian Government in its time of need.</p>
<p>The delegation that was there yesterday did commit to support the Haitian people in the aftermath of the assassination. That includes with a review of security of critical infrastructure with Haitian Government officials. So we’ve been in close contact with Haitian Government officials. We are reviewing the request for assistance that they have sent in, and we’re also doing our own assessment of what would be most beneficial to the people of Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just briefly, one more thing on Haiti. The Americans there who have been accused in the assassination, has – is there any update on consular access or any type of view about whether they – about their treatment and their – whether they’re culpable?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are aware of detention of a third U.S. citizen. We continue to monitor the situation closely. As in all cases, we will provide appropriate consular services to detained U.S. citizens. Obviously privacy considerations preclude us from saying much more, but I do suspect that once we have had access to all three American citizens who are detained, we’ll be in a position to confirm that.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-JORDAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Speaking of detained U.S. citizens, there was a verdict and a sentence handed down in Jordan today against two people, one of whom is an American citizen. I’m wondering if you have anything to say about that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are closely monitoring the case of Bassem Awadallah in Jordan. We take seriously any allegation of abuse, and we always emphasize the importance of respecting fair trial guarantees, humane treatment. We’re providing all appropriate consular assistance in line with our commitment to assisting U.S. citizens abroad. We have, in fact, visited Mr. Awadallah five times since April of this year. The most recent visit occurred just a few days ago, on July 11th.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right, but that doesn’t speak to the actual verdict and sentence, which is what I’m asking you about.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any comment on the verdict. But as I’ve said before, we always emphasize – and this goes back to Said’s question earlier – the importance of fair trials and guarantees of humane treatment around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The journalist in Morocco who you talked about at the very beginning, right, was he – is he an American citizen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any indication he is an American citizen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But – and yet you have a position on the verdict in that case, but none in this. So what do we – what do we read into that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You think that this – the guy in Jordan could be guilty?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Each case is different.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s why I’m asking you why you don’t have anything to say about the verdict.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We are going to – we are going to speak based on the facts and the circumstances as they are known to us, but obviously these cases are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So does that mean that you’re not clear on the facts and circumstances of Mr. Awadallah’s case?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think what is very clear to us is that journalists, and hopefully everyone here can agree with this, don’t belong behind bars, that they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, no, I agree with that. I’m not talking about the Morocco case.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That they shouldn’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m talking about case in Jordan. Is it the case that in this situation you do not have all the facts or you – you’re not clear enough on the facts and circumstances of the verdict, of the trial that you will – that you’re not clear enough so that you can’t render an opinion on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What is fair to say is that when the facts and the circumstances are clear to us and when we determine that we can best move the ball forward by speaking publicly, we will never hesitate to do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CUBA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Cuba, real quick?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Back in 2015, July 2015 when relations were restored and President Obama said that it was – the policy of sanctions and so on was a failed policy. And then there was a great deal of hope and so on. But then the preceding administration collapsed all that hope down. But you guys seem to be following the same kind of policy as the previous administration. What are you doing, let’s say, to show people that there are actually – there are benefits to good governance and all that stuff?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I certainly would not say that we are following the previous – the policy of the previous administration. As you know, our Cuba policy is under review. But importantly – and I think this is a pivotal distinction – our policy, as you heard from the Secretary, it focuses on the wellbeing of the Cuban people, and at the center of that policy are democracy and our human rights.</p>
<p>And what we are assessing in the context of that policy review is how the United States can best support the aspirations of the Cuban people. So that policy review remains ongoing. It is something – the issue of human rights on the island is very important to us, and we’re seeing yesterday and today in the streets all throughout Cuba that it is very important, as you might expect, to the Cuban people as well. And as we undertake this review, at the center of that review will be the welfare and the wellbeing of those Cuban people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>That’s exactly what the previous administration said their policy was towards Cuba, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, we haven’t spoken – we haven’t spoken &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So until your review is complete, why is Said incorrect in saying that you’re following – you’re doing the exact same thing that the Trump administration did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, he was speaking of our policies towards Cuba. And again, our &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, yeah. You haven’t changed the previous administration’s policies, right, so until that review is complete, you’re doing the same thing, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I can assure you that we are going about this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You’re doing the same thing as the previous administration did, right? You haven’t changed the policy.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have not announced our Cuba policy, but what we have said is that democracy and human rights are at the center of it.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on that, does the administration still consider Cuba a state sponsor of terrorism?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We – there’s been no change. As you know, the state sponsor of terrorism list is –it’s evaluated, and the report is released once a year. When we have a new report to release, we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s part of the policy review in general of – for Cuba policy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are always reviewing issues of state sponsorship for countries around the world pursuant to the requirement to put forward the state sponsor of terrorism list. Our review of Cuba and Cuba policy, it is taking place in parallel to that.</p>
<p>Thank &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So separate, but parallel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think that is a fair characterization.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have time for one &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure, one last question.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ethiopia. The election results came out this past weekend. The United States has voiced concern previously about the atmosphere in which the elections were to be held. What’s your view on the election results? Do you think they confer legitimacy on Prime Minister Abiy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, the Secretary himself has spoken to this. It was late last month, June 21st, he issued a statement noting that the elections took place against the backdrop of grave instability, including increasing interethnic and intercommunal conflicts and an electoral process that was not free or fair for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p>The boycott of the elections by opposition parties, the detention of vocal political leaders, the ongoing violence in multiple parts of the country – look, all of this underscores the need to launch an inclusive effort to build a national consensus on the governance of Ethiopia that, importantly, preserves the sovereignty and the unity of the state and strengthens rather than undermines the constitutional order.</p>
<p>In this period following the election, it’s critical that Ethiopians come together to confront growing divisions. We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and to refrain from inciting others to violence. And we’ll be watching the situation very carefully going forward. Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:57 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>3:15 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you, everyone, for bearing with us today. I’m sorry we got a late start. I just have a few things at the top before we take some questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MODOLVA"></a> First, today is an important day for Moldova. We are pleased to announce that the United States has donated 500,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to Moldova, the first shipment to arrive today, July 12th. This donation, which was announced Friday, July 9th, will increase the number of vaccinated Moldovans by more than 100 percent, and it comes in addition to over $7 million in U.S. aid provided to Moldova since the beginning of the pandemic last year.</p>
<p>Separately, the United States congratulates the people of Moldova on their July 11th early parliamentary elections. We echo the preliminary findings of the OSCE and ODIHR, which found that the elections were well administered, they were competitive, and that the fundamental freedoms were largely respected. We urge Moldovan authorities to address concerns raised by ODIHR in its report, including enhancing full impartiality of the Central Election Commission and effective campaign finance oversight, and addressing the insufficient legal framework to regulate electoral dispute resolution.</p>
<p>We are committed to strengthening our partnership with Moldova based on shared democratic values and we look forward to working with the new government to grow our bilateral relationship and our cooperation.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-PHILIPPINESCHINA"></a> Today marks the fifth anniversary of the landmark decision in the arbitration between the Philippines and China on the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Five years ago, the Arbitral Tribunal, constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention, delivered a unanimous and enduring decision firmly rejecting the PRC’s expansive South China Sea maritime claims as having no basis in international law.</p>
<p>Yesterday evening, as you probably saw, Secretary Blinken released an official statement supporting this important ruling.</p>
<p>Many of our partners and allies, including Australia, Canada, Denmark, France, Germany, Japan, New Zealand, the Philippines, and the EU, issued statements or took to social media to demonstrate global support for the rules-based maritime order.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken told senior PRC officials in Anchorage early this year, quote, “The alternative to a rules-based order is a world in which might makes right and winners take all, and that would be a far more violent and unstable world for all of us.”</p>
<p>We call on the PRC to abide by its obligations under international law, to cease its provocative behavior, and to demonstrate respect for the rights of all countries, those both big and small.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIATIGRAY"></a> Next, the United States is gravely concerned by reports of ongoing hostilities in western Tigray and evidence of escalating military conflict there. Escalating fighting will undermine critical ongoing efforts to deliver humanitarian relief to famine-affected populations in Tigray.</p>
<p>We again call on the Tigrayan Defense Forces, the Amhara regional forces, and Ethiopian National Defense Forces to move towards a negotiated ceasefire in the interests of civilians in the region and to preserve the unity of the Ethiopian state. We strongly condemn any retaliatory attacks that have been or may be directed against civilians in the Tigray region, whether by organized military or security forces or by rogue elements. The United States further calls on all armed actors to comply with their international humanitarian legal obligations, including regarding the protection of civilians. All those who are responsible for violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses must be held accountable.</p>
<p>As we have consistently said, any effort to change the internal boundaries of Ethiopia by force is unacceptable. Any issue of such national importance, like borders, would be an issue for the Ethiopian people to decide through consensual dialogue, not by the barrel of a gun.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MOROCCO"></a> The United States is disappointed by reports that a court in Morocco has sentenced journalist Soulaiman Raissouni to five years in prison. We note Mr. Raissouni has alleged there were violations of fair trial guarantees. We believe the judicial process that led to his verdict contradicts the Moroccan system’s fundamental promise of fair trials for individuals accused of crimes, and it is inconsistent with the promise of the 2011 constitution and His Majesty King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda.</p>
<p>We also have concerns about the case’s negative impact on freedom of expression and freedom of association in Morocco. Press freedom is foundational to prosperous and secure societies, and governments must ensure that journalists can safely perform their essential roles without fear of unjust detention, violence, or threats. We are following this case closely as well as those of other detained journalists in Morocco, including Omar Radi, and we have raised these concerns with the Moroccan Government and we will continue to do so.</p>
<p>With that, I am happy to move to your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. In addition – on Afghanistan, in addition to the change in command that happened earlier today, the embassy announced overnight that it’s going to resume immigrant visa processing. And I am just wondering, is this resumption going to make a dent in the backlog, or how much of a dent will it make in the backlog? Does it affect the relocation plans or the option for relocation, and is anything – has anything been decided on that front?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you are correct that the embassy has announced over Twitter that it will resume immigrant visa interviews this week, and that does include the SIV process. As you know, the SIV process is written into law. It was designed by Congress and involves more than a dozen steps, and that includes both a role for the Department of State as well as for the Department of Homeland Security. As we’ve said before, there are approximately 18,000 Afghan principal applicants at some stage of this process as of May of 2021.</p>
<p>Approximately half of those applicants are at some stage of the process pending applicant action, so in other words, approximately 9,000 or half of these applicants need to take action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case. About 30 percent of these applicants are awaiting a decision at the chief of mission stage and the final 20 percent were approved by the chief of mission stage and they’re moving through the application process, either in the petition or the visa processing stages.</p>
<p>You are also right in your question that we have mobilized significant resources to do all we can to make a dent in the applicants. As you know, we have been very clear and consistent that we have – the United States has – a special responsibility to those who have assisted us in different ways over the years, often at great risk to themselves, sometimes to their families as well. That is also why we have identified a group of SIV applicants – that is to say, individuals who were already somewhere in that SIV processing chain – whom at the right time before the military withdrawal is complete later this year relocate or at least offer to relocate to a third country as they go through their SIV application processing. We have been in conversations, diplomatic discussions with a number of countries around the world. These have – discussions have occurred at any number of levels, to include senior levels, but we don’t have any updates for you regarding that.</p>
<p>The other point I would make is that throughout this process, we have prioritized the safety and the security of those who, often at great risk to themselves, have helped the United States over the years. And so we will be in some cases constrained in terms of what we can say publicly about relocation, about numbers, about certain details. But as soon as we have more to share on that front, we will do so.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, but how much of a – once the interviews resume, how many can they do? How many can – how much of a dent do you think you can make in the backlog?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, we are moving just as quickly as we can. The &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You can’t say – just say that so I don’t keep – because I’m going to keep asking the question until you – if you don’t know, that’s fine. But I’m just – that’s my question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, we have already made significant progress in shortening the period it requires for an applicant to go from the start of the process to – through the visa provision stage. We have shortened that by a number of months and we have done that by surging individuals, by – through operations in Kabul, but the other important point is that much of this adjudication and processing that takes place at the chief of mission stage need not and does not take place in Kabul. This is a point that we have made in terms of our embassy staffing posture in Kabul. We are able to process individuals at the chief of mission stage from here in Washington.</p>
<p>And the other point I would make – again, this program is defined in statute. It was passed by Congress, designed by Congress. We will continue to work with Congress to find ways that we could potentially streamline these operations, knowing that there are to date more than 18,000 people who have – who are somewhere in that process. Again, our goal is to shorten that process as much as we can in a way that is pursuant to the safety and security needs of these individuals but also responsible in the way that we are processing the individuals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So since the President’s announcement that all troops would be gone by the end – by September 11th and now August 31st – but since the initial announcement back in May, how many SIV applicants – applications have been approved, and how many of those approved visa holders have been admitted to the United States? May, June, July – that’s three months.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We can see if we can provide a snapshot of that three-month period. I don’t have that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, is it more than zero? I don’t know. I’m &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll see if we can provide specific numbers.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Anything else on Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, sure. Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> If it’s on Afghanistan, yeah, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I’ve just got one on Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTANTURKEY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Turkish President Erdogan says Turkey and the U.S. have reached an agreement on security for HKIA. Is this true? Can we get details if it is? The 2020 Doha agreement says no U.S. military can remain in Afghanistan. Will any U.S. military personnel assigned to airport security be rebranded as diplomats and given diplomatic passports?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, what I can say is that we have had discussions with our Turkish partners in the context of broader cooperation in Afghanistan. Those discussions are ongoing. We don’t have anything to announce today. I know that last week the Department of Defense read out a couple of those conversations, but I don’t have any additional details to share for you now.</p>
<p>We certainly welcome Turkey’s constructive role when it comes to the withdrawal and the – and the broader safety and security situation in Afghanistan, also with support for the diplomatic process.</p>
<p>When it comes to U.S. personnel on the ground, I would need to refer you to DOD for details of that.</p>
<p>Connor.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on SIVs.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thinking of what you said about the limited commentary you can give us on numbers and everything, can you give us any sense of the scale of how many people are in this group that you’ve identified? Is it in the hundreds? As you’ve said, there are 18,000 applicants in total. How many of them would be expected to be relocated?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are making an assessment based on the needs, based on the safety and security of those applicants. We don’t have numbers to share. And again, we’re going to be limited in the details that we ultimately will be able to share. But as we do, we will do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You can’t give us any sense of like hundreds, thousands?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>At this point, I don’t have any specific numbers to share.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And then on Ambassador Khalilzad’s travel to the region, which was announced on Saturday, does he have a specific message he’s bringing to the Taliban? Is he going to offer incentives or give them a warning if they don’t cooperate in peace negotiations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think his message will be consistent with the message that we have reiterated all along, and that is that we continue to call for an end to ongoing violence. We know that violence has been driven largely by the Taliban. We know that a negotiated settlement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban is really the only way to end 40 years of violence and, importantly, to bring to Afghanistan’s people the safety and security and the peace that they seek.</p>
<p>And as so as Ambassador Khalilzad is there, he will urge the sides to engage in serious negotiations, to try to determine that political roadmap for a future for Afghanistan that leads to a just and durable settlement. Both of those are very important to us. A settlement cannot be durable if it is not just, and that has been a guiding principle of us all along – of ours all along.</p>
<p>We also know in the context of the recent uptick in violence – we’ve made this point before, but the world will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. Importantly, legitimacy and assistance and popular mandate within Afghanistan for any Afghan Government can only be possible if that government, again, has the support of the people, and for the United States and for the international community, if it has a fundamental and basic respect for human rights. For us that’s non-negotiable.</p>
<p>In the interim, we’ll continue, as you’ve heard, to support the ANDSF. That support will transition and form over time. But what won’t transition and form over time is the partnership, the partnership we will maintain with the Afghan people, with Afghanistan’s leaders, as we support this diplomacy seeking a just and durable political settlement.</p>
<p>Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just to add on Afghanistan, I don’t know if this is – if you all do this here, so hopefully this isn’t out of school. But would it be possible at some point to get someone to walk us through the process that the SIVs undergo just while all the details and the destinations are being worked out? Because then we can write about it with – from a place of greater understanding of what the challenges and the whole process and the parameters will be that apply to all these applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That is something we do here, and happy to take that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; and take that back. I think there would be some good utility. Again, it’s a process, and there would be good utility because it’s a process that is not uncomplicated. There are a number of steps that take place in country, that take place back here. And so we’ll take that back and let you know.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, can I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Anything else?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong> Ned, yeah, just one on Afghanistan.  I just can’t – what does it mean, “the world will not accept the imposition of a government by force?”  And you say that – for that – for us that’s non-negotiable.  But what does that mean?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The basic respect for human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But what does that mean &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; that it’s non-negotiable? What are you going to do if and when that happens, when there is the government imposed by force?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, I think this goes back to the two criteria that we’ve spoken to: it’s just and it’s durable.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In order for any government &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But you seem to – you seem to think that the Taliban care about being named and shamed.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And I don’t – I just don’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think – and more importantly, this department and our allies and partners around the world think – that any government that might come to power in Afghanistan will require not an insignificant degree of assistance from the international community. And the international community has been very clear that any government that doesn’t respect the basic and the fundamental rights of its people won’t be in a position to accrue that international support. That is what we’re calling for: a just settlement.</p>
<p>If a settlement is not just, it won’t be durable. And it may not be durable in large part because the international community won’t be there to offer it the backing that successive – well, certainly that in the past 20 years – central governments in Afghanistan have required.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ISPAL"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. Moving on to the Palestinian issue, today the special rapporteur for human rights for the Palestinian territories, Michael Lynk, called the occupation a war crime. Do you agree that the occupation is a war crime, I mean, in the spirit of this presentation today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’ve seen those comments. We aren’t going to evaluate or respond to every statement. To be clear, the State Department has never used such terminology. We are committed to promoting respect for human rights in Israel and the West Bank and the Gaza Strip. We have an enduring partnership with Israel, and we discuss a wide range of issues with the Israeli Government, and that includes human rights. We discuss them with Israel just as we do with other – every other partner around the world.</p>
<p>We continue to emphasize to both Israel and to the Palestinian Authority the need to refrain from unilateral action that exacerbates tension. This includes annexation of territory. It includes settlement activity. It includes demolitions. It includes incitement of violence. It includes support for terrorism, and that includes providing compensation to individual imprisoned for acts of terrorism.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, let me ask you about this specific case. There is a Palestinian feminist and leader and known leftist, Khalida Jarrar, who has been in and out of prison for the past 10 years. There are never any charges. She is a Palestinian legislator. She is guilty of being a leftie or maybe even a communist, and she is boisterous in her speech and so on, but that’s why she has been in prison.</p>
<p>Well, yesterday – she is prison now – she is supposed to be let out next October. Yesterday her daughter died. She is 30 years told. They are preventing her from going – joining in the funeral. Would you call on the Israelis to allow her to go and be in the funeral procession of her daughter?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, I am not in a position to weigh in on the merits of any particular case today. Again, what – the point I’ve made before is the operative one, that whether it is our Israeli partners, whether it’s a partner around the world, we consistently raise human rights. We also, importantly, remain committed to – in seeing to it that Palestinians are able to live equally in peace, in security, in dignity.</p>
<p>That is incredibly important to us. It is really at the foundation of our approach to this conflict – the idea that both Israelis and Palestinians deserve equal measures of these elements, of these very important elements. And it is why, as you’ve seen, we have already begun to re-establish that partnership with the Palestinian people. We are moving ahead with re-establishing our ties with the Palestinian Authority. Of course, Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity not only to speak with President Abbas but also to meet in person with him.</p>
<p>As you know, DAS, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State, Hady Amr is in the region right now. He is meeting with and will be meeting in the coming days with Israeli officials, with Palestinian officials, but also with elements of civil society. And his interaction and his upcoming, forthcoming meetings with elements of civil society are important to us because that is what we know needs to be empowered through all of this. And so Deputy Assistant Secretary Amr will have a series of meetings where he’ll be – will be able to push forward with some of this important work.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> We understand. But on this issue of administrative detention which is practiced by Israel time and time and time again without any charge. I mean, when people are charged with something, that is clear, but they keep arresting people and sometimes they go on for 20 years, 15 years, under administrative detention. Does that – doesn’t that bother you as a basic violation of a very basic human right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, we have spoken about administrative detention before. We have made clear that whether it’s our closest friends or other partners around the world we don’t shy away from raising issues of human rights. In the case of Israeli and Palestinians, again, our policy is predicated on the idea that Palestinians deserve equal measures of freedom, of safety, of security, and dignity. And this gets to your question.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for taking my question. So the Chinese Government came out strongly against Secretary Blinken’s statement regarding the fifth anniversary of the international tribunal’s ruling on the – China’s – at The Hague, China’s expansive claims in South China Sea. It was foreign ministry spokesman Zhao Lijian called it – called the ruling a waste of paper.</p>
<p>So my question is: Wouldn’t it be easier for the U.S. State Department to push its position on this ruling if the U.S. Government ratifies UNCLOS, the UN Convention on the Law of the Seas? And so – and with that – and further to that question, is there – is there an effort underway within the U.S. Government to ratify UNCLOS? Is it under consideration? Is it a priority for this administration to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the point I would make is that since UNCLOS was adopted, every U.S. administration has recognized its provisions on traditional uses of the ocean as reflecting customary international law and has recognized that the United States would abide by UNCLOS with respect to traditional uses of the sea. And that includes the assertion of rights in maritime spaces.</p>
<p>Now, for the PRC, the PRC is a state party to UNCLOS. The PRC has agreed to abide by compulsory dispute settlement with regard to arbitration. But by ignoring the 2016 arbitral tribunal ruling on the South China Sea and dismissing it, as you said, as a mere scrap of paper, Beijing is in clear violation of its obligations under UNCLOS.</p>
<p>Look, for us, this is not a question of the United States against the People’s Republic of China or any other country. For us, this is an affirmative policy of the free and open Indo-Pacific and beyond that, the rules-based international system that every country in the world, big and small, has an obligation to abide by.</p>
<p>So again, when it comes to territorial claims, for example, the United States doesn’t take a position on that. When it comes to these maritime claims, we do endorse the unanimous, decisive ruling that was put forward by the arbitral council. So if you want to ask about which country is being more faithful to the principles that undergird UNCLOS, I think you have a pretty clear answer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But it’s – it is or is not a commitment of this administration to get the Senate to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have an update for you on potential Senate ratification, but again, every administration since UNCLOS has gone into effect has abided by its core underlying principles.</p>
<p>Nadia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-DISIS"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And Nadia, while I’m thinking of it, you asked earlier about ISIS. I’m happy to offer some &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; context there and perhaps save my colleagues some response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Some emailing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The Secretary had an opportunity – I guess it was late last month – to travel to Italy and to join his Italian counterpart, Luigi Di Maio, as a co-host of the D-ISIS coalition ministerial. And that coalition remains critically important to our efforts, and the coalition, we heard in Italy, is united in its determination to see ISIS destroyed.</p>
<p>On that, the global coalition has destroyed 100 percent of ISIS’s fraudulent territorial so-called caliphate. The ISIS leader, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, of course, is no longer with us. We have heard a clear determination from the global coalition to see to it that ISIS won’t be allowed to reconstitute that territorial caliphate. Through our diplomatic efforts, this global coalition has continued to grow and now stands at, I believe, 83 members. There are 78 countries and five international organizations. And this includes a broad swath of regions: 26 members from Africa and Asia as well. And we continue to expand that partnership and cooperation against a common enemy.</p>
<p>Of course, that is not to say that ISIS does not continue to pose a threat, and we have continued to work through the coalition bilaterally, multilaterally, and in other forms to provide support to our partners in the Middle East, in Africa, who are facing these horrific attacks from the terrorist group.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you for that. I have two questions on Iran and Yemen. On Iran, Iran Foreign Minister Mr. Javad Zarif said that the talks in Vienna is nearing an end, and apparently he gave a very comprehensive report to the Shura Council talking about what he called illegal U.S. sanctions and the impact on the oil and on the banking sectors.</p>
<p>Does the administration share his view that, actually, the talks are about to be concluded and you’re going to reach an agreement? What is he basing his assessment on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I cannot speak to what he’s basing his assessment on. I can speak to our – where we stand on this, and that is that Special Envoy Malley and his team are prepared to return to Vienna for a seventh round of talks as soon as they are scheduled. Look, questions about when or whether Iran would be prepared to start a seventh round or reach an understanding on a mutual return to the JCPOA, those can only be addressed by Tehran. They can’t be routed here. We’ve made very clear that we are prepared to return to a seventh round. Again, we’re not imposing a deadline on these talks, but Secretary Blinken has made the point, I’ve made the point from here as well, that we are conscious that as time proceeds, Iran’s nuclear advances will have a bearing on our view of ultimately returning to the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So again, we stand ready to resume negotiations. We continue to believe that diplomacy is the most effective means at our disposal to achieve what we seek, and that is verifiably and – verifiably and permanently ensuring that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And on Yemen quickly, can you brief us on what’s the latest the administration is doing to encourage the Houthis to come back to the negotiation table? There was a time when Mr. Lenderking will go to the region very often, and there were some encouraging signs, but now it seems to be silent. So are – these talks are kind of hitting a dead end? Would you say that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m sorry, what was the final part of your question?</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-YEMEN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The talks, are they hitting a dead end? Are we not going anywhere, in any direction?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, absolutely not. And Special Envoy Lenderking and his team continue to work very closely with the UN special envoy, continue to work very closely with our partners in the region. Of course, you know last week Special Envoy Lenderking met with the Saudi deputy minister of defense. He has recently undertaken a series of meetings to continue this diplomatic push. There is a serious proposal on the table. The Houthis are the ones who – despite these constructive ideas that have been put forward, the Houthis are the ones who continue to perpetrate these horrifying attacks, including on Yemeni civilians. Just in Marib on – late last month, June 29th, the horrific attack that took the life of a child.</p>
<p>We also know that the Houthi offensive only exacerbates the humanitarian crisis that Yemen is in right now. We are supporting this diplomacy as a means to bring about an end to this long-running conflict, but also knowing that this diplomacy is the most effective means to mitigate and to ease the humanitarian burden on the Yemeni people. And so we are working urgently. Special Envoy Lenderking is working urgently. We know that our partners in the UN are doing the same, and we’ll continue to do that with a combination of both carrots and sticks.</p>
<p>And as you know, we continue to apply pressure to the Houthis in the context of both domestic and international sanctions. Just on June 10th we sanctioned 12 individuals and entities and a vessel related to an international network used to facilitate the provision of – I believe it is millions of dollars to Houthis in cooperation with the Qods Force. This was in addition to the designation in May of two Houthi leaders, both of whom have played a significant role in this offensive against Marib.</p>
<p>So our message is very clear. The Houthis need to show us that they are serious about diplomacy, and they can do that by ceasing this offensive and by easing the humanitarian plight on their own people. And this is something we have been working very concertedly with our partners and allies towards.</p>
<p>Yes, Tracy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-HAITI"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can I ask a Haiti question, please?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary again reiterated the importance of elections before the end of the year. Elections have never solved Haiti’s problems, ever, so I’m just wondering if you could explain to me the thinking behind this imperative that there be elections to settle Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I would start with the proposition that for us, this is about institutions. It’s about Haiti’s institutions. We continue to support the Haitian people and their constitution, knowing that the constitution needs to be an enduring framework for what happens next. And so yes, in our view there need to be free and fair elections. They need to happen this year – legislative elections, presidential elections – pursuant to the Haitian constitution. And that is precisely why we have continued to support them.</p>
<p>We have continued even in recent hours. And as you know, there was an interagency delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday. It included representation from the Department of State. And the delegation continued to encourage Haiti’s political actors and its stakeholders to build an inclusive Haitian consensus to peacefully navigate and overcome this crisis. And to do that, we continue to believe that what needs to govern this is the Haitian constitution and Haiti’s institutions, and ultimately, in an effort to bolster Haiti’s democracy.</p>
<p>Yes, Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Quick follow-up on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Haiti still? Or – Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Conor, go for it, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I just ask about the security assistance aspect of that? That’s something that apparently was discussed yesterday. Is there any timeframe for the administration to make a decision on potential security assistance? What, if anything, could be in the cards?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So our immediate focus – and this was a focus of the delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday – is determining the assistance that Haiti may need with this investigation. And after close consultation with Haitian officials in recent days and again on Sunday, we believe our focus should be assisting the Haitian Government with navigating the investigation into the assassination of President Moise, determining who is culpable, and supporting the Haitian Government as it seeks justice in this case. And FBI and DHS officials have also traveled to Port-au-Prince. They’re working to determine what assistance the United States can provide to the Haitian Government in its time of need.</p>
<p>The delegation that was there yesterday did commit to support the Haitian people in the aftermath of the assassination. That includes with a review of security of critical infrastructure with Haitian Government officials. So we’ve been in close contact with Haitian Government officials. We are reviewing the request for assistance that they have sent in, and we’re also doing our own assessment of what would be most beneficial to the people of Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just briefly, one more thing on Haiti. The Americans there who have been accused in the assassination, has – is there any update on consular access or any type of view about whether they – about their treatment and their – whether they’re culpable?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are aware of detention of a third U.S. citizen. We continue to monitor the situation closely. As in all cases, we will provide appropriate consular services to detained U.S. citizens. Obviously privacy considerations preclude us from saying much more, but I do suspect that once we have had access to all three American citizens who are detained, we’ll be in a position to confirm that.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-JORDAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Speaking of detained U.S. citizens, there was a verdict and a sentence handed down in Jordan today against two people, one of whom is an American citizen. I’m wondering if you have anything to say about that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are closely monitoring the case of Bassem Awadallah in Jordan. We take seriously any allegation of abuse, and we always emphasize the importance of respecting fair trial guarantees, humane treatment. We’re providing all appropriate consular assistance in line with our commitment to assisting U.S. citizens abroad. We have, in fact, visited Mr. Awadallah five times since April of this year. The most recent visit occurred just a few days ago, on July 11th.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right, but that doesn’t speak to the actual verdict and sentence, which is what I’m asking you about.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any comment on the verdict. But as I’ve said before, we always emphasize – and this goes back to Said’s question earlier – the importance of fair trials and guarantees of humane treatment around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The journalist in Morocco who you talked about at the very beginning, right, was he – is he an American citizen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any indication he is an American citizen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But – and yet you have a position on the verdict in that case, but none in this. So what do we – what do we read into that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You think that this – the guy in Jordan could be guilty?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Each case is different.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s why I’m asking you why you don’t have anything to say about the verdict.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We are going to – we are going to speak based on the facts and the circumstances as they are known to us, but obviously these cases are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So does that mean that you’re not clear on the facts and circumstances of Mr. Awadallah’s case?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think what is very clear to us is that journalists, and hopefully everyone here can agree with this, don’t belong behind bars, that they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, no, I agree with that. I’m not talking about the Morocco case.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That they shouldn’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m talking about case in Jordan. Is it the case that in this situation you do not have all the facts or you – you’re not clear enough on the facts and circumstances of the verdict, of the trial that you will – that you’re not clear enough so that you can’t render an opinion on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What is fair to say is that when the facts and the circumstances are clear to us and when we determine that we can best move the ball forward by speaking publicly, we will never hesitate to do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CUBA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Cuba, real quick?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Back in 2015, July 2015 when relations were restored and President Obama said that it was – the policy of sanctions and so on was a failed policy. And then there was a great deal of hope and so on. But then the preceding administration collapsed all that hope down. But you guys seem to be following the same kind of policy as the previous administration. What are you doing, let’s say, to show people that there are actually – there are benefits to good governance and all that stuff?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I certainly would not say that we are following the previous – the policy of the previous administration. As you know, our Cuba policy is under review. But importantly – and I think this is a pivotal distinction – our policy, as you heard from the Secretary, it focuses on the wellbeing of the Cuban people, and at the center of that policy are democracy and our human rights.</p>
<p>And what we are assessing in the context of that policy review is how the United States can best support the aspirations of the Cuban people. So that policy review remains ongoing. It is something – the issue of human rights on the island is very important to us, and we’re seeing yesterday and today in the streets all throughout Cuba that it is very important, as you might expect, to the Cuban people as well. And as we undertake this review, at the center of that review will be the welfare and the wellbeing of those Cuban people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>That’s exactly what the previous administration said their policy was towards Cuba, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, we haven’t spoken – we haven’t spoken &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So until your review is complete, why is Said incorrect in saying that you’re following – you’re doing the exact same thing that the Trump administration did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, he was speaking of our policies towards Cuba. And again, our &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, yeah. You haven’t changed the previous administration’s policies, right, so until that review is complete, you’re doing the same thing, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I can assure you that we are going about this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You’re doing the same thing as the previous administration did, right? You haven’t changed the policy.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have not announced our Cuba policy, but what we have said is that democracy and human rights are at the center of it.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on that, does the administration still consider Cuba a state sponsor of terrorism?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We – there’s been no change. As you know, the state sponsor of terrorism list is –it’s evaluated, and the report is released once a year. When we have a new report to release, we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s part of the policy review in general of – for Cuba policy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are always reviewing issues of state sponsorship for countries around the world pursuant to the requirement to put forward the state sponsor of terrorism list. Our review of Cuba and Cuba policy, it is taking place in parallel to that.</p>
<p>Thank &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So separate, but parallel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think that is a fair characterization.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have time for one &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure, one last question.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ethiopia. The election results came out this past weekend. The United States has voiced concern previously about the atmosphere in which the elections were to be held. What’s your view on the election results? Do you think they confer legitimacy on Prime Minister Abiy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, the Secretary himself has spoken to this. It was late last month, June 21st, he issued a statement noting that the elections took place against the backdrop of grave instability, including increasing interethnic and intercommunal conflicts and an electoral process that was not free or fair for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p>The boycott of the elections by opposition parties, the detention of vocal political leaders, the ongoing violence in multiple parts of the country – look, all of this underscores the need to launch an inclusive effort to build a national consensus on the governance of Ethiopia that, importantly, preserves the sovereignty and the unity of the state and strengthens rather than undermines the constitutional order.</p>
<p>In this period following the election, it’s critical that Ethiopians come together to confront growing divisions. We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and to refrain from inciting others to violence. And we’ll be watching the situation very carefully going forward. Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:57 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
