<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 15:30:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Reported Massacre in Mali</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/reported-massacre-in-mali/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 15:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are following the extremely disturbing accounts of large numbers of people killed earlier this week in the village of Mourah in the Mopti region of central Mali. We offer our condolences to the families of all civilians who died.</p>
<p>We are concerned that many reports suggest that the perpetrators were unaccountable forces from the Kremlin-backed Wagner Group. Other reports claim the Malian Armed Forces (FAMa) had targeted elements of known violent extremist groups. These conflicting reports illustrate the urgent need for the Malian transition authorities to give impartial investigators free, unfettered, and safe access to the area where these tragic events unfolded.</p>
<p>Immediate access to eyewitnesses and to the many individuals who are said to be in government custody is essential set the record straight. We call on Mali’s transition government to grant access to the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali (MINUSMA) to conduct a rigorous investigation as mandated by the UN Security Council. Failure to provide a thorough and credible accounting of the facts and accountability will only serve to sow divisions in Malian society, undermine the credibility, legitimacy, and reputation of the FAMa, drive communities into the hands of violent extremist groups, and create conditions for more violence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are following the extremely disturbing accounts of large numbers of people killed earlier this week in the village of Mourah in the Mopti region of central Mali. We offer our condolences to the families of all civilians who died.</p>
<p>We are concerned that many reports suggest that the perpetrators were unaccountable forces from the Kremlin-backed Wagner Group. Other reports claim the Malian Armed Forces (FAMa) had targeted elements of known violent extremist groups. These conflicting reports illustrate the urgent need for the Malian transition authorities to give impartial investigators free, unfettered, and safe access to the area where these tragic events unfolded.</p>
<p>Immediate access to eyewitnesses and to the many individuals who are said to be in government custody is essential set the record straight. We call on Mali’s transition government to grant access to the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali (MINUSMA) to conduct a rigorous investigation as mandated by the UN Security Council. Failure to provide a thorough and credible accounting of the facts and accountability will only serve to sow divisions in Malian society, undermine the credibility, legitimacy, and reputation of the FAMa, drive communities into the hands of violent extremist groups, and create conditions for more violence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Chuck Todd of NBC’s Meet the Press</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-chuck-todd-of-nbcs-meet-the-press-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 15:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330871</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And joining me now is the Secretary of State, Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, welcome back to Meet the Press.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, Chuck.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me start with the news of the Russians pulling back from Kyiv, focusing, it appears now, on the East where they’ve had a bit more military success.  Are we in a new phase in this war?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Chuck, we may be.  I think this is evidence that Russia’s original plans to take over the whole country, including Kyiv, have been dealt a devastating setback.  They are regrouping.  They may be focusing on the East.  But let’s keep in mind they still have the ability to wreak massive death and destruction, including in places like Kyiv, with airpower and missiles.  And at the same time, they may be regrouping; they may be recalibrating.  We’re focused on what they’re doing, not what they’re saying.  And if it’s a refocus on the East, there’s still a tremendous amount that’s going to be ahead of us.  As President Biden said recently, this could go on for some time, and the question is how much death and destruction Russia wreaks in the meantime.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Are we going to help Ukraine reinforce sort of now the Central and Western part of the country, reinforce Kyiv so that essentially the Russians don’t even think about coming back?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chuck, we’re doing that every single day.  Just over the course of this administration we’ve provided more than $2.3 billion in security assistance – in the last month alone, $1.6 billion – the very kinds of things that have made the Ukrainians incredibly effective in dealing with this Russian onslaught, in pushing it back, in setting it back.  And look, what we’ve already seen is a strategic setback and maybe even defeat for Russia.</p>
<p>Russia had three goals going into this: to subjugate Ukraine to its will, to deny its sovereignty and its independence; to assert Russian power; and to divide the West, divide the alliance.  And on all three fronts, it’s failed.  Ukraine is now more united.  It’s – a sovereign, independent Ukraine is going to be there a lot longer than Vladimir Putin is on the scene.  Russian power has actually been vastly diminished.  The military has greatly underperformed.  Its economy is reeling.  And of course, NATO, the West, are more united than in any time in recent memory.  So on those grounds alone, we’ve already seen a dramatic setback for Russia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You have just described a situation – and Richard Engel was telling me that there are people in Ukraine going, hey, we’ve got Putin in as weak of a spot as we’ve had him in a long time.  This is actually not the time to suddenly negotiate a way for him to get out of this.  So – and nobody wants to see more war.  At the same time, nobody – I don’t think a lot of people, including the President of the United States, wants to see Putin remain in power after this.  So can we really end this with giving Putin some sort of gain in the Donbas?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chuck, the – how this war ends is up to two things.  It’s up to the Ukrainian people and their elected representatives, including President Zelenskyy.  We’ll support whatever they want to do in terms of how this war comes to an end.  And as to Mr. Putin’s future, that’s up to the Russian people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But do you acknowledge he’s in a weak moment?  I mean, is this a moment – is this a moment that we’re – if he’s – if we – if we let him lie and he wreaks havoc again, are we going to regret not taking advantage of this moment?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Again, it’s up to, in the first instance, Ukrainians when it comes to what’s going on in Ukraine, and Russians when it comes to what’s going on in Russia.  And here’s the thing:  Even though he’s been set back, even though I believe this is already a strategic defeat for Vladimir Putin, the death and destruction that he is wreaking every single day in Ukraine, the images that are on our TVs and on social media every single day are terrible.  And so there’s also a strong interest in bringing those to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I want to ask about the Zelenskyy – potential Zelenskyy-Putin face-to-face in Turkey.  How realistic is that?  And does President Zelenskyy – does he have the ability to negotiate sanctions relief with Putin?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So how realistic it is, very hard to say.  The Ukrainians have sought a direct engagement with President Putin for President Zelenskyy.  President Putin has rejected that repeatedly.  We’ll see if he goes forward with anything.  But again, our focus is on making sure that we’re doing everything possible to strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the negotiating table, including with a potential meeting between President Zelenskyy and President Putin.  And that’s exactly what we’re doing.  We’ve been supporting Ukraine.  We’ve been imposing extraordinary pressure on Russia.  We’ve been solidifying our own alliance.  All of that goes to strengthening Ukraine’s hand when it comes to any negotiations with Russia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Again, I want to go back to – what is – can Zelenskyy negotiate sanctions relief at all here or not?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The entire international community that’s come together to impose those sanctions on Russia will be looking to see what Ukraine is doing and what it wants to do.  And if it concludes that it can bring this war to an end, stop the death and destruction, and continue to assert its independence and its sovereignty, and ultimately that requires the lifting of sanctions, of course we’re going to look at that.  The purpose of the sanctions, Chuck, is not to be there indefinitely.  It’s to change Russia’s conduct.  And if, as a result of negotiations, the sanctions, the pressure, the support for Ukraine, we achieve just that, then at some point the sanctions will go away.  But that is profoundly up to Russia and what it does going forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The restrengthening of the ruble – and I understand there’s some market manipulation there to do that – but there clearly is some signs that the ruble is strengthened. Obviously, Europe – there are plenty of European countries that continue to pay Russia for oil and gas.  Is there more that can be done to tighten – to tighten these sanctions again?  Because it looks like he’s found some ways around them.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Chuck, first, virtually all of the forecasts show Russia’s economy contracting by 10 percent this year.  That is dramatic, especially at a time when other economies, including our own, are rebounding dramatically.  Second, when it comes to the ruble, it’s more than a little manipulation, it’s a lot of manipulation.  People are being prevented from unloading rubles.  That’s artificially propping up the value.  That’s not sustainable.  So I think you’re going to see that change.  We’ve seen the most extraordinary exodus of virtually every leading business from around the world leaving Russia – everything from McDonald’s to Toyota.  And that’s having not just an immediate impact, but a long-term impact.</p>
<p>And then the export controls that we’ve imposed on Russia, denying it the technology it needs to modernize industry after industry, that’s going to have an increasing bite.  Having said that, to your point, we’re working every single day with partners and allies around the world to make sure that we’re tightening the sanctions, closing any loopholes, adding new ones.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Whose side is time on here?  If this is a six – if this is going to drag out another six months, can Ukraine’s military hold up?  Can the European alliance hold up?  Can Putin survive economically?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chuck, when it comes to the fundamentals, which is to say Putin’s objective in subjugating Ukraine to his will, on denying, taking away its sovereignty and independence, time is certainly not on Vladimir Putin’s side because, as I said, a sovereign, independent Ukraine has demonstrated it’s going to be around a lot longer than Vladimir Putin is on the scene.  The real question, though, again, is what happens in the meantime.  If this goes on, how much death, how much destruction is there?  And that is terrible.</p>
<p>So we have a strong interest, the Ukrainians have a strong interest, in ending that.  We’re all working toward that.  The way to do that is to give Ukraine the strongest possible hand, to put as much pressure as we possibly can on Russia while we’re strengthening our own defenses.  That’s exactly what we’ve been doing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Antony Blinken, appreciate you coming on and sharing the administration’s perspective.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Chuck.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And joining me now is the Secretary of State, Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, welcome back to Meet the Press.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, Chuck.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me start with the news of the Russians pulling back from Kyiv, focusing, it appears now, on the East where they’ve had a bit more military success.  Are we in a new phase in this war?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Chuck, we may be.  I think this is evidence that Russia’s original plans to take over the whole country, including Kyiv, have been dealt a devastating setback.  They are regrouping.  They may be focusing on the East.  But let’s keep in mind they still have the ability to wreak massive death and destruction, including in places like Kyiv, with airpower and missiles.  And at the same time, they may be regrouping; they may be recalibrating.  We’re focused on what they’re doing, not what they’re saying.  And if it’s a refocus on the East, there’s still a tremendous amount that’s going to be ahead of us.  As President Biden said recently, this could go on for some time, and the question is how much death and destruction Russia wreaks in the meantime.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Are we going to help Ukraine reinforce sort of now the Central and Western part of the country, reinforce Kyiv so that essentially the Russians don’t even think about coming back?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chuck, we’re doing that every single day.  Just over the course of this administration we’ve provided more than $2.3 billion in security assistance – in the last month alone, $1.6 billion – the very kinds of things that have made the Ukrainians incredibly effective in dealing with this Russian onslaught, in pushing it back, in setting it back.  And look, what we’ve already seen is a strategic setback and maybe even defeat for Russia.</p>
<p>Russia had three goals going into this: to subjugate Ukraine to its will, to deny its sovereignty and its independence; to assert Russian power; and to divide the West, divide the alliance.  And on all three fronts, it’s failed.  Ukraine is now more united.  It’s – a sovereign, independent Ukraine is going to be there a lot longer than Vladimir Putin is on the scene.  Russian power has actually been vastly diminished.  The military has greatly underperformed.  Its economy is reeling.  And of course, NATO, the West, are more united than in any time in recent memory.  So on those grounds alone, we’ve already seen a dramatic setback for Russia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You have just described a situation – and Richard Engel was telling me that there are people in Ukraine going, hey, we’ve got Putin in as weak of a spot as we’ve had him in a long time.  This is actually not the time to suddenly negotiate a way for him to get out of this.  So – and nobody wants to see more war.  At the same time, nobody – I don’t think a lot of people, including the President of the United States, wants to see Putin remain in power after this.  So can we really end this with giving Putin some sort of gain in the Donbas?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chuck, the – how this war ends is up to two things.  It’s up to the Ukrainian people and their elected representatives, including President Zelenskyy.  We’ll support whatever they want to do in terms of how this war comes to an end.  And as to Mr. Putin’s future, that’s up to the Russian people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But do you acknowledge he’s in a weak moment?  I mean, is this a moment – is this a moment that we’re – if he’s – if we – if we let him lie and he wreaks havoc again, are we going to regret not taking advantage of this moment?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Again, it’s up to, in the first instance, Ukrainians when it comes to what’s going on in Ukraine, and Russians when it comes to what’s going on in Russia.  And here’s the thing:  Even though he’s been set back, even though I believe this is already a strategic defeat for Vladimir Putin, the death and destruction that he is wreaking every single day in Ukraine, the images that are on our TVs and on social media every single day are terrible.  And so there’s also a strong interest in bringing those to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I want to ask about the Zelenskyy – potential Zelenskyy-Putin face-to-face in Turkey.  How realistic is that?  And does President Zelenskyy – does he have the ability to negotiate sanctions relief with Putin?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So how realistic it is, very hard to say.  The Ukrainians have sought a direct engagement with President Putin for President Zelenskyy.  President Putin has rejected that repeatedly.  We’ll see if he goes forward with anything.  But again, our focus is on making sure that we’re doing everything possible to strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the negotiating table, including with a potential meeting between President Zelenskyy and President Putin.  And that’s exactly what we’re doing.  We’ve been supporting Ukraine.  We’ve been imposing extraordinary pressure on Russia.  We’ve been solidifying our own alliance.  All of that goes to strengthening Ukraine’s hand when it comes to any negotiations with Russia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Again, I want to go back to – what is – can Zelenskyy negotiate sanctions relief at all here or not?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The entire international community that’s come together to impose those sanctions on Russia will be looking to see what Ukraine is doing and what it wants to do.  And if it concludes that it can bring this war to an end, stop the death and destruction, and continue to assert its independence and its sovereignty, and ultimately that requires the lifting of sanctions, of course we’re going to look at that.  The purpose of the sanctions, Chuck, is not to be there indefinitely.  It’s to change Russia’s conduct.  And if, as a result of negotiations, the sanctions, the pressure, the support for Ukraine, we achieve just that, then at some point the sanctions will go away.  But that is profoundly up to Russia and what it does going forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The restrengthening of the ruble – and I understand there’s some market manipulation there to do that – but there clearly is some signs that the ruble is strengthened. Obviously, Europe – there are plenty of European countries that continue to pay Russia for oil and gas.  Is there more that can be done to tighten – to tighten these sanctions again?  Because it looks like he’s found some ways around them.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Chuck, first, virtually all of the forecasts show Russia’s economy contracting by 10 percent this year.  That is dramatic, especially at a time when other economies, including our own, are rebounding dramatically.  Second, when it comes to the ruble, it’s more than a little manipulation, it’s a lot of manipulation.  People are being prevented from unloading rubles.  That’s artificially propping up the value.  That’s not sustainable.  So I think you’re going to see that change.  We’ve seen the most extraordinary exodus of virtually every leading business from around the world leaving Russia – everything from McDonald’s to Toyota.  And that’s having not just an immediate impact, but a long-term impact.</p>
<p>And then the export controls that we’ve imposed on Russia, denying it the technology it needs to modernize industry after industry, that’s going to have an increasing bite.  Having said that, to your point, we’re working every single day with partners and allies around the world to make sure that we’re tightening the sanctions, closing any loopholes, adding new ones.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Whose side is time on here?  If this is a six – if this is going to drag out another six months, can Ukraine’s military hold up?  Can the European alliance hold up?  Can Putin survive economically?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chuck, when it comes to the fundamentals, which is to say Putin’s objective in subjugating Ukraine to his will, on denying, taking away its sovereignty and independence, time is certainly not on Vladimir Putin’s side because, as I said, a sovereign, independent Ukraine has demonstrated it’s going to be around a lot longer than Vladimir Putin is on the scene.  The real question, though, again, is what happens in the meantime.  If this goes on, how much death, how much destruction is there?  And that is terrible.</p>
<p>So we have a strong interest, the Ukrainians have a strong interest, in ending that.  We’re all working toward that.  The way to do that is to give Ukraine the strongest possible hand, to put as much pressure as we possibly can on Russia while we’re strengthening our own defenses.  That’s exactly what we’ve been doing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Antony Blinken, appreciate you coming on and sharing the administration’s perspective.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Chuck.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Dana Bash of CNN’s State of the Union</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-dana-bash-of-cnns-state-of-the-union-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 14:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330868</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Joining me now is U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Thank you so much for joining me this morning.  So I want to start with those horrific images and reports from Bucha.  What is your reaction?  And do you see evidence here of crimes against humanity?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Dana, you can’t help but see these images as a punch to the gut.  And look, we’ve said before Russia’s aggression that we thought it was likely that they would commit atrocities.  Since the aggression, we’ve come out and said that we believe that Russian forces have committed war crimes and we’ve been working to document that, to provide the information that we have to the relevant institutions and organizations that will put all of this together, and there needs to be accountability for it.</p>
<p>But I think the most important thing is we can’t become numb to this.  We can’t normalize this.  This is the reality of what’s going on every single day as long as Russia’s brutality against Ukraine continues.  That’s why it needs to come to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And the Ukrainian foreign minister said Russia aims to eliminate as many Ukrainians as they can.  Beyond war crimes, do you see this as genocide?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, we will look hard and document everything that we see, put it all together, make sure that the relevant institutions and organizations that are looking at this – including the State Department – have everything they need to assess exactly what took place in Ukraine, who’s responsible, and what it amounts to.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let’s talk about the punishment here.  The EU is already saying it will impose new, even harsher sanctions over this.  What about the U.S.?  Would the U.S. impose more sanctions, for example, on Russian oil, cracking down on all Russian banks, banning energy payments from the SWIFT banking system?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Dana, we’re doing this every single day.  We’re tightening the existing sanctions.  We’re adding new ones.  We’re doing it in full coordination with Europeans and other partners around the world.  And one of the results is that the Russian economy is reeling.  There are forecasts by most of the major forecasters that its economy is going to contract by 10 percent this year, and that’s in stark contrast to economies like our own, which are growing rapidly.  We’re seeing an exodus of every major company from Russia.  And over the long term, the export controls that we’ve imposed means that they will not have the technology they need to modernize key aspects of their economy and their future.</p>
<p>So these sanctions are having a big bite now, they’re going to have a big bite going forward as long as this lasts, and we are every single day making sure that they’re not only tightened, but increased.  We announced additional sanctions just a couple of days ago.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  They still have a lifeline, particularly when it comes to their energy sector.  Is that something that the U.S. is considering along with its Western allies?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re in constant conversation with allies and partners about the most effective ways to tighten, to strengthen the sanctions, and at the same time, we’re very focused on making sure that Europe has the energy it needs not only to get through this year and this winter, which it has, but next year as well.  But the other thing, Dana, is this:  If you step back and look at this, this has already been a dramatic strategic setback for Russia and, I would say, a strategic defeat.</p>
<p>They had three aims going into this.  One was to subjugate Ukraine to Russia’s will, to take away its sovereignty and independence.  The second was to assert Russian power.  The third was to divide the West and NATO.  On all three fronts, it’s already lost.  Ukraine, its sovereignty and independence, is going to be there a lot longer than Vladimir Putin is going to be on the scene.  The Russian military has dramatically underperformed.  Its economy is reeling.  And the West, NATO, are more united than any time I can remember.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me ask you about that military statement that you just made for a minute because the new intelligence that is out there says that they are shifting specifically to the eastern part of Ukraine militarily.  And President Zelenskyy actually said that the Russians are pulling back from Kyiv.  We’ve actually seen that now.  You’ve said it’s what they do, not what they say.  We saw that.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What does that tell you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we are seeing that.  It’s, I think, too early to say what that actually means because they could be regrouping and restocking and replenishing and then coming back to Kyiv.  It’s also very possible that what we’re seeing is what it seems to be, which is a focus to the East and the South.  But Dana, even there, if that’s what they’re doing, then I think that the Ukrainians have already demonstrated that unless they’re able to move every single Ukrainian out of whatever piece of territory they’re trying to hold, it’s not going to last because the will of the Ukrainian people is clear:  They will not be subjected to a Russian occupation whether that’s in and around Kyiv or whether that’s in the East and the South.</p>
<p>But here is the problem:  In the meantime, the terrible death and destruction that you started with is going to continue.  And that’s why it is so urgent that Russia end this war of aggression and we do everything that we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to strengthen our own defenses.  All of that is going to strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the negotiating table and hopefully bring this to a quicker end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  There are reports that Soviet-era tanks will be transferred to Ukraine.  Can you tell me about the U.S. role in facilitating that?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Dana, I can’t get into specific weapon systems.  What I can say is this:  First, we have provided, just over the course of this administration, $2.3 billion in security assistance of one kind or another to Ukraine, just $1.6 billion in the last month alone.  That includes many different weapon systems.  And let me give you one example of this:  Between the United States and our allies and partners, for every Russian tank, there are or will soon be in Ukraine more than 10 anti-tank systems for every Russian tank.</p>
<p>So across the board, what we’re trying to do is to make sure that Ukrainians have the systems that they need, that they can use, and they can use right away.  And that’s what’s been happening.  It’s been incredibly effective because of the courage and bravery of the Ukrainian forces.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So what you just described sounds like the U.S. facilitating those tanks going in.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We are working with countries around the world to facilitate the movement of the systems that the Ukrainians can actually use into Ukraine one way or another.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  This week Ukraine floated the idea of taking a Switzerland-like position of neutrality in Europe as part of a peace deal with Russia, but only if Western nations provide security guarantees if Ukraine is attacked.  Would the U.S. help provide those security guarantees?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So Dana, first, all of this is up to the Ukrainians, which is to say that if they negotiate something that meets their needs, that preserves their sovereignty, their independence, we will back it.  And we’re not going to be less Ukrainian than Ukrainians.  We’re not going to be more Ukrainian than Ukrainians.  So first and foremost, it’s up to them, to their elected representatives, to President Zelenskyy.</p>
<p>When it comes to the future, we and allies and partners are going to want to make sure that we do everything we can to ensure that this can’t happen again and that Ukraine has the means to defend itself, to deter further Russian aggression.  So we will look at anything that we can do to back up that kind of outcome.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sounds like that’s a yes because this is coming from the Ukrainians, as you know.  But they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No, I’m not going to get – yeah, I’m not going to get ahead of any details of what might come into some kind of agreement.  But we’re going to want to make sure that we do what we can to help Ukraine defend itself going forward, to deter future Russian aggression.  There are many things that could go into that, but I’m not going to get ahead of them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Before I let you go, the Biden administration announced this week that you will lift a Trump-era pandemic restriction called Title 42, which restricted immigration at the Southern border.  It comes as your administration says there could be up to 18,000 apprehensions of undocumented migrants per day.  Does the administration see an influx of migrants as a problem, and can you guarantee that they will be treated humanely?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Dana, first, when it comes to Title 42, all along we’ve been following the science.  That’s what this is about.  So when the CDC and others conclude that the science doesn’t warrant that, as is now happening, then we’ll take action.</p>
<p>Here’s my focus and the Vice President’s focus as well:  We’re focused on making sure that people throughout our hemisphere have opportunities at home going forward so they’re not faced with this really hard choice of leaving everything behind and trying to come to the United States.  So building that kind of opportunity, creating what one of my colleagues has called a “right to remain,” is our focus.</p>
<p>In the nearer term, the focus I have is trying to make sure that transit countries in particular take steps to make sure that it – that folks who might come or try to come to the United States through their countries can’t do that.  So that’s what I’m focused on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for your time.  I really appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks.  Great to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Joining me now is U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Thank you so much for joining me this morning.  So I want to start with those horrific images and reports from Bucha.  What is your reaction?  And do you see evidence here of crimes against humanity?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Dana, you can’t help but see these images as a punch to the gut.  And look, we’ve said before Russia’s aggression that we thought it was likely that they would commit atrocities.  Since the aggression, we’ve come out and said that we believe that Russian forces have committed war crimes and we’ve been working to document that, to provide the information that we have to the relevant institutions and organizations that will put all of this together, and there needs to be accountability for it.</p>
<p>But I think the most important thing is we can’t become numb to this.  We can’t normalize this.  This is the reality of what’s going on every single day as long as Russia’s brutality against Ukraine continues.  That’s why it needs to come to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And the Ukrainian foreign minister said Russia aims to eliminate as many Ukrainians as they can.  Beyond war crimes, do you see this as genocide?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, we will look hard and document everything that we see, put it all together, make sure that the relevant institutions and organizations that are looking at this – including the State Department – have everything they need to assess exactly what took place in Ukraine, who’s responsible, and what it amounts to.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let’s talk about the punishment here.  The EU is already saying it will impose new, even harsher sanctions over this.  What about the U.S.?  Would the U.S. impose more sanctions, for example, on Russian oil, cracking down on all Russian banks, banning energy payments from the SWIFT banking system?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Dana, we’re doing this every single day.  We’re tightening the existing sanctions.  We’re adding new ones.  We’re doing it in full coordination with Europeans and other partners around the world.  And one of the results is that the Russian economy is reeling.  There are forecasts by most of the major forecasters that its economy is going to contract by 10 percent this year, and that’s in stark contrast to economies like our own, which are growing rapidly.  We’re seeing an exodus of every major company from Russia.  And over the long term, the export controls that we’ve imposed means that they will not have the technology they need to modernize key aspects of their economy and their future.</p>
<p>So these sanctions are having a big bite now, they’re going to have a big bite going forward as long as this lasts, and we are every single day making sure that they’re not only tightened, but increased.  We announced additional sanctions just a couple of days ago.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  They still have a lifeline, particularly when it comes to their energy sector.  Is that something that the U.S. is considering along with its Western allies?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re in constant conversation with allies and partners about the most effective ways to tighten, to strengthen the sanctions, and at the same time, we’re very focused on making sure that Europe has the energy it needs not only to get through this year and this winter, which it has, but next year as well.  But the other thing, Dana, is this:  If you step back and look at this, this has already been a dramatic strategic setback for Russia and, I would say, a strategic defeat.</p>
<p>They had three aims going into this.  One was to subjugate Ukraine to Russia’s will, to take away its sovereignty and independence.  The second was to assert Russian power.  The third was to divide the West and NATO.  On all three fronts, it’s already lost.  Ukraine, its sovereignty and independence, is going to be there a lot longer than Vladimir Putin is going to be on the scene.  The Russian military has dramatically underperformed.  Its economy is reeling.  And the West, NATO, are more united than any time I can remember.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Let me ask you about that military statement that you just made for a minute because the new intelligence that is out there says that they are shifting specifically to the eastern part of Ukraine militarily.  And President Zelenskyy actually said that the Russians are pulling back from Kyiv.  We’ve actually seen that now.  You’ve said it’s what they do, not what they say.  We saw that.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What does that tell you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we are seeing that.  It’s, I think, too early to say what that actually means because they could be regrouping and restocking and replenishing and then coming back to Kyiv.  It’s also very possible that what we’re seeing is what it seems to be, which is a focus to the East and the South.  But Dana, even there, if that’s what they’re doing, then I think that the Ukrainians have already demonstrated that unless they’re able to move every single Ukrainian out of whatever piece of territory they’re trying to hold, it’s not going to last because the will of the Ukrainian people is clear:  They will not be subjected to a Russian occupation whether that’s in and around Kyiv or whether that’s in the East and the South.</p>
<p>But here is the problem:  In the meantime, the terrible death and destruction that you started with is going to continue.  And that’s why it is so urgent that Russia end this war of aggression and we do everything that we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to strengthen our own defenses.  All of that is going to strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the negotiating table and hopefully bring this to a quicker end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  There are reports that Soviet-era tanks will be transferred to Ukraine.  Can you tell me about the U.S. role in facilitating that?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Dana, I can’t get into specific weapon systems.  What I can say is this:  First, we have provided, just over the course of this administration, $2.3 billion in security assistance of one kind or another to Ukraine, just $1.6 billion in the last month alone.  That includes many different weapon systems.  And let me give you one example of this:  Between the United States and our allies and partners, for every Russian tank, there are or will soon be in Ukraine more than 10 anti-tank systems for every Russian tank.</p>
<p>So across the board, what we’re trying to do is to make sure that Ukrainians have the systems that they need, that they can use, and they can use right away.  And that’s what’s been happening.  It’s been incredibly effective because of the courage and bravery of the Ukrainian forces.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So what you just described sounds like the U.S. facilitating those tanks going in.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We are working with countries around the world to facilitate the movement of the systems that the Ukrainians can actually use into Ukraine one way or another.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  This week Ukraine floated the idea of taking a Switzerland-like position of neutrality in Europe as part of a peace deal with Russia, but only if Western nations provide security guarantees if Ukraine is attacked.  Would the U.S. help provide those security guarantees?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So Dana, first, all of this is up to the Ukrainians, which is to say that if they negotiate something that meets their needs, that preserves their sovereignty, their independence, we will back it.  And we’re not going to be less Ukrainian than Ukrainians.  We’re not going to be more Ukrainian than Ukrainians.  So first and foremost, it’s up to them, to their elected representatives, to President Zelenskyy.</p>
<p>When it comes to the future, we and allies and partners are going to want to make sure that we do everything we can to ensure that this can’t happen again and that Ukraine has the means to defend itself, to deter further Russian aggression.  So we will look at anything that we can do to back up that kind of outcome.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sounds like that’s a yes because this is coming from the Ukrainians, as you know.  But they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No, I’m not going to get – yeah, I’m not going to get ahead of any details of what might come into some kind of agreement.  But we’re going to want to make sure that we do what we can to help Ukraine defend itself going forward, to deter future Russian aggression.  There are many things that could go into that, but I’m not going to get ahead of them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Before I let you go, the Biden administration announced this week that you will lift a Trump-era pandemic restriction called Title 42, which restricted immigration at the Southern border.  It comes as your administration says there could be up to 18,000 apprehensions of undocumented migrants per day.  Does the administration see an influx of migrants as a problem, and can you guarantee that they will be treated humanely?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Dana, first, when it comes to Title 42, all along we’ve been following the science.  That’s what this is about.  So when the CDC and others conclude that the science doesn’t warrant that, as is now happening, then we’ll take action.</p>
<p>Here’s my focus and the Vice President’s focus as well:  We’re focused on making sure that people throughout our hemisphere have opportunities at home going forward so they’re not faced with this really hard choice of leaving everything behind and trying to come to the United States.  So building that kind of opportunity, creating what one of my colleagues has called a “right to remain,” is our focus.</p>
<p>In the nearer term, the focus I have is trying to make sure that transit countries in particular take steps to make sure that it – that folks who might come or try to come to the United States through their countries can’t do that.  So that’s what I’m focused on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for your time.  I really appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks.  Great to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 14:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Brussels, Belgium, April 5 to 7, 2022, to attend the NATO Foreign Ministerial. At the Ministerial, the Secretary will have the opportunity to highlight NATO’s essential role in preserving Transatlantic security, including our joint efforts to hold President Putin accountable and promote a swift end to his senseless and destructive war of choice against Ukraine. The Secretary will discuss continued Allied efforts to provide support for Ukraine. The Secretary will also join a G7 ministerial meeting and hold additional discussions with other Allies and partners.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Brussels, Belgium, April 5 to 7, 2022, to attend the NATO Foreign Ministerial. At the Ministerial, the Secretary will have the opportunity to highlight NATO’s essential role in preserving Transatlantic security, including our joint efforts to hold President Putin accountable and promote a swift end to his senseless and destructive war of choice against Ukraine. The Secretary will discuss continued Allied efforts to provide support for Ukraine. The Secretary will also join a G7 ministerial meeting and hold additional discussions with other Allies and partners.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Robinson’s Travel to Poland, Latvia, and Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-for-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-robinsons-travel-to-poland-latvia-and-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 20:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement (INL) Todd D. Robinson traveled to Poland March 30 – April 2. While in Warsaw, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with Ukrainian civil society organizations. During his visit to Rzeszow, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police, as well as members of the Embassy Kyiv team who are on the frontlines of the response to the crisis caused by Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. He underscored the Department of State’s commitment to providing emergency medical and protective equipment to the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police to support their efforts to rescue and protect civilians.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Robinson is traveling to Riga, Latvia April 3-5. While in Riga, the Assistant Secretary is meeting with Latvian government officials to discuss border security and efforts to further combat corruption and transnational organized crime.</p>
<p>Finally, Assistant Secretary Robinson will travel to Berlin, Germany April 5-6 where he will participate in a ministerial support conference on Moldova. The Assistant Secretary will co-chair a roundtable focused on effective border management and preventing trafficking in persons.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> or visit @StateINL on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement (INL) Todd D. Robinson traveled to Poland March 30 – April 2. While in Warsaw, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with Ukrainian civil society organizations. During his visit to Rzeszow, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police, as well as members of the Embassy Kyiv team who are on the frontlines of the response to the crisis caused by Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. He underscored the Department of State’s commitment to providing emergency medical and protective equipment to the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police to support their efforts to rescue and protect civilians.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Robinson is traveling to Riga, Latvia April 3-5. While in Riga, the Assistant Secretary is meeting with Latvian government officials to discuss border security and efforts to further combat corruption and transnational organized crime.</p>
<p>Finally, Assistant Secretary Robinson will travel to Berlin, Germany April 5-6 where he will participate in a ministerial support conference on Moldova. The Assistant Secretary will co-chair a roundtable focused on effective border management and preventing trafficking in persons.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> or visit @StateINL on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Delivery of Humanitarian Assistance to Tigray and Afar Regions</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/delivery-of-humanitarian-assistance-to-tigray-and-afar-regions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 20:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes steps by the Government of Ethiopia and regional authorities to implement a cessation of hostilities. We commend them on the delivery of humanitarian assistance over recent days to Ethiopians in the Tigray and Afar regions. Over one hundred thousand Ethiopians will receive life-saving food from the two initial convoys that have mobilized in the past three days. This is an important step toward implementing the cessation of hostilities and addressing the urgent humanitarian needs in both regions. Now, we urge all stakeholders to make every effort possible to sustain the delivery of life-saving assistance.</p>
<p>The United States appreciates the extraordinary efforts of humanitarian actors to enable this delivery of humanitarian assistance. Operating in difficult circumstances across Ethiopia, humanitarian actors continue to show their agility, dedication, and commitment to serving those in need. We call on all parties in conflict-affected regions to ensure the safety of humanitarian staff. The United States supports and acknowledges the positive undertakings in this regard made by the Government of Ethiopia and the regional authorities in Tigray and Afar.</p>
<p>We urge all parties to build upon this positive humanitarian development to take the difficult next steps to realize peace in northern Ethiopia. The United States will continue to do everything within our power to assist all Ethiopians in need throughout the country and support an inclusive political process to achieve progress toward common security and prosperity for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes steps by the Government of Ethiopia and regional authorities to implement a cessation of hostilities. We commend them on the delivery of humanitarian assistance over recent days to Ethiopians in the Tigray and Afar regions. Over one hundred thousand Ethiopians will receive life-saving food from the two initial convoys that have mobilized in the past three days. This is an important step toward implementing the cessation of hostilities and addressing the urgent humanitarian needs in both regions. Now, we urge all stakeholders to make every effort possible to sustain the delivery of life-saving assistance.</p>
<p>The United States appreciates the extraordinary efforts of humanitarian actors to enable this delivery of humanitarian assistance. Operating in difficult circumstances across Ethiopia, humanitarian actors continue to show their agility, dedication, and commitment to serving those in need. We call on all parties in conflict-affected regions to ensure the safety of humanitarian staff. The United States supports and acknowledges the positive undertakings in this regard made by the Government of Ethiopia and the regional authorities in Tigray and Afar.</p>
<p>We urge all parties to build upon this positive humanitarian development to take the difficult next steps to realize peace in northern Ethiopia. The United States will continue to do everything within our power to assist all Ethiopians in need throughout the country and support an inclusive political process to achieve progress toward common security and prosperity for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Israeli Minister of Regional Cooperation Esawi Frej</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-israeli-minister-of-regional-cooperation-esawi-frej/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 20:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli Minister of Regional Cooperation Esawi Frej earlier today in Washington and expressed her condolences regarding the recent wave of terrorist attacks in Israel. They discussed efforts to strengthen Israeli-Palestinian economic relations in a way that brings tangible improvements to the quality of life of the Palestinian people while also enhancing and deepening Israel’s integration in the region. They also spoke about efforts to expand normalization and the importance of building on normalization agreements to further progress on the Israeli-Palestinian peace track. They discussed the importance of all Palestinians and Israelis living safely and securely with equal measures of freedom, dignity, and prosperity. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the administration’s commitment to a two-state solution, and the importance of reducing intercommunal tensions in Israel ahead of the religious holidays.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli Minister of Regional Cooperation Esawi Frej earlier today in Washington and expressed her condolences regarding the recent wave of terrorist attacks in Israel. They discussed efforts to strengthen Israeli-Palestinian economic relations in a way that brings tangible improvements to the quality of life of the Palestinian people while also enhancing and deepening Israel’s integration in the region. They also spoke about efforts to expand normalization and the importance of building on normalization agreements to further progress on the Israeli-Palestinian peace track. They discussed the importance of all Palestinians and Israelis living safely and securely with equal measures of freedom, dignity, and prosperity. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the administration’s commitment to a two-state solution, and the importance of reducing intercommunal tensions in Israel ahead of the religious holidays.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Jordanian Foreign Minister Safadi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-jordanian-foreign-minister-safadi-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 19:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Jordanian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman H. Safadi to reaffirm the deep strategic relationship between the United States and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the need for calm in Jerusalem during April as Muslims, Jews, and Christians celebrate Ramadan, Passover, and Easter. The Secretary also spoke of his recent participation in the Negev Summit and ways regional partners can work together to support the Palestinian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Jordan’s steadfast support for Ukraine, especially in the United Nations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Jordanian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman H. Safadi to reaffirm the deep strategic relationship between the United States and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the need for calm in Jerusalem during April as Muslims, Jews, and Christians celebrate Ramadan, Passover, and Easter. The Secretary also spoke of his recent participation in the Negev Summit and ways regional partners can work together to support the Palestinian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Jordan’s steadfast support for Ukraine, especially in the United Nations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 18:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their recent meeting in Warsaw, Poland. The Secretary highlighted U.S. efforts to provide Ukraine the support it needs to defend against the Russian Federation’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war. The Secretary emphasized the United States’ unyielding and steadfast support for Ukraine, and lauded Ukraine’s commitment to engaging in diplomacy. He stressed that the United States, Allies, and partners will continue to hold accountable those responsible for atrocities committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their recent meeting in Warsaw, Poland. The Secretary highlighted U.S. efforts to provide Ukraine the support it needs to defend against the Russian Federation’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war. The Secretary emphasized the United States’ unyielding and steadfast support for Ukraine, and lauded Ukraine’s commitment to engaging in diplomacy. He stressed that the United States, Allies, and partners will continue to hold accountable those responsible for atrocities committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing on the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-on-the-u-s-strategy-to-prevent-conflict-and-promote-stability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 17:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  And I’ll let everybody know that while we called this a State Department briefing, it’s actually an interagency briefing today with our colleagues from USAID and the Department of Defense, whom we’re very glad to do this with today.</p>
<p>So good morning once again, everyone, and thank you for joining us.  Today we will be discussing what we can describe as the latest progress in implementing the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  As a quick reminder here at the top, this morning’s briefing is on the record but its contents are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>Okay.  It is my pleasure to let everyone on the line know that we are joined today by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne Witkowsky; we’re also joined by Assistant to the USAID Administrator for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization Robert Jenkins; and Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy at the Department of Defense Joseph McMenamin; and also from here at State, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli from the Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>We’re going to start off with some opening remarks from several of our briefers today, and then we’ll open it up to just a few of your questions.  Okay.  And with that, I’d like to go ahead and turn it over to Assistant Secretary Witkowsky.  Ma’am.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:  </b>Thank you, J.T., and hello to those who have joined.  I’m Anne Witkowsky, Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations.</p>
<p>The President, with support of the U.S. Congress, has initiated a new stage in our implementation of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 and the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  We are moving forward in a spirit of partnership to implement the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability – Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and the coastal West Africa region, which is Benin, Cote d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.</p>
<p>Under the strategy, we’ll begin developing comprehensive 10-year plans for each location.  These plans will emphasize locally driven solutions, long-term visions for our combined efforts, and evidence-based learning.  We recognize that close cooperation between the United States and likeminded regional, national, and local actors, including civil society, will be key to the success of the strategy.  We will tailor our shared approaches to the unique circumstances of local and regional contexts.</p>
<p>A decade-long outlook supports greater consistency across U.S. administrations and commitment to working with partners over the long term.  We will create feedback loops through monitoring and evaluations that will inform learning as we implement the plans with our partners.  In this way, the strategy presents the U.S. Government with a unique opportunity to balance a long-term view with near-term adaptation.</p>
<p>With a focus on locally driven efforts and solutions tailored to local contexts, planning under the strategy will seek to address emerging threats and address the underlying causes of violence and instability.  Our objective is to build resilience to prevent conflicts and crises from breaking out or deteriorating further.</p>
<p>This strategy requires a whole-of-government effort to integrated diplomacy, development, security-sector engagement.  We reflect this whole-of-government approach in our representation here on the call with USAID’s Rob Jenkins; Joe McMenamin, my colleague from the Defense Department; as well as Roman Napoli from the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>In sum, with the announcement of these priority countries, we are taking the next step to chart a new way forward in how the United States partners with other nations to address the challenges of conflict and instability.  The announcement today is also the next critical step in translating the ambitious goals of the bipartisan Global Fragility Act into reality.  Implementing the strategy will prove challenging, but it also affords us an opportunity to bring new ideas, resources, and collective action to some very pressing and important problems.  Our prosperity and security depend on peaceful, self-reliant, and stable economic and security partners.</p>
<p>With that, I will turn it over to Rob.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Well, thank you, Anne, and good morning, everyone.  An important part of the strategy and its implementation will be partnerships.  As the President has said, our diplomats, officers, and experts will work in close cooperation with multilateral organizations and a wide variety of local partners in each nation where these efforts will be pursued, including civil society organizations, community leaders, businesses, and government officials.  Those who are closest and most vulnerable to these challenges know best where the opportunities for peace and stability lie.  They represent the strongest source of promise and immunity from destabilizing forces, and we must support their strength and their resilience.</p>
<p>We know not only is going it alone not smart, it doesn’t work.  My administrator, Samantha Power of USAID, has challenged all of us to maximize the extent to which we can work directly with local partners, working in true, respectful, and effective partnership with the governments, communities and people we are trying to help.  We have learned many lessons in the last two decades, and some of them are very hard lessons.  One of them is we’re not only wasting time if we think we can impose our plan on a situation and expect to achieve success by force of will, number of boots on the ground, or amounts of dollars spent.  We’re wasting time, energy, money, and goodwill to do it alone.</p>
<p>Our lodestar must be inclusive development, working with governments and the people we’re there to help and working with on true partnerships, respectful partnerships as equals.  And inclusive development is co-creation, joint implementation, and acknowledging that we’re in support, helping our friends and partners where they are and where they live.</p>
<p>Thank you.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Joe at the Department of Defense.</p>
<p><b>MR MCMENAMIN:</b>  Thank you, Rob.  My name, just a refresher, Joe McMenamin, and I serve as the principal director for counternarcotics and stabilization policy under the assistant secretary of defense for special operations and low-intensity conflict in the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.  I’d like to thank you all for the opportunity to talk about Department of Defense efforts and (inaudible) in support of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p>Our counternarcotics and stabilization policy office is the lead for the department’s implementation of the Global Fragility Act and is responsible for a vast set of policy issues including counternarcotics, stabilization, UN peacekeeping, and civil affairs.  Several of these areas touch Global Fragility Act issues.  The department is proud to support and has been working closely with the Department of State, USAID, and other agencies well before the Global Fragility Act was passed in December 2019.</p>
<p>We have been joined at the hip for many years, to include laying the groundwork for eventually what became the Stabilization Assistance Review, written together in a collaborative fashion.  Specific to the Global Fragility Act, we worked closely on the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, the prologue, and the country selection.  Such efforts will continue as the Global Fragility Act implementation begins.</p>
<p>The Global Fragility Act reflects the administration’s view of emerging threats and opportunities and outlines guiding principles to inform our whole-of-government work in partnership with other countries, institutions, and organizations.  We too have learned a lot from our past stabilization experiences around the world.  One example of the lessons has been the importance of the interagency working closely together in unstable spaces to consolidate gains for long-lasting effects.  When the interagency isn’t coordinated or present, stabilization efforts are not lasting.  We, DOD, are in support of State and USAID, but it’s really a government approach to prevent conflict and promote stability.  I believe this is where the Global Fragility Act will be invaluable in achieving long-term success.</p>
<p>In the department, we’re still concerned about violent extremist organizations, as they often pose as supporters and providers of stability to the citizenry while obviously actually undermining stability of the state as a whole.  Long-term partner engagement will build resilience against violent extremist recruitment and the spread of terrorism.  DOD has a strong and lasting bilateral relationship with a lot of the Global Fragility Act selected countries led by our office, the joint staff regional offices, as well as the combatant commands.  Our combatant commands will play a key role in the implementation of this activity.</p>
<p>USAID’s Bureau of Conflict Prevention and Stabilization often assigns and has assigned liaison officers in our office, Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy, to the combatant commands to facilitate interagency coordination.  Likewise, DOD assigns military officers at State and USAID.  Diplomacy, development, and defense cooperation are at an all-time high.</p>
<p>Finally, preventing, promoting stability, and trying to get ahead of challenges before they arise is important and difficult work.  The Global Fragility Act success depends on close cooperation and coordination between U.S. Government agencies.  And I think this is a great step forward in that endeavor.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Joe.  At this point, Cynthia, would you go ahead and give the instructions again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly, and once again, ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 and then 0.  You will hear a tone acknowledging that you are in queue.  We will take the questions in the order that they queue up.  You may remove yourself from queue by pressing the same 1-0 command.  So once again, 1 and then 0 for any questions or comments, and one moment, please.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  Okay.  Let’s go for our first question to Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thank you for doing this.  The text released today mentioned the conflict in Ukraine.  How do you expect that will influence your strategy with the partner countries named today?  And along those lines, will USAID help Taiwan deliver its humanitarian assistance to Ukraine?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Thank you for that question.  First of all, on the selection of countries, I want to underscore that the set of countries and sub-regions illustrates our commitment to partnering with a variety of countries to respond to a variety of challenges that are weakening state capacity and legitimacy.  We want to acknowledge the complexity of these challenges in different contexts and want to work together with our partner countries, their governments, their civil society, and their private sectors to bolster their abilities and resources to resist these threats.</p>
<p>As we watch the conflict deepen and expand, the shocks of the war in Ukraine are being felt beyond Ukraine’s borders.  We are seeing it as millions have fled Ukraine to seek safe refuge and the real threat to food security for millions and millions of people worldwide in places that are already quite vulnerable to hunger.  So the effects are the – of the conflict are complex, and it will touch all aspects of affected countries, but the point here is that the strategy elevates conflict prevention as a priority and will unite our actions – our U.S. actions – in the diplomatic, development, and security sector spheres.  The events we’re seeing today reiterate the importance of an integrated U.S. whole-of-government approach tailored to these most pressing challenges in our partner countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Thank you for the question about Ukraine.  As you probably know, USAID and our State Department colleagues are doing an amazing amount of work both inside Ukraine and outside to help IDPs, refugees; continue our support to the Ukrainian Government and communities inside Ukraine.  Unfortunately, I’m not aware of any planning regarding Taiwan and assistance to Ukraine, so I’d have to get back to you through my press office on that.  I – my not being aware does not necessarily mean there isn’t some planning going on.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Kemi Osukoya.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Yes, go ahead.  We can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, okay, thank you.  I was wondering if you could talk more about your plan – your strategic plan in Africa, in particular in West Africa, in Sudan, and also Somalia.</p>
<p>Hello?  Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Yes.  Yes, thank you very much.  Yes, thank you very much for the question.  The – yes, thank you.</p>
<p>The decisions that were taken, the selection of partner countries that we’re going forward with today within Africa, are within coastal West Africa and in Mozambique.  So we’re going to be focusing under the U.S. strategy on those countries, building on our lessons learned, and moving forward with our whole-of-government, 10-year, locally led plans.  It is, however, the case that our effort under this strategy will help us learn lessons not only as they apply to the countries that we have announced today in moving forward under the Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, but also, we hope, in the future will be applicable to places such as the countries that you’ve identified.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  And – great.  Once again, if you’d like to get into our question queue with our briefers, dial 1 then 0.  We’ll stand by just a moment.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And once again, that is 1 and then 0 for your questions or comments.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, folks.  Well, once again, thank you so much for dialing in today.  We appreciate your participation in our briefing this afternoon.  I do want to take this opportunity to once again thank our briefers from here at the Department of State’s Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky; our colleague from USAID, the Bureau for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization, Assistant to the Administrator Rob Jenkins; and from over at DOD, Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy Joe McMenamin; and again, from here at the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli.</p>
<p>Again, appreciate everyone calling in.  At this point the briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a nice rest of your day and a nice weekend.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  And I’ll let everybody know that while we called this a State Department briefing, it’s actually an interagency briefing today with our colleagues from USAID and the Department of Defense, whom we’re very glad to do this with today.</p>
<p>So good morning once again, everyone, and thank you for joining us.  Today we will be discussing what we can describe as the latest progress in implementing the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  As a quick reminder here at the top, this morning’s briefing is on the record but its contents are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>Okay.  It is my pleasure to let everyone on the line know that we are joined today by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne Witkowsky; we’re also joined by Assistant to the USAID Administrator for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization Robert Jenkins; and Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy at the Department of Defense Joseph McMenamin; and also from here at State, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli from the Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>We’re going to start off with some opening remarks from several of our briefers today, and then we’ll open it up to just a few of your questions.  Okay.  And with that, I’d like to go ahead and turn it over to Assistant Secretary Witkowsky.  Ma’am.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:  </b>Thank you, J.T., and hello to those who have joined.  I’m Anne Witkowsky, Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations.</p>
<p>The President, with support of the U.S. Congress, has initiated a new stage in our implementation of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 and the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  We are moving forward in a spirit of partnership to implement the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability – Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and the coastal West Africa region, which is Benin, Cote d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.</p>
<p>Under the strategy, we’ll begin developing comprehensive 10-year plans for each location.  These plans will emphasize locally driven solutions, long-term visions for our combined efforts, and evidence-based learning.  We recognize that close cooperation between the United States and likeminded regional, national, and local actors, including civil society, will be key to the success of the strategy.  We will tailor our shared approaches to the unique circumstances of local and regional contexts.</p>
<p>A decade-long outlook supports greater consistency across U.S. administrations and commitment to working with partners over the long term.  We will create feedback loops through monitoring and evaluations that will inform learning as we implement the plans with our partners.  In this way, the strategy presents the U.S. Government with a unique opportunity to balance a long-term view with near-term adaptation.</p>
<p>With a focus on locally driven efforts and solutions tailored to local contexts, planning under the strategy will seek to address emerging threats and address the underlying causes of violence and instability.  Our objective is to build resilience to prevent conflicts and crises from breaking out or deteriorating further.</p>
<p>This strategy requires a whole-of-government effort to integrated diplomacy, development, security-sector engagement.  We reflect this whole-of-government approach in our representation here on the call with USAID’s Rob Jenkins; Joe McMenamin, my colleague from the Defense Department; as well as Roman Napoli from the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>In sum, with the announcement of these priority countries, we are taking the next step to chart a new way forward in how the United States partners with other nations to address the challenges of conflict and instability.  The announcement today is also the next critical step in translating the ambitious goals of the bipartisan Global Fragility Act into reality.  Implementing the strategy will prove challenging, but it also affords us an opportunity to bring new ideas, resources, and collective action to some very pressing and important problems.  Our prosperity and security depend on peaceful, self-reliant, and stable economic and security partners.</p>
<p>With that, I will turn it over to Rob.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Well, thank you, Anne, and good morning, everyone.  An important part of the strategy and its implementation will be partnerships.  As the President has said, our diplomats, officers, and experts will work in close cooperation with multilateral organizations and a wide variety of local partners in each nation where these efforts will be pursued, including civil society organizations, community leaders, businesses, and government officials.  Those who are closest and most vulnerable to these challenges know best where the opportunities for peace and stability lie.  They represent the strongest source of promise and immunity from destabilizing forces, and we must support their strength and their resilience.</p>
<p>We know not only is going it alone not smart, it doesn’t work.  My administrator, Samantha Power of USAID, has challenged all of us to maximize the extent to which we can work directly with local partners, working in true, respectful, and effective partnership with the governments, communities and people we are trying to help.  We have learned many lessons in the last two decades, and some of them are very hard lessons.  One of them is we’re not only wasting time if we think we can impose our plan on a situation and expect to achieve success by force of will, number of boots on the ground, or amounts of dollars spent.  We’re wasting time, energy, money, and goodwill to do it alone.</p>
<p>Our lodestar must be inclusive development, working with governments and the people we’re there to help and working with on true partnerships, respectful partnerships as equals.  And inclusive development is co-creation, joint implementation, and acknowledging that we’re in support, helping our friends and partners where they are and where they live.</p>
<p>Thank you.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Joe at the Department of Defense.</p>
<p><b>MR MCMENAMIN:</b>  Thank you, Rob.  My name, just a refresher, Joe McMenamin, and I serve as the principal director for counternarcotics and stabilization policy under the assistant secretary of defense for special operations and low-intensity conflict in the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.  I’d like to thank you all for the opportunity to talk about Department of Defense efforts and (inaudible) in support of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p>Our counternarcotics and stabilization policy office is the lead for the department’s implementation of the Global Fragility Act and is responsible for a vast set of policy issues including counternarcotics, stabilization, UN peacekeeping, and civil affairs.  Several of these areas touch Global Fragility Act issues.  The department is proud to support and has been working closely with the Department of State, USAID, and other agencies well before the Global Fragility Act was passed in December 2019.</p>
<p>We have been joined at the hip for many years, to include laying the groundwork for eventually what became the Stabilization Assistance Review, written together in a collaborative fashion.  Specific to the Global Fragility Act, we worked closely on the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, the prologue, and the country selection.  Such efforts will continue as the Global Fragility Act implementation begins.</p>
<p>The Global Fragility Act reflects the administration’s view of emerging threats and opportunities and outlines guiding principles to inform our whole-of-government work in partnership with other countries, institutions, and organizations.  We too have learned a lot from our past stabilization experiences around the world.  One example of the lessons has been the importance of the interagency working closely together in unstable spaces to consolidate gains for long-lasting effects.  When the interagency isn’t coordinated or present, stabilization efforts are not lasting.  We, DOD, are in support of State and USAID, but it’s really a government approach to prevent conflict and promote stability.  I believe this is where the Global Fragility Act will be invaluable in achieving long-term success.</p>
<p>In the department, we’re still concerned about violent extremist organizations, as they often pose as supporters and providers of stability to the citizenry while obviously actually undermining stability of the state as a whole.  Long-term partner engagement will build resilience against violent extremist recruitment and the spread of terrorism.  DOD has a strong and lasting bilateral relationship with a lot of the Global Fragility Act selected countries led by our office, the joint staff regional offices, as well as the combatant commands.  Our combatant commands will play a key role in the implementation of this activity.</p>
<p>USAID’s Bureau of Conflict Prevention and Stabilization often assigns and has assigned liaison officers in our office, Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy, to the combatant commands to facilitate interagency coordination.  Likewise, DOD assigns military officers at State and USAID.  Diplomacy, development, and defense cooperation are at an all-time high.</p>
<p>Finally, preventing, promoting stability, and trying to get ahead of challenges before they arise is important and difficult work.  The Global Fragility Act success depends on close cooperation and coordination between U.S. Government agencies.  And I think this is a great step forward in that endeavor.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Joe.  At this point, Cynthia, would you go ahead and give the instructions again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly, and once again, ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 and then 0.  You will hear a tone acknowledging that you are in queue.  We will take the questions in the order that they queue up.  You may remove yourself from queue by pressing the same 1-0 command.  So once again, 1 and then 0 for any questions or comments, and one moment, please.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  Okay.  Let’s go for our first question to Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thank you for doing this.  The text released today mentioned the conflict in Ukraine.  How do you expect that will influence your strategy with the partner countries named today?  And along those lines, will USAID help Taiwan deliver its humanitarian assistance to Ukraine?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Thank you for that question.  First of all, on the selection of countries, I want to underscore that the set of countries and sub-regions illustrates our commitment to partnering with a variety of countries to respond to a variety of challenges that are weakening state capacity and legitimacy.  We want to acknowledge the complexity of these challenges in different contexts and want to work together with our partner countries, their governments, their civil society, and their private sectors to bolster their abilities and resources to resist these threats.</p>
<p>As we watch the conflict deepen and expand, the shocks of the war in Ukraine are being felt beyond Ukraine’s borders.  We are seeing it as millions have fled Ukraine to seek safe refuge and the real threat to food security for millions and millions of people worldwide in places that are already quite vulnerable to hunger.  So the effects are the – of the conflict are complex, and it will touch all aspects of affected countries, but the point here is that the strategy elevates conflict prevention as a priority and will unite our actions – our U.S. actions – in the diplomatic, development, and security sector spheres.  The events we’re seeing today reiterate the importance of an integrated U.S. whole-of-government approach tailored to these most pressing challenges in our partner countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Thank you for the question about Ukraine.  As you probably know, USAID and our State Department colleagues are doing an amazing amount of work both inside Ukraine and outside to help IDPs, refugees; continue our support to the Ukrainian Government and communities inside Ukraine.  Unfortunately, I’m not aware of any planning regarding Taiwan and assistance to Ukraine, so I’d have to get back to you through my press office on that.  I – my not being aware does not necessarily mean there isn’t some planning going on.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Kemi Osukoya.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Yes, go ahead.  We can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, okay, thank you.  I was wondering if you could talk more about your plan – your strategic plan in Africa, in particular in West Africa, in Sudan, and also Somalia.</p>
<p>Hello?  Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Yes.  Yes, thank you very much.  Yes, thank you very much for the question.  The – yes, thank you.</p>
<p>The decisions that were taken, the selection of partner countries that we’re going forward with today within Africa, are within coastal West Africa and in Mozambique.  So we’re going to be focusing under the U.S. strategy on those countries, building on our lessons learned, and moving forward with our whole-of-government, 10-year, locally led plans.  It is, however, the case that our effort under this strategy will help us learn lessons not only as they apply to the countries that we have announced today in moving forward under the Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, but also, we hope, in the future will be applicable to places such as the countries that you’ve identified.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  And – great.  Once again, if you’d like to get into our question queue with our briefers, dial 1 then 0.  We’ll stand by just a moment.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And once again, that is 1 and then 0 for your questions or comments.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, folks.  Well, once again, thank you so much for dialing in today.  We appreciate your participation in our briefing this afternoon.  I do want to take this opportunity to once again thank our briefers from here at the Department of State’s Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky; our colleague from USAID, the Bureau for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization, Assistant to the Administrator Rob Jenkins; and from over at DOD, Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy Joe McMenamin; and again, from here at the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli.</p>
<p>Again, appreciate everyone calling in.  At this point the briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a nice rest of your day and a nice weekend.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
