<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 13:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Croatia Statehood Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/croatia-statehood-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 04:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Croatia as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Croatia are steadfast Allies and partners, and our relationship is defined by shared values that help us progress on critical fronts, including strengthening trade and investment ties, enhancing energy security, and confronting the climate crisis.</p>
<p>This year, we also commemorate the 30th anniversary of the Croatian Armed Forces, and the United States offers its thanks for the decades of close military cooperation our two countries have enjoyed.  Our thriving defense partnership is evidenced by our continued participation in joint and NATO training exercises, which are again in the spotlight during Defender Europe 2021.  A valued NATO Ally, Croatia is an important contributor to both Transatlantic security and European prosperity.</p>
<p>As we continue to face the challenges posed by the COVID-19 pandemic and deepen our bilateral relationship, the United States stands with Croatia.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Croatia as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Croatia are steadfast Allies and partners, and our relationship is defined by shared values that help us progress on critical fronts, including strengthening trade and investment ties, enhancing energy security, and confronting the climate crisis.</p>
<p>This year, we also commemorate the 30th anniversary of the Croatian Armed Forces, and the United States offers its thanks for the decades of close military cooperation our two countries have enjoyed.  Our thriving defense partnership is evidenced by our continued participation in joint and NATO training exercises, which are again in the spotlight during Defender Europe 2021.  A valued NATO Ally, Croatia is an important contributor to both Transatlantic security and European prosperity.</p>
<p>As we continue to face the challenges posed by the COVID-19 pandemic and deepen our bilateral relationship, the United States stands with Croatia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Media Freedom Coalition Statement on the Arrest of Roman Protasevich</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/media-freedom-coalition-statement-on-the-arrest-of-roman-protasevich/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 13:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of Austria, Bulgaria, Canada, Cyprus, the Czech Republic, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Greece, Iceland, Latvia, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, North Macedonia, Slovakia, Slovenia, Switzerland, Ukraine, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Begin text:</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition condemn in the strongest terms Belarus’ forced diversion and landing of a commercial aircraft and subsequent arrest of journalist Roman Protasevich.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This unprecedented and shocking action constitutes a full frontal attack on media freedom and has serious implications on the right of freedom of expression and opinion more broadly.  This action is all the more troubling when seen in the context of the large-scale campaign to silence independent voices in Belarus, including the May 18 raid on the offices of independent news site </span><a href="http://tut.by/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">tut.by</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the subsequent arrest of several staff.  Some 400 journalists and workers in the media in Belarus have faced various forms of repression in the course of the August 9 election and its aftermath.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Media Freedom Coalition demands the immediate and unconditional release of Mr. Protasevich as well as other journalists and media workers who have been detained in Belarus for doing their jobs.  Those responsible must be held accountable for attacks on journalists and media workers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Media freedom is an important part of democratic societies and essential to the protection of human rights and fundamental freedoms.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">End text.</span></i></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of Austria, Bulgaria, Canada, Cyprus, the Czech Republic, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Greece, Iceland, Latvia, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, North Macedonia, Slovakia, Slovenia, Switzerland, Ukraine, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Begin text:</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition condemn in the strongest terms Belarus’ forced diversion and landing of a commercial aircraft and subsequent arrest of journalist Roman Protasevich.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This unprecedented and shocking action constitutes a full frontal attack on media freedom and has serious implications on the right of freedom of expression and opinion more broadly.  This action is all the more troubling when seen in the context of the large-scale campaign to silence independent voices in Belarus, including the May 18 raid on the offices of independent news site </span><a href="http://tut.by/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">tut.by</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the subsequent arrest of several staff.  Some 400 journalists and workers in the media in Belarus have faced various forms of repression in the course of the August 9 election and its aftermath.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Media Freedom Coalition demands the immediate and unconditional release of Mr. Protasevich as well as other journalists and media workers who have been detained in Belarus for doing their jobs.  Those responsible must be held accountable for attacks on journalists and media workers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Media freedom is an important part of democratic societies and essential to the protection of human rights and fundamental freedoms.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">End text.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Appointment of Ambassador Arnold Chacon to serve as Chargé d’Affaires to Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/appointment-of-ambassador-arnold-chacon-to-serve-as-charge-daffaires-to-canada/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Today, Secretary Blinken designated Ambassador Arnold Chacon to serve as Chargé d’Affaires ad interim at U.S. Embassy Ottawa.  A career diplomat with the rank of Career Minister, Ambassador Chacon is currently detailed from the Department of State to the National Defense University as Senior Vice President. Ambassador Chacon previously served as the Director General of the Foreign Service and Director of Human Resources and U.S. Ambassador to Guatemala.</p>
<p align="left">Ambassador Chacon’s appointment underscores the United States’ strong commitment to Canada and the Canadian people.  He will lead the U.S. government’s diplomatic engagement in Canada by advancing the Roadmap for a Renewed U.S.-Canada Partnership, including trade, climate change, COVID-19 response and recovery, and global and regional security issues.</p>
<p align="left">The United States highly values its close partnership with Canada, and Ambassador Chacon is dedicated to advancing the bilateral relationship.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Today, Secretary Blinken designated Ambassador Arnold Chacon to serve as Chargé d’Affaires ad interim at U.S. Embassy Ottawa.  A career diplomat with the rank of Career Minister, Ambassador Chacon is currently detailed from the Department of State to the National Defense University as Senior Vice President. Ambassador Chacon previously served as the Director General of the Foreign Service and Director of Human Resources and U.S. Ambassador to Guatemala.</p>
<p align="left">Ambassador Chacon’s appointment underscores the United States’ strong commitment to Canada and the Canadian people.  He will lead the U.S. government’s diplomatic engagement in Canada by advancing the Roadmap for a Renewed U.S.-Canada Partnership, including trade, climate change, COVID-19 response and recovery, and global and regional security issues.</p>
<p align="left">The United States highly values its close partnership with Canada, and Ambassador Chacon is dedicated to advancing the bilateral relationship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Indian External Affairs Minister Jaishankar</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-indian-external-affairs-minister-jaishankar-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 22:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken welcomed Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar to the Department of State, where he reaffirmed the Administration’s commitment to deepening the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar discussed a broad range of issues, including COVID-19 relief, efforts to strengthen Indo-Pacific cooperation through the Quad, and a shared commitment to combating the climate crisis and enhancing multilateral cooperation, including at the UN Security Council. Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar also discussed regional developments, the coup in Burma, and continuing support for Afghanistan.  Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar pledged to continue their cooperation on shared economic and regional security priorities.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken welcomed Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar to the Department of State, where he reaffirmed the Administration’s commitment to deepening the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar discussed a broad range of issues, including COVID-19 relief, efforts to strengthen Indo-Pacific cooperation through the Quad, and a shared commitment to combating the climate crisis and enhancing multilateral cooperation, including at the UN Security Council. Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar also discussed regional developments, the coup in Burma, and continuing support for Afghanistan.  Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar pledged to continue their cooperation on shared economic and regional security priorities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Briefing with Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Principal Advisor to the Administrator Mark Feierstein, and Experts On the Administration’s Budget Proposal for the Department of State and USAID for Fiscal Year 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-briefing-with-deputy-secretary-of-state-for-management-and-resources-brian-p-mckeon-u-s-agency-for-international-development-usaid-principal-advisor-to-the-administrator-mark-feierstein/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian P. McKeon, Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources, Mark Feierstein, Principal Advisor to the Administrator, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 21:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brian P. McKeon, Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources</p>
<p>Mark Feierstein, Principal Advisor to the Administrator, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Thank you, and good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining us for this on-the-record briefing on the details of the Fiscal Year 2022 budget request for the State Department and USAID that was released earlier today. With us on the line are State Department Deputy Secretary for Management and Resources Brian McKeon and the USAID Administrator’s Principal Advisor Mark Feierstein.</p>
<p>Also joining us today is Director Douglas Pitkin of the State Department’s Bureau of Budget and Planning; Dr. Tracy Carson, Acting Director of the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance; and USAID Budget Director Tricia Schmitt.</p>
<p>To start us off, I’ll be turning the call over to Deputy Secretary McKeon and Advisor Feierstein for their opening remarks, and then afterward our participants will take a few of your questions.</p>
<p>Again, just as a quick reminder, this briefing is on the record, but the contents of the call are embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>
<p>And with that, let’s go to Deputy Secretary McKeon. Sir.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>Thank you, JT. Good afternoon, everybody. Thanks for joining us. You’re doing great service, working hard on the afternoon before Memorial Day weekend.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken noted in his press release, the FY22 Presidents’ budget request includes historic investments across the interagency that will lay the foundation for shared growth and prosperity for decades to come.</p>
<p>I want to share a few toplines from the request for the State Department and USAID, starting with a number of $58.5 billion, a more than 5 billion – or 10 percent – increase over the FY 2021 level. I am pleased to be joined on this call by Mark Feierstein, the Principal Advisor to Administrator Power, who will speak to the budget request for USAID. The relationship between our department and AID is critical in achieving the President’s foreign policy and development goals, and we’re fortunate to have such effective partners. And all the senior leaders here and at AID know each other very well, so we don’t have to build a working relationship, because we already have it.</p>
<p>The first thing I want to highlight is the investment this budget makes in our workforce, which is our greatest asset. As one of the President’s earliest national security memoranda states, quote, “the revitalization of our national security and foreign policy institutions is essential to advancing America’s security, prosperity, and values, accelerating our domestic renewal, and delivering results for all Americans.” End quote. That’s why this budget includes the largest staffing increase for the Department in a decade, covering both the Foreign and Civil Service.</p>
<p>But it’s not just about adding new positions. It’s about ensuring that we recruit and – this is essential – retain the right people: a workforce that represents the full diversity and talent of the United States. The Secretary’s appointment of Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley as the Department’s first ever Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer is just one step in that effort. We are taking steps to revitalize the Department by ensuring that our employees have the tools and training they need to be successful.</p>
<p>We are also investing in the programs and capabilities we need to address the challenges of our time. For example, the budget includes: $10 billion for global health programs, including $1 billion to strengthen pandemic preparedness, which is an $800 million increase; 2.5 billion across the interagency to address climate change, more than quadruple the FY21 level, in close coordination with Special Presidential Envoy Former Secretary Kerry; and increases in democracy and governance programs to stem the tide of rising authoritarianism.</p>
<p>Our State and USAID budget directors will provide additional details on these sectors and other key investments, including the inclusion of more predictable resources to sustain consular services for Americans traveling, working, and living overseas, and additional investments in our cybersecurity and other technology modernization efforts.</p>
<p>We are also requesting the resources we need to support our commitments to key allies and partners, both in this budget and in separate requests. For example, we will be working with the Congress to seek an additional 8,000 Afghan Special Immigrant Visas to meet our commitment to those who have supported our efforts in Afghanistan at great risk to themselves and their families. We are working with the interagency to accelerate SIV processing so we can make use of those visas. We are also continuing to work with the international community on the provision of additional assistance to the Afghan people and government toward a shared goal of prosperity and security for the country.</p>
<p>Finally, this budget is a demonstration of renewed U.S. leadership in the international community. It fully funds our commitments to UN peacekeeping and other international organizations and provides more than $10 billion in humanitarian assistance, including to support a refugee admissions level of up to 125,000. We cannot advance our interests by withdrawing from the world stage. We need to be in the room working with our partners and competitors alike, fighting for our interests.</p>
<p>We will have more to say about the budget over the coming weeks and months about how it reflects and resources our goals and our values as we work with the Congress to secure this funding. I’ll stop here now and turn it over to Mark.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN: </b>Well thank you, Brian, and good afternoon, everybody, and thanks so much for joining. I am very pleased to be joining my friend and State Department colleague, Brian McKeon, to discuss the Biden-Harris administration’s Fiscal Year 2022 budget request. We at USAID are grateful for Deputy Secretary McKeon’s partnership and commitment to the notion that our diplomacy and development efforts abroad are complementary and interdependent.</p>
<p>The FY22 budget request includes 27.7 billion for the U.S. Agency for International Development’s fully and partially managed accounts. It signals President Biden’s commitment to reassert the United States’s role as a leader in global development and humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>From day one, President Biden made clear that development, alongside defense and diplomacy, is critical to American foreign policy. This is not only reflected in the FY 2022 budget request, but also in the President’s decision to elevate the USAID administrator as a standing member of the National Security Council.</p>
<p>This budget also reflects the nature and complexity of the challenges that we face in the 21st century – those that cannot be confined within national borders and require multilateral efforts to confront. Simply put, building back better at home also requires building back better overseas.</p>
<p>By fighting COVID-19 abroad, we stem the rise of variants that can lead to outbreaks at home. When incomes rise in developing countries, those countries become more self-reliant and less dependent on U.S. support. When we deliver aid to those affected by natural disasters or humanitarian crises, we demonstrate the best of American values and build the goodwill that inspires action and cooperation from our allies.</p>
<p>The ongoing pandemic illustrates the importance of USAID’s efforts to bolster health systems globally. We must fight COVID-19 everywhere it exists and work to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks.</p>
<p>We also face an urgent climate crisis which literally poses a threat to some countries’ existence and is also a threat to our own national security. The impacts of climate change lead to conflict, hunger, displacement, and other extreme weather events that cost lives and damage critical infrastructure at home.</p>
<p>Accompanying the existential threats of climate change and the spread of infectious disease is the threat posed by the rise of malign actors undermining the rule of law and democratic norms. Amid the 15-year democratic decline globally documented by Freedom House, nine more countries slipped into a state of autocracy in the last five years alone. USAID’s democracy programming confronts authoritarianism and combats corruption and misinformation through partnerships with government reformers and civil society actors seeking to hold illiberal regimes accountable.</p>
<p>Poverty, violence, and misrule often lead people to leave their countries in search of better opportunities abroad. In Central America, USAID is committed to addressing the root causes of irregular migration by tackling the violence, corruption, and lack of opportunity that drive so many to risk their lives and the lives of their children. Our approach includes a greater emphasis on building economic resilience, identifying and addressing conditions in emigration hot spots, and improving living conditions by promoting good governance.</p>
<p>The United States is also the world’s largest donor for global humanitarian assistance, and we will continue to leverage our contributions to get other countries to do more. The budget request includes 6.3 billion to address needs resulting from man-made emergencies in countries like Yemen, Ethiopia, and Venezuela, as well as natural disasters such as earthquakes, typhoons, and volcano eruptions like we’ve seen recently in the Democratic Republic of Congo and Saint Vincent and the Grenadines. And we’ll not just respond to crises, but invest in resilience and risk reduction efforts that reduce the economic and human cost of disasters.</p>
<p>Now, none of this work would be possible without an investment in our workforce, which is why this request includes $1.9 billion to boost our Civil Service and Foreign Service staffing and create a workforce that reflects the diversity of our country. We are committed to building the most diverse, and most talented, workforce in USAID history.</p>
<p>In sum, the President’s Budget Request released today reflects the reality that America’s security is inextricably linked to that of other nations around the world. This budget proposal is a reflection of the critical importance of development and humanitarian assistance in advancing U.S. interests and upholding American values.</p>
<p>Thank you and we look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. And with that, just a quick reminder to dial 1-0 to get into our question queue. And let’s go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b>You are open, Mr. Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Okay, thanks. Happy Memorial Day weekend, almost. I’ve got two things, they’re both very brief. The first one is – and forgive me, because my math is absolutely atrocious – but a little back-of-the-envelope addition just from the fact sheets and what you’ve said on this call suggests that almost a third of the total is taken up by climate change, health, staffing, and other – and other things like that, including – let me see, I had it written down. Anyway, I just want to know: Is that correct? I mean, it seems like a substantial percentage of this budget – oh, humanitarian assistance was the other one. Is that – am I correct that that’s almost 30 billion of the total 58.5?</p>
<p>And then just one other thing, and that is: Already some human rights groups are talking about how this is – how the foreign military financing for Egypt contradicts the administration’s “no blank check” policy. Is it – it’s always been my understanding that that funding level was – is relatively static and isn’t something that you guys just change in the request; it’s something that Congress weighs in on. Is that correct, as well? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN: </b>I’m going to defer to the deputy secretary on the – and Tracy Carson and Tricia Schmitt on the one-third piece since they’re steeped in all the numbers, and I’m as good at math as you are, Matt.</p>
<p><b>MR PITKIN: </b>This is Doug Pitkin. I’ll start, I guess. Certainly on the climate and the health, those are certainly large elements of the request. While the workforce is an element, it is – in terms of dollar terms, it’s not the most significant number increase. Another key priority in the request is an increase of $600 million to pay our contributions to the UN, including peacekeeping as well as arrears from prior years. So I think in terms of the workforce numbers between State and AID, the increase is probably closer to about 350 million all told, including AID.</p>
<p>But certainly, climate, health, and international contributions are relatively larger amounts, as well as, I believe, Central America. So I’ll let Tracy clarify further.</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON: </b>Absolutely. The health, humanitarian assistance, and climate total is roughly 21.6 million. So there’s 10 million for health, there’s 10 million for humanitarian assistance, and then there’s – I’m sorry, there’s 10 billion for health, 10 billion for humanitarian assistance, and then 1.6 billion for climate. And Doug is absolutely correct – Central America is $861 million, and so they do constitute a sizeable amount of the foreign assistance request.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. With that, let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler. Jennifer?</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you for doing the call. I was wondering if you could get into more specifics about the funding for increasing cybersecurity here, especially in light of today’s latest cyber attack? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PITKIN: </b>This is Doug Pitkin. I can start with the State portion. For the State Department we’re requesting a total increase of approximately 160 million in cybersecurity funding over our current levels. And this reflects a combination of ongoing programs managed by our chief information officer and our Bureau of Diplomatic Security, as well as a number of specific initiatives to respond to the threats identified by the SolarWinds incidents over the last few months. And so for State it’s a topline increase of $160 million for cybersecurity over current levels.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Tricia, do you want to speak to the cyber level for USAID and what the full amount is?</p>
<p><b>MS SCHMITT:</b> Sure. For our overall operational expenses account at USAID, it is 1.9 billion, which includes increases for our staffing, our – it does include our increased investments for information technology and modernization. The funding will include upgrades to support our – again, the modernization pieces but the actual IT piece as well with ’21 enacted.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Let’s go to the line of Simon Ateba.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you for taking my question. This is Simon Ateba with Today News Africa in Washington, D.C. The Trump administration defunded several programs that were taking place in Africa. I was wondering if you can talk a little bit more about how the Biden administration’s budget will benefit programs and interventions by USAID and State Department in Africa. And will those interventions be dependent on human rights, democracy, and so on? And how much exactly is going to Africa? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> Go ahead, Tracy or Tricia.</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON:</b> Yeah, I’ll take that. The request for Africa is $7.6 billion across a range of accounts. It includes the robust support for democracy, rights, and governance, as well as support for economic growth activities, as well as some of our supports to help with civilian security assistance around a range of countries on the continent. You’ll see notable increases for – are in – you’ll see notable increases for engagement, especially with democracy, rights, and governance, (inaudible) USAID core requirement.</p>
<p>I’ll turn to (inaudible) if you’ve got anything else.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Yeah, I’m happy to speak to that as well. So first, thank you for the question. And Africa is of course of utmost importance to USAID. We with State have a joint regional strategy that focuses on four goals. First is to increase economic growth. Second to – is to promote security. Third is to strengthen democracy and human rights. And fourth is to promote inclusive country-level development.</p>
<p>We have some programs that are specific to Africa, such as Prosper Africa. We’re investing $80 million there, and that program is designed to connect U.S. and African businesses with new buyers, suppliers, and investment opportunities. We also have a Power Africa program which began in the Obama administration. For that we’re requesting $57.5 million, and we’re going to use that to continue to promote sub-Saharan Africa’s transition to cleaner and renewable energy. And then we have global programs like Feed the Future, where we promote agricultural development and our investments in Africa are quite significant under that. Similarly, we have health programs that are fairly generous on the African continent. So overall, we – I think we – this very much speaks to the needs that the – that Africa has these days.</p>
<p>But I don’t if, Tricia, do you want to – have anything?</p>
<p><b>MS SCHMITT:</b> No, that’s it. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay, let’s go to the line of Tracy Wilkinson with the <i>Los Angeles Times</i>.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you. I wanted to go back to the question of Central America for a minute and maybe a little more detail, if at all possible, on the 861 million being assigned there. Obviously, that’s the first part of the 4 billion that President Biden has offered the region. But as you know, there’s a lot of controversy about where that money should go, to whom, et cetera. And so to what extent did strings attach to this money or discussion about what – who it should go to, which government first and then – which governments first and then which organizations and different entities within the countries? I’m just curious if there was more discussion about that and anything put in writing about how to disburse these funds. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> So you packed a lot into your question, Tracy. Just at a high level, as you indicated, the President during the campaign promised 4 billion over four years. This is the first step in meeting that commitment. It’s going to focus on strengthening rule of law, democratic governance, strengthening civil society, and improving respect for human rights. I know from the experience of when a similar program was initiated at the end of the Obama-Biden administration and Vice President Biden was leading the effort for the administration, there was a fair amount of, shall we say, conditionality in conversations with the Central American governments, putting requests upon them on certain things that they were going to do in terms of their own investments but also conditions on – related to corruption and governance.</p>
<p>And so I expect we will have some similar conversations. But – and a lot of the funds at that time were disbursed to NGOs more than the governments, but I don’t know that we’ve got this all laid out in detail at this time. I’d defer to other colleagues if they want to add any thoughts.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Well, I would just speak to how we’re carrying this out in practice. And just to offer one example, you may have seen an announcement a few days ago from USAID with regard to funding in El Salvador. And we had been supporting the attorney general’s office there and the supreme court, but we were concerned about certain steps that were taken there, and that we have – we pivot that money towards civil society. So we recognize that in some cases we don’t have perfect development partners, but we’re confident that we can identify in Central America – and this is true around the world – that we can identify reformers within government, people who have the political will to carry out democratic reform. And we’re also confident we can identify civil society actors who can hold their governments accountable and carry out our mutual development objectives. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> And we do have some more questions in the queue, but I’m aware, sir, Mr. Deputy Secretary, that you have a hard stop with us this afternoon. Are you able to carry on or do you need to go, sir?</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> Can do one more, but I realize – and I apologize – didn’t address Matt Lee’s question on Egypt. Let me just do that quickly. You are correct, Matt; it is steady state funding. I think the FMF number’s been at $1.3 billion for several years. We’re going to have conversations with the Congress and the Government of Egypt on the best way to use our assistance to meet our interests, including on human rights. That’s what we’d say about that right now.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Thank you, sir. Let’s go to the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you very much. I really appreciate you taking the time. I really very quickly skimmed through the numbers here, so it’s possible that there’s something I’ve missed. Given everything that Biden has promised, State Department has promised, and how you might be different to past administrations – and when I say that I’m going as far back as Reagan administration – and you want to build back better. Can you respond with two things in focus? One, the African diaspora and the African – the indigenous African diaspora and the indigenous independent media. If you are to help support with your four goals Africa, are you saying here, besides the climate and the health portions, that you are going to try to do this without supporting indigenous African-led development here? Or can you point me to where that is in this budget request? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> USAID, this – think we’d defer to you to address this first.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Yeah, happy to take this. So look, everything that we do around the world is designed to support local actors, and that is certainly true in Africa as well. So we put together a strategy, we put together a budget that is based on consultations with governments, with civil society, with private sector in the region. And you mentioned diaspora, and diaspora is a very, very important element of this as well. In many cases, they are the – some of the leading actors and investors in their home countries. So we try to work with them as well, and the goal here, of course, is to leverage – use our technical assistance, use our resources to leverage the talents of others and to leverage the resources of others, and that certainly includes the diaspora communities. But thank you for the question.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. Let’s quickly go to the line of David Wainer at Bloomberg.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you for doing this. Could you please clarify the funding you mentioned for programs that help Afghans who worked with U.S. personnel? And just to clarify, are these translators, and what is the total cost of helping those people? And how is that request any different from the 2021 budget? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>So the program that I think folks are familiar with is called the Afghan Special Immigrant Visa program. Congress provides authorization for a certain number of visas each year. Typically, in the last few years, they’ve provided 4,000 slots. We&#8217;re asking for 8,000 this year. The spending is on – typically on the mandatory side of the budget, not the discretionary. Obviously the cost of actually processing the visa applications, doing the interviews, and their initial resettlement – that&#8217;s kind of baked into the budget and how we do our work as a department. The Congress has set forth categories of prioritization in the SIV program. I don&#8217;t have the categories in front of me, but the translators, interpreters are in – I believe in tier one of the categories.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>And I think we have time for just one last quick question. Let’s go to Rachel Oswald at <i>Congressional Quarterly</i>.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Yes, we have you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Can you talk a little bit about what funding is directed toward refugee assistance, specifically rebuilding capacity for admissions domestically?</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>Tracy, I don&#8217;t have the PRM number at my fingertips – several billion dollars, but I don&#8217;t have the exact number. Tracy, do you have that?</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON: </b>My apologies. I was on – I was talking on mute. The PRM number for refugee assistance is (inaudible) billion dollars, and this includes support for up to 125,000 refugees as well as support to reinitiate humanitarian assistance via UNRWA.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>I – you were boxed out for a second, Tracy. I couldn&#8217;t hear the number – the billion dollars.</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON: </b>Oh, $3.8 billion for refugee assistance, and that includes support for up to 125,000 refugees as part of the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>Right. And more broadly to your question, the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration is taking steps to rebuild the infrastructure here in the United States with the local resettlement agencies, helping them with financial assistance, and staffing up its own bureau because they need some additional positions to meet the ambitious target that the President has set for us.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay, very well. So we’re actually over time now, three minutes after the hour. I would like to give a special thanks to our experts on the line today with us, Deputy Secretary McKeon, Principal Advisor Feierstein, Director Pitkin, Acting Director Dr. Carson, and Budget Director Tricia Schmitt. This does conclude our call today. With that, the embargo is lifted. Please have a great weekend.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brian P. McKeon, Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources</p>
<p>Mark Feierstein, Principal Advisor to the Administrator, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Thank you, and good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining us for this on-the-record briefing on the details of the Fiscal Year 2022 budget request for the State Department and USAID that was released earlier today. With us on the line are State Department Deputy Secretary for Management and Resources Brian McKeon and the USAID Administrator’s Principal Advisor Mark Feierstein.</p>
<p>Also joining us today is Director Douglas Pitkin of the State Department’s Bureau of Budget and Planning; Dr. Tracy Carson, Acting Director of the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance; and USAID Budget Director Tricia Schmitt.</p>
<p>To start us off, I’ll be turning the call over to Deputy Secretary McKeon and Advisor Feierstein for their opening remarks, and then afterward our participants will take a few of your questions.</p>
<p>Again, just as a quick reminder, this briefing is on the record, but the contents of the call are embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>
<p>And with that, let’s go to Deputy Secretary McKeon. Sir.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>Thank you, JT. Good afternoon, everybody. Thanks for joining us. You’re doing great service, working hard on the afternoon before Memorial Day weekend.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken noted in his press release, the FY22 Presidents’ budget request includes historic investments across the interagency that will lay the foundation for shared growth and prosperity for decades to come.</p>
<p>I want to share a few toplines from the request for the State Department and USAID, starting with a number of $58.5 billion, a more than 5 billion – or 10 percent – increase over the FY 2021 level. I am pleased to be joined on this call by Mark Feierstein, the Principal Advisor to Administrator Power, who will speak to the budget request for USAID. The relationship between our department and AID is critical in achieving the President’s foreign policy and development goals, and we’re fortunate to have such effective partners. And all the senior leaders here and at AID know each other very well, so we don’t have to build a working relationship, because we already have it.</p>
<p>The first thing I want to highlight is the investment this budget makes in our workforce, which is our greatest asset. As one of the President’s earliest national security memoranda states, quote, “the revitalization of our national security and foreign policy institutions is essential to advancing America’s security, prosperity, and values, accelerating our domestic renewal, and delivering results for all Americans.” End quote. That’s why this budget includes the largest staffing increase for the Department in a decade, covering both the Foreign and Civil Service.</p>
<p>But it’s not just about adding new positions. It’s about ensuring that we recruit and – this is essential – retain the right people: a workforce that represents the full diversity and talent of the United States. The Secretary’s appointment of Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley as the Department’s first ever Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer is just one step in that effort. We are taking steps to revitalize the Department by ensuring that our employees have the tools and training they need to be successful.</p>
<p>We are also investing in the programs and capabilities we need to address the challenges of our time. For example, the budget includes: $10 billion for global health programs, including $1 billion to strengthen pandemic preparedness, which is an $800 million increase; 2.5 billion across the interagency to address climate change, more than quadruple the FY21 level, in close coordination with Special Presidential Envoy Former Secretary Kerry; and increases in democracy and governance programs to stem the tide of rising authoritarianism.</p>
<p>Our State and USAID budget directors will provide additional details on these sectors and other key investments, including the inclusion of more predictable resources to sustain consular services for Americans traveling, working, and living overseas, and additional investments in our cybersecurity and other technology modernization efforts.</p>
<p>We are also requesting the resources we need to support our commitments to key allies and partners, both in this budget and in separate requests. For example, we will be working with the Congress to seek an additional 8,000 Afghan Special Immigrant Visas to meet our commitment to those who have supported our efforts in Afghanistan at great risk to themselves and their families. We are working with the interagency to accelerate SIV processing so we can make use of those visas. We are also continuing to work with the international community on the provision of additional assistance to the Afghan people and government toward a shared goal of prosperity and security for the country.</p>
<p>Finally, this budget is a demonstration of renewed U.S. leadership in the international community. It fully funds our commitments to UN peacekeeping and other international organizations and provides more than $10 billion in humanitarian assistance, including to support a refugee admissions level of up to 125,000. We cannot advance our interests by withdrawing from the world stage. We need to be in the room working with our partners and competitors alike, fighting for our interests.</p>
<p>We will have more to say about the budget over the coming weeks and months about how it reflects and resources our goals and our values as we work with the Congress to secure this funding. I’ll stop here now and turn it over to Mark.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN: </b>Well thank you, Brian, and good afternoon, everybody, and thanks so much for joining. I am very pleased to be joining my friend and State Department colleague, Brian McKeon, to discuss the Biden-Harris administration’s Fiscal Year 2022 budget request. We at USAID are grateful for Deputy Secretary McKeon’s partnership and commitment to the notion that our diplomacy and development efforts abroad are complementary and interdependent.</p>
<p>The FY22 budget request includes 27.7 billion for the U.S. Agency for International Development’s fully and partially managed accounts. It signals President Biden’s commitment to reassert the United States’s role as a leader in global development and humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>From day one, President Biden made clear that development, alongside defense and diplomacy, is critical to American foreign policy. This is not only reflected in the FY 2022 budget request, but also in the President’s decision to elevate the USAID administrator as a standing member of the National Security Council.</p>
<p>This budget also reflects the nature and complexity of the challenges that we face in the 21st century – those that cannot be confined within national borders and require multilateral efforts to confront. Simply put, building back better at home also requires building back better overseas.</p>
<p>By fighting COVID-19 abroad, we stem the rise of variants that can lead to outbreaks at home. When incomes rise in developing countries, those countries become more self-reliant and less dependent on U.S. support. When we deliver aid to those affected by natural disasters or humanitarian crises, we demonstrate the best of American values and build the goodwill that inspires action and cooperation from our allies.</p>
<p>The ongoing pandemic illustrates the importance of USAID’s efforts to bolster health systems globally. We must fight COVID-19 everywhere it exists and work to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks.</p>
<p>We also face an urgent climate crisis which literally poses a threat to some countries’ existence and is also a threat to our own national security. The impacts of climate change lead to conflict, hunger, displacement, and other extreme weather events that cost lives and damage critical infrastructure at home.</p>
<p>Accompanying the existential threats of climate change and the spread of infectious disease is the threat posed by the rise of malign actors undermining the rule of law and democratic norms. Amid the 15-year democratic decline globally documented by Freedom House, nine more countries slipped into a state of autocracy in the last five years alone. USAID’s democracy programming confronts authoritarianism and combats corruption and misinformation through partnerships with government reformers and civil society actors seeking to hold illiberal regimes accountable.</p>
<p>Poverty, violence, and misrule often lead people to leave their countries in search of better opportunities abroad. In Central America, USAID is committed to addressing the root causes of irregular migration by tackling the violence, corruption, and lack of opportunity that drive so many to risk their lives and the lives of their children. Our approach includes a greater emphasis on building economic resilience, identifying and addressing conditions in emigration hot spots, and improving living conditions by promoting good governance.</p>
<p>The United States is also the world’s largest donor for global humanitarian assistance, and we will continue to leverage our contributions to get other countries to do more. The budget request includes 6.3 billion to address needs resulting from man-made emergencies in countries like Yemen, Ethiopia, and Venezuela, as well as natural disasters such as earthquakes, typhoons, and volcano eruptions like we’ve seen recently in the Democratic Republic of Congo and Saint Vincent and the Grenadines. And we’ll not just respond to crises, but invest in resilience and risk reduction efforts that reduce the economic and human cost of disasters.</p>
<p>Now, none of this work would be possible without an investment in our workforce, which is why this request includes $1.9 billion to boost our Civil Service and Foreign Service staffing and create a workforce that reflects the diversity of our country. We are committed to building the most diverse, and most talented, workforce in USAID history.</p>
<p>In sum, the President’s Budget Request released today reflects the reality that America’s security is inextricably linked to that of other nations around the world. This budget proposal is a reflection of the critical importance of development and humanitarian assistance in advancing U.S. interests and upholding American values.</p>
<p>Thank you and we look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. And with that, just a quick reminder to dial 1-0 to get into our question queue. And let’s go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b>You are open, Mr. Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Okay, thanks. Happy Memorial Day weekend, almost. I’ve got two things, they’re both very brief. The first one is – and forgive me, because my math is absolutely atrocious – but a little back-of-the-envelope addition just from the fact sheets and what you’ve said on this call suggests that almost a third of the total is taken up by climate change, health, staffing, and other – and other things like that, including – let me see, I had it written down. Anyway, I just want to know: Is that correct? I mean, it seems like a substantial percentage of this budget – oh, humanitarian assistance was the other one. Is that – am I correct that that’s almost 30 billion of the total 58.5?</p>
<p>And then just one other thing, and that is: Already some human rights groups are talking about how this is – how the foreign military financing for Egypt contradicts the administration’s “no blank check” policy. Is it – it’s always been my understanding that that funding level was – is relatively static and isn’t something that you guys just change in the request; it’s something that Congress weighs in on. Is that correct, as well? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN: </b>I’m going to defer to the deputy secretary on the – and Tracy Carson and Tricia Schmitt on the one-third piece since they’re steeped in all the numbers, and I’m as good at math as you are, Matt.</p>
<p><b>MR PITKIN: </b>This is Doug Pitkin. I’ll start, I guess. Certainly on the climate and the health, those are certainly large elements of the request. While the workforce is an element, it is – in terms of dollar terms, it’s not the most significant number increase. Another key priority in the request is an increase of $600 million to pay our contributions to the UN, including peacekeeping as well as arrears from prior years. So I think in terms of the workforce numbers between State and AID, the increase is probably closer to about 350 million all told, including AID.</p>
<p>But certainly, climate, health, and international contributions are relatively larger amounts, as well as, I believe, Central America. So I’ll let Tracy clarify further.</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON: </b>Absolutely. The health, humanitarian assistance, and climate total is roughly 21.6 million. So there’s 10 million for health, there’s 10 million for humanitarian assistance, and then there’s – I’m sorry, there’s 10 billion for health, 10 billion for humanitarian assistance, and then 1.6 billion for climate. And Doug is absolutely correct – Central America is $861 million, and so they do constitute a sizeable amount of the foreign assistance request.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. With that, let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler. Jennifer?</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you for doing the call. I was wondering if you could get into more specifics about the funding for increasing cybersecurity here, especially in light of today’s latest cyber attack? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PITKIN: </b>This is Doug Pitkin. I can start with the State portion. For the State Department we’re requesting a total increase of approximately 160 million in cybersecurity funding over our current levels. And this reflects a combination of ongoing programs managed by our chief information officer and our Bureau of Diplomatic Security, as well as a number of specific initiatives to respond to the threats identified by the SolarWinds incidents over the last few months. And so for State it’s a topline increase of $160 million for cybersecurity over current levels.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Tricia, do you want to speak to the cyber level for USAID and what the full amount is?</p>
<p><b>MS SCHMITT:</b> Sure. For our overall operational expenses account at USAID, it is 1.9 billion, which includes increases for our staffing, our – it does include our increased investments for information technology and modernization. The funding will include upgrades to support our – again, the modernization pieces but the actual IT piece as well with ’21 enacted.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Let’s go to the line of Simon Ateba.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you for taking my question. This is Simon Ateba with Today News Africa in Washington, D.C. The Trump administration defunded several programs that were taking place in Africa. I was wondering if you can talk a little bit more about how the Biden administration’s budget will benefit programs and interventions by USAID and State Department in Africa. And will those interventions be dependent on human rights, democracy, and so on? And how much exactly is going to Africa? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> Go ahead, Tracy or Tricia.</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON:</b> Yeah, I’ll take that. The request for Africa is $7.6 billion across a range of accounts. It includes the robust support for democracy, rights, and governance, as well as support for economic growth activities, as well as some of our supports to help with civilian security assistance around a range of countries on the continent. You’ll see notable increases for – are in – you’ll see notable increases for engagement, especially with democracy, rights, and governance, (inaudible) USAID core requirement.</p>
<p>I’ll turn to (inaudible) if you’ve got anything else.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Yeah, I’m happy to speak to that as well. So first, thank you for the question. And Africa is of course of utmost importance to USAID. We with State have a joint regional strategy that focuses on four goals. First is to increase economic growth. Second to – is to promote security. Third is to strengthen democracy and human rights. And fourth is to promote inclusive country-level development.</p>
<p>We have some programs that are specific to Africa, such as Prosper Africa. We’re investing $80 million there, and that program is designed to connect U.S. and African businesses with new buyers, suppliers, and investment opportunities. We also have a Power Africa program which began in the Obama administration. For that we’re requesting $57.5 million, and we’re going to use that to continue to promote sub-Saharan Africa’s transition to cleaner and renewable energy. And then we have global programs like Feed the Future, where we promote agricultural development and our investments in Africa are quite significant under that. Similarly, we have health programs that are fairly generous on the African continent. So overall, we – I think we – this very much speaks to the needs that the – that Africa has these days.</p>
<p>But I don’t if, Tricia, do you want to – have anything?</p>
<p><b>MS SCHMITT:</b> No, that’s it. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay, let’s go to the line of Tracy Wilkinson with the <i>Los Angeles Times</i>.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you. I wanted to go back to the question of Central America for a minute and maybe a little more detail, if at all possible, on the 861 million being assigned there. Obviously, that’s the first part of the 4 billion that President Biden has offered the region. But as you know, there’s a lot of controversy about where that money should go, to whom, et cetera. And so to what extent did strings attach to this money or discussion about what – who it should go to, which government first and then – which governments first and then which organizations and different entities within the countries? I’m just curious if there was more discussion about that and anything put in writing about how to disburse these funds. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> So you packed a lot into your question, Tracy. Just at a high level, as you indicated, the President during the campaign promised 4 billion over four years. This is the first step in meeting that commitment. It’s going to focus on strengthening rule of law, democratic governance, strengthening civil society, and improving respect for human rights. I know from the experience of when a similar program was initiated at the end of the Obama-Biden administration and Vice President Biden was leading the effort for the administration, there was a fair amount of, shall we say, conditionality in conversations with the Central American governments, putting requests upon them on certain things that they were going to do in terms of their own investments but also conditions on – related to corruption and governance.</p>
<p>And so I expect we will have some similar conversations. But – and a lot of the funds at that time were disbursed to NGOs more than the governments, but I don’t know that we’ve got this all laid out in detail at this time. I’d defer to other colleagues if they want to add any thoughts.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Well, I would just speak to how we’re carrying this out in practice. And just to offer one example, you may have seen an announcement a few days ago from USAID with regard to funding in El Salvador. And we had been supporting the attorney general’s office there and the supreme court, but we were concerned about certain steps that were taken there, and that we have – we pivot that money towards civil society. So we recognize that in some cases we don’t have perfect development partners, but we’re confident that we can identify in Central America – and this is true around the world – that we can identify reformers within government, people who have the political will to carry out democratic reform. And we’re also confident we can identify civil society actors who can hold their governments accountable and carry out our mutual development objectives. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> And we do have some more questions in the queue, but I’m aware, sir, Mr. Deputy Secretary, that you have a hard stop with us this afternoon. Are you able to carry on or do you need to go, sir?</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> Can do one more, but I realize – and I apologize – didn’t address Matt Lee’s question on Egypt. Let me just do that quickly. You are correct, Matt; it is steady state funding. I think the FMF number’s been at $1.3 billion for several years. We’re going to have conversations with the Congress and the Government of Egypt on the best way to use our assistance to meet our interests, including on human rights. That’s what we’d say about that right now.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Thank you, sir. Let’s go to the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you very much. I really appreciate you taking the time. I really very quickly skimmed through the numbers here, so it’s possible that there’s something I’ve missed. Given everything that Biden has promised, State Department has promised, and how you might be different to past administrations – and when I say that I’m going as far back as Reagan administration – and you want to build back better. Can you respond with two things in focus? One, the African diaspora and the African – the indigenous African diaspora and the indigenous independent media. If you are to help support with your four goals Africa, are you saying here, besides the climate and the health portions, that you are going to try to do this without supporting indigenous African-led development here? Or can you point me to where that is in this budget request? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</b> USAID, this – think we’d defer to you to address this first.</p>
<p><b>MR FEIERSTEIN:</b> Yeah, happy to take this. So look, everything that we do around the world is designed to support local actors, and that is certainly true in Africa as well. So we put together a strategy, we put together a budget that is based on consultations with governments, with civil society, with private sector in the region. And you mentioned diaspora, and diaspora is a very, very important element of this as well. In many cases, they are the – some of the leading actors and investors in their home countries. So we try to work with them as well, and the goal here, of course, is to leverage – use our technical assistance, use our resources to leverage the talents of others and to leverage the resources of others, and that certainly includes the diaspora communities. But thank you for the question.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. Let’s quickly go to the line of David Wainer at Bloomberg.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you for doing this. Could you please clarify the funding you mentioned for programs that help Afghans who worked with U.S. personnel? And just to clarify, are these translators, and what is the total cost of helping those people? And how is that request any different from the 2021 budget? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>So the program that I think folks are familiar with is called the Afghan Special Immigrant Visa program. Congress provides authorization for a certain number of visas each year. Typically, in the last few years, they’ve provided 4,000 slots. We&#8217;re asking for 8,000 this year. The spending is on – typically on the mandatory side of the budget, not the discretionary. Obviously the cost of actually processing the visa applications, doing the interviews, and their initial resettlement – that&#8217;s kind of baked into the budget and how we do our work as a department. The Congress has set forth categories of prioritization in the SIV program. I don&#8217;t have the categories in front of me, but the translators, interpreters are in – I believe in tier one of the categories.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>And I think we have time for just one last quick question. Let’s go to Rachel Oswald at <i>Congressional Quarterly</i>.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Yes, we have you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Can you talk a little bit about what funding is directed toward refugee assistance, specifically rebuilding capacity for admissions domestically?</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>Tracy, I don&#8217;t have the PRM number at my fingertips – several billion dollars, but I don&#8217;t have the exact number. Tracy, do you have that?</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON: </b>My apologies. I was on – I was talking on mute. The PRM number for refugee assistance is (inaudible) billion dollars, and this includes support for up to 125,000 refugees as well as support to reinitiate humanitarian assistance via UNRWA.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>I – you were boxed out for a second, Tracy. I couldn&#8217;t hear the number – the billion dollars.</p>
<p><b>MS CARSON: </b>Oh, $3.8 billion for refugee assistance, and that includes support for up to 125,000 refugees as part of the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</p>
<p><b>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </b>Right. And more broadly to your question, the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration is taking steps to rebuild the infrastructure here in the United States with the local resettlement agencies, helping them with financial assistance, and staffing up its own bureau because they need some additional positions to meet the ambitious target that the President has set for us.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay, very well. So we’re actually over time now, three minutes after the hour. I would like to give a special thanks to our experts on the line today with us, Deputy Secretary McKeon, Principal Advisor Feierstein, Director Pitkin, Acting Director Dr. Carson, and Budget Director Tricia Schmitt. This does conclude our call today. With that, the embargo is lifted. Please have a great weekend.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Indian Minister of External Affairs Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-indian-minister-of-external-affairs-dr-subrahmanyam-jaishankar-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 19:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a special pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  It’s wonderful to have him at the State Department, and very important as well because the United States and India are working together on so many of the most important challenges of our time and ones that are having a profound impact on the lives of our citizens.  And we are united in confronting COVID-19 together, we’re united in dealing with the challenge posed by climate change, and we are partnered together directly through the Quad and other institutions at the United Nations in dealing with many of the challenges that we face in the region and around the world.</p>
<p>The partnership between the United States and India is vital, it’s strong, and I think it’s increasingly productive.  So I’m very pleased to have the foreign minister here today and we have, as usual, a lot to talk about.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Tony.  Well, let me echo the Secretary’s remarks.  It’s first of all a great pleasure to be back.  This is the first cabinet-level visit from India to the new administration, and I’m of course delighted that I see someone as a counterpart with whom I’ve worked for many years.  We have a lot of issues to discuss.  I think our relations have grown stronger over the years, and I’m very confident they’ll continue to do so.  But I also want to take the opportunity to express to the Secretary and through him to the administration, to the United States, for the strong support and solidarity at a moment of great difficulty for us.  So as he said, we have many things to talk about, but I thought that’s something I should express.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  We were – we know.  We remember in the earlier days of COVID, India was there for the United States, something we’ll never forget, and now we want to make sure that we’re there for and with India.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a special pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  It’s wonderful to have him at the State Department, and very important as well because the United States and India are working together on so many of the most important challenges of our time and ones that are having a profound impact on the lives of our citizens.  And we are united in confronting COVID-19 together, we’re united in dealing with the challenge posed by climate change, and we are partnered together directly through the Quad and other institutions at the United Nations in dealing with many of the challenges that we face in the region and around the world.</p>
<p>The partnership between the United States and India is vital, it’s strong, and I think it’s increasingly productive.  So I’m very pleased to have the foreign minister here today and we have, as usual, a lot to talk about.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Tony.  Well, let me echo the Secretary’s remarks.  It’s first of all a great pleasure to be back.  This is the first cabinet-level visit from India to the new administration, and I’m of course delighted that I see someone as a counterpart with whom I’ve worked for many years.  We have a lot of issues to discuss.  I think our relations have grown stronger over the years, and I’m very confident they’ll continue to do so.  But I also want to take the opportunity to express to the Secretary and through him to the administration, to the United States, for the strong support and solidarity at a moment of great difficulty for us.  So as he said, we have many things to talk about, but I thought that’s something I should express.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  We were – we know.  We remember in the earlier days of COVID, India was there for the United States, something we’ll never forget, and now we want to make sure that we’re there for and with India.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Colombian Vice President Ramírez</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-colombian-vice-president-ramirez/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 19:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Colombian Vice President and Foreign Minister-Designate Marta Lucía Ramírez today at the Department of State. The Secretary reaffirmed the enduring partnership our two countries have maintained for decades, based on a commitment to democracy, the security of our people, and mutual prosperity. He expressed his concern and condolences for the loss of life during recent protests in Colombia and reiterated the unquestionable right of citizens to protest peacefully. He welcomed the national dialogue President Duque has convened as an opportunity for the Colombian people to work together to construct a peaceful, prosperous future. The Secretary reiterated his appreciation for the U.S.-Colombia partnership, and pledged to continue our close cooperation to support lasting peace in Colombia, coordinate an effective health response to the pandemic, and facilitate inclusive economic growth as our hemisphere recovers.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Colombian Vice President and Foreign Minister-Designate Marta Lucía Ramírez today at the Department of State. The Secretary reaffirmed the enduring partnership our two countries have maintained for decades, based on a commitment to democracy, the security of our people, and mutual prosperity. He expressed his concern and condolences for the loss of life during recent protests in Colombia and reiterated the unquestionable right of citizens to protest peacefully. He welcomed the national dialogue President Duque has convened as an opportunity for the Colombian people to work together to construct a peaceful, prosperous future. The Secretary reiterated his appreciation for the U.S.-Colombia partnership, and pledged to continue our close cooperation to support lasting peace in Colombia, coordinate an effective health response to the pandemic, and facilitate inclusive economic growth as our hemisphere recovers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>State Department and U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) FY 2022 Budget Request</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/state-department-and-u-s-agency-for-international-development-usaid-fy-2022-budget-request/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 Budget requests $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID. The funding request invests in the core foundations of our country’s strength and delivers for the American people, including by working with allies and partners to address the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, promote and defend our democratic values, and engage China in the Indo-Pacific and globally from a position of collective strength. This budget will enable the Department of State and USAID to help achieve the President’s vision of restoring U.S. leadership and delivering security and prosperity for all Americans.</p>
<p>The Department of State and USAID use diplomatic and development tools to advance U.S. interests and deliver for all Americans. After four years of neglect, the State and USAID Budget request significantly increases funding for climate initiatives, makes needed investments in global health security, enhances our support for the promotion and protection of democracy, human rights, labor rights, and rule of law, reasserts U.S. global humanitarian leadership, including rebuilding U.S. refugee resettlement, increases economic and security assistance to Central America to address the root causes of irregular migration, reinvigorates the diplomatic and development workforce, and meets our international obligations, all while supporting efforts to advance racial equity and inclusion in foreign assistance and within foreign affairs agencies.</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 budget request includes $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, an increase of $5.5 billion or 10 percent over the FY 2021 enacted level. It:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ensures the United States is Better Prepared to Prevent, Detect, and Respond to Future Biological Threats and Pandemics. </strong>The budget request expands American leadership in global health security in order to address long-term impacts of COVID-19 and to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks, whether naturally occurring, accidental, or deliberate. The budget request includes $10.1 billion for global health programs of which nearly $1 billion would fund global health security programs and support to end the COVID-19 pandemic, an increase of over $800 million above the FY 2021 enacted level. This nearly $1 billion would expand Global Health Security Agenda capacity-building programs to additional countries and increase investments in crosscutting research and viral discovery programs to detect and stamp out future infectious disease outbreaks before they become pandemics. These funds also support global pandemic preparedness efforts, including a health security financing mechanism developed alongside U.S. partners and allies to catalyze increased investment in pandemic prevention and preparedness for future outbreaks. Funding would also support the global Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator platform to deploy tests, treatments, and vaccines around the world. Global health activities supported in the FY 2022 budget request build upon existing global health security infrastructure developed through decades of U.S. investment as well as emergency supplemental funding over the past year and the $10.8 billion provided in the American Rescue Plan Act for the Department and USAID to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>
<li><strong>Responds to the Climate Crisis. </strong>The budget request tackles the climate emergency head-on, providing more than $2.5 billion across all government agencies for international climate programs, more than four times the 2021 enacted level, to rally the world against this urgent threat that cannot be defeated by a single nation alone. The budget request includes $1.25 billion for the Green Climate Fund, with funding split between the Department and Treasury. The request also includes over $700 million in State and USAID bilateral, regional, and global climate-related assistance. The United States would provide $485 million to support other multilateral climate initiatives, including $100 million for international climate adaptation programs. The budget request also proposes funding for staffing increases to develop new centers of climate expertise at the Department of State and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation. By reestablishing U.S. leadership on climate change, these increased climate investments would revitalize America’s coalitions with its allies and help mobilize the rest of the international community to increase its contributions.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes Collaborative U.S. Leadership in Central America. </strong>It is critical to revitalize U.S. leadership in Central America and to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America to the United States. To that end, the budget request invests $861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion. These resources would allow the United States to work with partners in the region to strengthen host government accountability in curtailing endemic corruption, expanding economic opportunity, improving governance, and reducing violence and insecurity.</li>
<li><strong>Restores America’s Standing in International Organizations. </strong>To ensure we are in a position to uphold and defend the principles and values of the international order we helped build, we must meet U.S. commitments to international peacekeeping and pay our assessed dues to international organizations on time and in full, reversing the chronic underfunding of these critical programs by the previous administration. The budget request provides approximately $500 million more than last year, for a total of nearly $2 billion, for UN peacekeeping missions, including $300 million to begin reducing cap-related arrears accumulated over the past four years, with the intention of fully paying these arrears within two years. The budget request also makes investments to restore America’s standing in the world by providing funding, including for the payment of arrears where applicable, to support international organizations and related programs, including the World Health Organization, the UN Population Fund, and the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, while continuing to press for needed reforms. These investments position us to lead in international organizations with our like-minded partners.</li>
<li><strong>Advances U.S. Humanitarian Leadership, Rebuilds U.S. Refugee Resettlement. </strong>Humanitarian needs are at historic levels as COVID-19 has exacerbated existing challenges from ongoing and new complex emergencies. The budget request provides the resources necessary to rebuild the badly damaged U.S. refugee admissions program and support up to 125,000 admissions in 2022. It provides over $10 billion in humanitarian assistance to support vulnerable people abroad, including refugees, conflict victims, and other displaced persons.</li>
<li><strong>Promotes and Defends our Democratic Values and Counters Rising Authoritarianism. </strong>This budget will enable the United States to lead efforts with our democratic allies and partners to support open and free societies, strengthen democratic institutions, combat growing authoritarianism and corruption, increase respect for human rights, support marginalized populations, and strengthen partner capacity to protect democratic systems against malign influence from China, Russia, and other authoritarian states. This programming would complement international efforts stemming from the Administration’s Summit for Democracy to strengthen democratic institutions, honestly confront nations that are backsliding, and forge a common agenda.</li>
<li><strong>Supports U.S. Partners in the Middle East and Advances Peace in the Region. </strong>The budget request fully funds U.S. commitments to key allies in the Middle East, including Israel and Jordan. The budget request funds assistance programs and humanitarian aid for Palestinians, including support for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA). The United States will maintain steadfast support for Israel as the Administration renews relations with Palestinian leadership, restores economic and humanitarian assistance for Palestinians, and works to advance freedom, prosperity, and security for the Israeli and Palestinian people alike.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes the Foreign Policy Workforce to Deliver for All Americans</strong>through increases in funding for the Department’s and USAID’s greatest asset, our people. The FY 2022 request proposes funding for the largest State staffing increase in a decade, building a diplomatic and development corps that fully represents America in all its talent and   By empowering our workforce and deepening our expertise, we will be able to successfully address 21st century challenges on global health, climate, and technology. State’s new Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer will lead the charge to implement our Diversity and Inclusion Strategic Plan across the Department.</li>
<li><strong>Invests in Information Technology (IT) Modernization and Stronger Cybersecurity</strong>across State and USAID, providing more secure and mobile communication tools enabling our workforce to succeed in the modern information environment, with greater agility, collaboration, and access to data. An increase of more than $100 million for State’s cybersecurity is crucial to mitigating the evolving cybersecurity threat landscape. The Department and the Agency remain prime targets of malicious state- and non-state actors, as evidenced by the recent attacks.</li>
<li><strong>Supports Consular Services to Assist Americans, Promote Prosperity, and Advance U.S. Interests.</strong>The request includes a direct appropriation of $320 million to provide a stable source of support for consular services provided to American citizens and foreign visa applicants who come to visit, study, and invest in our communities in light of reduced fee revenue due to the pandemic, as well as continuing authorities allowing fees collected to support a wider array of consular activity through FY 2022.</li>
<li><strong>Sustains Security for our Worldwide Presence at $6.1 billion,</strong>protecting our personnel, embassies, and cybersecurity around the globe. These include initiatives to expand real-time threat monitoring, accelerate security vetting, and the construction or renovation of embassies and consulates in Vietnam, Democratic Republic of Congo, Bosnia, South Africa, and France.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, please visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/fy-2022-international-affairs-budget/">www.state.gov/cj</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 Budget requests $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID. The funding request invests in the core foundations of our country’s strength and delivers for the American people, including by working with allies and partners to address the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, promote and defend our democratic values, and engage China in the Indo-Pacific and globally from a position of collective strength. This budget will enable the Department of State and USAID to help achieve the President’s vision of restoring U.S. leadership and delivering security and prosperity for all Americans.</p>
<p>The Department of State and USAID use diplomatic and development tools to advance U.S. interests and deliver for all Americans. After four years of neglect, the State and USAID Budget request significantly increases funding for climate initiatives, makes needed investments in global health security, enhances our support for the promotion and protection of democracy, human rights, labor rights, and rule of law, reasserts U.S. global humanitarian leadership, including rebuilding U.S. refugee resettlement, increases economic and security assistance to Central America to address the root causes of irregular migration, reinvigorates the diplomatic and development workforce, and meets our international obligations, all while supporting efforts to advance racial equity and inclusion in foreign assistance and within foreign affairs agencies.</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 budget request includes $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, an increase of $5.5 billion or 10 percent over the FY 2021 enacted level. It:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ensures the United States is Better Prepared to Prevent, Detect, and Respond to Future Biological Threats and Pandemics. </strong>The budget request expands American leadership in global health security in order to address long-term impacts of COVID-19 and to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks, whether naturally occurring, accidental, or deliberate. The budget request includes $10.1 billion for global health programs of which nearly $1 billion would fund global health security programs and support to end the COVID-19 pandemic, an increase of over $800 million above the FY 2021 enacted level. This nearly $1 billion would expand Global Health Security Agenda capacity-building programs to additional countries and increase investments in crosscutting research and viral discovery programs to detect and stamp out future infectious disease outbreaks before they become pandemics. These funds also support global pandemic preparedness efforts, including a health security financing mechanism developed alongside U.S. partners and allies to catalyze increased investment in pandemic prevention and preparedness for future outbreaks. Funding would also support the global Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator platform to deploy tests, treatments, and vaccines around the world. Global health activities supported in the FY 2022 budget request build upon existing global health security infrastructure developed through decades of U.S. investment as well as emergency supplemental funding over the past year and the $10.8 billion provided in the American Rescue Plan Act for the Department and USAID to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>
<li><strong>Responds to the Climate Crisis. </strong>The budget request tackles the climate emergency head-on, providing more than $2.5 billion across all government agencies for international climate programs, more than four times the 2021 enacted level, to rally the world against this urgent threat that cannot be defeated by a single nation alone. The budget request includes $1.25 billion for the Green Climate Fund, with funding split between the Department and Treasury. The request also includes over $700 million in State and USAID bilateral, regional, and global climate-related assistance. The United States would provide $485 million to support other multilateral climate initiatives, including $100 million for international climate adaptation programs. The budget request also proposes funding for staffing increases to develop new centers of climate expertise at the Department of State and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation. By reestablishing U.S. leadership on climate change, these increased climate investments would revitalize America’s coalitions with its allies and help mobilize the rest of the international community to increase its contributions.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes Collaborative U.S. Leadership in Central America. </strong>It is critical to revitalize U.S. leadership in Central America and to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America to the United States. To that end, the budget request invests $861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion. These resources would allow the United States to work with partners in the region to strengthen host government accountability in curtailing endemic corruption, expanding economic opportunity, improving governance, and reducing violence and insecurity.</li>
<li><strong>Restores America’s Standing in International Organizations. </strong>To ensure we are in a position to uphold and defend the principles and values of the international order we helped build, we must meet U.S. commitments to international peacekeeping and pay our assessed dues to international organizations on time and in full, reversing the chronic underfunding of these critical programs by the previous administration. The budget request provides approximately $500 million more than last year, for a total of nearly $2 billion, for UN peacekeeping missions, including $300 million to begin reducing cap-related arrears accumulated over the past four years, with the intention of fully paying these arrears within two years. The budget request also makes investments to restore America’s standing in the world by providing funding, including for the payment of arrears where applicable, to support international organizations and related programs, including the World Health Organization, the UN Population Fund, and the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, while continuing to press for needed reforms. These investments position us to lead in international organizations with our like-minded partners.</li>
<li><strong>Advances U.S. Humanitarian Leadership, Rebuilds U.S. Refugee Resettlement. </strong>Humanitarian needs are at historic levels as COVID-19 has exacerbated existing challenges from ongoing and new complex emergencies. The budget request provides the resources necessary to rebuild the badly damaged U.S. refugee admissions program and support up to 125,000 admissions in 2022. It provides over $10 billion in humanitarian assistance to support vulnerable people abroad, including refugees, conflict victims, and other displaced persons.</li>
<li><strong>Promotes and Defends our Democratic Values and Counters Rising Authoritarianism. </strong>This budget will enable the United States to lead efforts with our democratic allies and partners to support open and free societies, strengthen democratic institutions, combat growing authoritarianism and corruption, increase respect for human rights, support marginalized populations, and strengthen partner capacity to protect democratic systems against malign influence from China, Russia, and other authoritarian states. This programming would complement international efforts stemming from the Administration’s Summit for Democracy to strengthen democratic institutions, honestly confront nations that are backsliding, and forge a common agenda.</li>
<li><strong>Supports U.S. Partners in the Middle East and Advances Peace in the Region. </strong>The budget request fully funds U.S. commitments to key allies in the Middle East, including Israel and Jordan. The budget request funds assistance programs and humanitarian aid for Palestinians, including support for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA). The United States will maintain steadfast support for Israel as the Administration renews relations with Palestinian leadership, restores economic and humanitarian assistance for Palestinians, and works to advance freedom, prosperity, and security for the Israeli and Palestinian people alike.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes the Foreign Policy Workforce to Deliver for All Americans</strong>through increases in funding for the Department’s and USAID’s greatest asset, our people. The FY 2022 request proposes funding for the largest State staffing increase in a decade, building a diplomatic and development corps that fully represents America in all its talent and   By empowering our workforce and deepening our expertise, we will be able to successfully address 21st century challenges on global health, climate, and technology. State’s new Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer will lead the charge to implement our Diversity and Inclusion Strategic Plan across the Department.</li>
<li><strong>Invests in Information Technology (IT) Modernization and Stronger Cybersecurity</strong>across State and USAID, providing more secure and mobile communication tools enabling our workforce to succeed in the modern information environment, with greater agility, collaboration, and access to data. An increase of more than $100 million for State’s cybersecurity is crucial to mitigating the evolving cybersecurity threat landscape. The Department and the Agency remain prime targets of malicious state- and non-state actors, as evidenced by the recent attacks.</li>
<li><strong>Supports Consular Services to Assist Americans, Promote Prosperity, and Advance U.S. Interests.</strong>The request includes a direct appropriation of $320 million to provide a stable source of support for consular services provided to American citizens and foreign visa applicants who come to visit, study, and invest in our communities in light of reduced fee revenue due to the pandemic, as well as continuing authorities allowing fees collected to support a wider array of consular activity through FY 2022.</li>
<li><strong>Sustains Security for our Worldwide Presence at $6.1 billion,</strong>protecting our personnel, embassies, and cybersecurity around the globe. These include initiatives to expand real-time threat monitoring, accelerate security vetting, and the construction or renovation of embassies and consulates in Vietnam, Democratic Republic of Congo, Bosnia, South Africa, and France.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, please visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/fy-2022-international-affairs-budget/">www.state.gov/cj</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The President’s Fiscal Year 2022 Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-presidents-fiscal-year-2022-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Administration has submitted to Congress the President’s Budget for Fiscal Year 2022. As we continue to make progress defeating the pandemic and getting our economy back on track, this budget makes historic investments that will help us build back better, leaving us stronger at home and on the world stage.</p>
<p>The President’s Budget for FY 2022 requests $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, a 10 percent increase over FY 2021 as enacted. These resources will position us to advance the Administration’s foreign policy agenda on behalf of the American people. It also reflects the importance the Administration places on U.S. global leadership and the fact that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests.</p>
<p>These increased diplomatic and foreign assistance resources will enable us to deliver for the American people by bolstering global health security, addressing the climate crisis, helping tackle the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, reasserting American leadership to promote democracy and counter rising authoritarianism, providing international humanitarian leadership, and meeting competition head on from nations that do not share our values of freedom, democracy, and respect for human rights.</p>
<p>This budget supports the Department’s consular activities that protect Americans. It also invests in our foreign policy and development workforce to ensure that it fully represents America in all its talent and diversity and that it has the necessary 21st century tools and technology at its disposal to deliver results for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>More generally, the budget includes the two historic plans the President has already put forward — the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan – and reinvests in education, research, public health, and other foundations of our country’s strength.  Enacting this budget this year will strengthen our Nation’s economy and lay the foundation for shared prosperity, while also improving our Nation’s long-term fiscal health.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Administration has submitted to Congress the President’s Budget for Fiscal Year 2022. As we continue to make progress defeating the pandemic and getting our economy back on track, this budget makes historic investments that will help us build back better, leaving us stronger at home and on the world stage.</p>
<p>The President’s Budget for FY 2022 requests $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, a 10 percent increase over FY 2021 as enacted. These resources will position us to advance the Administration’s foreign policy agenda on behalf of the American people. It also reflects the importance the Administration places on U.S. global leadership and the fact that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests.</p>
<p>These increased diplomatic and foreign assistance resources will enable us to deliver for the American people by bolstering global health security, addressing the climate crisis, helping tackle the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, reasserting American leadership to promote democracy and counter rising authoritarianism, providing international humanitarian leadership, and meeting competition head on from nations that do not share our values of freedom, democracy, and respect for human rights.</p>
<p>This budget supports the Department’s consular activities that protect Americans. It also invests in our foreign policy and development workforce to ensure that it fully represents America in all its talent and diversity and that it has the necessary 21st century tools and technology at its disposal to deliver results for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>More generally, the budget includes the two historic plans the President has already put forward — the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan – and reinvests in education, research, public health, and other foundations of our country’s strength.  Enacting this budget this year will strengthen our Nation’s economy and lay the foundation for shared prosperity, while also improving our Nation’s long-term fiscal health.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Withhold and Release Orders (WROs) for Seafood Products Imported from the Dalian Ocean Fishing Company</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-withhold-and-release-orders-wros-for-seafood-products-imported-from-the-dalian-ocean-fishing-company/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, an agency of the Department of Homeland Security, issued <a class="external-link" href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/national-media-release/cbp-issues-withhold-release-order-chinese-fishing-fleet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Withhold Release Orders (WROs)</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> for seafood products imported from the Dalian Ocean Fishing Company, a firm in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for which there is credible evidence of the use of forced labor to harvest its seafood, primarily tuna.  As a result, the United States is prohibiting the import of seafood products from this company.</p>
<p>U.S. law forbids the importation of products made with forced labor.  Today’s action helps stop human rights abusers from profiting from forced labor.  It is also another example of the United States taking measures to address harmful fishing practices.  In 2020, the Department revoked more than a dozen visas for individuals complicit in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing with links to human trafficking.</p>
<p>Reports of the use of forced labor by PRC fishing vessels were described in the Department’s <a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/2020-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/china/">2020 Human Rights Report.</a>  The report noted other PRC firms that abuse migrant workers subjected to forced labor.  These workers are forced to work 18 to 22 hours a day, often in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.  They are prevented from leaving their ships while facing hunger, restricted communication, inadequate medical care, degrading living and working conditions, physical abuse, and debt-based coercion.  The Department of Labor similarly has reported on widespread use of forced labor in the PRC’s distant-water fishing fleet.</p>
<p>The United States will promote accountability for those who use forced labor to exploit individuals for profit, and we will work with our international partners to ensure that the voiceless are heard and protected.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, an agency of the Department of Homeland Security, issued <a class="external-link" href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/national-media-release/cbp-issues-withhold-release-order-chinese-fishing-fleet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Withhold Release Orders (WROs)</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> for seafood products imported from the Dalian Ocean Fishing Company, a firm in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for which there is credible evidence of the use of forced labor to harvest its seafood, primarily tuna.  As a result, the United States is prohibiting the import of seafood products from this company.</p>
<p>U.S. law forbids the importation of products made with forced labor.  Today’s action helps stop human rights abusers from profiting from forced labor.  It is also another example of the United States taking measures to address harmful fishing practices.  In 2020, the Department revoked more than a dozen visas for individuals complicit in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing with links to human trafficking.</p>
<p>Reports of the use of forced labor by PRC fishing vessels were described in the Department’s <a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/2020-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/china/">2020 Human Rights Report.</a>  The report noted other PRC firms that abuse migrant workers subjected to forced labor.  These workers are forced to work 18 to 22 hours a day, often in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.  They are prevented from leaving their ships while facing hunger, restricted communication, inadequate medical care, degrading living and working conditions, physical abuse, and debt-based coercion.  The Department of Labor similarly has reported on widespread use of forced labor in the PRC’s distant-water fishing fleet.</p>
<p>The United States will promote accountability for those who use forced labor to exploit individuals for profit, and we will work with our international partners to ensure that the voiceless are heard and protected.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
