<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 12:46:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-jerusalem-ramallah-cairo-and-amman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 11:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman May 24-27, 2021.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken is undertaking this trip at the request of President Biden. He will first travel to Jerusalem, where he will meet with Israeli President Reuven Rivlin, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi, and other senior Israeli officials. In Ramallah, he will meet with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas, Prime Minister Mohammad Shtayyeh, and other senior officials from the Palestinian Authority. Secretary Blinken will then travel to Cairo to meet with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi and Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry. The Secretary will conclude his trip with a stop in Amman to meet with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi.</p>
<p>The United States has engaged in intensive diplomacy to bring an end to the hostilities in Gaza. Secretary Blinken is traveling to the region to discuss essential follow-up efforts to consolidate the ceasefire and reduce risks of further conflict over the coming months.</p>
<p>For any questions, please email <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter @StateDept_NEA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman May 24-27, 2021.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken is undertaking this trip at the request of President Biden. He will first travel to Jerusalem, where he will meet with Israeli President Reuven Rivlin, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi, and other senior Israeli officials. In Ramallah, he will meet with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas, Prime Minister Mohammad Shtayyeh, and other senior officials from the Palestinian Authority. Secretary Blinken will then travel to Cairo to meet with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi and Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry. The Secretary will conclude his trip with a stop in Amman to meet with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi.</p>
<p>The United States has engaged in intensive diplomacy to bring an end to the hostilities in Gaza. Secretary Blinken is traveling to the region to discuss essential follow-up efforts to consolidate the ceasefire and reduce risks of further conflict over the coming months.</p>
<p>For any questions, please email <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter @StateDept_NEA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States’ Actions to Press for the Resolution of the Crisis in the Tigray Region of Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-actions-to-press-for-the-resolution-of-the-crisis-in-the-tigray-region-of-ethiopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 23:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245722</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has deepening concerns about the ongoing crisis in Ethiopia’s Tigray region as well as other threats to the sovereignty, national unity, and territorial integrity of Ethiopia. People in Tigray continue to suffer human rights violations, abuses, and atrocities, and urgently needed humanitarian relief is being blocked by the Ethiopian and Eritrean militaries as well as other armed actors. Despite significant diplomatic engagement, the parties to the conflict in Tigray have taken no meaningful steps to end hostilities or pursue a peaceful resolution of the political crisis. The United States condemns in the strongest terms the killings, forced removals, systemic sexual violence, and other human rights violations and abuses. We are equally appalled by the destruction of civilian property including water sources, hospitals, and medical facilities, taking place in Tigray. We call on the Ethiopian government to meet public commitments to hold accountable all those responsible for human rights violations and abuses, to protect civilians, and to ensure unhindered humanitarian access. We call for the Eritrean government to live up to its public commitment and immediately return its troops to internationally recognized Eritrean territory. Without an immediate cessation of hostilities and a rapid expansion of humanitarian access, current and significant food insecurity could lead to famine.</p>
<p>The time for action from the international community is now. Today, I am announcing a visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act on the issuance of visas for any current or former Ethiopian or Eritrean government officials, members of the security forces, or other individuals—to include Amhara regional and irregular forces and members of the Tigray People’s Liberation Front (TPLF)—responsible for, or complicit in, undermining resolution of the crisis in Tigray. This includes those who have conducted wrongful violence or other abuses against people in the Tigray region of Ethiopia, as well as those who have hindered access of humanitarian assistance to those in the region. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions. Should those responsible for undermining a resolution of the crisis in Tigray fail to reverse course, they should anticipate further actions from the United States and the international community. We call on other governments to join us in taking these actions.</p>
<p>Additionally, we have imposed wide-ranging restrictions on economic and security assistance to Ethiopia and will bring our defense trade control policy in line with them. We will continue humanitarian assistance and certain other critical aid to Ethiopia in areas such as health, food security, basic education, support for women and girls, human rights and democracy, good governance, and conflict mitigation, consistent with available authorities. The United States will continue its existing broad restrictions on assistance to Eritrea.</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its calls for a durable, political solution to the crisis. We are committed to supporting efforts to resolve the crisis in Tigray and help Ethiopians advance reconciliation and dialogue to overcome current divisions.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has deepening concerns about the ongoing crisis in Ethiopia’s Tigray region as well as other threats to the sovereignty, national unity, and territorial integrity of Ethiopia. People in Tigray continue to suffer human rights violations, abuses, and atrocities, and urgently needed humanitarian relief is being blocked by the Ethiopian and Eritrean militaries as well as other armed actors. Despite significant diplomatic engagement, the parties to the conflict in Tigray have taken no meaningful steps to end hostilities or pursue a peaceful resolution of the political crisis. The United States condemns in the strongest terms the killings, forced removals, systemic sexual violence, and other human rights violations and abuses. We are equally appalled by the destruction of civilian property including water sources, hospitals, and medical facilities, taking place in Tigray. We call on the Ethiopian government to meet public commitments to hold accountable all those responsible for human rights violations and abuses, to protect civilians, and to ensure unhindered humanitarian access. We call for the Eritrean government to live up to its public commitment and immediately return its troops to internationally recognized Eritrean territory. Without an immediate cessation of hostilities and a rapid expansion of humanitarian access, current and significant food insecurity could lead to famine.</p>
<p>The time for action from the international community is now. Today, I am announcing a visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act on the issuance of visas for any current or former Ethiopian or Eritrean government officials, members of the security forces, or other individuals—to include Amhara regional and irregular forces and members of the Tigray People’s Liberation Front (TPLF)—responsible for, or complicit in, undermining resolution of the crisis in Tigray. This includes those who have conducted wrongful violence or other abuses against people in the Tigray region of Ethiopia, as well as those who have hindered access of humanitarian assistance to those in the region. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions. Should those responsible for undermining a resolution of the crisis in Tigray fail to reverse course, they should anticipate further actions from the United States and the international community. We call on other governments to join us in taking these actions.</p>
<p>Additionally, we have imposed wide-ranging restrictions on economic and security assistance to Ethiopia and will bring our defense trade control policy in line with them. We will continue humanitarian assistance and certain other critical aid to Ethiopia in areas such as health, food security, basic education, support for women and girls, human rights and democracy, good governance, and conflict mitigation, consistent with available authorities. The United States will continue its existing broad restrictions on assistance to Eritrea.</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its calls for a durable, political solution to the crisis. We are committed to supporting efforts to resolve the crisis in Tigray and help Ethiopians advance reconciliation and dialogue to overcome current divisions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diversion of Ryanair Flight to Belarus and Arrest of Journalist</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/diversion-of-ryanair-flight-to-belarus-and-arrest-of-journalist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 22:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States strongly condemns the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist Raman Pratasevich in Minsk. We demand his immediate release. This shocking act perpetrated by the Lukashenka regime endangered the lives of more than 120 passengers, including U.S. citizens. Initial reports suggesting the involvement of the Belarusian security services and the use of Belarusian military aircraft to escort the plane are deeply concerning and require full investigation.</p>
<p>We are closely coordinating our response with our partners, including the EU and Lithuanian and Greek officials. Given indications the forced landing was based on false pretenses, we support the earliest possible meeting of the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization to review these events.</p>
<p>Independent media are an essential pillar supporting the rule of law and a vital component of a democratic society. The United States once again condemns the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing harassment and arbitrary detention of journalists. We stand with the Belarusian people in their aspirations for a free, democratic, and prosperous future and support their call for the regime to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States strongly condemns the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist Raman Pratasevich in Minsk. We demand his immediate release. This shocking act perpetrated by the Lukashenka regime endangered the lives of more than 120 passengers, including U.S. citizens. Initial reports suggesting the involvement of the Belarusian security services and the use of Belarusian military aircraft to escort the plane are deeply concerning and require full investigation.</p>
<p>We are closely coordinating our response with our partners, including the EU and Lithuanian and Greek officials. Given indications the forced landing was based on false pretenses, we support the earliest possible meeting of the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization to review these events.</p>
<p>Independent media are an essential pillar supporting the rule of law and a vital component of a democratic society. The United States once again condemns the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing harassment and arbitrary detention of journalists. We stand with the Belarusian people in their aspirations for a free, democratic, and prosperous future and support their call for the regime to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken On CNN’s Fareed Zakaria GPS with Fareed Zakaria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-cnns-fareed-zakaria-gps-with-fareed-zakaria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Joining me now is the Secretary of State, Antony Blinken.  Welcome, Mr. Secretary.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks, Fareed.  It’s great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  President Biden says that he thinks now that there is a ceasefire in – between the Israelis and Palestinians – there is a significant opportunity for even more positive developments, or a “genuine opportunity,” I think, if I’m quoting him correctly.  And I’m wondering:  Is there really?  I mean, you have an Israeli Government that seems pretty unyielding.  You have a Palestinian Authority led by an 85-year-old man who doesn’t – is too scared to hold elections for fear of what will happen.  Hamas controls Gaza.  Is there really a prospect of some kind of movement towards a genuine political solution?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Fareed, I think there has to be.  I think both sides are reminded that we have to find a way to break the cycle, because if we don’t, it will repeat itself at great cost and at great human suffering on all sides.  Look, we worked very hard with this intense but behind-the-scenes diplomacy to get to the ceasefire, and I think President Biden leading this effort made the judgment that we could be most effective in doing that.  And ultimately, after this intensive effort across the government, we got to where everyone wanted to be, which was to end the violence. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But now, as the President said, I think it’s incumbent upon all of us to try to make the turn to start to build something more positive.  And what that means at heart is that Palestinians and Israelis alike have to know in their day-in and day-out lives equal measures of opportunity, of security, of dignity, something that you touched on in your piece in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Washington Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this week. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Will you use, as a template, the last peace plan put forward by the United States Government that is the peace plan shepherded by Jared Kushner?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, I don’t think we’re at the – in a place where the – getting to some kind of a negotiation for what ultimately, I think, has to be the result, which is a two-state solution, is the first order of business.  We have to start building back in concrete ways and offering some genuine hope, prospects, opportunity in the lives of people. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And of course, in the first instance, we’ve got to deal with the humanitarian situation, which is grave in Gaza.  We’ve got to start to bring countries together to support reconstruction and development.  And as we’re doing that, we’ll be re-engaging with the Palestinians, of course, continuing our deep engagement with the Israelis, and trying to put in place conditions that allow us over time hopefully to advance a genuine peace process.  But that is not the immediate order of business.  We have a lot of work to do to get to that point.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  But does the United States Government still endorse the outlines of that plan?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  We’re going to look at everything that’s been done before, learn from that just as we have in other areas, and see what makes sense and what doesn’t.  But our focus right now relentlessly is on dealing with the humanitarian situation, starting to be – to do reconstruction and rebuild, and engage intensely with everyone, with Palestinians, with Israelis, with partners in the region. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Prime Minister Netanyahu says that he will form a national unity government, but not with any Israeli Arabs in it.  Israeli Arabs, as you know, make up 20 percent of the population of Israel.  Is that a positive step?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, I don’t do politics, whether it’s our politics or Israeli politics.  They have to make their own judgments, and the government will be formed eventually, one way or another.  We leave that to the Israelis.  But we will work with, obviously, the current Israeli Government, whatever government emerges from the current process, and it’s really a decision for Israelis to make, not us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  But you have been very clear in being in favor of democracy and worrying about the decay of democracy in countries.  Is it a step forward for democracy for a national government explicitly, on racial lines, to rule out 20 percent of its population?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, one thing that’s been, I think, deeply disturbing about recent events has been the inter-communal violence.  And that’s something that we have not seen, at least in recent years.  And I believe and I hope that Israelis of all persuasions will find ways to come together to try to make sure that that doesn’t happen again.  And hopefully that finds expression as well in their politics and in their governments.  But again, these are decisions for Israelis to make, not for us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Let me ask you while we’re on the Middle East, Mr. Secretary:  The Biden administration, President Biden when he was campaigning said as soon as I become president, we will rejoin the Iran nuclear deal.  The Iranians said the same thing.  We’re now four months into the administration.  Nothing has happened.  Both sides said there seems to be a – something of a stand-off.  And Iran is meanwhile visibly enriching, the very thing people like you warned about when – again, when Joe Biden was campaigning.  Isn’t this a failure of diplomacy?  Shouldn’t you guys have been able to get back into the deal within a week or two?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Two things, Fareed.  First, I think the steps that Iran is taking underscore the urgency of trying to get Iran back into compliance with its obligations under the nuclear deal, the deal that stopped their – the dangerous aspects of their nuclear program, the prospect that they could have fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  We’ve had, I think, five rounds of conversations now, of talks now, indirect in Vienna.  And in fact, our team’s going back to Vienna in the coming days to pursue that.  I think we’ve actually made progress in clarifying what each side needs to do to get back into full compliance.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The outstanding question, the question that we don’t have an answer to yet, is whether Iran, at the end of the day, is willing to do what is necessary to come back into compliance with the agreement.  That’s the proposition that we’re testing.  But it’s getting, I think, through these rounds of discussions and talks, clearer and clearer what needs to happen.  The question is:  Is Iran prepared to do it?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Well, the Iranians say that that’s actually not what’s happening, what – the United States – the Biden administration has moved the goalposts, that rather than talking about simply both sides getting back to the original deal, doing what was required to comply, the Biden administration is now saying they want to talk about ballistic missiles, they want to talk about regional issues, they want to talk about extending the timeline.  Are you willing to go back to the original deal as it was?  Because the Iranians say they are willing to get back to that tomorrow. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Fareed, we’ve been very clear.  We are fully prepared to go back to the original deal as it was.  That’s our initial objective.  And we – again, we don’t know if the Iranians are.  If we do, if we succeed in that, then we can use that as a foundation both to look at how we can make the deal itself potentially longer and stronger, and also engage on these other issues, whether it’s Iran’s support for terrorism, its proliferation, its destabilizing support for different proxies throughout the Middle East. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of that does need to be engaged and something we need to deal with, but we’ve been very clear that from our perspective, the first step needs to be a return to mutual compliance.  That’s what we’re working on and that’s where we still don’t know if Iran is willing to say yes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Saudi Arabia says that it now is willing to contemplate better relations with Iran.  Is this a recognition by Saudi Arabia that its strategy so far has not really worked?  Is it a sign that we could see a peace deal in Yemen and we could see an easing of tensions over places like Qatar and Lebanon?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, there needs to be a peace deal in Yemen.  We’re working very hard on that.  We’ve been doing that from day one.  And I think Saudi Arabia has clearly indicated by some of the things that it’s done that it now wants to move in that direction, so that’s very positive.  We need to get the Houthis to come along.  And that, in turn, I think depends significantly on whether Iran is ready to make clear to the Houthis that they need to engage positively and need to resolve this war. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So to the extent that there is a better relationship between Saudi Arabia and Iran, that can produce or help produce at least more positive results in ending some of these other conflicts, ending some of these proxy battles, which are incredibly dangerous, incredibly potentially destabilizing, and have a real human toll.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  And do you see a shift in Saudi foreign policy?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, my sense is that, again, on Yemen in particular, where we’ve engaged intensely – we have a senior envoy who is doing this every single day – the Saudis have been engaged productively in trying to bring this war to an end.  We need to see the same kind of response from the Houthis who continue to hold out, and Iran should use the influence it has to move them in that direction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  You just met with the Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov, and I was wondering:  I mean, this is a country that has, by the acknowledgement of U.S. intelligence, engaged in what is possibly the largest cyber hack of America ever, massed 100,000 troops on Ukraine’s border, and still continues to, in various ways, oppose U.S. interests and – essentially to kind of act as a spoiler on the world stage. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, we had, I think, a constructive, very businesslike conversation over the course of nearly two hours, but President Biden has been very clear with President Putin, and I repeated what President Biden has said to President Putin, to Foreign Minister Lavrov, and that’s this:  We would prefer to have a more stable, predictable relationship with Russia.  We’ve all got lots of things going on around the world and lots of work that we’re trying to do to make the lives of our citizens a little bit better.  A more stable, predictable relationship with them, I think, would be good for us, good for them, and I’d even argue good for the world.  And there are clearly areas where it’s in our mutual interest to find ways to cooperate, whether it’s on Afghanistan, whether it’s on so-called strategic stability, arms control agreements, whether it’s on dealing with climate change. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But equally clear – and the President has been very resolute on this – if Russia continues to take reckless and aggressive actions aimed at us or aimed at our allies and partners, we will respond, not for purposes of escalating, not to seek conflict, but to defend our interests.  And that was the nature of the conversation that I had with Foreign Minister Lavrov.  It’s really important to be very clear about what you’re doing, why you’re doing it.  And ultimately, it is up to Russia to decide whether it wants to have that more predictable, stable relationship.  We need to test the proposition.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you for coming on the show.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks for having me, Fareed.  It’s great to be with you.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Joining me now is the Secretary of State, Antony Blinken.  Welcome, Mr. Secretary.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks, Fareed.  It’s great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  President Biden says that he thinks now that there is a ceasefire in – between the Israelis and Palestinians – there is a significant opportunity for even more positive developments, or a “genuine opportunity,” I think, if I’m quoting him correctly.  And I’m wondering:  Is there really?  I mean, you have an Israeli Government that seems pretty unyielding.  You have a Palestinian Authority led by an 85-year-old man who doesn’t – is too scared to hold elections for fear of what will happen.  Hamas controls Gaza.  Is there really a prospect of some kind of movement towards a genuine political solution?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Fareed, I think there has to be.  I think both sides are reminded that we have to find a way to break the cycle, because if we don’t, it will repeat itself at great cost and at great human suffering on all sides.  Look, we worked very hard with this intense but behind-the-scenes diplomacy to get to the ceasefire, and I think President Biden leading this effort made the judgment that we could be most effective in doing that.  And ultimately, after this intensive effort across the government, we got to where everyone wanted to be, which was to end the violence. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But now, as the President said, I think it’s incumbent upon all of us to try to make the turn to start to build something more positive.  And what that means at heart is that Palestinians and Israelis alike have to know in their day-in and day-out lives equal measures of opportunity, of security, of dignity, something that you touched on in your piece in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Washington Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this week. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Will you use, as a template, the last peace plan put forward by the United States Government that is the peace plan shepherded by Jared Kushner?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, I don’t think we’re at the – in a place where the – getting to some kind of a negotiation for what ultimately, I think, has to be the result, which is a two-state solution, is the first order of business.  We have to start building back in concrete ways and offering some genuine hope, prospects, opportunity in the lives of people. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And of course, in the first instance, we’ve got to deal with the humanitarian situation, which is grave in Gaza.  We’ve got to start to bring countries together to support reconstruction and development.  And as we’re doing that, we’ll be re-engaging with the Palestinians, of course, continuing our deep engagement with the Israelis, and trying to put in place conditions that allow us over time hopefully to advance a genuine peace process.  But that is not the immediate order of business.  We have a lot of work to do to get to that point.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  But does the United States Government still endorse the outlines of that plan?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  We’re going to look at everything that’s been done before, learn from that just as we have in other areas, and see what makes sense and what doesn’t.  But our focus right now relentlessly is on dealing with the humanitarian situation, starting to be – to do reconstruction and rebuild, and engage intensely with everyone, with Palestinians, with Israelis, with partners in the region. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Prime Minister Netanyahu says that he will form a national unity government, but not with any Israeli Arabs in it.  Israeli Arabs, as you know, make up 20 percent of the population of Israel.  Is that a positive step?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, I don’t do politics, whether it’s our politics or Israeli politics.  They have to make their own judgments, and the government will be formed eventually, one way or another.  We leave that to the Israelis.  But we will work with, obviously, the current Israeli Government, whatever government emerges from the current process, and it’s really a decision for Israelis to make, not us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  But you have been very clear in being in favor of democracy and worrying about the decay of democracy in countries.  Is it a step forward for democracy for a national government explicitly, on racial lines, to rule out 20 percent of its population?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, one thing that’s been, I think, deeply disturbing about recent events has been the inter-communal violence.  And that’s something that we have not seen, at least in recent years.  And I believe and I hope that Israelis of all persuasions will find ways to come together to try to make sure that that doesn’t happen again.  And hopefully that finds expression as well in their politics and in their governments.  But again, these are decisions for Israelis to make, not for us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Let me ask you while we’re on the Middle East, Mr. Secretary:  The Biden administration, President Biden when he was campaigning said as soon as I become president, we will rejoin the Iran nuclear deal.  The Iranians said the same thing.  We’re now four months into the administration.  Nothing has happened.  Both sides said there seems to be a – something of a stand-off.  And Iran is meanwhile visibly enriching, the very thing people like you warned about when – again, when Joe Biden was campaigning.  Isn’t this a failure of diplomacy?  Shouldn’t you guys have been able to get back into the deal within a week or two?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Two things, Fareed.  First, I think the steps that Iran is taking underscore the urgency of trying to get Iran back into compliance with its obligations under the nuclear deal, the deal that stopped their – the dangerous aspects of their nuclear program, the prospect that they could have fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  We’ve had, I think, five rounds of conversations now, of talks now, indirect in Vienna.  And in fact, our team’s going back to Vienna in the coming days to pursue that.  I think we’ve actually made progress in clarifying what each side needs to do to get back into full compliance.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The outstanding question, the question that we don’t have an answer to yet, is whether Iran, at the end of the day, is willing to do what is necessary to come back into compliance with the agreement.  That’s the proposition that we’re testing.  But it’s getting, I think, through these rounds of discussions and talks, clearer and clearer what needs to happen.  The question is:  Is Iran prepared to do it?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Well, the Iranians say that that’s actually not what’s happening, what – the United States – the Biden administration has moved the goalposts, that rather than talking about simply both sides getting back to the original deal, doing what was required to comply, the Biden administration is now saying they want to talk about ballistic missiles, they want to talk about regional issues, they want to talk about extending the timeline.  Are you willing to go back to the original deal as it was?  Because the Iranians say they are willing to get back to that tomorrow. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Fareed, we’ve been very clear.  We are fully prepared to go back to the original deal as it was.  That’s our initial objective.  And we – again, we don’t know if the Iranians are.  If we do, if we succeed in that, then we can use that as a foundation both to look at how we can make the deal itself potentially longer and stronger, and also engage on these other issues, whether it’s Iran’s support for terrorism, its proliferation, its destabilizing support for different proxies throughout the Middle East. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of that does need to be engaged and something we need to deal with, but we’ve been very clear that from our perspective, the first step needs to be a return to mutual compliance.  That’s what we’re working on and that’s where we still don’t know if Iran is willing to say yes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Saudi Arabia says that it now is willing to contemplate better relations with Iran.  Is this a recognition by Saudi Arabia that its strategy so far has not really worked?  Is it a sign that we could see a peace deal in Yemen and we could see an easing of tensions over places like Qatar and Lebanon?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, there needs to be a peace deal in Yemen.  We’re working very hard on that.  We’ve been doing that from day one.  And I think Saudi Arabia has clearly indicated by some of the things that it’s done that it now wants to move in that direction, so that’s very positive.  We need to get the Houthis to come along.  And that, in turn, I think depends significantly on whether Iran is ready to make clear to the Houthis that they need to engage positively and need to resolve this war. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So to the extent that there is a better relationship between Saudi Arabia and Iran, that can produce or help produce at least more positive results in ending some of these other conflicts, ending some of these proxy battles, which are incredibly dangerous, incredibly potentially destabilizing, and have a real human toll.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  And do you see a shift in Saudi foreign policy?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, my sense is that, again, on Yemen in particular, where we’ve engaged intensely – we have a senior envoy who is doing this every single day – the Saudis have been engaged productively in trying to bring this war to an end.  We need to see the same kind of response from the Houthis who continue to hold out, and Iran should use the influence it has to move them in that direction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  You just met with the Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov, and I was wondering:  I mean, this is a country that has, by the acknowledgement of U.S. intelligence, engaged in what is possibly the largest cyber hack of America ever, massed 100,000 troops on Ukraine’s border, and still continues to, in various ways, oppose U.S. interests and – essentially to kind of act as a spoiler on the world stage. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, we had, I think, a constructive, very businesslike conversation over the course of nearly two hours, but President Biden has been very clear with President Putin, and I repeated what President Biden has said to President Putin, to Foreign Minister Lavrov, and that’s this:  We would prefer to have a more stable, predictable relationship with Russia.  We’ve all got lots of things going on around the world and lots of work that we’re trying to do to make the lives of our citizens a little bit better.  A more stable, predictable relationship with them, I think, would be good for us, good for them, and I’d even argue good for the world.  And there are clearly areas where it’s in our mutual interest to find ways to cooperate, whether it’s on Afghanistan, whether it’s on so-called strategic stability, arms control agreements, whether it’s on dealing with climate change. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But equally clear – and the President has been very resolute on this – if Russia continues to take reckless and aggressive actions aimed at us or aimed at our allies and partners, we will respond, not for purposes of escalating, not to seek conflict, but to defend our interests.  And that was the nature of the conversation that I had with Foreign Minister Lavrov.  It’s really important to be very clear about what you’re doing, why you’re doing it.  And ultimately, it is up to Russia to decide whether it wants to have that more predictable, stable relationship.  We need to test the proposition.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you for coming on the show.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks for having me, Fareed.  It’s great to be with you.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken On ABC’s This Week with George Stephanopoulos</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-abcs-this-week-with-george-stephanopoulos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.  Welcome to This Week.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s start with the ceasefire.  President Biden pushed it privately, welcomed it publicly.  Both sides are claiming a sort of victory right now, but has anything really changed?  What’s to prevent this cycle of violence from kicking up again, maybe very soon?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, first, George, it was critical to get to the ceasefire, and President Biden’s focus on relentless, determined, but quiet diplomacy is what got us to where we needed to be, which is to get the violence ended as quickly as possible, to stop more human suffering, and to at least put ourselves in position to make a turn, to make a pivot to building something more positive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That has to start now with dealing with the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza, then reconstruction, rebuilding what’s been lost, and, critically, engaging both sides in trying to start to make real improvements in the lives of people so that Israelis and Palestinians can live with equal measures of security, of peace, and of dignity.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You stress that word “equal” right there.  That seems to be a new emphasis for this administration.  We haven’t heard that a lot in the past, equal rights for Palestinians and Israelis.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, it’s vitally important that Palestinians feel hope and have opportunity and can live in security, just as it is for Israelis.  And there should be equal measures.  And in a democratic society, that is, I think, an obligation of the – of any government.  So ultimately, I think that that hope, that security, that dignity can – will be found in a Palestinian state. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But meanwhile, we have to do everything we can both to address the immediate situation, which is humanitarian, reconstruction in Gaza, starting to improve people’s lives in a concrete way, and ultimately get to a place where we can get negotiations and move towards something that brings a lasting resolution to the problem.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you still want to work towards a two-state solution, but is that really still possible?  Is there anything constructive the United States can do?  It doesn’t seem like efforts have created much fruit in the past.  And – or is this new emphasis you’re putting on equal rights really the start of a longer-term shift?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  President Biden’s been very clear that he remains committed to a two-state solution.  Look, ultimately, it is the only way to ensure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, the only way to give the Palestinians the state to which they’re entitled.  That’s where we have to go.  But that, I don’t think, is something for – necessarily for today.  We have to start putting in place the conditions that would allow both sides to engage in a meaningful and positive way toward two states.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first instance, we have to deal with making this turn from the violence – we got the ceasefire – and now deal with the humanitarian situation, deal with reconstruction, and deepen our existing engagement with Palestinians and with Israelis alike.  But the most &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President wants &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I was going to say, George, the most important thing is this:  What I hope that everyone takes from this is that if there isn’t positive change, and particularly if we can’t find a way for – to help Palestinians live with more dignity and with more hope, the cycle’s likely to repeat itself, and that is in no one’s interest.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you want rebuilding; you say you want reconstruction.  The President said he wants to do that without restocking Hamas – rebuilding Gaza without restocking Hamas.  How do you do that?  They’re in charge in Gaza.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Look, we’ve worked in the past and we can continue to work with trusted, independent parties that can help do the reconstruction and the development, not some quasi-governmental authority.  And the fact of the matter is Hamas has brought nothing but ruin to the Palestinian people: its gross mismanagement of Gaza while it’s been in charge, and of course, these indiscriminate rocket attacks on Israeli civilians, which have elicited the response that they did because Israel has a right to defend itself.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I think what’s the real challenge here is to help the Palestinians, and particularly to help moderate Palestinians and the Palestinian Authority deliver better results for their people.  And of course, Israel has a profound role to play in that too.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President reiterated his strong support for Israel on Friday, but he’s coming under increased pressure from progressives.  Bernie Sanders has introduced a resolution of disapproval over a new arms sale to Israel.  Others like Rashida Tlaib and AOC say the U.S. should not be rubber-stamping arms sales to Israel when they use the weapons to abuse Palestinian rights.  What’s your response to that?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, happily, George, one of the things I don’t do in this job is I don’t do politics.  I focus on the policy.  So I’ll leave the politics to others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But here’s what I can say:  We got to the result thanks to President Biden’s relentless focus on this quiet but, I think, effective diplomacy in getting to a ceasefire and stopping the violence in 11 days.  If you go back and look at previous crises, they’ve lasted a lot longer, but of course, every single day that these things go on, we see a tremendous loss in human life and in human suffering.  And we were determined to get – to bring that to an end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to arms sales, two things.  First, the President’s been equally clear:  We are committed to giving Israel the means to defend itself, especially when it comes to these indiscriminate rocket attacks against civilians.  Any country would respond to that, and we – we’re committed to Israel’s defense.  At the same time, any arms sale is going to be done in full consultation with Congress.  We’re committed to that.  And we want to make sure that that process works effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Your administration’s continuing to pursue nuclear negotiations with Iran, but 42 Republican senators have called on the President to end the negotiations, make it clear that sanctions will remain in place because of Iranian funding of Hamas.  Do you believe that Iran is funding Hamas?  And if they are, should the sanctions stay in place?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  George, Iran is engaged in a number of activities, including funding extremist groups, supporting terrorism more broadly, supporting very dangerous proxies that are taking destabilizing actions throughout the Middle East, proliferating weapons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And two things on that.  One, an Iran with a nuclear weapon or with the capability to build one in very short order is going to act with even greater impunity in those areas, which just adds to the urgency of trying to put the nuclear problem back in the box that the nuclear agreement put it in.  And, of course, many of these actions are going forward now while the – and have gone forward over the last few years under the so-called maximum pressure being exerted by the previous administration, and clearly did not get the result that we all seek, which is to curb all of these activities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the first thing that we need to do is put the nuclear problem back in the box.  That’s why we’re committed to trying to see if Iran will come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the so-called JCPOA – that’s what we’re engaged in now – and then use that as a platform to build on and to try to deal with these other issues.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The Iranians say the decision to raise – to lift some of the sanctions has already been made.  Is that true? </span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We’re – we’ve been now over – we’re about to have our, I think, fifth round of discussions in Vienna with the Iranians.  And what these discussions and talks – indirect, as you know – have done is they’ve clarified what each side needs to do in order to come back into compliance.  So we know what sanctions would need to be lifted if they’re inconsistent with the nuclear agreement.  But as important and indeed more important, Iran, I think, knows what it needs to do to come back into compliance on the nuclear side.  And what we haven’t yet seen is whether Iran is ready and willing to make a decision to do what it has to do.  That’s the test and we don’t yet have an answer.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Finally, let’s talk about the North Korea nuclear program.  At his meeting with the South Korean prime minister on Friday, the President said he was prepared to re-engage with the North Koreans under the right conditions.  Right now, the best estimates are that the North Korean nuclear arsenal has doubled in recent years, about 45 weapons right now.  Does the United States have to accept that North Korea will remain a nuclear power?  Do we have to learn to live with a nuclear North Korea?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We don’t and we shouldn’t, but let’s be honest:  This is a hard problem.  Previous administrations, Republican and Democrat alike, have tried to tackle it, and no one’s fully succeeded, to say the least.  In fact, the program has gotten more advanced and more dangerous over time.  And we’ve looked at different approaches that were taken, including basically doing nothing for nothing or trying to do – get everything for everything.  Neither has worked.  We engaged in an intensive review.  We looked at what every previous administration has done.  We consulted very closely with our allies and partners, starting with South Korea and Japan.  I was there with Secretary Austin.  We just had President Moon’s visit.  All of that as well as the view of experts on all sides was factored in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And what President Biden determined was the best chance we have to achieve the objective of the total denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula is to engage diplomatically with North Korea on a deliberate, calibrated approach where we seek to make progress toward that goal.  I don’t think there’s going to be a grand bargain where this gets resolved in one fell swoop.  It’s got to be clearly calibrated diplomacy, clear steps from the North Koreans, and it moves forward in that way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, we put that forward.  We’re waiting to see if Pyongyang actually wants to engage.  The ball’s in their court.  We’ve made clear we’re prepared to pursue this diplomatically even as the sanctions remain in place because North Korea continues to engage in activities that are clearly prohibited by the United Nations.  But we’re prepared to do the diplomacy.  The question is:  Is North Korea? </span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Secretary Blinken, thanks for your time this morning.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.  Welcome to This Week.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s start with the ceasefire.  President Biden pushed it privately, welcomed it publicly.  Both sides are claiming a sort of victory right now, but has anything really changed?  What’s to prevent this cycle of violence from kicking up again, maybe very soon?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, first, George, it was critical to get to the ceasefire, and President Biden’s focus on relentless, determined, but quiet diplomacy is what got us to where we needed to be, which is to get the violence ended as quickly as possible, to stop more human suffering, and to at least put ourselves in position to make a turn, to make a pivot to building something more positive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That has to start now with dealing with the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza, then reconstruction, rebuilding what’s been lost, and, critically, engaging both sides in trying to start to make real improvements in the lives of people so that Israelis and Palestinians can live with equal measures of security, of peace, and of dignity.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You stress that word “equal” right there.  That seems to be a new emphasis for this administration.  We haven’t heard that a lot in the past, equal rights for Palestinians and Israelis.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, it’s vitally important that Palestinians feel hope and have opportunity and can live in security, just as it is for Israelis.  And there should be equal measures.  And in a democratic society, that is, I think, an obligation of the – of any government.  So ultimately, I think that that hope, that security, that dignity can – will be found in a Palestinian state. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But meanwhile, we have to do everything we can both to address the immediate situation, which is humanitarian, reconstruction in Gaza, starting to improve people’s lives in a concrete way, and ultimately get to a place where we can get negotiations and move towards something that brings a lasting resolution to the problem.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you still want to work towards a two-state solution, but is that really still possible?  Is there anything constructive the United States can do?  It doesn’t seem like efforts have created much fruit in the past.  And – or is this new emphasis you’re putting on equal rights really the start of a longer-term shift?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  President Biden’s been very clear that he remains committed to a two-state solution.  Look, ultimately, it is the only way to ensure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, the only way to give the Palestinians the state to which they’re entitled.  That’s where we have to go.  But that, I don’t think, is something for – necessarily for today.  We have to start putting in place the conditions that would allow both sides to engage in a meaningful and positive way toward two states.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first instance, we have to deal with making this turn from the violence – we got the ceasefire – and now deal with the humanitarian situation, deal with reconstruction, and deepen our existing engagement with Palestinians and with Israelis alike.  But the most &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President wants &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I was going to say, George, the most important thing is this:  What I hope that everyone takes from this is that if there isn’t positive change, and particularly if we can’t find a way for – to help Palestinians live with more dignity and with more hope, the cycle’s likely to repeat itself, and that is in no one’s interest.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you want rebuilding; you say you want reconstruction.  The President said he wants to do that without restocking Hamas – rebuilding Gaza without restocking Hamas.  How do you do that?  They’re in charge in Gaza.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Look, we’ve worked in the past and we can continue to work with trusted, independent parties that can help do the reconstruction and the development, not some quasi-governmental authority.  And the fact of the matter is Hamas has brought nothing but ruin to the Palestinian people: its gross mismanagement of Gaza while it’s been in charge, and of course, these indiscriminate rocket attacks on Israeli civilians, which have elicited the response that they did because Israel has a right to defend itself.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I think what’s the real challenge here is to help the Palestinians, and particularly to help moderate Palestinians and the Palestinian Authority deliver better results for their people.  And of course, Israel has a profound role to play in that too.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President reiterated his strong support for Israel on Friday, but he’s coming under increased pressure from progressives.  Bernie Sanders has introduced a resolution of disapproval over a new arms sale to Israel.  Others like Rashida Tlaib and AOC say the U.S. should not be rubber-stamping arms sales to Israel when they use the weapons to abuse Palestinian rights.  What’s your response to that?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, happily, George, one of the things I don’t do in this job is I don’t do politics.  I focus on the policy.  So I’ll leave the politics to others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But here’s what I can say:  We got to the result thanks to President Biden’s relentless focus on this quiet but, I think, effective diplomacy in getting to a ceasefire and stopping the violence in 11 days.  If you go back and look at previous crises, they’ve lasted a lot longer, but of course, every single day that these things go on, we see a tremendous loss in human life and in human suffering.  And we were determined to get – to bring that to an end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to arms sales, two things.  First, the President’s been equally clear:  We are committed to giving Israel the means to defend itself, especially when it comes to these indiscriminate rocket attacks against civilians.  Any country would respond to that, and we – we’re committed to Israel’s defense.  At the same time, any arms sale is going to be done in full consultation with Congress.  We’re committed to that.  And we want to make sure that that process works effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Your administration’s continuing to pursue nuclear negotiations with Iran, but 42 Republican senators have called on the President to end the negotiations, make it clear that sanctions will remain in place because of Iranian funding of Hamas.  Do you believe that Iran is funding Hamas?  And if they are, should the sanctions stay in place?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  George, Iran is engaged in a number of activities, including funding extremist groups, supporting terrorism more broadly, supporting very dangerous proxies that are taking destabilizing actions throughout the Middle East, proliferating weapons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And two things on that.  One, an Iran with a nuclear weapon or with the capability to build one in very short order is going to act with even greater impunity in those areas, which just adds to the urgency of trying to put the nuclear problem back in the box that the nuclear agreement put it in.  And, of course, many of these actions are going forward now while the – and have gone forward over the last few years under the so-called maximum pressure being exerted by the previous administration, and clearly did not get the result that we all seek, which is to curb all of these activities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the first thing that we need to do is put the nuclear problem back in the box.  That’s why we’re committed to trying to see if Iran will come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the so-called JCPOA – that’s what we’re engaged in now – and then use that as a platform to build on and to try to deal with these other issues.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The Iranians say the decision to raise – to lift some of the sanctions has already been made.  Is that true? </span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We’re – we’ve been now over – we’re about to have our, I think, fifth round of discussions in Vienna with the Iranians.  And what these discussions and talks – indirect, as you know – have done is they’ve clarified what each side needs to do in order to come back into compliance.  So we know what sanctions would need to be lifted if they’re inconsistent with the nuclear agreement.  But as important and indeed more important, Iran, I think, knows what it needs to do to come back into compliance on the nuclear side.  And what we haven’t yet seen is whether Iran is ready and willing to make a decision to do what it has to do.  That’s the test and we don’t yet have an answer.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Finally, let’s talk about the North Korea nuclear program.  At his meeting with the South Korean prime minister on Friday, the President said he was prepared to re-engage with the North Koreans under the right conditions.  Right now, the best estimates are that the North Korean nuclear arsenal has doubled in recent years, about 45 weapons right now.  Does the United States have to accept that North Korea will remain a nuclear power?  Do we have to learn to live with a nuclear North Korea?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We don’t and we shouldn’t, but let’s be honest:  This is a hard problem.  Previous administrations, Republican and Democrat alike, have tried to tackle it, and no one’s fully succeeded, to say the least.  In fact, the program has gotten more advanced and more dangerous over time.  And we’ve looked at different approaches that were taken, including basically doing nothing for nothing or trying to do – get everything for everything.  Neither has worked.  We engaged in an intensive review.  We looked at what every previous administration has done.  We consulted very closely with our allies and partners, starting with South Korea and Japan.  I was there with Secretary Austin.  We just had President Moon’s visit.  All of that as well as the view of experts on all sides was factored in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And what President Biden determined was the best chance we have to achieve the objective of the total denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula is to engage diplomatically with North Korea on a deliberate, calibrated approach where we seek to make progress toward that goal.  I don’t think there’s going to be a grand bargain where this gets resolved in one fell swoop.  It’s got to be clearly calibrated diplomacy, clear steps from the North Koreans, and it moves forward in that way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, we put that forward.  We’re waiting to see if Pyongyang actually wants to engage.  The ball’s in their court.  We’ve made clear we’re prepared to pursue this diplomatically even as the sanctions remain in place because North Korea continues to engage in activities that are clearly prohibited by the United Nations.  But we’re prepared to do the diplomacy.  The question is:  Is North Korea? </span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Secretary Blinken, thanks for your time this morning.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yemen National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/yemen-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer bests wishes to the people of Yemen on the occasion of your 31st National Unity Day.  The United States appreciates the Republic of Yemen Government’s ongoing commitments towards achieving peace in Yemen.</p>
<p>An inclusive and lasting resolution of this conflict is a top priority for the United States.  I look forward to the continued engagement between our countries and other partners to achieve peace, and I affirm our commitment to helping bring about a prosperous future for all Yemenis.  May you enjoy a celebratory National Unity Day.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer bests wishes to the people of Yemen on the occasion of your 31st National Unity Day.  The United States appreciates the Republic of Yemen Government’s ongoing commitments towards achieving peace in Yemen.</p>
<p>An inclusive and lasting resolution of this conflict is a top priority for the United States.  I look forward to the continued engagement between our countries and other partners to achieve peace, and I affirm our commitment to helping bring about a prosperous future for all Yemenis.  May you enjoy a celebratory National Unity Day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Turkish Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-turkish-foreign-minister-cavusoglu-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 23:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlüt Çavuşoğlu today. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu discussed the importance of cooperation between the United States and Turkey, including our shared interests in Syria and Afghanistan. The Secretary noted continuing U.S. support for talks between NATO Allies Turkey and Greece and emphasized the importance of promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlüt Çavuşoğlu today. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu discussed the importance of cooperation between the United States and Turkey, including our shared interests in Syria and Afghanistan. The Secretary noted continuing U.S. support for talks between NATO Allies Turkey and Greece and emphasized the importance of promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling for a Civilian-Led Transition of Power to a Democratically Elected Government in Chad</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/calling-for-a-civilian-led-transition-of-power-to-a-democratically-elected-government-in-chad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 23:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States supports the recommendations of the African Union Peace and Security Council regarding Chad, and we join the African Union and our international partners in calling for a peaceful, timely, and civilian-led transition of power to a democratically elected government before October 2022.</p>
<p>The Chadian people deserve an inclusive national dialogue where all stakeholders can come together to decide the future of their country. Chad’s political transition should include a new national constitution, a concrete plan and timeline for elections, and support for strong institutions such as a representative National Assembly, an independent judicial system, and a reformed National Independent Electoral Commission. A representative, democratically elected government is the best path to long-term prosperity and stability in Chad and the region.</p>
<p>The United States has long stood with the people of Chad in advocating for democratic, representative government, and we will continue to support the people of Chad, the African Union, and our international partners in advocating for a timely transition to elected, civilian government.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States supports the recommendations of the African Union Peace and Security Council regarding Chad, and we join the African Union and our international partners in calling for a peaceful, timely, and civilian-led transition of power to a democratically elected government before October 2022.</p>
<p>The Chadian people deserve an inclusive national dialogue where all stakeholders can come together to decide the future of their country. Chad’s political transition should include a new national constitution, a concrete plan and timeline for elections, and support for strong institutions such as a representative National Assembly, an independent judicial system, and a reformed National Independent Electoral Commission. A representative, democratically elected government is the best path to long-term prosperity and stability in Chad and the region.</p>
<p>The United States has long stood with the people of Chad in advocating for democratic, representative government, and we will continue to support the people of Chad, the African Union, and our international partners in advocating for a timely transition to elected, civilian government.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Palestinian Authority President Abbas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-palestinian-authority-president-abbas-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas. The Secretary and President welcomed the ceasefire and discussed measures to ensure that it holds. The Secretary underscored the U.S. commitment to working with the Palestinian Authority and the United Nations to provide rapid humanitarian assistance and to marshal international support for Gaza and Gaza reconstruction efforts. The Secretary and President expressed their appreciation for Egypt’s mediation efforts and committed to retaining open lines of communication at all levels. The President welcomed Secretary Blinken&#8217;s planned travel to the region, where the Secretary will meet with Palestinian, Israeli, and regional counterparts to discuss relief efforts and working together to build better futures for Palestinians and Israelis.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas. The Secretary and President welcomed the ceasefire and discussed measures to ensure that it holds. The Secretary underscored the U.S. commitment to working with the Palestinian Authority and the United Nations to provide rapid humanitarian assistance and to marshal international support for Gaza and Gaza reconstruction efforts. The Secretary and President expressed their appreciation for Egypt’s mediation efforts and committed to retaining open lines of communication at all levels. The President welcomed Secretary Blinken&#8217;s planned travel to the region, where the Secretary will meet with Palestinian, Israeli, and regional counterparts to discuss relief efforts and working together to build better futures for Palestinians and Israelis.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inaugural U.S.-Lebanon Defense Resourcing Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/inaugural-u-s-lebanon-defense-resourcing-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 16:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State and the Lebanese Armed Forces held their inaugural Defense Resourcing Conference on May 21, 2021.  Senior Official for Arms Control and International Security C.S. Eliot Kang headed the U.S. delegation and Lebanese Armed Forces (LAF) Commander General Joseph Aoun headed the Lebanese delegation.  Other U.S. participants included Acting Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs Mara Karlin, U.S. Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Regional Security and Security Assistance Mira Resnick, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Levant Affairs Aimee Cutrona, and representatives from the Office of the Secretary of Defense and the Defense Security Cooperation Agency.</p>
<p>In this virtual conference, the delegations highlighted the strength of the U.S.-LAF partnership and discussed ways to deepen security cooperation.  Participants commemorated the completion of a non-binding five-year security assistance roadmap that aligns anticipated annual U.S. support to the LAF with shared priorities in counterterrorism, border security, and defense institution building, which will enable effective joint planning for future defense requirements.</p>
<p>The delegations discussed the deteriorating economic, political, and humanitarian conditions affecting the Lebanese people and military.  The U.S. Department of State renewed its commitment to the LAF by announcing $120 million in Foreign Military Financing (FMF) assistance to Lebanon for fiscal year 2021, subject to Congressional notification procedures, representing a $15 million increase over prior-year levels.  Lebanon is one of the largest recipients globally of U.S. Department of State security assistance.</p>
<p>The delegations also discussed ways to leverage the full range of authorities under U.S. law through which the United States can provide additional assistance to the LAF as it grapples with the economic crises in Lebanon.  Earlier this month, for instance, the U.S. Department of Defense notified Lebanon of the planned transfer of three Protector-class patrol boats to the Lebanese Navy, which, upon delivery in 2022, will enhance the Lebanese Navy’s ability to counter external and regional threats, and protect freedom of navigation and commerce in the maritime domain.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State looks forward to reviewing progress on the U.S.-LAF partnership at the next Defense Resourcing Conference in 2022.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State and the Lebanese Armed Forces held their inaugural Defense Resourcing Conference on May 21, 2021.  Senior Official for Arms Control and International Security C.S. Eliot Kang headed the U.S. delegation and Lebanese Armed Forces (LAF) Commander General Joseph Aoun headed the Lebanese delegation.  Other U.S. participants included Acting Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs Mara Karlin, U.S. Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Regional Security and Security Assistance Mira Resnick, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Levant Affairs Aimee Cutrona, and representatives from the Office of the Secretary of Defense and the Defense Security Cooperation Agency.</p>
<p>In this virtual conference, the delegations highlighted the strength of the U.S.-LAF partnership and discussed ways to deepen security cooperation.  Participants commemorated the completion of a non-binding five-year security assistance roadmap that aligns anticipated annual U.S. support to the LAF with shared priorities in counterterrorism, border security, and defense institution building, which will enable effective joint planning for future defense requirements.</p>
<p>The delegations discussed the deteriorating economic, political, and humanitarian conditions affecting the Lebanese people and military.  The U.S. Department of State renewed its commitment to the LAF by announcing $120 million in Foreign Military Financing (FMF) assistance to Lebanon for fiscal year 2021, subject to Congressional notification procedures, representing a $15 million increase over prior-year levels.  Lebanon is one of the largest recipients globally of U.S. Department of State security assistance.</p>
<p>The delegations also discussed ways to leverage the full range of authorities under U.S. law through which the United States can provide additional assistance to the LAF as it grapples with the economic crises in Lebanon.  Earlier this month, for instance, the U.S. Department of Defense notified Lebanon of the planned transfer of three Protector-class patrol boats to the Lebanese Navy, which, upon delivery in 2022, will enhance the Lebanese Navy’s ability to counter external and regional threats, and protect freedom of navigation and commerce in the maritime domain.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State looks forward to reviewing progress on the U.S.-LAF partnership at the next Defense Resourcing Conference in 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
