<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 16:33:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The United States Takes Further Actions against the Burmese Military Regime</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-takes-further-actions-against-the-burmese-military-regime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>In response to the brutal campaign of violence perpetrated by the Burmese military regime and to continue imposing costs in connection with the military coup, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Assets Control is designating today 22 individuals connected to the regime, pursuant to Executive Order 14014 “Blocking Property With Respect to the Situation in Burma.” These include three additional State Administration Council (SAC) members and four military-appointed cabinet members, as well as 15 adult children or spouses of previously designated Burmese military officials whose financial networks have contributed to military officials’ ill-gotten gains.</p>
<p>In addition, the U.S. Department of Commerce is adding Wanbao Mining, Ltd., two of its subsidiaries, and King Royal Technologies to its Entity List.  These entities provide revenue and/or other support to the Burmese military, and Wanbao Mining and its subsidiaries have long been implicated in labor rights violations and human rights abuses, including at the Letpadaung copper mine.</p>
<p>Today’s measures further demonstrate that we will continue to take additional action against, and impose costs on, the military and its leaders until they reverse course and provide for a return to democracy.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to promoting accountability for the Burmese military, the SAC, and all those who have provided support for the military coup. The United States will continue to urge the Burmese military to fully cooperate in expeditious implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus, and immediately restore Burma’s path to democracy.  The United States will remain a steadfast advocate for the people of Burma’s ability to determine the future of their country.</p>
<p>For more information about today’s action, see Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0260" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release </span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and Commerce’s <a class="external-link" href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/07/commerce-increases-restrictions-burmese-military-adding-four-entities" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>In response to the brutal campaign of violence perpetrated by the Burmese military regime and to continue imposing costs in connection with the military coup, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Assets Control is designating today 22 individuals connected to the regime, pursuant to Executive Order 14014 “Blocking Property With Respect to the Situation in Burma.” These include three additional State Administration Council (SAC) members and four military-appointed cabinet members, as well as 15 adult children or spouses of previously designated Burmese military officials whose financial networks have contributed to military officials’ ill-gotten gains.</p>
<p>In addition, the U.S. Department of Commerce is adding Wanbao Mining, Ltd., two of its subsidiaries, and King Royal Technologies to its Entity List.  These entities provide revenue and/or other support to the Burmese military, and Wanbao Mining and its subsidiaries have long been implicated in labor rights violations and human rights abuses, including at the Letpadaung copper mine.</p>
<p>Today’s measures further demonstrate that we will continue to take additional action against, and impose costs on, the military and its leaders until they reverse course and provide for a return to democracy.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to promoting accountability for the Burmese military, the SAC, and all those who have provided support for the military coup. The United States will continue to urge the Burmese military to fully cooperate in expeditious implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus, and immediately restore Burma’s path to democracy.  The United States will remain a steadfast advocate for the people of Burma’s ability to determine the future of their country.</p>
<p>For more information about today’s action, see Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0260" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release </span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and Commerce’s <a class="external-link" href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/07/commerce-increases-restrictions-burmese-military-adding-four-entities" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Schedule &#8211; July 2, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-schedule-july-2-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                    ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND </u></strong></p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>ACTING ASSISTANT SECRETARY FOR EUROPEAN AND EURASIAN AFFAIRS PHILIP T. REEKER </u></strong></p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker is on travel to Ohrid, North Macedonia, from July 1-3, 2021. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-reekers-travel-to-italy-albania-and-north-macedonia/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE </u></strong></p>
<p>No Department Press Briefing</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                    ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND </u></strong></p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>ACTING ASSISTANT SECRETARY FOR EUROPEAN AND EURASIAN AFFAIRS PHILIP T. REEKER </u></strong></p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker is on travel to Ohrid, North Macedonia, from July 1-3, 2021. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-reekers-travel-to-italy-albania-and-north-macedonia/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE </u></strong></p>
<p>No Department Press Briefing</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Eighth U.S.-Tajikistan Annual Bilateral Consultations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-eighth-u-s-tajikistan-annual-bilateral-consultations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The State Department hosted Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin and a delegation from the Government of Tajikistan for the eighth U.S.-Tajikistan Annual Bilateral Consultations on July 1, following 30 years of bilateral partnership between the United States and Tajikistan.</p>
<p>The United States delegation, led by Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs Dean Thompson, reiterated the United States’ commitment to Tajikistan’s independence, sovereignty, and prosperity and cited our shared goal of a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan. The delegations discussed issues related to security and law enforcement, human rights, and energy and the economy.  Participants affirmed their countries&#8217; commitments to jointly address regional security threats, cooperate on efforts to counter terrorism, and professionalize security services.  Officials discussed opportunities for advancing mutual goals to promote religious freedom and combat trafficking in persons.  The delegations also discussed joint initiatives to increase regional connectivity and improve bilateral trade and investment opportunities.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The State Department hosted Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin and a delegation from the Government of Tajikistan for the eighth U.S.-Tajikistan Annual Bilateral Consultations on July 1, following 30 years of bilateral partnership between the United States and Tajikistan.</p>
<p>The United States delegation, led by Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs Dean Thompson, reiterated the United States’ commitment to Tajikistan’s independence, sovereignty, and prosperity and cited our shared goal of a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan. The delegations discussed issues related to security and law enforcement, human rights, and energy and the economy.  Participants affirmed their countries&#8217; commitments to jointly address regional security threats, cooperate on efforts to counter terrorism, and professionalize security services.  Officials discussed opportunities for advancing mutual goals to promote religious freedom and combat trafficking in persons.  The delegations also discussed joint initiatives to increase regional connectivity and improve bilateral trade and investment opportunities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga On Release of the Section 353 Report (aka Corrupt Actors List)</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-envoy-for-the-northern-triangle-ricardo-zuniga-on-release-of-the-section-353-report-aka-corrupt-actors-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much, and thanks very much for joining us, everyone.  We wanted to take a moment to offer a bit of context on what you saw from Secretary Blinken earlier today.  As you saw, we transmitted to Congress and released publicly our Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List.</p>
<p>We have joining us today Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga, who will offer some remarks at the top of the call and who will then look forward to taking your questions on today’s report.</p>
<p>So without further ado, I’ll offer a reminder that this call is embargoed until its conclusion, but I will then turn it over to Ricardo to get us started.  Over to you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Ned, thank you very much.  So thank all of you for joining us today for this briefing.  As the White House recently emphasized, combating corruption is a U.S. national security priority.  As you know, President Biden and Vice President Harris are very focused on leveraging their experience – years of experience – in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, and these two topics come together very closely in that part of the world because corruption and attacks on democracy are viewed as some of the most important root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  They hobble governance, they distort markets, they undercut development efforts, and ultimately, they demoralize a population that decides to embark on a very dangerous irregular migration to Mexico and the United States because they don’t believe they can build their futures at home.</p>
<p>Today the Secretary of State announced the transmittal to Congress of the Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List, a report required by Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act.  So this report lists individuals from Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador who have undermined democratic processes or institutions, engaged in significant corruption, or who have obstructed investigations into such acts.</p>
<p>So these efforts are very much in support of the people of Central America.  The citizens of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador have consistently repudiated corruption, demanded accountability from their governments and private actors, and acted in defense of democratic institutions.  Unfortunately, all too often corruption and abuse from office go unpunished even though they are often investigated by public servants who are attempting to complete their work.  The United States stands with Central American citizens, organizations, and public servants who are committed to promoting the public good.</p>
<p>We’re committed to generating opportunity and hope among the people of the region in the face of attacks on democratic institutions and setbacks on the rule of law and efforts to combat impunity.  So we will use the full range of tools, including actions like this one provided by Congress, to shine a light on corruption and encourage the strengthening of democratic institutions to make life better for our neighbors in Central America.</p>
<p>So with that, I’ll take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Wonderful.  Operator, if you want to repeat the instructions for asking a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  Once again, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1, then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Ted Hesson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It’s Ted Hesson with Reuters.  One thing we noticed with this list of actors is there didn’t seem to be too many officials who were involved or allegedly involved in narco-crimes, and specifically with Guatemala’s UCN party.  And we were wondering why that was, if there was a reason for it, and what your response is to that.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So, there was no effort to exclude people who were involved in narco-trafficking, and in fact, some of the people who were listed do have some affiliation with either trafficking or with criminal organizations.  This is – this list is one of a variety of tools that we have available for providing accountability for corruption and undemocratic actions.  It’s also not a final list.  This is an initial list provided in response to the congressional mandate.  It’s required at least once a year, so we will use this and other tools to highlight people who are involved either in corrupt acts or in obstructing the democratic process, or perhaps we can use other tools as well to highlight people who are involved in organized crime.  So this is – this list is not exclusive of that, and there certainly was no effort to exclude people who were potentially involved in organized crime activity.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Chris Sherman.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, good afternoon.  Thank you.  This piggybacks a bit on Ted’s question.  But obviously, this could always be a longer list, and you said this was just the initial one, but can you speak at all to how the line was drawn at where these are?  Obviously, there are some people in the region.  You had expected to see some other names on there.  Can you talk about how it was composed?</p>
<p>And in terms of (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; is that just an initial step?  Could there be harsher sanctions for these people?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So I’ll start with the second part first.  And yes, the action that we take under this authority does not exclude other sanctions, and in fact, a number of the people who are on this list have been the subject of other measures by – from the United States, including by the Department of State, to hold them accountable.</p>
<p>The list was prepared based on an extensive review of credible information that we had that was both classified and unclassified information pertaining to the known engagement in acts that undermine democratic processes or institutions who are involved in significant corruption or in obstruction into investigation into such acts of corruption.  We vetted those names.  There was more of a focus on – because this list is intended to both identify people involved in these actions and to dissuade future activity, certainly there was more attention to more recent cases where we had more recent information and for people who were either currently involved in government or near or were in positions of influence to demonstrate that that’s – this is our area of focus.</p>
<p>As you said, this is not a – we don’t view this as the end of the action but as an initial response to the request from Congress.  We are also considering if additional actions will be taken based on information we developed during the – during our – the organization of this list.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Rafael Bernal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you for having this.  I guess that they asked a couple questions that I had, but I noticed in the Salvadoran list you have a couple of actors here who allegedly engaged with the Chinese in inappropriate behaviors.  What’s the message that you want to give Central American, at least government officials, et cetera, on their engagement with other world powers that might be wanting to move in into the region, particularly China and Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So the real message there as it relates to this list is that it’s the type of activity that we’re targeting.  If there’s corruption around efforts to build influence, certainly that is something that is going to get a great deal of scrutiny.</p>
<p>But again, it has to do, in the case of this list, with the act of – acting corruptly to obtain or to act on behalf of another actor.  And certainly there – in the cases that you cite, there was concern, very much concern at the time expressed by people in El Salvador and which United States echoed, regarding the use of corruption to try to expand the influence in a commercial deal.  And that is very much at issue.</p>
<p>We certainly are aware of there being the real line between normal economic competition and competition that is undermined by the use of purchasing influence or by suborning actors inside of Central America to act on behalf of – well, really any power should – those are all of great concern to us.</p>
<p>So one thing is the normal economic competition that you would have, and the other is actions that are corrupt and that are in – on behalf of an external actor that seeks to build influence that way.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go the line of Matthew Russell Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks a lot.  And thanks, thanks for doing the call.  I wanted to ask about Honduras.  In looking at the list, you have former President Pepe Lobo, you have current Congressman Oscar Najera, and you mention this <em>Cachiros</em>.  But being here in the Southern District of New York court and covering the trials of the brother of the current president and of Geovanny Fuentes Ramirez, it’s clear that President Juan Orlando Hernandez is mentioned repeatedly by Department of Justice prosecutors as not only getting campaign contributions from drug traffickers but perhaps being involved in it himself.  So I’m wondering:  On this specific case, can you say what the reasoning is of not having him on the list?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So for questions about U.S. criminal prosecutions, we obviously refer you to the Department of Justice.  We do – this list is intended to demonstrate that we have a commitment to the rule of law and to fighting impunity in Honduras.  We’ve made that clear in our communications with governments across the region, including Honduras, and we’ve made clear that leaders who seek a close relationship with the United States have to demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p>We use, again, a variety of tools for promoting accountability and combating impunity.  This is one – this list is one of several tools that we use for that purpose.  We do work with other actors in Honduras in government, in civil society, in private sector, and – but again, our primary commitment is to leaders who demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, it looks like we’ve exhausted the questions in queue unless anyone else wishes to jump in.  I want to thank our speaker, Special Envoy Zuniga, for spending some time with us today.  And thank you to everyone who called in, and we look forward to speaking with you soon.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>Thank you very much, Ned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much, and thanks very much for joining us, everyone.  We wanted to take a moment to offer a bit of context on what you saw from Secretary Blinken earlier today.  As you saw, we transmitted to Congress and released publicly our Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List.</p>
<p>We have joining us today Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga, who will offer some remarks at the top of the call and who will then look forward to taking your questions on today’s report.</p>
<p>So without further ado, I’ll offer a reminder that this call is embargoed until its conclusion, but I will then turn it over to Ricardo to get us started.  Over to you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Ned, thank you very much.  So thank all of you for joining us today for this briefing.  As the White House recently emphasized, combating corruption is a U.S. national security priority.  As you know, President Biden and Vice President Harris are very focused on leveraging their experience – years of experience – in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, and these two topics come together very closely in that part of the world because corruption and attacks on democracy are viewed as some of the most important root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  They hobble governance, they distort markets, they undercut development efforts, and ultimately, they demoralize a population that decides to embark on a very dangerous irregular migration to Mexico and the United States because they don’t believe they can build their futures at home.</p>
<p>Today the Secretary of State announced the transmittal to Congress of the Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List, a report required by Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act.  So this report lists individuals from Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador who have undermined democratic processes or institutions, engaged in significant corruption, or who have obstructed investigations into such acts.</p>
<p>So these efforts are very much in support of the people of Central America.  The citizens of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador have consistently repudiated corruption, demanded accountability from their governments and private actors, and acted in defense of democratic institutions.  Unfortunately, all too often corruption and abuse from office go unpunished even though they are often investigated by public servants who are attempting to complete their work.  The United States stands with Central American citizens, organizations, and public servants who are committed to promoting the public good.</p>
<p>We’re committed to generating opportunity and hope among the people of the region in the face of attacks on democratic institutions and setbacks on the rule of law and efforts to combat impunity.  So we will use the full range of tools, including actions like this one provided by Congress, to shine a light on corruption and encourage the strengthening of democratic institutions to make life better for our neighbors in Central America.</p>
<p>So with that, I’ll take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Wonderful.  Operator, if you want to repeat the instructions for asking a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  Once again, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1, then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Ted Hesson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It’s Ted Hesson with Reuters.  One thing we noticed with this list of actors is there didn’t seem to be too many officials who were involved or allegedly involved in narco-crimes, and specifically with Guatemala’s UCN party.  And we were wondering why that was, if there was a reason for it, and what your response is to that.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So, there was no effort to exclude people who were involved in narco-trafficking, and in fact, some of the people who were listed do have some affiliation with either trafficking or with criminal organizations.  This is – this list is one of a variety of tools that we have available for providing accountability for corruption and undemocratic actions.  It’s also not a final list.  This is an initial list provided in response to the congressional mandate.  It’s required at least once a year, so we will use this and other tools to highlight people who are involved either in corrupt acts or in obstructing the democratic process, or perhaps we can use other tools as well to highlight people who are involved in organized crime.  So this is – this list is not exclusive of that, and there certainly was no effort to exclude people who were potentially involved in organized crime activity.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Chris Sherman.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, good afternoon.  Thank you.  This piggybacks a bit on Ted’s question.  But obviously, this could always be a longer list, and you said this was just the initial one, but can you speak at all to how the line was drawn at where these are?  Obviously, there are some people in the region.  You had expected to see some other names on there.  Can you talk about how it was composed?</p>
<p>And in terms of (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; is that just an initial step?  Could there be harsher sanctions for these people?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So I’ll start with the second part first.  And yes, the action that we take under this authority does not exclude other sanctions, and in fact, a number of the people who are on this list have been the subject of other measures by – from the United States, including by the Department of State, to hold them accountable.</p>
<p>The list was prepared based on an extensive review of credible information that we had that was both classified and unclassified information pertaining to the known engagement in acts that undermine democratic processes or institutions who are involved in significant corruption or in obstruction into investigation into such acts of corruption.  We vetted those names.  There was more of a focus on – because this list is intended to both identify people involved in these actions and to dissuade future activity, certainly there was more attention to more recent cases where we had more recent information and for people who were either currently involved in government or near or were in positions of influence to demonstrate that that’s – this is our area of focus.</p>
<p>As you said, this is not a – we don’t view this as the end of the action but as an initial response to the request from Congress.  We are also considering if additional actions will be taken based on information we developed during the – during our – the organization of this list.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Rafael Bernal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you for having this.  I guess that they asked a couple questions that I had, but I noticed in the Salvadoran list you have a couple of actors here who allegedly engaged with the Chinese in inappropriate behaviors.  What’s the message that you want to give Central American, at least government officials, et cetera, on their engagement with other world powers that might be wanting to move in into the region, particularly China and Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So the real message there as it relates to this list is that it’s the type of activity that we’re targeting.  If there’s corruption around efforts to build influence, certainly that is something that is going to get a great deal of scrutiny.</p>
<p>But again, it has to do, in the case of this list, with the act of – acting corruptly to obtain or to act on behalf of another actor.  And certainly there – in the cases that you cite, there was concern, very much concern at the time expressed by people in El Salvador and which United States echoed, regarding the use of corruption to try to expand the influence in a commercial deal.  And that is very much at issue.</p>
<p>We certainly are aware of there being the real line between normal economic competition and competition that is undermined by the use of purchasing influence or by suborning actors inside of Central America to act on behalf of – well, really any power should – those are all of great concern to us.</p>
<p>So one thing is the normal economic competition that you would have, and the other is actions that are corrupt and that are in – on behalf of an external actor that seeks to build influence that way.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go the line of Matthew Russell Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks a lot.  And thanks, thanks for doing the call.  I wanted to ask about Honduras.  In looking at the list, you have former President Pepe Lobo, you have current Congressman Oscar Najera, and you mention this <em>Cachiros</em>.  But being here in the Southern District of New York court and covering the trials of the brother of the current president and of Geovanny Fuentes Ramirez, it’s clear that President Juan Orlando Hernandez is mentioned repeatedly by Department of Justice prosecutors as not only getting campaign contributions from drug traffickers but perhaps being involved in it himself.  So I’m wondering:  On this specific case, can you say what the reasoning is of not having him on the list?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So for questions about U.S. criminal prosecutions, we obviously refer you to the Department of Justice.  We do – this list is intended to demonstrate that we have a commitment to the rule of law and to fighting impunity in Honduras.  We’ve made that clear in our communications with governments across the region, including Honduras, and we’ve made clear that leaders who seek a close relationship with the United States have to demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p>We use, again, a variety of tools for promoting accountability and combating impunity.  This is one – this list is one of several tools that we use for that purpose.  We do work with other actors in Honduras in government, in civil society, in private sector, and – but again, our primary commitment is to leaders who demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, it looks like we’ve exhausted the questions in queue unless anyone else wishes to jump in.  I want to thank our speaker, Special Envoy Zuniga, for spending some time with us today.  And thank you to everyone who called in, and we look forward to speaking with you soon.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>Thank you very much, Ned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 1, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-1-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=256888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:49 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon.  Very good to see everyone.  It has been too long.  Looking forward to spending more time in this briefing room this month, in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Today, obviously, is a very important day here at the Department of State.  As you have seen and as you heard from Secretary Blinken, we rolled out the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report.  I am very pleased that we have joining us at the top of the briefing today Dr. Kari Johnstone.  She is the acting director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.  She will have some remarks, and then she’ll be happy to take your questions before we move on to our regularly scheduled program.</p>
<p>So without ado, Dr. Johnstone.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Thank you very much, Ned, and good afternoon to all of you.  I am pleased to be here with you.  Earlier today, Secretary Blinken released the State Department’s 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report, or the TIP Report, which examines governments’ efforts to combat human trafficking using a 3P framework of prosecuting traffickers, protecting victims, and preventing the crime.  This report reflects the U.S. Government’s commitment to global leadership on this key human rights, law enforcement, and national security issue.  It remains our principal diplomatic and diagnostic tool to guide our relations with foreign governments on human trafficking.</p>
<p>Let me first acknowledge that this was a challenging year for the department to produce the TIP Report due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.  We are thankful to our colleagues at embassies around the world and throughout the department who worked diligently to gather data and analyze trafficking trends and efforts.  I must also heartily thank our team in the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons for your dedication to the mission and to objectively assess governments’ efforts to meet the minimum standards as called for in the Trafficking Victim Protection Act.  We were careful to assess consistently and fairly the pandemic’s impact on governments’ anti-trafficking efforts.</p>
<p>This year’s report covers 188 countries and territories, including the United States, and the introduction focuses on the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic.  The introduction outlines how the COVID-19 pandemic exacerbated trafficking situations and increased significantly the number of people worldwide at risk to exploitation and how traffickers adapted their methods to take advantage of these circumstances.</p>
<p>The introduction also illustrates the innovative ways that many adapted their anti-trafficking efforts.  It emphasizes lessons learned from practitioners, offers ways to rebuild strong anti-trafficking strategies, and focuses on ways governments can prevent the compounding effects of crises on trafficking victims and vulnerable individuals.</p>
<p>The introduction also sought to elevate other important themes such as the struggle to realize racial equity, the importance of survivor leadership, the harmful effects of conspiracy theories related to trafficking, and the reality of familial trafficking.  We also included a box on state-sponsored trafficking in persons and, due to the scale of problem, one specifically on forced labor in China’s Xinjiang region and beyond.</p>
<p>I would also like to share some noteworthy results and tier movement within our report.  Overall, there are approximately the same number of downgrades and upgrades this year as other years.  On a positive note, there were several upgrades due to tangible progress governments made to combat trafficking around the world.  We saw progress even in countries where the trafficking challenges had been intractable over many years, despite the pandemic.  Several governments received upgrades to Tier 2 for increasing efforts to address trafficking with tangible achievements.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, not all countries made such progress.  Six countries received downgrades from Tier 1 to Tier 2, as the department assessed that the governments did not meet all four of the minimum standards and were not making appreciable progress compared to the previous year.  Twelve countries were downgraded from Tier 2 to the Tier 2 Watchlist, and two others were downgraded to Tier 3.</p>
<p>The department also made the determination that 11 countries continue to have a government policy or pattern of trafficking and inadequate enforcement mechanisms.  Some government officials in these countries were themselves part of the problem, directly compelling citizens or foreign nationals into sex trafficking, forced labor, or use as child soldiers.  We found that officials used their power to exploit their citizens or foreign nationals ranging from forced labor in local or national public works projects, military operations, economically important sectors, or as part of government-funded projects or missions abroad, as well as sexual slavery on government compounds.</p>
<p>This year 15 countries were also included on the 2021 Child Soldier Prevention Act list for having governmental armed groups or supporting nongovernmental armed groups that recruit or use children in armed conflict.</p>
<p>Finally, I would like to end with an inspirational note.  This year the department is recognizing eight Heroes who have devoted their lives to the fight against human trafficking.  The 2021 Heroes come from Albania, the Central African Republic, Gabon, Japan, Kazakhstan, Mexico, Qatar, and Spain.  We hope that you saw the video earlier today during the ceremony with the award presentations and heard their voices as each individually shared what they hoped to achieve with the award and their vision for the future.  These individuals inspire each of us to do more to advance the global fight against human trafficking and protect the victims and survivors of this crime.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Wonderful.  Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you for taking my question.  Yesterday the former president claimed that there has been an increase in women’s trafficking across the Mexican border.  Can you update us on this?  Are his claims true?  Do you have any data to either refute or to – or perhaps to acknowledge what he said?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  So I will say that in general measuring the scope of the problem of human trafficking remains a challenge for the entire anti-trafficking field.  It is a hidden crime that often victims do not come forward and self-identify like they do for a lot of other crimes like pickpocketing or other violent crimes.  So it is very difficult to measure the scope of the problem, and the Trafficking in Persons Report specifically is focused on assessing governments’ efforts across a specific list of criteria that are spelled out.  I mentioned earlier the TVPA minimum standards.  We do not assess the scope or the size of the problem in any given country given the challenges with measuring it, but we focus on governments’ efforts to meet commitments across the 3Ps of prosecution, protection, and prevention.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On the section on misinformation, have you tied any of that misinformation on trafficking to any foreign governments, and what is the U.S. Government doing to try to combat this threat and scope of that misinformation?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  And thank you very much for that important question.  In recent years, participants in online forums have spread a number of false and misleading claims about child sex trafficking in particular, sometimes deliberately deceiving the public through disinformation efforts connected to conspiracy theories unrelated to human trafficking.  The spread of misinformation has detrimental effects on the ability of the anti-trafficking community to protect those who have or are currently experiencing human trafficking and to bring traffickers to justice.</p>
<p>It is imperative that the public fully understand the negative effects that spreading and acting on these rumors or misinformation can have on victims and survivors, service providers, and the broader anti-trafficking field.  For example, a barrage of calls and tips related to misinformation about human trafficking online can overwhelm systems of intervention and care that have been established to respond to potential and confirmed cases of human trafficking.</p>
<p>So we focus in the report on the effects of this misinformation on the anti-trafficking field, not on who is stoking that misinformation.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you ever refer to DOJ for prosecution?  One particular group is well known for having participated in these false conspiracy theories.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  So generally, within the State Department’s writ on human trafficking, we are really focused on analyzing and reporting on human trafficking issues both within the United States and abroad.  Our colleagues at DOJ are the ones that are doing the investigating and looking at who is actually perpetrating that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you liaison – do you liaise with them, I should say, in making sure that they are aware of your reporting?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Absolutely.  We have a robust and very formal interagency – formal in a good sense – routinized, formalized interagency collaboration, and DOJ is one of our closest partners in that process.  So we do indeed share information and work closely with them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  If I could quickly follow up, do you work at all with the Global Engagement Center here within the building to try to determine if these are malicious government actors who are playing into these (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  That hasn’t been an area so far of our focus.  That’s a good question, though.  That’s something that we will pursue with them.  Thank you for raising it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On Ethiopia, it’s downgraded to Tier 2 Watch List.  How much did the conflict in Tigray contribute to that downgrading?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for that question.  In general, I mentioned the minimum standards that are spelled out in the Trafficking Victim Protection Act that list the criteria that we focus on when we are assessing government efforts and determining tier rankings for all 188 countries and territories in the report.  We do not look at things outside of those when we’re making our tier rankings.</p>
<p>So in the case of Ethiopia, we did determine that the government was not fully meeting the minimum standards and was not making significant efforts to do so, which is what defines a Tier 2 Watch List ranking.  The government investigated and prosecuted significantly fewer trafficking cases and did not convict any traffickers at the federal level during the reporting period.  Overall law enforcement efforts across regional-level actors also decreased.  And finally, the government did not report officially identifying any trafficking victims or referring any victims to care during the reporting period.  So those were the criteria consistent with the TVPA criteria that we assessed when we recommended and the Secretary approved a downgrade for Ethiopia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Mouhamed.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sure.  Other than aid restrictions, what can the U.S. do to press the countries who are listed in the Tier 3 list?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for that question.  One of the most important tools that we have is calling attention to the areas that all governments can improve their efforts in the Trafficking in Persons Report, talking with folks like you, raising awareness about the issue, and specific recommendations that we include in the country narrative for each of those countries in the report.  We also do engage directly with governments, including most Tier 3 governments, as well as advocates and others who can help raise awareness and may also help influence those governments, including partner governments, likeminded governments, international organizations, civil society, and also the private sector.  In some countries, that can be a particularly important and impactful voice.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government also does have a range of tools in addition to the TIP Report and the restrictions that come with countries placed on Tier 3 that we have used when appropriate for countries that are on Tier 3.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Rich.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just a question about how COVID-19 affected trafficking in persons here in the United States, and how does this report – or do you find that this report effectively informs U.S. Government agencies and those who would be involved in how the U.S. Government approaches this?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for that question.  That is one that we spent a lot of time this year looking at, as we assessed government efforts around the world, how the pandemic affected government capacity specifically on those anti-trafficking commitments, including in the United States.  And like there were in other parts of the world, the pandemic did, in fact, affect U.S. capacity.  Some of the major ways in particular on the law enforcement side that the pandemic affected the U.S. Government ability to prosecute traffickers: federal courts were closed or operating at limited capacity for part of the reporting period, many criminal proceedings were delayed, and human-trafficking-related trials were postponed.</p>
<p>Federal law enforcement also found ways to adapt, just like we saw in other countries.  The Secretary highlighted some of those this morning at the event.  The U.S. Government was able to shift to conduct forensic interviews remotely, for example.  On victim protection efforts, we also saw adaptations.  DOJ and HHS published comprehensive resource guides for grantees that are assisting trafficking victims, that included how to operate, provide services, and manage grants during the pandemic.  HHS also provided flexibilities in grant program performance reporting deadlines and technical assistance to support grantees transition to remote operations, so that they were able to continue to find and care for trafficking victims.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But still nothing can replace in-person and normal operations.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Indeed, we are all hoping that we will see diminishing effects of the pandemic and people will be able to do more of their work in person.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I just want to follow up on my earlier question about Afghanistan.  And thanks for briefing us.  So I was just wondering if there’s anything you can say about how the U.S. Government is going to – what is the strategy you’re continuing to monitor and advocate for combatting human trafficking and some of the specific problems referenced in the report regarding Afghanistan, given the changing nature of the relationship and the reduced mobility that the U.S. Government will have in Afghanistan after the withdrawal?  And anything you can say about the expectations of the Afghan Government itself, the capacity of the Afghan Government itself, to take the steps that are recommended.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you very much for that.  Sorry, didn’t mean to cut you off.  Thank you very much for that question.  As the United States withdraws forces from Afghanistan we will continue to support the peaceful, stable, future the Afghan people want and deserve, and to use our full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit, including to continue to support the Afghan Government to combat trafficking in persons and care for trafficking victims in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>As part of our enduring U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan, Secretary Blinken announced on June 4th that the United States is providing more than $266 million in new humanitarian assistance, bringing the total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan to nearly $3.9 billion since 2002.  In addition, on April 20th, Secretary Blinken announced plans to work with Congress to obligate nearly $300 million in additional civilian assistance to sustain and build upon the gains of the past 20 years.  We are not abandoning the people of Afghanistan on the whole array of issues that we collaborate with them, including on human trafficking, and we will continue to work both through our embassy and implementing partners that are implementing this kind of assistance to ensure that the government is able to both sustain and build on the progress that it has made.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And anything you would be able to say about the expectation of the Afghan Government’s ability to deal with this, as they face these new – additional challenges?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  I think that remains to be seen.  We will certainly do everything that we can, both through assistance and our diplomatic support to support the Afghan Government in its continued ability to both fight trafficking and support the victims.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just to follow on Missy’s question, with all due respect, I don’t know how we can say that we are going to continue to support the Afghan Government when we’re not going to be there.  And the future of the embassy itself is in question if we don’t have the agreement that was discussed in Brussels for Turkey to ensure – to secure the airport.  Bagram is being abandoned as we speak.  I don’t know how we’re going to carry that out, other than rhetorically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I’m happy to speak to that.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Go ahead.  Please.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Andrea, so the point we’ve consistently made – and you heard it from Dr. Johnstone as well – is that yes, we are withdrawing our military forces, as the President announced, but we intend to maintain a diplomatic presence in Kabul.  That is something that is important to us, given our enduring desire to have a continued partnership with the Afghan Government, and crucially with the Afghan people.</p>
<p>So it is absolutely not the case that we intend to abandon Afghanistan, that we intend to relent in our support for the Government of Afghanistan, that we intend to diminish our support and our partnership for the people of Afghanistan.  Obviously, that relationship will look different with the military withdrawal underway, and once it is completed in the coming weeks and months.  But that does not in any way diminish the commitment we have to the Afghan Government and to the Afghan people.  That is the point that is tremendously important to the Department of State, to Secretary Blinken, and to President Biden and the full administration.  It’s something that he made clear with President Ghani, with Chairman Abdullah as well in their visit to the White House in recent days.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Would you say that that’s predicated on our ability to maintain a diplomatic presence?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  And which we intend to do.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Which depends on the airport and a lot of other things.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  And the security at the airport, security at our embassy – as you know, President Biden, when he made this announcement, he made clear that the only troops, U.S. servicemembers, that would remain in-country were those necessary to safeguard our diplomatic compound in Kabul.  So that is very important to us, and it’s very important to us for one principal reason: because it facilitates that partnership with the Afghan Government and with the Afghan people, and that is something we intend to see continue.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just to follow up on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Any – let’s – before we move onto Afghanistan, anything else on the TIP Report, anything for Dr. Johnstone?  Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Let me give (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, I want to thank you for joining us today, and more importantly, thanks to you and to your team for all of your work in this important product, and very much appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Thank you, all.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Before we move into questions, let me just speak to a couple of elements at the top.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, President Biden committed that the United States will be the world’s arsenal of vaccines in the shared fight against COVID-19.  Since then, the administration has taken historic actions and is delivering on that presidential commitment.  Over the past several weeks, we have committed to sharing 580 million doses of vaccines to the world, including of course the 80 million doses of our own surplus U.S. supply.  These 80 million doses have now all been shared with 46 countries, the African Union, and CARICOM through a combination of bilateral sharing and sharing through COVAX.</p>
<p>Each country has received the specific number and type of U.S. vaccines they will be shipped, and by the end of this week, we will have already shipped out about 40 million doses to the Republic of Korea, Mexico, Canada, Brazil, Taiwan, Honduras, Colombia, Pakistan, Peru, Ecuador, Malaysia, and Bangladesh through a combination, again, of bilateral sharing and through COVAX as well.  The remaining doses will be shipped in the coming weeks as countries complete their own domestic set of operational, regulatory, and legal processes.  And we will continue to share even more doses in the summer months and beyond.</p>
<p>Next.  Today the Secretary of State announced the transmittal to Congress of the Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List, a report that’s required by Section 353 of the United States–Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act.  This report lists individuals from Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador who have undermined democratic processes or institutions, who have engaged in significant corruption, or who have obstructed investigations into such acts.</p>
<p>The United States fights for democracy and combats corruption and impunity in support of the people of the region.  The citizens of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador have consistently repudiated corruption, demanded accountability from their governments and private actors, and they’ve acted in defense of democratic institutions.  We stand with all those endeavoring to build a better, more hopeful future in these countries and in the broader region.</p>
<p>As today’s actions demonstrate, there are consequences when individuals – whether government officials or private actors – violate the principles of democracy, rule of law, and transparency that the people of the region deserve and, in fact, expect. The United States will continue to use a range of diplomatic and economic tools, including actions like this one, to shine light on corruption and encourage the strengthening of democratic institutions so that our neighbors in Central America can build brighter futures for their communities.</p>
<p>And finally, as you heard from Secretary Blinken earlier today, today marks the fifth anniversary of the terrorist attack at the Holey Artisan Bakery in Dhaka, Bangladesh, which resulted in the deaths of 20 people, including one U.S. citizen.  We extend our deepest condolences to the loved ones of the victims.  We stand with Bangladesh in our condemnation of terrorism and determination to prevent future such attacks.  We commend Bangladesh’s efforts to bring those responsible to justice and we recommit to our strong counterterrorism partnership to prevent future attacks.</p>
<p>So with that, I’m happy to go back to your questions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Is the U.S. days away from completing the U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan?  And does the President plan any sort of event or speech or travel to mark the withdrawal from Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you for your question.  So I will leave it to the Department of Defense to speak to the retrograde operation.  I know they have been able to provide updates in recent weeks and even recent days.  We&#8217;ve heard from the Pentagon, we&#8217;ve heard from senior DOD officials regarding their activities, their plans.  And most importantly, we&#8217;ve heard from the President, and the President noted earlier this year that it – the United States would be withdrawing militarily from Afghanistan, that withdrawal would be completed by the 20th anniversary of the September 11th attacks, September of this year, 2021.  But beyond that, I&#8217;m going to defer to the Department of Defense to speak to those operations and any detail they might be able to share.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you have any update on the Afghan visas for translators and others and their families?  Has another country agreed – can you give us a progress report on Guam or any other – and related but unrelated issue, the problem of the COVID outbreak among the local staff, I presume, and not FSOs, in Kabul?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Sure, I – first, you have heard from my colleagues in recent days, you have heard from other senior administration officials that this administration has a special responsibility to those brave Afghans who, over the years, have assisted the United States Government in myriad ways, whether acting as interpreters, acting as translators, other officials who have assisted us, often at great risk to themselves, sometime – at times, even to their families.</p>
<p>As we have said, we have identified a group of SIV applicants who have served in these roles, as well as other individuals who have assisted us over the years and who may be at risk.  They and their families will have the option to be relocated to a location outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown by September, as I alluded to before, so that they can complete their SIV process.  Importantly, these are individuals who are already in the SIV pipeline, and we would</p>
<p>— sounds like we may have a storm warning.  I will trust someone will let us know if we are in any imminent danger here. —</p>
<p>And, of course, we would undertake any relocation in full compliance with applicable laws and in full coordination with Congress.  We are engaging regularly with our partners in the interagency.  The State Department is not the only entity involved in this.  There are regular discussions with the Department of Defense, with the White House, with other entities who are involved in this.  I wouldn&#8217;t want to speak to those internal discussions, nor would I want to speak to any diplomatic discussions that may be ongoing with partner countries around the world.</p>
<p>I will also say that we will share information as we are able, consistent with concerns we have for the security of those involved.  Again, our paramount concern is the safety and security of those who have worked with us over the years in Afghanistan.  That is precisely why we have identified a group of applicants who will have the option of being relocated with their families. And, of course, we wouldn&#8217;t want to do anything or share any information that could add to the risk they already face.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Just – there have been reports of a census of perhaps 18,000 people in this category, plus families, making it an overall group of about 70,000.  Would you argue with that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, what we have said is that there are about 18,000 Afghan principal applicants who are at some stage as of right now in the SIV application process.  As of May 2021, about 50 percent of those applicants, or some 9,000 applicants, are at an initial stage of the process pending applicant action.  In other words, approximately 9,000 of these 18,000 applicants need to take some sort of action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case.</p>
<p>Now, we haven&#8217;t attached numbers to the group we have identified for potential relocation, but 18,000 is the aggregate number of principal Afghan applicants who are at some stage of the SIV application process.</p>
<p>And you reminded me that you did ask about the implications of the ongoing COVID outbreak at our embassy in Kabul.  We have issued department guidance for embassy operations worldwide, and consistent with that, Embassy Kabul is operating on a reduced staffing posture.  The embassy, as we’ve said, has suspended visa interviews, but visa processing does not require in-person – but visa processing that does not require in-person interactions with applicants continues.  Of course, much of this also takes place at the chief-of-mission stage, and much of that takes place from Washington.  And we will resume interviewing qualified SIV applicants in Kabul as soon as it’s safe to do so.  The embassy does continue to issue visas to Afghans whose applications are fully approved.</p>
<p>Jessica.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>I have a question:  If the embassy in – closes in Kabul, will the U.S. still be able to provide aid from afar without the embassy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Would we still be able to provide a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Would you still be able to provide aid to the Afghan Government if the embassy in Kabul, for whatever reason, is forced to close?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>So again, it is our intention to maintain a diplomatic presence in Kabul.  As the President said, the only American servicemembers who will remain in Afghanistan are those required to protect the diplomatic presence there.  And that’s because the diplomatic presence is something that enables us, in an effective way, to continue to partner with the Afghan Government and Afghan people.  I wouldn’t want to entertain hypotheticals or contingencies.  Of course, we are planning for any number of contingencies, and I can say that regardless of what happens, our partnership with the Afghan Government, with the Afghan people will not diminish, it will always endure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you have any red lines for – if the shape of the Afghan Government changes, say Ghani falls, you have somebody else emerge – are there any red lines?  Or say the Taliban become the foremost partner – do you have any red lines which could affect the amount of aid or whether or not you provide aid at all?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, of course, it is up to the Afghan people to select their leaders.  What we do know is that the international community and the Afghan people, of course, will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan.  Legitimacy and assistance for any Afghan government can only be possible if that government has the consent of the Afghan people, and critically, I would say, has fundamental respect for human rights.  That is what we know.  Any attempt to install a new Afghan government by force will not be accepted internationally.  It will not be accepted by the Afghan people.  And the United States and our partners around the world will be watching very carefully the human rights situation and the conditions for the Afghan people, who we know have suffered from years of war, years of violence – the gains that have been achieved we know are fragile, and we will be watching very carefully to do all we can to protect those gains, especially for Afghanistan’s girls, its women, its minorities as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>One last clarification:  To say that the Ghani government is no longer on top, will the U.S. still continue to fund money towards government-led or associated factions like, say, the army, maybe schools in government-controlled areas or – if the government falls, does that mean that all of Afghanistan suddenly is cut off?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, again, I wouldn’t want to entertain any hypotheticals or contingencies like that.  Again, what we know is that any government that is installed by force will not be accepted, it will not be considered legitimate, and it will not receive assistance from the international community.  What I can say broadly is that, of course, it is our intention to continue to support the Afghanistan National Defense and Security Forces, the ANDSF.  It right now is a standing force of more than 300,000 Afghan personnel.  Our support, the contours of that support, of course, will change as we transition from a direct train, advise, and assist mission through NATO.  And – but we will continue to provide assistance to the ANDSF going forward.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Very quickly?  Another topic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Couple quick – couple more quick questions on Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>I know we also have an event at 3:45, so I’m mindful of the clock.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Oh &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, you said that the SIV applicants you’ve identified would be moved before the withdrawal, but our reporting indicates that the retrograde will be done within the next coming days.  So how do you square those two?  Is this evacuation imminent or the relocation imminent?  Do you have more of a concrete timeline you can share with us?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, again, I’m going to leave it to the Department of Defense to speak to the timeline of their retrograde operations.  What the President has said is that it would be completed before September, and what we have said is that we have identified a group of applicants who are already in train who will have the option to be relocated outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military withdrawal in September.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you know where they will be relocated, like which countries will help the United States sheltering them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  So as I said before, there are certain details we’ll be in a position to share – and I expect we’ll be a position to share additional details in the coming days and the coming weeks – and there are some details that we may not be able to share because of security concerns.  Again, our paramount concern in all of this, the reason we are offering this option to a group of SIV applicants is out of concern for their safety, their wellbeing.  And so we wouldn’t want to share any details that could potentially jeopardize that.  But as we do have additional details to share, I can assure you we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  I have two questions about Afghanistan and Turkey.  Do you have any concerns that the new designation of Turkey as a country implicated in the use of children as soldiers would have an impact on the ongoing talks between the U.S. and Turkey to guard the international airport in Kabul?</p>
<p>And second question:  With the meeting today between the Secretary Blinken and his Tajik counterpart, what role does the U.S. want Tajikistan and Uzbekistan maybe to play in Afghanistan?  And was any security or military arrangement was discussed during those talks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you for that.  So the Trafficking in Persons Report, the TIP Report, it is not a political document.  It is based on facts.  It is based on analysis and our assessment of those – of that information that we are able to glean from a variety of resources.  That includes reporting from the U.S. Government, classified and unclassified, open-source information, everything that would help to inform our assessment of various governments’ progress or lack thereof when it comes to trafficking in persons.  So I would not want to link the report today with what – the discussions we are engaging in, the constructive discussions we’re engaging in with Turkey in the context of Afghanistan or any other area of shared interest.</p>
<p>As you know, President Biden had a opportunity to meet face to face with President Erdogan not all that long ago, just last month.  And as they’ve said, the – Turkey’s role in Afghanistan was discussed in that context.  Turkey has been a very constructive and very helpful partner when it comes to Afghanistan.  Turkey has been supportive of the diplomacy.  Turkey, of course, is an important NATO Ally, but I wouldn’t want to go beyond that in terms of details of &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So the U.S. is not – is not planning to impose any restrictions on – military restrictions on Turkey over this designation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  So these designations, the implications of them, we will be able to speak to that later this year.  As you know, there are – there is the potential for waivers that would come down from the President, but that will happen, if it does, in the coming months.  I’m not in a position to speak to that at the moment.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Moving on to another topic.  There was a report that the Walla website, Israeli website, that the Israeli Government requested the Biden administration or asked the Biden administration to postpone the reopening of the consulate in East Jerusalem.  Can you enlighten us on what’s happening with that regard, with this issue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Happy to.  So as the Secretary said in Jerusalem – he said this publicly; he also said this privately in his meetings with our Israeli and Palestinian Authority counterparts – but he made very clear that we will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem because it strengthens our ability to do what we have said we intend to do, and that is to rebuild our engagement with the Palestinian Authority and, crucially, with the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>So I don&#8217;t have any private diplomatic conversations to detail for you or to read out, but it remains our intention to move forward with that process.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, I have a couple more questions.  But I wanted to ask you also about the PLO office in Washington.  Any progress on that score?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I don&#8217;t have any update for you there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>You don’t either.  Okay.  Are you in touch with the Palestinian Authority in any way?  Is there any kind of communication ongoing?  There was – there were reports that the PA has submitted like 30 points or something to that effect for negotiations or resuming negotiations.  The PA President Abbas was in Amman yesterday talking to – with the King of Jordan, who is prepared to come to Washington and so on.  Is there something ongoing?  Are you in communication with them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  There is regular engagement with the Palestinian Authority, just as there is regular engagement with our Israeli counterparts.  It is something that happens from this building.  It’s something that happens from within this administration and in regular course.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And finally, I know that you issued a statement last week on the killing of Nizar Banat in custody with the Palestinian Security Forces.  But have you spoken to any Palestinian figures, Palestinian authority figures?  I know that the head of intelligence in – the Palestinians’ intelligence Majed Faraj is very close to perhaps the Intelligence Community in the United States; he’s in regular contact, and so on.  Have you spoken to them?  Because this is apparently a common practice.  It was done time and again.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We have made very clear, Said, that we are deeply disturbed by reports that non-uniformed members of the Palestinian Authority Security Forces harassed and used forced – used force against protesters and journalists during the public demonstrations calling for accountability for the death that you mentioned, the death of Nizar Banat.  We have strongly urged security services and security forces to conduct themselves in a professional manner and to respect freedom of expression, the work of journalists, and the right of Palestinians to protest peacefully.  This is not something – these are not points that are unique to this context for us. These are statements that we make universally around the world as well.</p>
<p>In this particular context, we have noted that the Palestinian Authority has announced the establishment of a commission to investigate Mr. Banat’s death.  As we stated previously, it’s important that the PA conducts a thorough and transparent investigation to ensure full accountability of this case.  We have made those expectations very clear to the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, please, I have two quick questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Michel, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>One on Morocco.  Brett McGurk, White House National Security Council coordinator for the Middle East, was quoted saying that the U.S. has no intention of reversing its recognition of Morocco’s sovereignty over Western Sahara.  Is this the administration position now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>It remains the administration position.  I don&#8217;t have any update for you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Are you changing in U.S. policy towards this recognition?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>There is no change.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And one on Lebanon – I&#8217;ve been asking about this since the meeting that the Secretary held in Italy with the Saudi foreign minister and the French foreign minister:  What was the goal of this meeting and why you didn&#8217;t have any answer on this request for two, three days?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well (inaudible) we did issue a tweet noting the meeting.  The tweet also did discuss some of the substance of the meeting.  These are two governments that have – with whom we share interests when it comes to Lebanon.  I think broadly we have made very clear in our engagement with other interested parties, including the Saudis, including the French, including any number of other governments around the world, that our expectation is that Lebanon&#8217;s leaders show sufficient flexibility to form a government that is willing and capable of, importantly, true and fundamental reform so that the Lebanese people can realize their full potential.</p>
<p>The Lebanese people, we have long said, deserve a government that will urgently implement the necessary reforms to rescue the country&#8217;s deteriorating economy.  The humanitarian conditions for the people of Lebanon are increasingly dire.  The Lebanese economy is in crisis, and that is chiefly because of decades of corruption, of mismanagement by Lebanon&#8217;s political leaders. We continue to call upon them to put aside their partisan brinksmanship, to change course, and to work for the common good of their people, of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>The international community has been clear that concrete actions remain absolutely crucial to unlocking longer-term structural support for Lebanon.  All of this was discussed in the trilateral meeting with Secretary Blinken and his French and Saudi counterparts.  There is shared international interest in seeing stability brought to Lebanon, in humanitarian relief provided to the Lebanese people, and affording and equipping the Lebanese people with a government that they deserve, chiefly a government that serves their interests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes, Rich.  Yup.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Just wondering if the Secretary or the administration had paid note to President Xi Jinping’s address, using some fairly aggressive language towards the West and in general, like heads bashed against the bloody great wall of steel.  Was the administration surprised?  Was there a concern about the tenor of the address?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, of course, we’re aware that the Chinese Communist Party commemorated its 100th anniversary today.  We&#8217;re aware of President Xi&#8217;s remarks.  We’ve taken note on them, but we&#8217;re not going to comment on the specifics.  I think this administration, over the course of several months, has been very clear about our impressions of the CCP in general, but I don’t have a specific response for you on President Xi&#8217;s remarks today.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>I wanted to follow up on the Joby Warrick report in the – in <em>The Washington Post</em>, excuse me – about 100 missile silos being detected, which would be an extraordinary number or total, according to the Monterey experts, 145 across China out of a fairly small nuclear arsenal.  What do you think their intention is?  What is your analysis on that?  And whether you have any further comment on the crackdown in Hong Kong of <em>Apple Daily</em>.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>On the crackdown in Hong Kong?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Of <em>Apple Daily.</em></p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>So let me start with your first question and the reported build-up, the article that was in <em>The Washington Post</em>, the independent analysis that has been done.  I think what is fair to say is that these reports and other developments suggest that the PRC’s nuclear arsenal will grow more quickly, and to a higher level than perhaps previously anticipated.  This buildup – it is concerning.  It raises questions about the PRC’s intent.  And for us, it reinforces the importance of pursuing practical measures to reduce nuclear risks.  Despite what appears to be PRC obfuscation, this rapid buildup has become more difficult to hide, and it highlights how the PRC appears, again, to be deviating from decades of nuclear strategy based around minimum deterrents.</p>
<p>These advances, again, to our minds highlight why it’s in everyone’s interests that nuclear powers talk to one another directly about reducing nuclear dangers and avoiding miscalculations.  We encourage Beijing to engage with us on practical measures to reduce the risks of destabilizing arms races, potential – potentially destabilizing tensions.  This is precisely why President Biden prioritized strategic stability in his engagement with President Putin.  The same basis, the same rationale would apply to engagement with another nuclear power, the PRC.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  If I may, can we have a comment about Switzerland, which decided to buy the F-35 jets?  It’s a 6.5 billion contract.  And how will this contract impact the relationship between the United States and Switzerland, which is a neutral country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, we do welcome the Federal Council’s decision announced yesterday in its Air 2030 defense procurement competition.  The United States is proud to have provided Switzerland with world-class air defense products over quite a bit of time, over the past five decades, respecting Swiss sovereignty in the process, supporting Swiss national security, and partnering with Switzerland on economic and technological advancements.</p>
<p>We look forward to building on that proven record of success and deepening that partnership to our mutual benefit – to the benefit of Switzerland, to the benefit of the United States following this week’s announcement.  We do appreciate the opportunity we were given to participate in this competition, and we stand ready for our governments to work together not only in the course of this contract, but of course, for decades to come.  We offer our congratulations to the aircraft makers and others who were involved in this competition, and we look forward to deepening that partnership.</p>
<p>I’m mindful of the clock because we do have a bilateral engagement coming up.  I’ll take a couple more questions here.  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On Lebanon?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Lebanon?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Lebanon.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Lebanon, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Three days ago, the Secretary met with Pope Francis, and Lebanon was on the agenda, we understood.  And today, the Vatican is convening a summit to discuss Lebanon crisis.  Did that summit topic come up during the Secretary and the pope conversation, knowing that the head of the Catholic Church in Lebanon who was attending this summit is pushing toward internationalizing this crisis?  Do you have anything to comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, we issued a readout of the Secretary’s meeting with his holiness the pope.  It was a meeting that, as I believe we said, lasted for some 40 minutes.  It was wide-ranging.  They discussed the plight of the world’s most vulnerable, of the world’s most disadvantaged, and Lebanon was a topic during that conversation.  As I noted before in response to a different question, the people of Lebanon have suffered tremendously because of corruption, because of mismanagement, because of political infighting in their country, and the humanitarian toll has been especially devastating.</p>
<p>So it’s no surprise that the humanitarian conditions there and the need to provide much-needed relief to the people of Lebanon did feature in that one-on-one discussion between the Secretary and Pope Francis.</p>
<p>Yes, Jenny.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is the State Department involved in the response to the condo collapse in Florida given the number of foreign nationals who are believed to be impacted?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, of course, Miami is truly an international city, and we’ve seen that reflected in some of the tragic stories emanating from the Surfside condo collapse.  It’s a city that represents this hemisphere and well beyond.  And so it also stands to reason that the department has been engaged in supporting foreign missions in their efforts to locate and to assist their citizens who may have been in some way involved or implicated in the partial collapse of the Champlain Towers in Surfside last week.</p>
<p>The department is on the ground.  We are working closely with local, with state, with federal and foreign mission personnel in conjunction with other interagency partners to assist in response to this tragedy.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  I have two questions.  A follow-up on the Western Sahara:  You said the U.S. is not planning to reverse the recognition of the Western Sahara’s Morocco land.  So the question is:  How does the U.S. view the Moroccan proposal for autonomy for that disputed area?  And is the U.S. planning to launch a new diplomatic effort to find maybe an – a solution to this issue?</p>
<p>And second, on Yemen, in light of the strong condemnation yesterday from the State Department over the ongoing military offensive by the Houthis in Marib, is the U.S. fed up with the Houthi stance not to engage in the diplomatic effort?  And is the U.S. planning to maybe adopt a drastic approach against the Houthis if they decided not to engage in the U.S. or in the international diplomatic efforts to find a solution to the crisis in Yemen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, when it comes to Morocco and the Western Sahara, as I said before, we don’t have any updates in terms of the United States recognition of Moroccan sovereignty.</p>
<p>When it comes to the broader issue, what I’ll say is that we do support a credible UN-led political process to stabilize the situation and to secure a cessation of any hostilities.  We are consulting with the parties, we are consulting with other governments in the region and beyond, about how best to bring a halt to the violence and ultimately to achieve a lasting settlement to this long-running conflict.  We strongly support UN efforts to appoint a personal envoy of the secretary-general for the Western Sahara and to do that as quickly as possible, and we’re prepared to continue to be actively engaged with all sides in support of that individual.</p>
<p>When it comes to Yemen, you asked if we are fed up with the Houthi attacks.  The answer to that is yes.  We are beyond fed up.  We are horrified by the repeated attacks on Marib.  We strongly condemn the Houthi missile attack on a residential neighborhood in Marib on June 29th.  It took civilian lives, including the life of a child.  We believe it is long past time to end the conflict in Yemen and to provide immediate relief to the Yemeni people.</p>
<p>What we know is that the Houthis’ offensive in Marib is exacerbating the humanitarian crisis faced by the people of Yemen.  It is by many accounts home to the world’s worst humanitarian catastrophe.  For the Houthis to continue this brutal offensive while there is a serious proposal before them, a proposal that would meet their long-held and stated demands for a plan with practical steps to facilitate the flow of goods into and within Yemen, implement a nationwide ceasefire, and initiate inclusive political talks – that is what separates the Houthis from other Yemenis who are actively working towards peace, who strike us as being serious about peace.</p>
<p>What concerns us is the loss of life.  What concerns us is the fact that this offensive continues to set back the process for a durable political solution to this long-running conflict.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  North Korea.  Briefly, do you have any comment on the Kim Jong-un diet?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And the serious implications, obviously.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I don’t have any particular comment on that.  As you know, Andrea, we have completed a review of our policy towards the DPRK.  It’s a policy that is predicated first and foremost on diminishing the threat to our interests in the region, to our partners who are in the region, and it’s a policy that’s predicated on the utility of diplomacy.  We believe that through practical, clear-eyed engagement with our allies and partners and with the DPRK we can achieve progress on what remains our goal, and that is ultimately the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  That’s what we’re focused on.  It &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Any response to that policy review and to the initiatives, to the overtures?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Look, we have made very clear our willingness to sit down anytime, anywhere with representatives of the DPRK.  Ambassador Kim, our special envoy for the DPRK, has recently been in the Republic of Korea, where he met with South Korean officials, where he met trilaterally with South Korean and Japanese officials.  He reiterated there that we are prepared anytime, anywhere to engage in diplomacy with the DPRK, and we are awaiting a constructive response from the DPRK.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, everyone.  Sorry we need to cut this short.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:45 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:49 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon.  Very good to see everyone.  It has been too long.  Looking forward to spending more time in this briefing room this month, in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Today, obviously, is a very important day here at the Department of State.  As you have seen and as you heard from Secretary Blinken, we rolled out the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report.  I am very pleased that we have joining us at the top of the briefing today Dr. Kari Johnstone.  She is the acting director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.  She will have some remarks, and then she’ll be happy to take your questions before we move on to our regularly scheduled program.</p>
<p>So without ado, Dr. Johnstone.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Thank you very much, Ned, and good afternoon to all of you.  I am pleased to be here with you.  Earlier today, Secretary Blinken released the State Department’s 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report, or the TIP Report, which examines governments’ efforts to combat human trafficking using a 3P framework of prosecuting traffickers, protecting victims, and preventing the crime.  This report reflects the U.S. Government’s commitment to global leadership on this key human rights, law enforcement, and national security issue.  It remains our principal diplomatic and diagnostic tool to guide our relations with foreign governments on human trafficking.</p>
<p>Let me first acknowledge that this was a challenging year for the department to produce the TIP Report due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.  We are thankful to our colleagues at embassies around the world and throughout the department who worked diligently to gather data and analyze trafficking trends and efforts.  I must also heartily thank our team in the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons for your dedication to the mission and to objectively assess governments’ efforts to meet the minimum standards as called for in the Trafficking Victim Protection Act.  We were careful to assess consistently and fairly the pandemic’s impact on governments’ anti-trafficking efforts.</p>
<p>This year’s report covers 188 countries and territories, including the United States, and the introduction focuses on the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic.  The introduction outlines how the COVID-19 pandemic exacerbated trafficking situations and increased significantly the number of people worldwide at risk to exploitation and how traffickers adapted their methods to take advantage of these circumstances.</p>
<p>The introduction also illustrates the innovative ways that many adapted their anti-trafficking efforts.  It emphasizes lessons learned from practitioners, offers ways to rebuild strong anti-trafficking strategies, and focuses on ways governments can prevent the compounding effects of crises on trafficking victims and vulnerable individuals.</p>
<p>The introduction also sought to elevate other important themes such as the struggle to realize racial equity, the importance of survivor leadership, the harmful effects of conspiracy theories related to trafficking, and the reality of familial trafficking.  We also included a box on state-sponsored trafficking in persons and, due to the scale of problem, one specifically on forced labor in China’s Xinjiang region and beyond.</p>
<p>I would also like to share some noteworthy results and tier movement within our report.  Overall, there are approximately the same number of downgrades and upgrades this year as other years.  On a positive note, there were several upgrades due to tangible progress governments made to combat trafficking around the world.  We saw progress even in countries where the trafficking challenges had been intractable over many years, despite the pandemic.  Several governments received upgrades to Tier 2 for increasing efforts to address trafficking with tangible achievements.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, not all countries made such progress.  Six countries received downgrades from Tier 1 to Tier 2, as the department assessed that the governments did not meet all four of the minimum standards and were not making appreciable progress compared to the previous year.  Twelve countries were downgraded from Tier 2 to the Tier 2 Watchlist, and two others were downgraded to Tier 3.</p>
<p>The department also made the determination that 11 countries continue to have a government policy or pattern of trafficking and inadequate enforcement mechanisms.  Some government officials in these countries were themselves part of the problem, directly compelling citizens or foreign nationals into sex trafficking, forced labor, or use as child soldiers.  We found that officials used their power to exploit their citizens or foreign nationals ranging from forced labor in local or national public works projects, military operations, economically important sectors, or as part of government-funded projects or missions abroad, as well as sexual slavery on government compounds.</p>
<p>This year 15 countries were also included on the 2021 Child Soldier Prevention Act list for having governmental armed groups or supporting nongovernmental armed groups that recruit or use children in armed conflict.</p>
<p>Finally, I would like to end with an inspirational note.  This year the department is recognizing eight Heroes who have devoted their lives to the fight against human trafficking.  The 2021 Heroes come from Albania, the Central African Republic, Gabon, Japan, Kazakhstan, Mexico, Qatar, and Spain.  We hope that you saw the video earlier today during the ceremony with the award presentations and heard their voices as each individually shared what they hoped to achieve with the award and their vision for the future.  These individuals inspire each of us to do more to advance the global fight against human trafficking and protect the victims and survivors of this crime.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Wonderful.  Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you for taking my question.  Yesterday the former president claimed that there has been an increase in women’s trafficking across the Mexican border.  Can you update us on this?  Are his claims true?  Do you have any data to either refute or to – or perhaps to acknowledge what he said?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  So I will say that in general measuring the scope of the problem of human trafficking remains a challenge for the entire anti-trafficking field.  It is a hidden crime that often victims do not come forward and self-identify like they do for a lot of other crimes like pickpocketing or other violent crimes.  So it is very difficult to measure the scope of the problem, and the Trafficking in Persons Report specifically is focused on assessing governments’ efforts across a specific list of criteria that are spelled out.  I mentioned earlier the TVPA minimum standards.  We do not assess the scope or the size of the problem in any given country given the challenges with measuring it, but we focus on governments’ efforts to meet commitments across the 3Ps of prosecution, protection, and prevention.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On the section on misinformation, have you tied any of that misinformation on trafficking to any foreign governments, and what is the U.S. Government doing to try to combat this threat and scope of that misinformation?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  And thank you very much for that important question.  In recent years, participants in online forums have spread a number of false and misleading claims about child sex trafficking in particular, sometimes deliberately deceiving the public through disinformation efforts connected to conspiracy theories unrelated to human trafficking.  The spread of misinformation has detrimental effects on the ability of the anti-trafficking community to protect those who have or are currently experiencing human trafficking and to bring traffickers to justice.</p>
<p>It is imperative that the public fully understand the negative effects that spreading and acting on these rumors or misinformation can have on victims and survivors, service providers, and the broader anti-trafficking field.  For example, a barrage of calls and tips related to misinformation about human trafficking online can overwhelm systems of intervention and care that have been established to respond to potential and confirmed cases of human trafficking.</p>
<p>So we focus in the report on the effects of this misinformation on the anti-trafficking field, not on who is stoking that misinformation.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you ever refer to DOJ for prosecution?  One particular group is well known for having participated in these false conspiracy theories.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  So generally, within the State Department’s writ on human trafficking, we are really focused on analyzing and reporting on human trafficking issues both within the United States and abroad.  Our colleagues at DOJ are the ones that are doing the investigating and looking at who is actually perpetrating that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you liaison – do you liaise with them, I should say, in making sure that they are aware of your reporting?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Absolutely.  We have a robust and very formal interagency – formal in a good sense – routinized, formalized interagency collaboration, and DOJ is one of our closest partners in that process.  So we do indeed share information and work closely with them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  If I could quickly follow up, do you work at all with the Global Engagement Center here within the building to try to determine if these are malicious government actors who are playing into these (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  That hasn’t been an area so far of our focus.  That’s a good question, though.  That’s something that we will pursue with them.  Thank you for raising it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On Ethiopia, it’s downgraded to Tier 2 Watch List.  How much did the conflict in Tigray contribute to that downgrading?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for that question.  In general, I mentioned the minimum standards that are spelled out in the Trafficking Victim Protection Act that list the criteria that we focus on when we are assessing government efforts and determining tier rankings for all 188 countries and territories in the report.  We do not look at things outside of those when we’re making our tier rankings.</p>
<p>So in the case of Ethiopia, we did determine that the government was not fully meeting the minimum standards and was not making significant efforts to do so, which is what defines a Tier 2 Watch List ranking.  The government investigated and prosecuted significantly fewer trafficking cases and did not convict any traffickers at the federal level during the reporting period.  Overall law enforcement efforts across regional-level actors also decreased.  And finally, the government did not report officially identifying any trafficking victims or referring any victims to care during the reporting period.  So those were the criteria consistent with the TVPA criteria that we assessed when we recommended and the Secretary approved a downgrade for Ethiopia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Mouhamed.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sure.  Other than aid restrictions, what can the U.S. do to press the countries who are listed in the Tier 3 list?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for that question.  One of the most important tools that we have is calling attention to the areas that all governments can improve their efforts in the Trafficking in Persons Report, talking with folks like you, raising awareness about the issue, and specific recommendations that we include in the country narrative for each of those countries in the report.  We also do engage directly with governments, including most Tier 3 governments, as well as advocates and others who can help raise awareness and may also help influence those governments, including partner governments, likeminded governments, international organizations, civil society, and also the private sector.  In some countries, that can be a particularly important and impactful voice.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government also does have a range of tools in addition to the TIP Report and the restrictions that come with countries placed on Tier 3 that we have used when appropriate for countries that are on Tier 3.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Rich.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just a question about how COVID-19 affected trafficking in persons here in the United States, and how does this report – or do you find that this report effectively informs U.S. Government agencies and those who would be involved in how the U.S. Government approaches this?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for that question.  That is one that we spent a lot of time this year looking at, as we assessed government efforts around the world, how the pandemic affected government capacity specifically on those anti-trafficking commitments, including in the United States.  And like there were in other parts of the world, the pandemic did, in fact, affect U.S. capacity.  Some of the major ways in particular on the law enforcement side that the pandemic affected the U.S. Government ability to prosecute traffickers: federal courts were closed or operating at limited capacity for part of the reporting period, many criminal proceedings were delayed, and human-trafficking-related trials were postponed.</p>
<p>Federal law enforcement also found ways to adapt, just like we saw in other countries.  The Secretary highlighted some of those this morning at the event.  The U.S. Government was able to shift to conduct forensic interviews remotely, for example.  On victim protection efforts, we also saw adaptations.  DOJ and HHS published comprehensive resource guides for grantees that are assisting trafficking victims, that included how to operate, provide services, and manage grants during the pandemic.  HHS also provided flexibilities in grant program performance reporting deadlines and technical assistance to support grantees transition to remote operations, so that they were able to continue to find and care for trafficking victims.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But still nothing can replace in-person and normal operations.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Indeed, we are all hoping that we will see diminishing effects of the pandemic and people will be able to do more of their work in person.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I just want to follow up on my earlier question about Afghanistan.  And thanks for briefing us.  So I was just wondering if there’s anything you can say about how the U.S. Government is going to – what is the strategy you’re continuing to monitor and advocate for combatting human trafficking and some of the specific problems referenced in the report regarding Afghanistan, given the changing nature of the relationship and the reduced mobility that the U.S. Government will have in Afghanistan after the withdrawal?  And anything you can say about the expectations of the Afghan Government itself, the capacity of the Afghan Government itself, to take the steps that are recommended.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Yeah, thank you very much for that.  Sorry, didn’t mean to cut you off.  Thank you very much for that question.  As the United States withdraws forces from Afghanistan we will continue to support the peaceful, stable, future the Afghan people want and deserve, and to use our full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit, including to continue to support the Afghan Government to combat trafficking in persons and care for trafficking victims in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>As part of our enduring U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan, Secretary Blinken announced on June 4th that the United States is providing more than $266 million in new humanitarian assistance, bringing the total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan to nearly $3.9 billion since 2002.  In addition, on April 20th, Secretary Blinken announced plans to work with Congress to obligate nearly $300 million in additional civilian assistance to sustain and build upon the gains of the past 20 years.  We are not abandoning the people of Afghanistan on the whole array of issues that we collaborate with them, including on human trafficking, and we will continue to work both through our embassy and implementing partners that are implementing this kind of assistance to ensure that the government is able to both sustain and build on the progress that it has made.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And anything you would be able to say about the expectation of the Afghan Government’s ability to deal with this, as they face these new – additional challenges?</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  I think that remains to be seen.  We will certainly do everything that we can, both through assistance and our diplomatic support to support the Afghan Government in its continued ability to both fight trafficking and support the victims.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just to follow on Missy’s question, with all due respect, I don’t know how we can say that we are going to continue to support the Afghan Government when we’re not going to be there.  And the future of the embassy itself is in question if we don’t have the agreement that was discussed in Brussels for Turkey to ensure – to secure the airport.  Bagram is being abandoned as we speak.  I don’t know how we’re going to carry that out, other than rhetorically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I’m happy to speak to that.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Go ahead.  Please.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Andrea, so the point we’ve consistently made – and you heard it from Dr. Johnstone as well – is that yes, we are withdrawing our military forces, as the President announced, but we intend to maintain a diplomatic presence in Kabul.  That is something that is important to us, given our enduring desire to have a continued partnership with the Afghan Government, and crucially with the Afghan people.</p>
<p>So it is absolutely not the case that we intend to abandon Afghanistan, that we intend to relent in our support for the Government of Afghanistan, that we intend to diminish our support and our partnership for the people of Afghanistan.  Obviously, that relationship will look different with the military withdrawal underway, and once it is completed in the coming weeks and months.  But that does not in any way diminish the commitment we have to the Afghan Government and to the Afghan people.  That is the point that is tremendously important to the Department of State, to Secretary Blinken, and to President Biden and the full administration.  It’s something that he made clear with President Ghani, with Chairman Abdullah as well in their visit to the White House in recent days.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Would you say that that’s predicated on our ability to maintain a diplomatic presence?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  And which we intend to do.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Which depends on the airport and a lot of other things.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  And the security at the airport, security at our embassy – as you know, President Biden, when he made this announcement, he made clear that the only troops, U.S. servicemembers, that would remain in-country were those necessary to safeguard our diplomatic compound in Kabul.  So that is very important to us, and it’s very important to us for one principal reason: because it facilitates that partnership with the Afghan Government and with the Afghan people, and that is something we intend to see continue.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just to follow up on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Any – let’s – before we move onto Afghanistan, anything else on the TIP Report, anything for Dr. Johnstone?  Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Let me give (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, I want to thank you for joining us today, and more importantly, thanks to you and to your team for all of your work in this important product, and very much appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS JOHNSTONE:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Thank you, all.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Before we move into questions, let me just speak to a couple of elements at the top.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, President Biden committed that the United States will be the world’s arsenal of vaccines in the shared fight against COVID-19.  Since then, the administration has taken historic actions and is delivering on that presidential commitment.  Over the past several weeks, we have committed to sharing 580 million doses of vaccines to the world, including of course the 80 million doses of our own surplus U.S. supply.  These 80 million doses have now all been shared with 46 countries, the African Union, and CARICOM through a combination of bilateral sharing and sharing through COVAX.</p>
<p>Each country has received the specific number and type of U.S. vaccines they will be shipped, and by the end of this week, we will have already shipped out about 40 million doses to the Republic of Korea, Mexico, Canada, Brazil, Taiwan, Honduras, Colombia, Pakistan, Peru, Ecuador, Malaysia, and Bangladesh through a combination, again, of bilateral sharing and through COVAX as well.  The remaining doses will be shipped in the coming weeks as countries complete their own domestic set of operational, regulatory, and legal processes.  And we will continue to share even more doses in the summer months and beyond.</p>
<p>Next.  Today the Secretary of State announced the transmittal to Congress of the Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List, a report that’s required by Section 353 of the United States–Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act.  This report lists individuals from Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador who have undermined democratic processes or institutions, who have engaged in significant corruption, or who have obstructed investigations into such acts.</p>
<p>The United States fights for democracy and combats corruption and impunity in support of the people of the region.  The citizens of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador have consistently repudiated corruption, demanded accountability from their governments and private actors, and they’ve acted in defense of democratic institutions.  We stand with all those endeavoring to build a better, more hopeful future in these countries and in the broader region.</p>
<p>As today’s actions demonstrate, there are consequences when individuals – whether government officials or private actors – violate the principles of democracy, rule of law, and transparency that the people of the region deserve and, in fact, expect. The United States will continue to use a range of diplomatic and economic tools, including actions like this one, to shine light on corruption and encourage the strengthening of democratic institutions so that our neighbors in Central America can build brighter futures for their communities.</p>
<p>And finally, as you heard from Secretary Blinken earlier today, today marks the fifth anniversary of the terrorist attack at the Holey Artisan Bakery in Dhaka, Bangladesh, which resulted in the deaths of 20 people, including one U.S. citizen.  We extend our deepest condolences to the loved ones of the victims.  We stand with Bangladesh in our condemnation of terrorism and determination to prevent future such attacks.  We commend Bangladesh’s efforts to bring those responsible to justice and we recommit to our strong counterterrorism partnership to prevent future attacks.</p>
<p>So with that, I’m happy to go back to your questions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Is the U.S. days away from completing the U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan?  And does the President plan any sort of event or speech or travel to mark the withdrawal from Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you for your question.  So I will leave it to the Department of Defense to speak to the retrograde operation.  I know they have been able to provide updates in recent weeks and even recent days.  We&#8217;ve heard from the Pentagon, we&#8217;ve heard from senior DOD officials regarding their activities, their plans.  And most importantly, we&#8217;ve heard from the President, and the President noted earlier this year that it – the United States would be withdrawing militarily from Afghanistan, that withdrawal would be completed by the 20th anniversary of the September 11th attacks, September of this year, 2021.  But beyond that, I&#8217;m going to defer to the Department of Defense to speak to those operations and any detail they might be able to share.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you have any update on the Afghan visas for translators and others and their families?  Has another country agreed – can you give us a progress report on Guam or any other – and related but unrelated issue, the problem of the COVID outbreak among the local staff, I presume, and not FSOs, in Kabul?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Sure, I – first, you have heard from my colleagues in recent days, you have heard from other senior administration officials that this administration has a special responsibility to those brave Afghans who, over the years, have assisted the United States Government in myriad ways, whether acting as interpreters, acting as translators, other officials who have assisted us, often at great risk to themselves, sometime – at times, even to their families.</p>
<p>As we have said, we have identified a group of SIV applicants who have served in these roles, as well as other individuals who have assisted us over the years and who may be at risk.  They and their families will have the option to be relocated to a location outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown by September, as I alluded to before, so that they can complete their SIV process.  Importantly, these are individuals who are already in the SIV pipeline, and we would</p>
<p>— sounds like we may have a storm warning.  I will trust someone will let us know if we are in any imminent danger here. —</p>
<p>And, of course, we would undertake any relocation in full compliance with applicable laws and in full coordination with Congress.  We are engaging regularly with our partners in the interagency.  The State Department is not the only entity involved in this.  There are regular discussions with the Department of Defense, with the White House, with other entities who are involved in this.  I wouldn&#8217;t want to speak to those internal discussions, nor would I want to speak to any diplomatic discussions that may be ongoing with partner countries around the world.</p>
<p>I will also say that we will share information as we are able, consistent with concerns we have for the security of those involved.  Again, our paramount concern is the safety and security of those who have worked with us over the years in Afghanistan.  That is precisely why we have identified a group of applicants who will have the option of being relocated with their families. And, of course, we wouldn&#8217;t want to do anything or share any information that could add to the risk they already face.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Just – there have been reports of a census of perhaps 18,000 people in this category, plus families, making it an overall group of about 70,000.  Would you argue with that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, what we have said is that there are about 18,000 Afghan principal applicants who are at some stage as of right now in the SIV application process.  As of May 2021, about 50 percent of those applicants, or some 9,000 applicants, are at an initial stage of the process pending applicant action.  In other words, approximately 9,000 of these 18,000 applicants need to take some sort of action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case.</p>
<p>Now, we haven&#8217;t attached numbers to the group we have identified for potential relocation, but 18,000 is the aggregate number of principal Afghan applicants who are at some stage of the SIV application process.</p>
<p>And you reminded me that you did ask about the implications of the ongoing COVID outbreak at our embassy in Kabul.  We have issued department guidance for embassy operations worldwide, and consistent with that, Embassy Kabul is operating on a reduced staffing posture.  The embassy, as we’ve said, has suspended visa interviews, but visa processing does not require in-person – but visa processing that does not require in-person interactions with applicants continues.  Of course, much of this also takes place at the chief-of-mission stage, and much of that takes place from Washington.  And we will resume interviewing qualified SIV applicants in Kabul as soon as it’s safe to do so.  The embassy does continue to issue visas to Afghans whose applications are fully approved.</p>
<p>Jessica.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>I have a question:  If the embassy in – closes in Kabul, will the U.S. still be able to provide aid from afar without the embassy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Would we still be able to provide a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Would you still be able to provide aid to the Afghan Government if the embassy in Kabul, for whatever reason, is forced to close?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>So again, it is our intention to maintain a diplomatic presence in Kabul.  As the President said, the only American servicemembers who will remain in Afghanistan are those required to protect the diplomatic presence there.  And that’s because the diplomatic presence is something that enables us, in an effective way, to continue to partner with the Afghan Government and Afghan people.  I wouldn’t want to entertain hypotheticals or contingencies.  Of course, we are planning for any number of contingencies, and I can say that regardless of what happens, our partnership with the Afghan Government, with the Afghan people will not diminish, it will always endure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you have any red lines for – if the shape of the Afghan Government changes, say Ghani falls, you have somebody else emerge – are there any red lines?  Or say the Taliban become the foremost partner – do you have any red lines which could affect the amount of aid or whether or not you provide aid at all?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, of course, it is up to the Afghan people to select their leaders.  What we do know is that the international community and the Afghan people, of course, will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan.  Legitimacy and assistance for any Afghan government can only be possible if that government has the consent of the Afghan people, and critically, I would say, has fundamental respect for human rights.  That is what we know.  Any attempt to install a new Afghan government by force will not be accepted internationally.  It will not be accepted by the Afghan people.  And the United States and our partners around the world will be watching very carefully the human rights situation and the conditions for the Afghan people, who we know have suffered from years of war, years of violence – the gains that have been achieved we know are fragile, and we will be watching very carefully to do all we can to protect those gains, especially for Afghanistan’s girls, its women, its minorities as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>One last clarification:  To say that the Ghani government is no longer on top, will the U.S. still continue to fund money towards government-led or associated factions like, say, the army, maybe schools in government-controlled areas or – if the government falls, does that mean that all of Afghanistan suddenly is cut off?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, again, I wouldn’t want to entertain any hypotheticals or contingencies like that.  Again, what we know is that any government that is installed by force will not be accepted, it will not be considered legitimate, and it will not receive assistance from the international community.  What I can say broadly is that, of course, it is our intention to continue to support the Afghanistan National Defense and Security Forces, the ANDSF.  It right now is a standing force of more than 300,000 Afghan personnel.  Our support, the contours of that support, of course, will change as we transition from a direct train, advise, and assist mission through NATO.  And – but we will continue to provide assistance to the ANDSF going forward.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Very quickly?  Another topic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Couple quick – couple more quick questions on Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>I know we also have an event at 3:45, so I’m mindful of the clock.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Oh &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, you said that the SIV applicants you’ve identified would be moved before the withdrawal, but our reporting indicates that the retrograde will be done within the next coming days.  So how do you square those two?  Is this evacuation imminent or the relocation imminent?  Do you have more of a concrete timeline you can share with us?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, again, I’m going to leave it to the Department of Defense to speak to the timeline of their retrograde operations.  What the President has said is that it would be completed before September, and what we have said is that we have identified a group of applicants who are already in train who will have the option to be relocated outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military withdrawal in September.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you know where they will be relocated, like which countries will help the United States sheltering them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  So as I said before, there are certain details we’ll be in a position to share – and I expect we’ll be a position to share additional details in the coming days and the coming weeks – and there are some details that we may not be able to share because of security concerns.  Again, our paramount concern in all of this, the reason we are offering this option to a group of SIV applicants is out of concern for their safety, their wellbeing.  And so we wouldn’t want to share any details that could potentially jeopardize that.  But as we do have additional details to share, I can assure you we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  I have two questions about Afghanistan and Turkey.  Do you have any concerns that the new designation of Turkey as a country implicated in the use of children as soldiers would have an impact on the ongoing talks between the U.S. and Turkey to guard the international airport in Kabul?</p>
<p>And second question:  With the meeting today between the Secretary Blinken and his Tajik counterpart, what role does the U.S. want Tajikistan and Uzbekistan maybe to play in Afghanistan?  And was any security or military arrangement was discussed during those talks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you for that.  So the Trafficking in Persons Report, the TIP Report, it is not a political document.  It is based on facts.  It is based on analysis and our assessment of those – of that information that we are able to glean from a variety of resources.  That includes reporting from the U.S. Government, classified and unclassified, open-source information, everything that would help to inform our assessment of various governments’ progress or lack thereof when it comes to trafficking in persons.  So I would not want to link the report today with what – the discussions we are engaging in, the constructive discussions we’re engaging in with Turkey in the context of Afghanistan or any other area of shared interest.</p>
<p>As you know, President Biden had a opportunity to meet face to face with President Erdogan not all that long ago, just last month.  And as they’ve said, the – Turkey’s role in Afghanistan was discussed in that context.  Turkey has been a very constructive and very helpful partner when it comes to Afghanistan.  Turkey has been supportive of the diplomacy.  Turkey, of course, is an important NATO Ally, but I wouldn’t want to go beyond that in terms of details of &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So the U.S. is not – is not planning to impose any restrictions on – military restrictions on Turkey over this designation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  So these designations, the implications of them, we will be able to speak to that later this year.  As you know, there are – there is the potential for waivers that would come down from the President, but that will happen, if it does, in the coming months.  I’m not in a position to speak to that at the moment.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Moving on to another topic.  There was a report that the Walla website, Israeli website, that the Israeli Government requested the Biden administration or asked the Biden administration to postpone the reopening of the consulate in East Jerusalem.  Can you enlighten us on what’s happening with that regard, with this issue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Happy to.  So as the Secretary said in Jerusalem – he said this publicly; he also said this privately in his meetings with our Israeli and Palestinian Authority counterparts – but he made very clear that we will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem because it strengthens our ability to do what we have said we intend to do, and that is to rebuild our engagement with the Palestinian Authority and, crucially, with the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>So I don&#8217;t have any private diplomatic conversations to detail for you or to read out, but it remains our intention to move forward with that process.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, I have a couple more questions.  But I wanted to ask you also about the PLO office in Washington.  Any progress on that score?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I don&#8217;t have any update for you there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>You don’t either.  Okay.  Are you in touch with the Palestinian Authority in any way?  Is there any kind of communication ongoing?  There was – there were reports that the PA has submitted like 30 points or something to that effect for negotiations or resuming negotiations.  The PA President Abbas was in Amman yesterday talking to – with the King of Jordan, who is prepared to come to Washington and so on.  Is there something ongoing?  Are you in communication with them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  There is regular engagement with the Palestinian Authority, just as there is regular engagement with our Israeli counterparts.  It is something that happens from this building.  It’s something that happens from within this administration and in regular course.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And finally, I know that you issued a statement last week on the killing of Nizar Banat in custody with the Palestinian Security Forces.  But have you spoken to any Palestinian figures, Palestinian authority figures?  I know that the head of intelligence in – the Palestinians’ intelligence Majed Faraj is very close to perhaps the Intelligence Community in the United States; he’s in regular contact, and so on.  Have you spoken to them?  Because this is apparently a common practice.  It was done time and again.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We have made very clear, Said, that we are deeply disturbed by reports that non-uniformed members of the Palestinian Authority Security Forces harassed and used forced – used force against protesters and journalists during the public demonstrations calling for accountability for the death that you mentioned, the death of Nizar Banat.  We have strongly urged security services and security forces to conduct themselves in a professional manner and to respect freedom of expression, the work of journalists, and the right of Palestinians to protest peacefully.  This is not something – these are not points that are unique to this context for us. These are statements that we make universally around the world as well.</p>
<p>In this particular context, we have noted that the Palestinian Authority has announced the establishment of a commission to investigate Mr. Banat’s death.  As we stated previously, it’s important that the PA conducts a thorough and transparent investigation to ensure full accountability of this case.  We have made those expectations very clear to the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, please, I have two quick questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Michel, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>One on Morocco.  Brett McGurk, White House National Security Council coordinator for the Middle East, was quoted saying that the U.S. has no intention of reversing its recognition of Morocco’s sovereignty over Western Sahara.  Is this the administration position now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>It remains the administration position.  I don&#8217;t have any update for you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Are you changing in U.S. policy towards this recognition?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>There is no change.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And one on Lebanon – I&#8217;ve been asking about this since the meeting that the Secretary held in Italy with the Saudi foreign minister and the French foreign minister:  What was the goal of this meeting and why you didn&#8217;t have any answer on this request for two, three days?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well (inaudible) we did issue a tweet noting the meeting.  The tweet also did discuss some of the substance of the meeting.  These are two governments that have – with whom we share interests when it comes to Lebanon.  I think broadly we have made very clear in our engagement with other interested parties, including the Saudis, including the French, including any number of other governments around the world, that our expectation is that Lebanon&#8217;s leaders show sufficient flexibility to form a government that is willing and capable of, importantly, true and fundamental reform so that the Lebanese people can realize their full potential.</p>
<p>The Lebanese people, we have long said, deserve a government that will urgently implement the necessary reforms to rescue the country&#8217;s deteriorating economy.  The humanitarian conditions for the people of Lebanon are increasingly dire.  The Lebanese economy is in crisis, and that is chiefly because of decades of corruption, of mismanagement by Lebanon&#8217;s political leaders. We continue to call upon them to put aside their partisan brinksmanship, to change course, and to work for the common good of their people, of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>The international community has been clear that concrete actions remain absolutely crucial to unlocking longer-term structural support for Lebanon.  All of this was discussed in the trilateral meeting with Secretary Blinken and his French and Saudi counterparts.  There is shared international interest in seeing stability brought to Lebanon, in humanitarian relief provided to the Lebanese people, and affording and equipping the Lebanese people with a government that they deserve, chiefly a government that serves their interests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes, Rich.  Yup.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Just wondering if the Secretary or the administration had paid note to President Xi Jinping’s address, using some fairly aggressive language towards the West and in general, like heads bashed against the bloody great wall of steel.  Was the administration surprised?  Was there a concern about the tenor of the address?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, of course, we’re aware that the Chinese Communist Party commemorated its 100th anniversary today.  We&#8217;re aware of President Xi&#8217;s remarks.  We’ve taken note on them, but we&#8217;re not going to comment on the specifics.  I think this administration, over the course of several months, has been very clear about our impressions of the CCP in general, but I don’t have a specific response for you on President Xi&#8217;s remarks today.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>I wanted to follow up on the Joby Warrick report in the – in <em>The Washington Post</em>, excuse me – about 100 missile silos being detected, which would be an extraordinary number or total, according to the Monterey experts, 145 across China out of a fairly small nuclear arsenal.  What do you think their intention is?  What is your analysis on that?  And whether you have any further comment on the crackdown in Hong Kong of <em>Apple Daily</em>.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>On the crackdown in Hong Kong?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Of <em>Apple Daily.</em></p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>So let me start with your first question and the reported build-up, the article that was in <em>The Washington Post</em>, the independent analysis that has been done.  I think what is fair to say is that these reports and other developments suggest that the PRC’s nuclear arsenal will grow more quickly, and to a higher level than perhaps previously anticipated.  This buildup – it is concerning.  It raises questions about the PRC’s intent.  And for us, it reinforces the importance of pursuing practical measures to reduce nuclear risks.  Despite what appears to be PRC obfuscation, this rapid buildup has become more difficult to hide, and it highlights how the PRC appears, again, to be deviating from decades of nuclear strategy based around minimum deterrents.</p>
<p>These advances, again, to our minds highlight why it’s in everyone’s interests that nuclear powers talk to one another directly about reducing nuclear dangers and avoiding miscalculations.  We encourage Beijing to engage with us on practical measures to reduce the risks of destabilizing arms races, potential – potentially destabilizing tensions.  This is precisely why President Biden prioritized strategic stability in his engagement with President Putin.  The same basis, the same rationale would apply to engagement with another nuclear power, the PRC.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  If I may, can we have a comment about Switzerland, which decided to buy the F-35 jets?  It’s a 6.5 billion contract.  And how will this contract impact the relationship between the United States and Switzerland, which is a neutral country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, we do welcome the Federal Council’s decision announced yesterday in its Air 2030 defense procurement competition.  The United States is proud to have provided Switzerland with world-class air defense products over quite a bit of time, over the past five decades, respecting Swiss sovereignty in the process, supporting Swiss national security, and partnering with Switzerland on economic and technological advancements.</p>
<p>We look forward to building on that proven record of success and deepening that partnership to our mutual benefit – to the benefit of Switzerland, to the benefit of the United States following this week’s announcement.  We do appreciate the opportunity we were given to participate in this competition, and we stand ready for our governments to work together not only in the course of this contract, but of course, for decades to come.  We offer our congratulations to the aircraft makers and others who were involved in this competition, and we look forward to deepening that partnership.</p>
<p>I’m mindful of the clock because we do have a bilateral engagement coming up.  I’ll take a couple more questions here.  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On Lebanon?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Lebanon?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Lebanon.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Lebanon, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Three days ago, the Secretary met with Pope Francis, and Lebanon was on the agenda, we understood.  And today, the Vatican is convening a summit to discuss Lebanon crisis.  Did that summit topic come up during the Secretary and the pope conversation, knowing that the head of the Catholic Church in Lebanon who was attending this summit is pushing toward internationalizing this crisis?  Do you have anything to comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, we issued a readout of the Secretary’s meeting with his holiness the pope.  It was a meeting that, as I believe we said, lasted for some 40 minutes.  It was wide-ranging.  They discussed the plight of the world’s most vulnerable, of the world’s most disadvantaged, and Lebanon was a topic during that conversation.  As I noted before in response to a different question, the people of Lebanon have suffered tremendously because of corruption, because of mismanagement, because of political infighting in their country, and the humanitarian toll has been especially devastating.</p>
<p>So it’s no surprise that the humanitarian conditions there and the need to provide much-needed relief to the people of Lebanon did feature in that one-on-one discussion between the Secretary and Pope Francis.</p>
<p>Yes, Jenny.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is the State Department involved in the response to the condo collapse in Florida given the number of foreign nationals who are believed to be impacted?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, of course, Miami is truly an international city, and we’ve seen that reflected in some of the tragic stories emanating from the Surfside condo collapse.  It’s a city that represents this hemisphere and well beyond.  And so it also stands to reason that the department has been engaged in supporting foreign missions in their efforts to locate and to assist their citizens who may have been in some way involved or implicated in the partial collapse of the Champlain Towers in Surfside last week.</p>
<p>The department is on the ground.  We are working closely with local, with state, with federal and foreign mission personnel in conjunction with other interagency partners to assist in response to this tragedy.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  I have two questions.  A follow-up on the Western Sahara:  You said the U.S. is not planning to reverse the recognition of the Western Sahara’s Morocco land.  So the question is:  How does the U.S. view the Moroccan proposal for autonomy for that disputed area?  And is the U.S. planning to launch a new diplomatic effort to find maybe an – a solution to this issue?</p>
<p>And second, on Yemen, in light of the strong condemnation yesterday from the State Department over the ongoing military offensive by the Houthis in Marib, is the U.S. fed up with the Houthi stance not to engage in the diplomatic effort?  And is the U.S. planning to maybe adopt a drastic approach against the Houthis if they decided not to engage in the U.S. or in the international diplomatic efforts to find a solution to the crisis in Yemen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Well, when it comes to Morocco and the Western Sahara, as I said before, we don’t have any updates in terms of the United States recognition of Moroccan sovereignty.</p>
<p>When it comes to the broader issue, what I’ll say is that we do support a credible UN-led political process to stabilize the situation and to secure a cessation of any hostilities.  We are consulting with the parties, we are consulting with other governments in the region and beyond, about how best to bring a halt to the violence and ultimately to achieve a lasting settlement to this long-running conflict.  We strongly support UN efforts to appoint a personal envoy of the secretary-general for the Western Sahara and to do that as quickly as possible, and we’re prepared to continue to be actively engaged with all sides in support of that individual.</p>
<p>When it comes to Yemen, you asked if we are fed up with the Houthi attacks.  The answer to that is yes.  We are beyond fed up.  We are horrified by the repeated attacks on Marib.  We strongly condemn the Houthi missile attack on a residential neighborhood in Marib on June 29th.  It took civilian lives, including the life of a child.  We believe it is long past time to end the conflict in Yemen and to provide immediate relief to the Yemeni people.</p>
<p>What we know is that the Houthis’ offensive in Marib is exacerbating the humanitarian crisis faced by the people of Yemen.  It is by many accounts home to the world’s worst humanitarian catastrophe.  For the Houthis to continue this brutal offensive while there is a serious proposal before them, a proposal that would meet their long-held and stated demands for a plan with practical steps to facilitate the flow of goods into and within Yemen, implement a nationwide ceasefire, and initiate inclusive political talks – that is what separates the Houthis from other Yemenis who are actively working towards peace, who strike us as being serious about peace.</p>
<p>What concerns us is the loss of life.  What concerns us is the fact that this offensive continues to set back the process for a durable political solution to this long-running conflict.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  North Korea.  Briefly, do you have any comment on the Kim Jong-un diet?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And the serious implications, obviously.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I don’t have any particular comment on that.  As you know, Andrea, we have completed a review of our policy towards the DPRK.  It’s a policy that is predicated first and foremost on diminishing the threat to our interests in the region, to our partners who are in the region, and it’s a policy that’s predicated on the utility of diplomacy.  We believe that through practical, clear-eyed engagement with our allies and partners and with the DPRK we can achieve progress on what remains our goal, and that is ultimately the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  That’s what we’re focused on.  It &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Any response to that policy review and to the initiatives, to the overtures?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Look, we have made very clear our willingness to sit down anytime, anywhere with representatives of the DPRK.  Ambassador Kim, our special envoy for the DPRK, has recently been in the Republic of Korea, where he met with South Korean officials, where he met trilaterally with South Korean and Japanese officials.  He reiterated there that we are prepared anytime, anywhere to engage in diplomacy with the DPRK, and we are awaiting a constructive response from the DPRK.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, everyone.  Sorry we need to cut this short.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:45 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland Travel to Paraguay, Panama, and El Salvador</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-of-state-for-political-affairs-victoria-nuland-travel-to-paraguay-panama-and-el-salvador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 22:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and an interagency delegation, including representatives from the National Security Council, the Department of Defense, and the U.S. Southern Command, visited Paraguay, Panama, and El Salvador from June 27-30.  The delegation met with Paraguayan President Mario Abdo Benitez, Paraguayan Foreign Minister Euclides Acevedo, and other cabinet members; with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Acting Foreign Minister Dayra Carrizo, as well as the Panama Canal Administrator Ricaurte Vásquez; and with Salvadoran President Nayib Bukele, Foreign Minister Alexandra Hill Tinoco, and other Salvadoran leaders.  They also met with successful young innovators, entrepreneurs, and other civil society leaders in the three countries to discuss their visions for the future.</p>
<p>During her trip, Under Secretary of State Nuland:</p>
<ul>
<li>Relaunched the U.S.-Paraguay Strategic Partnership Dialogue, which last met in 2016, to expand bilateral coordination on issues of mutual interest, including democracy and security, trade and investment, development and good governance, and cooperation with likeminded partners like Taiwan.</li>
<li>Announced the U.S. donation of one million Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine doses to Paraguay, with additional vaccine donations to Panama and El Salvador in the coming weeks. This is in addition to $2 billion in funding and additional vaccine donations to Gavi, which supported procurement and delivery of vaccines through COVAX the COVID-19 vaccine-sharing facility, for worldwide distribution.</li>
<li>Announced an agreement between Banco Sudameris and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), and a parallel agreement with Citibank, for $125 million of financing for Paraguayan Small and Medium Enterprises to focus on enabling women-owned and led businesses as well as those that benefit women, with 30 percent of DFC loan proceeds going to this purpose.</li>
<li>Announced the start of talks to establish a network of Small Business Development Centers in Paraguay to provide counseling and services to help small businesses grow and create jobs.</li>
<li>In a meeting with President Laurentino Cortizo, advanced our partnership with Panama to manage the ongoing challenges of irregular migration and forced displacement in and through the region.</li>
<li>Emphasized the importance of data privacy and customer trust in maintaining regional technological infrastructure integrity with Panamanian telecommunications sector leaders, recognizing Panama’s development toward serving as a digital hub for the region.</li>
<li>Reaffirmed the close relationship between the United States and Panama on key issues of climate change, and environmental preservation. Panama remains a leader in the region for championing the environment, and their aggressive climate goals make them the ideal hosts for the Energy and Climate Partnership of the Americas (ECPA) Ministerial in 2022 and the Our Ocean Conference in 2023.</li>
<li>Underscored U.S. support for Panama’s efforts to combat illicit finance, particularly through the joint Anti-Money Laundering and Anti-Corruption Task Force,</li>
<li>In El Salvador, reinforced U.S. support for strong democratic institutions, transparency, and rule of law in meetings with Salvadoran President Bukele Foreign Minister Hill, and in roundtables with civil society and with young Salvadoran political leaders.</li>
<li>Engaged with Salvadoran entrepreneurs on job creation and investment in the region to address one of the root causes of irregular migration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and an interagency delegation, including representatives from the National Security Council, the Department of Defense, and the U.S. Southern Command, visited Paraguay, Panama, and El Salvador from June 27-30.  The delegation met with Paraguayan President Mario Abdo Benitez, Paraguayan Foreign Minister Euclides Acevedo, and other cabinet members; with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Acting Foreign Minister Dayra Carrizo, as well as the Panama Canal Administrator Ricaurte Vásquez; and with Salvadoran President Nayib Bukele, Foreign Minister Alexandra Hill Tinoco, and other Salvadoran leaders.  They also met with successful young innovators, entrepreneurs, and other civil society leaders in the three countries to discuss their visions for the future.</p>
<p>During her trip, Under Secretary of State Nuland:</p>
<ul>
<li>Relaunched the U.S.-Paraguay Strategic Partnership Dialogue, which last met in 2016, to expand bilateral coordination on issues of mutual interest, including democracy and security, trade and investment, development and good governance, and cooperation with likeminded partners like Taiwan.</li>
<li>Announced the U.S. donation of one million Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine doses to Paraguay, with additional vaccine donations to Panama and El Salvador in the coming weeks. This is in addition to $2 billion in funding and additional vaccine donations to Gavi, which supported procurement and delivery of vaccines through COVAX the COVID-19 vaccine-sharing facility, for worldwide distribution.</li>
<li>Announced an agreement between Banco Sudameris and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), and a parallel agreement with Citibank, for $125 million of financing for Paraguayan Small and Medium Enterprises to focus on enabling women-owned and led businesses as well as those that benefit women, with 30 percent of DFC loan proceeds going to this purpose.</li>
<li>Announced the start of talks to establish a network of Small Business Development Centers in Paraguay to provide counseling and services to help small businesses grow and create jobs.</li>
<li>In a meeting with President Laurentino Cortizo, advanced our partnership with Panama to manage the ongoing challenges of irregular migration and forced displacement in and through the region.</li>
<li>Emphasized the importance of data privacy and customer trust in maintaining regional technological infrastructure integrity with Panamanian telecommunications sector leaders, recognizing Panama’s development toward serving as a digital hub for the region.</li>
<li>Reaffirmed the close relationship between the United States and Panama on key issues of climate change, and environmental preservation. Panama remains a leader in the region for championing the environment, and their aggressive climate goals make them the ideal hosts for the Energy and Climate Partnership of the Americas (ECPA) Ministerial in 2022 and the Our Ocean Conference in 2023.</li>
<li>Underscored U.S. support for Panama’s efforts to combat illicit finance, particularly through the joint Anti-Money Laundering and Anti-Corruption Task Force,</li>
<li>In El Salvador, reinforced U.S. support for strong democratic institutions, transparency, and rule of law in meetings with Salvadoran President Bukele Foreign Minister Hill, and in roundtables with civil society and with young Salvadoran political leaders.</li>
<li>Engaged with Salvadoran entrepreneurs on job creation and investment in the region to address one of the root causes of irregular migration.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Muhriddin</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-tajikistan-foreign-minister-muhriddin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 22:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin in Washington, D.C.  The Secretary welcomed the eighth iteration of the U.S.-Tajik Annual Bilateral Consultations held today at the State Department.  The Secretary reaffirmed the strength and importance of the U.S.-Tajikistan bilateral relationship and expressed his appreciation for Foreign Minister Muhriddin’s continued leadership on regional security issues.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister agreed that a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan would advance regional economic growth and integration.  The Secretary expressed a desire for further bilateral collaboration on promoting human rights and fundamental freedoms as well as economic development, and affirmed the U.S. commitment to Tajikistan’s security, stability, and territorial integrity.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin in Washington, D.C.  The Secretary welcomed the eighth iteration of the U.S.-Tajik Annual Bilateral Consultations held today at the State Department.  The Secretary reaffirmed the strength and importance of the U.S.-Tajikistan bilateral relationship and expressed his appreciation for Foreign Minister Muhriddin’s continued leadership on regional security issues.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister agreed that a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan would advance regional economic growth and integration.  The Secretary expressed a desire for further bilateral collaboration on promoting human rights and fundamental freedoms as well as economic development, and affirmed the U.S. commitment to Tajikistan’s security, stability, and territorial integrity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Uzbekistan Foreign Minister Kamilov</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-uzbekistan-foreign-minister-kamilov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 22:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Today in Washington, D.C., Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Uzbekistan’s Foreign Minister Abdulaziz Kamilov.  The Secretary expressed the United States’ desire to deepen its strategic partnership with Uzbekistan, noting that the two countries celebrate 30 years of diplomatic relations this year.  The Secretary offered support for Uzbekistan’s continuing reforms, including strengthening human rights and democracy.  The Secretary commended Uzbekistan’s initiatives to improve relations within Central Asia, noting the two countries’ active cooperation through the C5+1 regional diplomatic platform.  The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Uzbekistan&#8217;s continued support for a just and durable peace settlement in Afghanistan.  He also welcomed Uzbekistan&#8217;s focus on regional connectivity, including closer political and economic cooperation with Afghanistan in ways that would support prosperity and growth across Central and South Asia.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Today in Washington, D.C., Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Uzbekistan’s Foreign Minister Abdulaziz Kamilov.  The Secretary expressed the United States’ desire to deepen its strategic partnership with Uzbekistan, noting that the two countries celebrate 30 years of diplomatic relations this year.  The Secretary offered support for Uzbekistan’s continuing reforms, including strengthening human rights and democracy.  The Secretary commended Uzbekistan’s initiatives to improve relations within Central Asia, noting the two countries’ active cooperation through the C5+1 regional diplomatic platform.  The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Uzbekistan&#8217;s continued support for a just and durable peace settlement in Afghanistan.  He also welcomed Uzbekistan&#8217;s focus on regional connectivity, including closer political and economic cooperation with Afghanistan in ways that would support prosperity and growth across Central and South Asia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Uzbek Foreign Minister Abdulaziz Kamilov Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-uzbek-foreign-minister-abdulaziz-kamilov-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 21:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon.  I am very pleased to have Foreign Minister Kamilov here today.  We’ve spoken several times on the phone and by videoconference, but it’s very good to actually have you here in person.</p>
<p>A lot of good and important work being done this week on the vital relationship between the United States and Uzbekistan.  We have strong shared interests when it comes to security in the region, particularly with regard to Afghanistan.  Uzbekistan has been a leader in bringing countries in the region together, particularly with regard to economic and infrastructure connectivity, something else that we’ll talk about, as well as the bilateral relationship between our countries.</p>
<p>So welcome.  It’s very good to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER KAMILOV:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  First of all, I’d like to thank Mr. Secretary, Secretary Blinken, for inviting our interagency delegation of the Republic of Uzbekistan.  We have a broad agenda during this visit, and we are going to exchange views on the state and the future of our bilateral relations, as well as we will pay serious attention to the situation in the region, in Central Asia.</p>
<p>And a lot has been changing in the world and in the region, and that’s why, as Mr. Secretary said, of course, we will exchange views on the situation in Afghanistan, too.  And we have a lot of issues, a lot to speak about, and that’s why I’d like once again to thank the American friends we invite throughout the region.<strong>  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon.  I am very pleased to have Foreign Minister Kamilov here today.  We’ve spoken several times on the phone and by videoconference, but it’s very good to actually have you here in person.</p>
<p>A lot of good and important work being done this week on the vital relationship between the United States and Uzbekistan.  We have strong shared interests when it comes to security in the region, particularly with regard to Afghanistan.  Uzbekistan has been a leader in bringing countries in the region together, particularly with regard to economic and infrastructure connectivity, something else that we’ll talk about, as well as the bilateral relationship between our countries.</p>
<p>So welcome.  It’s very good to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER KAMILOV:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  First of all, I’d like to thank Mr. Secretary, Secretary Blinken, for inviting our interagency delegation of the Republic of Uzbekistan.  We have a broad agenda during this visit, and we are going to exchange views on the state and the future of our bilateral relations, as well as we will pay serious attention to the situation in the region, in Central Asia.</p>
<p>And a lot has been changing in the world and in the region, and that’s why, as Mr. Secretary said, of course, we will exchange views on the situation in Afghanistan, too.  And we have a lot of issues, a lot to speak about, and that’s why I’d like once again to thank the American friends we invite throughout the region.<strong>  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report Launch Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-2021-trafficking-in-persons-report-launch-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Good afternoon, and welcome. My name is Kari Johnstone. I am the acting director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining us virtually to mark the release of the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report, or the TIP Report. I am grateful to be here with Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>A quick word about our program today: First, Secretary Blinken will offer remarks on this year’s report. We will then honor this year’s eight wonderful TIP Report Heroes, who have dedicated their lives to combat human trafficking, and we will hear briefly from each of them in a pre-recorded video. I will offer brief closing remarks and then we hope you will click over to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access the report online.</p>
<p>I would like to start by thanking our colleagues across the State Department, including our overseas embassies, for the strong collaboration and time spent to produce an accurate and comprehensive report. And I want to give a second thank you – a special thank you and kudos to the staff of the Trafficking in Persons Office for your dedication and commitment. Your long hours and hard work producing this report make a difference. And finally, thank you to our colleagues across the U.S. Government as well as our vital partners in NGOs and international organizations, those with lived experience of human trafficking, and other experts who contributed to the TIP Report and work to facilitate progress in addressing human trafficking year-round.</p>
<p>And it is now such an honor to join Secretary Blinken here today. Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for elevating the issue of human trafficking and for hosting today’s event. Under your leadership, we look forward to advancing our efforts to combat human trafficking.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Thank you, Kari. Thank you very much for that introduction, but especially thank you for the terrific work leading the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons here at State. You and your team – and I know some of the team members are here with us today – did exceptional work producing this year’s report under the difficult circumstances of COVID-19.</p>
<p>Thanks to everyone else who&#8217;s here for joining us for what is a very important occasion. And a special thank you to the Heroes that we&#8217;re celebrating today, women and men around the world who have dedicated their careers to stopping human trafficking. They’re advocates, public servants, leaders of NGOs, and they help stop trafficking in all kinds of ways by supporting victims, helping to bring traffickers to justice, creating national action plans, addressing the root causes of trafficking.</p>
<p>In many ways, the fight against trafficking is fought on the local level, one community at a time. And we celebrate the brave people leading the fight, often at great risk to themselves. Trafficking in persons is an appalling crime. It&#8217;s a global crisis; it&#8217;s an enormous source of human suffering. By its nature, it&#8217;s often hidden from view. Exact figures are sometimes hard to determine. The estimate we often cite is that nearly 25 million people worldwide are victims of human trafficking. Many are compelled into commercial sex work. Many are forced to work in factories or fields, or to join armed groups. Millions of trafficking victims are children.</p>
<p>This crime is an affront to human rights; it&#8217;s an affront to human dignity. We fight it, you fight it, because it&#8217;s the right thing to do. It&#8217;s also in our interest to stop trafficking. We know it&#8217;s destabilizing to societies and to economies. So we must do everything we can as a country, but also as a global community, to stop trafficking wherever it occurs.</p>
<p>The State Department&#8217;s Trafficking in Persons Report is indeed the world&#8217;s most comprehensive resource of the anti-trafficking efforts being undertaken by governments around the globe. It reflects the United States longstanding commitment and bipartisan commitment to this issue. We see it from administration to administration, we see it in Congress, and it&#8217;s something that we should take pride in. It’s the product of a great deal of work by our team here in Washington, our embassies around the world, and by NGOs, by journalists, academics, and survivors who help us to identify and document trends in human trafficking so that governments worldwide can more effectively combat it.</p>
<p>Part of this report is our country data. This year, we assessed 188 countries, including the United States. Some made encouraging progress; some slid backward. It&#8217;s important to remember that progress against trafficking is rarely linear. Traffickers are constantly adapting their methods, and every country, including the United States, must keep adapting our own strategies to stay ahead of them. We&#8217;ve got to identify and acknowledge our own shortcomings and be willing to course correct when needed. The TIP Report can help us do that by laying out the significant steps the United States and other countries must take to fight this crime and protect victims.</p>
<p>In addition to the country data, this year’s report explores a few topics in depth. The first is the impact of COVID-19. In many places, as governments diverted resources to try to control the pandemic and address its secondary impacts, human traffickers seized the opportunity to grow their operations. People who were pushed into dire economic circumstances by the pandemic became more vulnerable to exploitation. And as more people spent hours online for school and work, traffickers used the internet to groom and recruit potential victims.</p>
<p>So the pandemic has had a real impact on this fight. It’s another reason why it’s so important to stop the pandemic as quickly as we can and help communities around the world. The longer it takes, the more people will become vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>We applaud those governments that found ways to step up their work against trafficking even during COVID. For example, in Paraguay, as thousands of citizens abroad sought to return home, the government established temporary quarantine facilities at the border. They asked everyone screening questions, and through those questions they were able to identify nearly 300 victims of human trafficking. That’s nearly four times the average number of victims they had identified in previous years. Then the Paraguayan Government moved those victims to their own dedicated facilities, where they began receiving critical health and social support services right away. It was a brilliant strategy for moving fast to help victims of trafficking when the opportunity presented itself.</p>
<p>Second, this year’s report focuses on state-sponsored human trafficking. We documented 11 countries where the government itself is the trafficker – for example, through forced labor on public work projects or in sectors of the economy that the government feels are particularly important.</p>
<p>For the 10th year in a row, the report documents how the Cuban Government has profited from exploitative overseas medical missions. They send doctors and other medical personnel abroad, fail to inform them of the terms of their contracts, confiscate their documents and salaries, threaten them and their family members when they try to leave.</p>
<p>We also report on what’s happening in Xinjiang, in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of China. The Chinese Government has detained more than 1 million people in as many as 1,200 state-run internment camps throughout Xinjiang. Many detainees are subjected to physical violence, sexual abuse, and torture to induce them to work producing apparel, electronics, solar equipment, agricultural products.</p>
<p>And while the practices are the most egregious in Xinjiang, this year’s report notes that China has subjected its citizens to coercive labor practices in other parts of the country as well. The United States has taken measures to stop Chinese goods made with forced labor from making their way into our country. For example, last year, the Departments of State, Commerce, Treasury, and Homeland Security issued a Xinjiang supply chain business advisory to alert U.S. companies of the economic, legal, and reputational exposure to or in connection with operations, supply chains, or laborers from Xinjiang.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to call on our partners around the world to join us in condemning China’s genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and in taking steps to prevent goods made with forced labor from entering our supply chains. Governments should protect and serve their citizens, not terrorize and subjugate them for profit.</p>
<p>And third, the report explicitly acknowledges the connection between systemic inequality and human trafficking. This is something many countries need to grapple with, including the United States. Part of doing right by our people means taking a hard look at the ways that our history and our policies have created the conditions for crimes like human trafficking, because traffickers prey on those who are vulnerable – those who are less likely to have access to good jobs or educational opportunities, who are less likely to be treated as equal by police or the justice system, and who are less likely to be believed when they report that they’re being targeted or abused.</p>
<p>If we’re serious about ending trafficking in persons, we must also work to root out systemic racism, sexism, and other forms of discrimination, and to build a more equitable society in every dimension. These goals go hand in hand. So let’s keep that in mind as we work to build back better from the devastation of the pandemic.</p>
<p>I often talked about how the most urgent challenges facing our world cannot be solved by any one country acting alone. That’s true for stopping COVID, it’s true for dealing with the climate crisis, it’s true for the fight against human trafficking. We need to work together, share information, hold each other accountable. That’s how we’ll create a world where no one is exploited by trafficking and everyone is able to live in safety and in dignity.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for your strong message and those encouraging words. You have long been a champion for anchoring U.S. foreign policy on ensuring human dignity and expanding opportunities for all.</p>
<p>I am thrilled to now turn to celebrating the 2021 TIP Report Heroes. Traditionally we have honored these Heroes in-person at this event. While we wish we could be together, due to COVID-19 precautions, our Heroes are joining us virtually again this year.</p>
<p>To get to know each of our honorees better, we asked this year’s Heroes to prepare short videos answering: “What do you hope to achieve through your anti-trafficking work?” In the following video, you will hear their responses. I am certain you will understand why we are honoring each of them today.</p>
<p>Please join me as we recognize and honor this year’s eight TIP Report Heroes.</p>
<p>(Video is played.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Imelda Poole, in recognition of her exceptional activism in combating human trafficking in Albania and across Europe that has achieved systemic change through grassroots action, employing big picture solutions to address the root causes of vulnerability to the crime, and empowering those with lived experience through her organization’s principles of freedom, justice, truth, and joy.</p>
<p><b>MS POOLE:</b> Hello. My name is Imelda Poole. Working with Mary Ward Loreto in Albania and RENATE across Europe, my dream for the future is a social economy with a change in law and its implementation which will adopt a trauma-informed, victim-centered, and human rights approach to the law, both in its practice and in terms of real life. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, in recognition of her herculean efforts in creating and driving the Central African Republic’s anti-trafficking response by operationalizing the country’s interagency committee, leading the development of the government’s first national action plan to combat human trafficking, and catalyzing action even in difficult conditions at often great personal sacrifice.</p>
<p><b>MS BEMAKA-SOUI:</b> (Via translation) I am Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, Advisor to the President on the Protection of Children and Child Soldiers. With this award, my goal will be to completely eradicate human trafficking in the Central African Republic and establish a new legal code on protection of victims of human trafficking in my country.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Chantal Sagbo Sasse, in recognition of her unwavering and heartfelt commitment to the protection and care of child trafficking victims, her creativity and persistence in raising awareness among community members and government officials about human trafficking, and her invaluable anti-trafficking contributions and expertise shared with the Government of Gabon.</p>
<p><b>MS SAGBO:</b> (Via translation) Hello, everyone. I am Chantal Sagbo, president and founder of the NGO Sifos. Sifos is a non-profit organization that has worked over the last 20 years to promote and protect human rights. Our biggest focus is fighting human trafficking and exploitation. Our vision for 2022 is to build an education and training center for victims, so that they can become the leaders of tomorrow. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shoichi Ibusuki, in recognition of his relentless persistence in advocating for the rights of foreign workers in Japan by providing legal representation to many who experienced exploitation, including forced labor, and by elevating the issue and insisting that the government strengthen its efforts to protect foreign workers.</p>
<p><b>MR IBUSUKI:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Ibusuki Shoichi from Tokyo. I am an attorney. Japan’s Technical Intern Training Program is a hotbed of human trafficking and intermediary exploitation. We aim to have this program abolished within the next few years. We will also create conditions where foreign workers can join together and insist on their rights. We will fight together with likeminded people around the world to fight human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shakhnoza Khassanova, in recognition of her extraordinary leadership in building the organizational capacity of civil society organizations and the judicial system in Kazakhstan to combat human trafficking, her central role in orchestrating humanitarian assistance and ensuring safe migration during the COVID-19 pandemic, and her steadfast dedication to the protection of vulnerable populations.</p>
<p><b>MS KHASSANOVA: </b> I’m Shakhnoza Khassanova, director of the public association, Legal Center for Women’s Initiatives, Sana Sezim, from Shymkent, Kazakhstan. It’s an honor to receive this prestigious Department of State TIP Hero Report Award. This award is a result of the ongoing joint effort of our team and all stakeholders who continue to provide assistance to migrant workers and victims of human trafficking during the pandemic. We hope that our cooperation in future will become stronger and continue contributing to fight against human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, in recognition of her resolute determination to hold human traffickers in Mexico accountable for their crimes, her persistent efforts to secure funding for the creation of multidisciplinary shelters for human trafficking victims, and her longstanding, dynamic leadership in the Attorney General’s Office.</p>
<p><b>MS CABRERA FIGUEROA:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, Specialized Prosecutor for Trafficking in Persons at the Office of the Attorney General of Mexico. In the coming years, through my work fighting human trafficking, I hope to: strengthen my team with more training and resources; rescue more victims and give them specialized care so they can reintegrate into society; and bring more perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Mohammed al-Obaidly, in recognition of his pivotal leadership in the ongoing implementation of bold and sweeping reforms in Qatar to strengthen protections for foreign workers and prevent forced labor, his perseverance to instill real changes, and his tireless efforts to enhance collaboration and forge connections with workers, the business community, and foreign governments.</p>
<p><b>MR AL-OBAIDLY: </b> (Via translation) Hello. My name is Mohammed Hasan al-Obaidly. In the area of combating human trafficking, I would like to develop a guide for the country to identify trafficking in persons victims and provide them with assistance and protection. I also would like to enhance international cooperation and coordination to combat this crime by creating an integrated international law enforcement and security system to prevent, detect and expose human trafficking crimes and bring their perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Rocio Mora-Nieto,<b> </b>in recognition of her exceptional dedication and efforts to combat sex trafficking in Spain for more than a quarter of a century, her unparalleled compassion and commitment for women exploited in commercial sex, and her highly effective outreach and victim-centered provision of services for victims of human trafficking.<b></b></p>
<p><b>MS NIETO:</b> (Via translation) I am Rocio Mora Nieto. I am the director of APRAMP Madrid, in Spain. I am very grateful for this award because it makes slavery visible. The slavery of thousands and thousands of women who are being trafficked for sexual exploitation. For me, it is crucial to give these women alternatives so that they can escape from this situation and have freedom and dignity in their lives so that no woman is a slave in our streets and in our industrial parks. Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> What an inspiring group of leaders. It is such an honor to celebrate your important work.</p>
<p>The TIP Report represents a key tool to effect positive change and encourage governments to increase and improve their anti-trafficking efforts. This includes the United States.</p>
<p>As we evaluated the ongoing impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on anti-trafficking efforts around the world for this year’s report, it was impossible to ignore the pandemic’s devastating effects. In the chaos and hardship of the last year, we have also seen excellent examples of leadership, resilience, adaptability across the anti-trafficking community – from international organizations to local NGOs, governments, and survivor leaders.</p>
<p>Mexico secured its first trafficking in persons conviction from a virtual court session in June 2020, just weeks after resuming legal proceedings following a two-month shutdown.</p>
<p>In Albania, Senegal, and Jordan, COVID-19 mitigation measures were combined with strategic outreach to populations vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>In addition to these great adaptations, I want to highlight another excellent resource that the department will release in the coming weeks – a guidance document on COVID-19 considerations for anti-trafficking efforts – developed by our Human Trafficking Expert Consultant Network, which comprises individuals with lived experience of human trafficking and other subject matter experts. This guide will include promising practices and helpful standard operating procedures to continue anti-trafficking efforts during a crisis – like this pandemic – while still integrating a trauma-informed approach. Considerable work remains to address the challenges we still face related to the pandemic, but we hope this guidance will advance the integration of a trauma-informed approach into any new crisis-related adaptations.</p>
<p>For the last few years, we have sought to increasingly highlight through our report the importance of governments engaging with survivors and implementing trauma-informed approaches when doing so. We have done so, and our report is all the stronger for it. For the second year, Network experts developed the “Topics of Special Interest” for this year’s report – one about the unique complexities in familial trafficking and another about unifying trauma-informed practices and survivor leadership.</p>
<p>The Network also helped us evaluate and improve the process we use to select photos for the TIP Report. We did this in response to recommendations made in previous years by experts with lived experience of human trafficking. You will notice as you flip through the introduction that there are more photos that include the input of those survivors being photographed. I know we still have a long way to go to truly realize a trauma-informed approach across our anti-trafficking efforts, but I am thankful for the Network experts who helped us to make concrete improvements this year. We will continue to raise the importance of survivor engagement in building a truly effective, comprehensive anti-trafficking response – not just on paper through the TIP Report – but in our year-round engagement with governments around the world.</p>
<p>We know that we can do even better, and we will seek to hold ourselves and – accountable and be transparent in our efforts. I am encouraged by the innovative adaptations of governments, NGOs, and survivor leaders to ensure that our anti-trafficking response is comprehensive and addresses issues as they arise. I look forward to working with all of you to continue the fight against human trafficking.</p>
<p>Thank you again for joining us today, and please remember to go to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access this year’s TIP Report online. Thank you all.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Good afternoon, and welcome. My name is Kari Johnstone. I am the acting director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining us virtually to mark the release of the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report, or the TIP Report. I am grateful to be here with Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>A quick word about our program today: First, Secretary Blinken will offer remarks on this year’s report. We will then honor this year’s eight wonderful TIP Report Heroes, who have dedicated their lives to combat human trafficking, and we will hear briefly from each of them in a pre-recorded video. I will offer brief closing remarks and then we hope you will click over to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access the report online.</p>
<p>I would like to start by thanking our colleagues across the State Department, including our overseas embassies, for the strong collaboration and time spent to produce an accurate and comprehensive report. And I want to give a second thank you – a special thank you and kudos to the staff of the Trafficking in Persons Office for your dedication and commitment. Your long hours and hard work producing this report make a difference. And finally, thank you to our colleagues across the U.S. Government as well as our vital partners in NGOs and international organizations, those with lived experience of human trafficking, and other experts who contributed to the TIP Report and work to facilitate progress in addressing human trafficking year-round.</p>
<p>And it is now such an honor to join Secretary Blinken here today. Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for elevating the issue of human trafficking and for hosting today’s event. Under your leadership, we look forward to advancing our efforts to combat human trafficking.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Thank you, Kari. Thank you very much for that introduction, but especially thank you for the terrific work leading the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons here at State. You and your team – and I know some of the team members are here with us today – did exceptional work producing this year’s report under the difficult circumstances of COVID-19.</p>
<p>Thanks to everyone else who&#8217;s here for joining us for what is a very important occasion. And a special thank you to the Heroes that we&#8217;re celebrating today, women and men around the world who have dedicated their careers to stopping human trafficking. They’re advocates, public servants, leaders of NGOs, and they help stop trafficking in all kinds of ways by supporting victims, helping to bring traffickers to justice, creating national action plans, addressing the root causes of trafficking.</p>
<p>In many ways, the fight against trafficking is fought on the local level, one community at a time. And we celebrate the brave people leading the fight, often at great risk to themselves. Trafficking in persons is an appalling crime. It&#8217;s a global crisis; it&#8217;s an enormous source of human suffering. By its nature, it&#8217;s often hidden from view. Exact figures are sometimes hard to determine. The estimate we often cite is that nearly 25 million people worldwide are victims of human trafficking. Many are compelled into commercial sex work. Many are forced to work in factories or fields, or to join armed groups. Millions of trafficking victims are children.</p>
<p>This crime is an affront to human rights; it&#8217;s an affront to human dignity. We fight it, you fight it, because it&#8217;s the right thing to do. It&#8217;s also in our interest to stop trafficking. We know it&#8217;s destabilizing to societies and to economies. So we must do everything we can as a country, but also as a global community, to stop trafficking wherever it occurs.</p>
<p>The State Department&#8217;s Trafficking in Persons Report is indeed the world&#8217;s most comprehensive resource of the anti-trafficking efforts being undertaken by governments around the globe. It reflects the United States longstanding commitment and bipartisan commitment to this issue. We see it from administration to administration, we see it in Congress, and it&#8217;s something that we should take pride in. It’s the product of a great deal of work by our team here in Washington, our embassies around the world, and by NGOs, by journalists, academics, and survivors who help us to identify and document trends in human trafficking so that governments worldwide can more effectively combat it.</p>
<p>Part of this report is our country data. This year, we assessed 188 countries, including the United States. Some made encouraging progress; some slid backward. It&#8217;s important to remember that progress against trafficking is rarely linear. Traffickers are constantly adapting their methods, and every country, including the United States, must keep adapting our own strategies to stay ahead of them. We&#8217;ve got to identify and acknowledge our own shortcomings and be willing to course correct when needed. The TIP Report can help us do that by laying out the significant steps the United States and other countries must take to fight this crime and protect victims.</p>
<p>In addition to the country data, this year’s report explores a few topics in depth. The first is the impact of COVID-19. In many places, as governments diverted resources to try to control the pandemic and address its secondary impacts, human traffickers seized the opportunity to grow their operations. People who were pushed into dire economic circumstances by the pandemic became more vulnerable to exploitation. And as more people spent hours online for school and work, traffickers used the internet to groom and recruit potential victims.</p>
<p>So the pandemic has had a real impact on this fight. It’s another reason why it’s so important to stop the pandemic as quickly as we can and help communities around the world. The longer it takes, the more people will become vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>We applaud those governments that found ways to step up their work against trafficking even during COVID. For example, in Paraguay, as thousands of citizens abroad sought to return home, the government established temporary quarantine facilities at the border. They asked everyone screening questions, and through those questions they were able to identify nearly 300 victims of human trafficking. That’s nearly four times the average number of victims they had identified in previous years. Then the Paraguayan Government moved those victims to their own dedicated facilities, where they began receiving critical health and social support services right away. It was a brilliant strategy for moving fast to help victims of trafficking when the opportunity presented itself.</p>
<p>Second, this year’s report focuses on state-sponsored human trafficking. We documented 11 countries where the government itself is the trafficker – for example, through forced labor on public work projects or in sectors of the economy that the government feels are particularly important.</p>
<p>For the 10th year in a row, the report documents how the Cuban Government has profited from exploitative overseas medical missions. They send doctors and other medical personnel abroad, fail to inform them of the terms of their contracts, confiscate their documents and salaries, threaten them and their family members when they try to leave.</p>
<p>We also report on what’s happening in Xinjiang, in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of China. The Chinese Government has detained more than 1 million people in as many as 1,200 state-run internment camps throughout Xinjiang. Many detainees are subjected to physical violence, sexual abuse, and torture to induce them to work producing apparel, electronics, solar equipment, agricultural products.</p>
<p>And while the practices are the most egregious in Xinjiang, this year’s report notes that China has subjected its citizens to coercive labor practices in other parts of the country as well. The United States has taken measures to stop Chinese goods made with forced labor from making their way into our country. For example, last year, the Departments of State, Commerce, Treasury, and Homeland Security issued a Xinjiang supply chain business advisory to alert U.S. companies of the economic, legal, and reputational exposure to or in connection with operations, supply chains, or laborers from Xinjiang.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to call on our partners around the world to join us in condemning China’s genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and in taking steps to prevent goods made with forced labor from entering our supply chains. Governments should protect and serve their citizens, not terrorize and subjugate them for profit.</p>
<p>And third, the report explicitly acknowledges the connection between systemic inequality and human trafficking. This is something many countries need to grapple with, including the United States. Part of doing right by our people means taking a hard look at the ways that our history and our policies have created the conditions for crimes like human trafficking, because traffickers prey on those who are vulnerable – those who are less likely to have access to good jobs or educational opportunities, who are less likely to be treated as equal by police or the justice system, and who are less likely to be believed when they report that they’re being targeted or abused.</p>
<p>If we’re serious about ending trafficking in persons, we must also work to root out systemic racism, sexism, and other forms of discrimination, and to build a more equitable society in every dimension. These goals go hand in hand. So let’s keep that in mind as we work to build back better from the devastation of the pandemic.</p>
<p>I often talked about how the most urgent challenges facing our world cannot be solved by any one country acting alone. That’s true for stopping COVID, it’s true for dealing with the climate crisis, it’s true for the fight against human trafficking. We need to work together, share information, hold each other accountable. That’s how we’ll create a world where no one is exploited by trafficking and everyone is able to live in safety and in dignity.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for your strong message and those encouraging words. You have long been a champion for anchoring U.S. foreign policy on ensuring human dignity and expanding opportunities for all.</p>
<p>I am thrilled to now turn to celebrating the 2021 TIP Report Heroes. Traditionally we have honored these Heroes in-person at this event. While we wish we could be together, due to COVID-19 precautions, our Heroes are joining us virtually again this year.</p>
<p>To get to know each of our honorees better, we asked this year’s Heroes to prepare short videos answering: “What do you hope to achieve through your anti-trafficking work?” In the following video, you will hear their responses. I am certain you will understand why we are honoring each of them today.</p>
<p>Please join me as we recognize and honor this year’s eight TIP Report Heroes.</p>
<p>(Video is played.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Imelda Poole, in recognition of her exceptional activism in combating human trafficking in Albania and across Europe that has achieved systemic change through grassroots action, employing big picture solutions to address the root causes of vulnerability to the crime, and empowering those with lived experience through her organization’s principles of freedom, justice, truth, and joy.</p>
<p><b>MS POOLE:</b> Hello. My name is Imelda Poole. Working with Mary Ward Loreto in Albania and RENATE across Europe, my dream for the future is a social economy with a change in law and its implementation which will adopt a trauma-informed, victim-centered, and human rights approach to the law, both in its practice and in terms of real life. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, in recognition of her herculean efforts in creating and driving the Central African Republic’s anti-trafficking response by operationalizing the country’s interagency committee, leading the development of the government’s first national action plan to combat human trafficking, and catalyzing action even in difficult conditions at often great personal sacrifice.</p>
<p><b>MS BEMAKA-SOUI:</b> (Via translation) I am Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, Advisor to the President on the Protection of Children and Child Soldiers. With this award, my goal will be to completely eradicate human trafficking in the Central African Republic and establish a new legal code on protection of victims of human trafficking in my country.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Chantal Sagbo Sasse, in recognition of her unwavering and heartfelt commitment to the protection and care of child trafficking victims, her creativity and persistence in raising awareness among community members and government officials about human trafficking, and her invaluable anti-trafficking contributions and expertise shared with the Government of Gabon.</p>
<p><b>MS SAGBO:</b> (Via translation) Hello, everyone. I am Chantal Sagbo, president and founder of the NGO Sifos. Sifos is a non-profit organization that has worked over the last 20 years to promote and protect human rights. Our biggest focus is fighting human trafficking and exploitation. Our vision for 2022 is to build an education and training center for victims, so that they can become the leaders of tomorrow. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shoichi Ibusuki, in recognition of his relentless persistence in advocating for the rights of foreign workers in Japan by providing legal representation to many who experienced exploitation, including forced labor, and by elevating the issue and insisting that the government strengthen its efforts to protect foreign workers.</p>
<p><b>MR IBUSUKI:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Ibusuki Shoichi from Tokyo. I am an attorney. Japan’s Technical Intern Training Program is a hotbed of human trafficking and intermediary exploitation. We aim to have this program abolished within the next few years. We will also create conditions where foreign workers can join together and insist on their rights. We will fight together with likeminded people around the world to fight human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shakhnoza Khassanova, in recognition of her extraordinary leadership in building the organizational capacity of civil society organizations and the judicial system in Kazakhstan to combat human trafficking, her central role in orchestrating humanitarian assistance and ensuring safe migration during the COVID-19 pandemic, and her steadfast dedication to the protection of vulnerable populations.</p>
<p><b>MS KHASSANOVA: </b> I’m Shakhnoza Khassanova, director of the public association, Legal Center for Women’s Initiatives, Sana Sezim, from Shymkent, Kazakhstan. It’s an honor to receive this prestigious Department of State TIP Hero Report Award. This award is a result of the ongoing joint effort of our team and all stakeholders who continue to provide assistance to migrant workers and victims of human trafficking during the pandemic. We hope that our cooperation in future will become stronger and continue contributing to fight against human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, in recognition of her resolute determination to hold human traffickers in Mexico accountable for their crimes, her persistent efforts to secure funding for the creation of multidisciplinary shelters for human trafficking victims, and her longstanding, dynamic leadership in the Attorney General’s Office.</p>
<p><b>MS CABRERA FIGUEROA:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, Specialized Prosecutor for Trafficking in Persons at the Office of the Attorney General of Mexico. In the coming years, through my work fighting human trafficking, I hope to: strengthen my team with more training and resources; rescue more victims and give them specialized care so they can reintegrate into society; and bring more perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Mohammed al-Obaidly, in recognition of his pivotal leadership in the ongoing implementation of bold and sweeping reforms in Qatar to strengthen protections for foreign workers and prevent forced labor, his perseverance to instill real changes, and his tireless efforts to enhance collaboration and forge connections with workers, the business community, and foreign governments.</p>
<p><b>MR AL-OBAIDLY: </b> (Via translation) Hello. My name is Mohammed Hasan al-Obaidly. In the area of combating human trafficking, I would like to develop a guide for the country to identify trafficking in persons victims and provide them with assistance and protection. I also would like to enhance international cooperation and coordination to combat this crime by creating an integrated international law enforcement and security system to prevent, detect and expose human trafficking crimes and bring their perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Rocio Mora-Nieto,<b> </b>in recognition of her exceptional dedication and efforts to combat sex trafficking in Spain for more than a quarter of a century, her unparalleled compassion and commitment for women exploited in commercial sex, and her highly effective outreach and victim-centered provision of services for victims of human trafficking.<b></b></p>
<p><b>MS NIETO:</b> (Via translation) I am Rocio Mora Nieto. I am the director of APRAMP Madrid, in Spain. I am very grateful for this award because it makes slavery visible. The slavery of thousands and thousands of women who are being trafficked for sexual exploitation. For me, it is crucial to give these women alternatives so that they can escape from this situation and have freedom and dignity in their lives so that no woman is a slave in our streets and in our industrial parks. Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> What an inspiring group of leaders. It is such an honor to celebrate your important work.</p>
<p>The TIP Report represents a key tool to effect positive change and encourage governments to increase and improve their anti-trafficking efforts. This includes the United States.</p>
<p>As we evaluated the ongoing impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on anti-trafficking efforts around the world for this year’s report, it was impossible to ignore the pandemic’s devastating effects. In the chaos and hardship of the last year, we have also seen excellent examples of leadership, resilience, adaptability across the anti-trafficking community – from international organizations to local NGOs, governments, and survivor leaders.</p>
<p>Mexico secured its first trafficking in persons conviction from a virtual court session in June 2020, just weeks after resuming legal proceedings following a two-month shutdown.</p>
<p>In Albania, Senegal, and Jordan, COVID-19 mitigation measures were combined with strategic outreach to populations vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>In addition to these great adaptations, I want to highlight another excellent resource that the department will release in the coming weeks – a guidance document on COVID-19 considerations for anti-trafficking efforts – developed by our Human Trafficking Expert Consultant Network, which comprises individuals with lived experience of human trafficking and other subject matter experts. This guide will include promising practices and helpful standard operating procedures to continue anti-trafficking efforts during a crisis – like this pandemic – while still integrating a trauma-informed approach. Considerable work remains to address the challenges we still face related to the pandemic, but we hope this guidance will advance the integration of a trauma-informed approach into any new crisis-related adaptations.</p>
<p>For the last few years, we have sought to increasingly highlight through our report the importance of governments engaging with survivors and implementing trauma-informed approaches when doing so. We have done so, and our report is all the stronger for it. For the second year, Network experts developed the “Topics of Special Interest” for this year’s report – one about the unique complexities in familial trafficking and another about unifying trauma-informed practices and survivor leadership.</p>
<p>The Network also helped us evaluate and improve the process we use to select photos for the TIP Report. We did this in response to recommendations made in previous years by experts with lived experience of human trafficking. You will notice as you flip through the introduction that there are more photos that include the input of those survivors being photographed. I know we still have a long way to go to truly realize a trauma-informed approach across our anti-trafficking efforts, but I am thankful for the Network experts who helped us to make concrete improvements this year. We will continue to raise the importance of survivor engagement in building a truly effective, comprehensive anti-trafficking response – not just on paper through the TIP Report – but in our year-round engagement with governments around the world.</p>
<p>We know that we can do even better, and we will seek to hold ourselves and – accountable and be transparent in our efforts. I am encouraged by the innovative adaptations of governments, NGOs, and survivor leaders to ensure that our anti-trafficking response is comprehensive and addresses issues as they arise. I look forward to working with all of you to continue the fight against human trafficking.</p>
<p>Thank you again for joining us today, and please remember to go to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access this year’s TIP Report online. Thank you all.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
