<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 13:54:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of Eid al-Fitr</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-eid-al-fitr-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 13:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my warmest greetings to Muslims and all those celebrating Eid al-Fitr in the United States and around the globe.</p>
<p>This celebration marks the completion of Ramadan, a month of fasting, reflection, charity, and generosity.  Eid morning begins with families and communities coming together for prayer services at mosques and community centers, followed by festivities and feasts with friends and neighbors.  Cultures worldwide have their own unique and vibrant Eid traditions, as diverse as Muslim communities themselves.  During this time of compassion and giving, we cannot forget those who are unable to celebrate this special holiday from the safety and comfort of their homes or with their communities, due to displacement by war, violence, or persecution.  The United States will continue efforts to pursue truth, justice, and accountability for members of religious minority groups suffering around the world.</p>
<p>Later this month, I look forward to hosting an Eid-al-Fitr reception at the State Department, where I will get the chance to break bread with leaders from across the Muslim community and reflect on the past year and our shared values.</p>
<p>Eid Mubarak to all celebrating this joyous day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my warmest greetings to Muslims and all those celebrating Eid al-Fitr in the United States and around the globe.</p>
<p>This celebration marks the completion of Ramadan, a month of fasting, reflection, charity, and generosity.  Eid morning begins with families and communities coming together for prayer services at mosques and community centers, followed by festivities and feasts with friends and neighbors.  Cultures worldwide have their own unique and vibrant Eid traditions, as diverse as Muslim communities themselves.  During this time of compassion and giving, we cannot forget those who are unable to celebrate this special holiday from the safety and comfort of their homes or with their communities, due to displacement by war, violence, or persecution.  The United States will continue efforts to pursue truth, justice, and accountability for members of religious minority groups suffering around the world.</p>
<p>Later this month, I look forward to hosting an Eid-al-Fitr reception at the State Department, where I will get the chance to break bread with leaders from across the Muslim community and reflect on the past year and our shared values.</p>
<p>Eid Mubarak to all celebrating this joyous day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 23:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their April 24 meeting in Kyiv.  The Secretary emphasized the United States’ robust support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russia’s brutal aggression.   The Secretary provided an update on plans for U.S. diplomats to return to Ukraine, including initial visits to Lviv this week and plans to return to Kyiv as soon as possible.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the Administration’s April 28 request to Congress for $33 billion in security, economic, and humanitarian aid to empower Ukraine to defeat the Kremlin’s unconscionable war.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their April 24 meeting in Kyiv.  The Secretary emphasized the United States’ robust support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russia’s brutal aggression.   The Secretary provided an update on plans for U.S. diplomats to return to Ukraine, including initial visits to Lviv this week and plans to return to Kyiv as soon as possible.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the Administration’s April 28 request to Congress for $33 billion in security, economic, and humanitarian aid to empower Ukraine to defeat the Kremlin’s unconscionable war.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Syria Special Envoy Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-syria-special-envoy-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Representatives of the Arab League, Egypt, the European Union, France, Germany, Iraq, Jordan, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States met in Paris on April 28 to discuss Syria.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We expressed our lasting commitment to alleviating the suffering of the Syrian people and welcomed the upcoming EU hosted Brussels 6 Conference for the future of Syria and the region. We emphasized the urgency of continuing to provide meaningful and sufficient support to Syrian refugees and host countries.</p>
<p>We reiterated our steadfast support to UNSE Geir Pedersen’s efforts to push forward a political solution that brings an end to the Syrian crisis on the basis of UNSCR 2254 and respects the unity and territorial integrity of Syria.</p>
<p>We stressed the importance of sustaining and increasing UN-mandated aid cross-border into Syria, the re-authorization of the cross-border aid delivery mechanism, that allows for life-saving humanitarian assistance to reach the Syrian people, and continued implementation of UNSCR 2585. Furthermore, we underlined the necessity to continue to press for accountability, especially for the most serious crimes perpetrated in Syria.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Representatives of the Arab League, Egypt, the European Union, France, Germany, Iraq, Jordan, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States met in Paris on April 28 to discuss Syria.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We expressed our lasting commitment to alleviating the suffering of the Syrian people and welcomed the upcoming EU hosted Brussels 6 Conference for the future of Syria and the region. We emphasized the urgency of continuing to provide meaningful and sufficient support to Syrian refugees and host countries.</p>
<p>We reiterated our steadfast support to UNSE Geir Pedersen’s efforts to push forward a political solution that brings an end to the Syrian crisis on the basis of UNSCR 2254 and respects the unity and territorial integrity of Syria.</p>
<p>We stressed the importance of sustaining and increasing UN-mandated aid cross-border into Syria, the re-authorization of the cross-border aid delivery mechanism, that allows for life-saving humanitarian assistance to reach the Syrian people, and continued implementation of UNSCR 2585. Furthermore, we underlined the necessity to continue to press for accountability, especially for the most serious crimes perpetrated in Syria.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apparent Massacre in Tadamon </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/apparent-massacre-in-tadamon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 23:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the atrocities depicted in a recently released video, which appears to show blindfolded, unarmed civilians being shot point-blank by an Assad regime official before falling into a mass grave in Tadamon, Syria, during a 2013 massacre that reportedly killed hundreds of Syrian civilians. The video, which suggests additional evidence of war crimes committed by the Assad regime, is yet another harrowing example of the horrors that the Syrian people have endured for more than a decade.</p>
<p>The State Department commends and continues to support the brave individuals who work to bring Assad and his regime to justice, often at the risk of their own lives.  This includes the vital work of Syrian civil society organizations to document violations of the law of armed conflict as well as human rights abuses and violations and their efforts to advance transitional justice.  The United States government remains firmly committed to securing accountability for the atrocities the Assad regime continues to inflict upon Syrians.  Accountability and justice for the crimes, violations, and abuses committed against Syrians are essential to a stable, just, and enduring peace in Syria and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the atrocities depicted in a recently released video, which appears to show blindfolded, unarmed civilians being shot point-blank by an Assad regime official before falling into a mass grave in Tadamon, Syria, during a 2013 massacre that reportedly killed hundreds of Syrian civilians. The video, which suggests additional evidence of war crimes committed by the Assad regime, is yet another harrowing example of the horrors that the Syrian people have endured for more than a decade.</p>
<p>The State Department commends and continues to support the brave individuals who work to bring Assad and his regime to justice, often at the risk of their own lives.  This includes the vital work of Syrian civil society organizations to document violations of the law of armed conflict as well as human rights abuses and violations and their efforts to advance transitional justice.  The United States government remains firmly committed to securing accountability for the atrocities the Assad regime continues to inflict upon Syrians.  Accountability and justice for the crimes, violations, and abuses committed against Syrians are essential to a stable, just, and enduring peace in Syria and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Building on Steps to End the Conflict in Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/building-on-steps-to-end-the-conflict-in-ethiopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 22:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Millions of people in Ethiopia continue to face acute food insecurity and extreme hunger as a direct result of conflict.  We are encouraged that the government of Ethiopia and regional authorities in Tigray and Afar have taken steps in recent weeks to enable the delivery of desperately needed food aid to war-affected communities.  We urge the parties to accelerate, uphold, and expand these efforts to ensure, as President Biden has said, immediate, sustained, and unimpeded humanitarian access to all Ethiopians affected by this conflict.  The United States stands ready to continue to assist in this life-saving endeavor.</p>
<p>In recent months, Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed has taken a series of encouraging actions that have laid the groundwork for an end to conflict, including lifting the state of emergency, releasing some political prisoners and detainees, and, in parallel with Tigrayan authorities, declaring an effective cessation of hostilities.  We are similarly encouraged that Tigrayan forces have withdrawn most of their forces from Afar and have reiterated their commitment to a peaceful resolution of the conflict.  We now urge the parties, as my team and I have in recent days, to seize the opportunity to advance a negotiated ceasefire, including the necessary security arrangements, and call for the restoration of essential services in Tigray on an urgent basis.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to a unified, prosperous, and sovereign Ethiopia and to supporting an inclusive political process to heal the country’s divisions and provide peace and security for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Millions of people in Ethiopia continue to face acute food insecurity and extreme hunger as a direct result of conflict.  We are encouraged that the government of Ethiopia and regional authorities in Tigray and Afar have taken steps in recent weeks to enable the delivery of desperately needed food aid to war-affected communities.  We urge the parties to accelerate, uphold, and expand these efforts to ensure, as President Biden has said, immediate, sustained, and unimpeded humanitarian access to all Ethiopians affected by this conflict.  The United States stands ready to continue to assist in this life-saving endeavor.</p>
<p>In recent months, Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed has taken a series of encouraging actions that have laid the groundwork for an end to conflict, including lifting the state of emergency, releasing some political prisoners and detainees, and, in parallel with Tigrayan authorities, declaring an effective cessation of hostilities.  We are similarly encouraged that Tigrayan forces have withdrawn most of their forces from Afar and have reiterated their commitment to a peaceful resolution of the conflict.  We now urge the parties, as my team and I have in recent days, to seize the opportunity to advance a negotiated ceasefire, including the necessary security arrangements, and call for the restoration of essential services in Tigray on an urgent basis.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to a unified, prosperous, and sovereign Ethiopia and to supporting an inclusive political process to heal the country’s divisions and provide peace and security for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – April 29, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-april-29-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 21:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=339666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-misc"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon. Thank you so much for joining today’s press briefing. I just have two updates at the top, and then I will start with taking your questions.</p>
<p>Today marks the twenty-fifth anniversary of the entry into force of the Chemical Weapons Convention, or CWC. For a quarter century, the United States has worked with its allies and partners to help rid the world of chemical weapons and also deter their use by anyone, anywhere, and under any circumstances.</p>
<p>In recent years the world has witnessed chemical weapons use that challenges the CWC’s core prohibitions: by the Assad regime and ISIS in Syria; by Russian Government operatives against the Skripals in the UK and Aleksey Navalny in Russia; and by the DPRK against Kim Jong Nam in Malaysia.</p>
<p>Syria remains in non-compliance with the CWC, and we will continue to work to hold the Assad regime accountable for its repeated use of chemical weapons against its own people.</p>
<p>We will also continue our efforts to hold the Kremlin accountable for its non-compliance with the CWC, repeated use of chemical weapons, and ongoing efforts to shield the Assad regime from accountability for its chemical weapons use. Furthermore, we will continue to closely monitor for the possible use of chemical munitions by Russian forces in Ukraine.</p>
<p>On this anniversary we renew our commitment to upholding the CWC, and also note the convention’s important role in contributing to U.S. national security.</p>
<p>And I’ll take a point of personal privilege to just acknowledge our State Department reporter colleague, Conor Finnegan of ABC. Conor, if you’re on, or even if you aren’t, I hope you get this message. We know this is your last day. I just want to take a moment to say thank you for all of your contributions, for your insightful and fair and consistent reporting. We certainly will miss you here, and wish you the very best on your next chapter.</p>
<p>Let’s start with Cindy Saine.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could you please confirm a report that American citizen and former U.S. Marine Willy Joseph Cancel was killed in Ukraine, fighting along Ukrainian forces? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Cindy. Well, we are aware of these reports, and certainly stand ready to provide all possible consular assistance to the family. However, out of respect to the family during this very difficult time, we don’t have anything further to announce.</p>
<p>We also do want to reiterate that U.S. citizens should not travel to Ukraine during this active armed conflict. It is a very dangerous situation – and the singling out of U.S. citizens in Ukraine by Russian Government security officials, and that U.S. citizens in Ukraine should depart immediately, if it is safe to do so using commercial or privately available ground transportation options.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Hi, Matt. Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-nepal"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey. Okay. I got two things, both brief. Yesterday, the Secretary when he was on the Hill was asked about this Chinese memory chip company, YMTC, and whether it is violating laws that provide the – laws against providing technology to Huawei and others. He did not have an answer. I’m wondering if you guys have looked into it and do have an answer now and, if you do, what that is.</p>
<p>And the second thing is are you aware of an incident in Nepal recently, where you – in relation to a custody – child custody case. U.S. Embassy guards or officials were assaulted. I believe this happened on the 16th. Anyway, are you – this involves a child who was apparently abducted to Nepal by one of her parents. And anyway, I know that you probably won’t be able to talk about that because of privacy, but I want to know if you have anything on the assault on embassy officials. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks. I’ll start with your second question. So the State Department is aware of reports of an alleged child abduction case in Nepal involving a U.S. citizen, and we are providing all appropriate consular assistance.</p>
<p>To your point on assaults on staff, I am just now learning about that in real time, so I don’t have anything to offer. But what I will say is what we continue to underscore from here, that one of the department’s highest priorities is the welfare of U.S. citizens overseas, and we also recognize that international parental child abduction cases are, by nature, extremely difficult. They’re also extremely complex, and we’re committed to doing everything that we can to assist in resolving these challenging cases.</p>
<p>To your first question, we don’t have anything to offer, but we’re certainly happy to take that back to the team and get you any updates as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) for taking my question. I hope you can hear me.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Laura.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-georgia"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thank you. Have any State Department officials met with Georgian President Salome Zourabichvili while she’s here in Washington? And is the State Department concerned that Russian threats to Georgia pose a risk to the U.S. interests in the region? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. I don’t have any meetings to read out at this time, but what I can say from here on Georgia: from the beginning, the American people have stood in solidarity with the people of Georgia and their desire to be a free and sovereign country. Over the years we’ve also developed into strategic partners working together towards our shared vision of Georgia fully integrated into the Euro-Atlantic family of nations, and as a part of a Europe whole, free, and at peace.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-afghanistan"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, thank you for your generous words. It’s been a privilege to be a part of this press corps.</p>
<p>Two questions for you. First, Secretary Blinken said yesterday, I think, during – or maybe on Tuesday, during his Senate testimony, that the upside for Afghan women is that the country has become relatively safer and more stable. We’ve seen yet another bombing in Kabul today. I’m wondering if you have any response to that bombing, and whether or not he stands by that statement.</p>
<p>And then second, if you can provide any update on the effort to return U.S. diplomats to Ukraine. Are they now overnighting in Lviv yet, and does the strike yesterday on Kyiv change that calculus at all? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Conor. So first I’m going to let the Secretary’s comments at his hearing speak for themselves, but what I’ll say from here is that we offer our sincere condolences to the families as well as the loved ones who were killed in these cowardly attacks. The United States condemns these attacks in what appears to be the targeting of members of minority groups in the strongest terms. The United States is also committed to supporting the ability of all Afghans, including members of religious minority groups, to practice their religion freely, without fear of violence against them. We are also extremely concerned about the rise of attacks in Afghanistan and call for an end to these cowardly attacks and for perpetrators to be brought to justice.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine2"></a> As far as your second question on diplomats in Ukraine, I would say that earlier this week our deputy chief of mission as well as members of our embassy team traveled to Lviv to continue our close collaboration with key partners, and that would include our ministry of foreign affairs of Ukraine. Our diplomats are returning to Ukraine this week on a temporary basis, and we envision more regular travel in the immediate future. Planning is also underway to resume Embassy Kyiv operations as soon as possible.</p>
<p>And then, Conor, if we still have you, just in response to the strike, we’re closely following the reports of yesterday’s strike, and we are also very sad to hear that the strike killed Vera Gyrych of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, a Ukrainian Service journalist, and we express our most heartfelt condolences to her family as well as her colleagues. The Kremlin’s war continues to wreak havoc on Ukraine and its people, with dire consequences for those who continue to stand for justice and tell the truth about its brutality.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) the secretary general of Hizballah, Hassan Nasrallah, said, that – threatened that that Iran could attack Israel directly and not through proxies. Do you have concerns over that, or how do you comment on this?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hiba, if we still have you, can you please repeat your question? The first part of your question was cut off.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Today the secretary general of Hizballah, Hassan Nasrallah, said in a speech that Iran could attack Israel directly and not through proxies. Do you have any comment on that? Do you have concerns also?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Hiba. We don’t have any particular response at this time. But if we have one soon, we’ll be sure to follow up.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Mariana Sanchez.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for taking my questions. Can you hear me well?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Mariana.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-brazil"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Perfect. So this last week there was this high level with State Department visit in Brazil, and on that I would like to ask some questions. Could you confirm that Brazilian authorities requested help from the Americans with the American nuclear submarine technology, and what the U.S. officials answered concerning this matter?</p>
<p>And the second question, the U.S. authorities said that they are following the electoral process in Brazil and they trust the institutions there. Two days ago the Brazilian president said that the military should be directly involved in counting the votes for the next presidential election. Is the U.S. following these new events, and would the State Department provide any comments on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Mariana. So I won’t get into too much of the specifics of the discussions, but I will reiterate that we did have principals recently in the region, our Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and our Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose Fernandez.</p>
<p>What I will say from here is that shared goals were discussed to protect the environment, mitigation of effects of climate change, recovery from COVID-19, and ways to build supply chain resilience. We also reinforced our cooperation in security and defense, and promoting peace and the rule of law, as well as our appreciation for the vibrant partnership that the United States does share with Brazil.</p>
<p>And as far as your second question on elections, we have nothing specific to offer on – at that time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Endale Getahun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Good afternoon, Jalina. Happy Friday to you. I hope you can hear me.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, thank you. Happy Friday to you as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ethiopiaeritrea"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. Thanks so much. I was just wondering if you have read the statement that was made by the Congress Bradley Sherman regarding – based on his tweet that said that he was waiting for the Secretary of State’s promise that he would probably publicly come up and determine for the – regarding the genocide take place in Tigray, Ethiopia or any statement that would be – because said he’s waiting, that the Secretary promised but so far has not made that publicly yet. And so do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>My also second questions: Do you have any reaction to the Eritrean Government, which has still occupied the western Tigray, including the neighboring Amhara troops or groups in western Tigray? But Eritreans-appointed officials has visited Russia. Possibly there is a negotiation for new military arms for Eritrea and possibly also, according to sources, that the Russians, possibly a warship, could be docked in Red Sea close to Eritrea. As you know, Eritrea is still occupied with Ethiopian authorities and Amhara regime in western Tigray. What’s your reaction on that and if you have those – those are two questions that I have, and thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So Endale, to your second question, I just don’t have anything to offer on that.</p>
<p>What I would say to your first question on the determination, on the atrocity determination, our position hasn’t changed and we are following the situation in Tigray as well as across northern Ethiopia very closely. We’re also deeply concerned by reported human rights abuses and violations.</p>
<p>In response to these credible reports, we regularly issue statements condemning these incidents and also call for accountability. The Secretary acknowledged to Congressman Sherman on Thursday that the State Department, by law, has the prerogative to issue atrocity determinations and, as a matter of policy, will issue one if and when appropriate.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Can you hear me, Jalina?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thanks so much. I wanted to follow up both on Conor and Cindy’s questions.</p>
<p>On Conor’s, can you just confirm how many trips the embassy staff has taken into Ukraine this week? Has it just been the one-day trip or have there been multiple, and are they overnighting at this point yet?</p>
<p>And then I know the State Department doesn’t track the number of Americans who are abroad, but do you have a rough estimate of how many Americans have gone to Ukraine to fight on behalf of the Ukrainian forces there? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So we don’t have an exact number to preview as far as the trips to Ukraine and overnight. We’ll be happy to share that whenever we do.</p>
<p>And as far as Americans fighting in Ukraine, we don’t have anything to share today on that as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ROK"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Wonderful. I have two questions today.</p>
<p>South Korean NGO launched one million leaflets into North Korea by balloon this week, and South Korean Government said it will enforce the anti-leaflet law which bans sending leaflets across the border. What is the State Department’s position on South Korean NGO’s efforts to send leaflets into North Korea?</p>
<p>And then my second question: U.S. think tanks this week released analysis that North Korea is continuing work to restore its nuclear test site. What is State Department’s reaction to North Korea’s continued preparations for a nuclear test? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So we are aware of reports that the DPRK may be preparing to conduct a nuclear test in the coming months. And such an action not only would be dangerous but it would also be deeply destabilizing to the region. It would blatantly violate international law as set out in multiple resolutions of the UN Security Council. It would also undermine the global nonproliferation regime.</p>
<p>The DPRK has already launched 13 ballistic missiles this year, including at least three ICBMs, and we urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activity and instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>As far as leaflets, we don’t have anything to share at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Alex Raufoglu.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine4"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, thank you, Jalina, and Happy Friday. Couple of questions here, and let me start with the – your early statement on fallen journalist Vira Hyrych, who worked for a U.S.-backed outlet. Will the State Department be willing to lead the investigation around her death, as well as the deaths of other reporters during this war – be investigated as a war crime?</p>
<p>And my second question is about November G20 summit, whose hosts received confirmation today that President Putin plans to attend. Do you have anything on how Washington will approach that event?</p>
<p>And lastly, any result on meetings at the State Department with Belarus president elect Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Alex, to your first question, broadly speaking, so evidence of criminality is mounting, and those who have unleashed, perpetrated, and ordered crimes must be held to account. We strongly condemn apparent atrocities by the Kremlin forces across Ukraine. And we’ve assessed that members of Russia’s forces have committed war crimes, and we continue to monitor atrocities being committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>To your second question on the G20, the United States continues to believe that it can’t be business as usual with regards to Russia’s participation with the international community or international institutions. The G20 president, Indonesia, is responsible for all the invitations, and outside of that we don’t have anything further to announce.</p>
<p>To your last question, we have issued a readout that’s found on our website.</p>
<p>We’ll take our last question from Hyejun So.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m not sure if you called my name, but did you call me? Hyejun So?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes. Hyejun So.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-rokdprk"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Thank you for taking my question. My question is very similar to the previous one from our colleague on North Korea, but it’s a – I saw a report that South Korean military authorities are closely monitoring North Korean military movement, judging from the assessment that there is a high chance of another test firing of missiles, possibly one of the ones that North Korea showed off at their military parade on the 25th. And I’m wondering if this kind of discussion or this kind of South Korean military authority assessment was discussed with U.S. in advance. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>What I would say from here is that we continue to closely monitor the situation on the Korean peninsula, and I’ll just underscore that we urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activity and instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s briefing. Thank you so much for joining. I hope you have a great weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-misc"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon. Thank you so much for joining today’s press briefing. I just have two updates at the top, and then I will start with taking your questions.</p>
<p>Today marks the twenty-fifth anniversary of the entry into force of the Chemical Weapons Convention, or CWC. For a quarter century, the United States has worked with its allies and partners to help rid the world of chemical weapons and also deter their use by anyone, anywhere, and under any circumstances.</p>
<p>In recent years the world has witnessed chemical weapons use that challenges the CWC’s core prohibitions: by the Assad regime and ISIS in Syria; by Russian Government operatives against the Skripals in the UK and Aleksey Navalny in Russia; and by the DPRK against Kim Jong Nam in Malaysia.</p>
<p>Syria remains in non-compliance with the CWC, and we will continue to work to hold the Assad regime accountable for its repeated use of chemical weapons against its own people.</p>
<p>We will also continue our efforts to hold the Kremlin accountable for its non-compliance with the CWC, repeated use of chemical weapons, and ongoing efforts to shield the Assad regime from accountability for its chemical weapons use. Furthermore, we will continue to closely monitor for the possible use of chemical munitions by Russian forces in Ukraine.</p>
<p>On this anniversary we renew our commitment to upholding the CWC, and also note the convention’s important role in contributing to U.S. national security.</p>
<p>And I’ll take a point of personal privilege to just acknowledge our State Department reporter colleague, Conor Finnegan of ABC. Conor, if you’re on, or even if you aren’t, I hope you get this message. We know this is your last day. I just want to take a moment to say thank you for all of your contributions, for your insightful and fair and consistent reporting. We certainly will miss you here, and wish you the very best on your next chapter.</p>
<p>Let’s start with Cindy Saine.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could you please confirm a report that American citizen and former U.S. Marine Willy Joseph Cancel was killed in Ukraine, fighting along Ukrainian forces? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Cindy. Well, we are aware of these reports, and certainly stand ready to provide all possible consular assistance to the family. However, out of respect to the family during this very difficult time, we don’t have anything further to announce.</p>
<p>We also do want to reiterate that U.S. citizens should not travel to Ukraine during this active armed conflict. It is a very dangerous situation – and the singling out of U.S. citizens in Ukraine by Russian Government security officials, and that U.S. citizens in Ukraine should depart immediately, if it is safe to do so using commercial or privately available ground transportation options.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Hi, Matt. Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-nepal"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey. Okay. I got two things, both brief. Yesterday, the Secretary when he was on the Hill was asked about this Chinese memory chip company, YMTC, and whether it is violating laws that provide the – laws against providing technology to Huawei and others. He did not have an answer. I’m wondering if you guys have looked into it and do have an answer now and, if you do, what that is.</p>
<p>And the second thing is are you aware of an incident in Nepal recently, where you – in relation to a custody – child custody case. U.S. Embassy guards or officials were assaulted. I believe this happened on the 16th. Anyway, are you – this involves a child who was apparently abducted to Nepal by one of her parents. And anyway, I know that you probably won’t be able to talk about that because of privacy, but I want to know if you have anything on the assault on embassy officials. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks. I’ll start with your second question. So the State Department is aware of reports of an alleged child abduction case in Nepal involving a U.S. citizen, and we are providing all appropriate consular assistance.</p>
<p>To your point on assaults on staff, I am just now learning about that in real time, so I don’t have anything to offer. But what I will say is what we continue to underscore from here, that one of the department’s highest priorities is the welfare of U.S. citizens overseas, and we also recognize that international parental child abduction cases are, by nature, extremely difficult. They’re also extremely complex, and we’re committed to doing everything that we can to assist in resolving these challenging cases.</p>
<p>To your first question, we don’t have anything to offer, but we’re certainly happy to take that back to the team and get you any updates as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) for taking my question. I hope you can hear me.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Laura.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-georgia"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thank you. Have any State Department officials met with Georgian President Salome Zourabichvili while she’s here in Washington? And is the State Department concerned that Russian threats to Georgia pose a risk to the U.S. interests in the region? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. I don’t have any meetings to read out at this time, but what I can say from here on Georgia: from the beginning, the American people have stood in solidarity with the people of Georgia and their desire to be a free and sovereign country. Over the years we’ve also developed into strategic partners working together towards our shared vision of Georgia fully integrated into the Euro-Atlantic family of nations, and as a part of a Europe whole, free, and at peace.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-afghanistan"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, thank you for your generous words. It’s been a privilege to be a part of this press corps.</p>
<p>Two questions for you. First, Secretary Blinken said yesterday, I think, during – or maybe on Tuesday, during his Senate testimony, that the upside for Afghan women is that the country has become relatively safer and more stable. We’ve seen yet another bombing in Kabul today. I’m wondering if you have any response to that bombing, and whether or not he stands by that statement.</p>
<p>And then second, if you can provide any update on the effort to return U.S. diplomats to Ukraine. Are they now overnighting in Lviv yet, and does the strike yesterday on Kyiv change that calculus at all? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Conor. So first I’m going to let the Secretary’s comments at his hearing speak for themselves, but what I’ll say from here is that we offer our sincere condolences to the families as well as the loved ones who were killed in these cowardly attacks. The United States condemns these attacks in what appears to be the targeting of members of minority groups in the strongest terms. The United States is also committed to supporting the ability of all Afghans, including members of religious minority groups, to practice their religion freely, without fear of violence against them. We are also extremely concerned about the rise of attacks in Afghanistan and call for an end to these cowardly attacks and for perpetrators to be brought to justice.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine2"></a> As far as your second question on diplomats in Ukraine, I would say that earlier this week our deputy chief of mission as well as members of our embassy team traveled to Lviv to continue our close collaboration with key partners, and that would include our ministry of foreign affairs of Ukraine. Our diplomats are returning to Ukraine this week on a temporary basis, and we envision more regular travel in the immediate future. Planning is also underway to resume Embassy Kyiv operations as soon as possible.</p>
<p>And then, Conor, if we still have you, just in response to the strike, we’re closely following the reports of yesterday’s strike, and we are also very sad to hear that the strike killed Vera Gyrych of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, a Ukrainian Service journalist, and we express our most heartfelt condolences to her family as well as her colleagues. The Kremlin’s war continues to wreak havoc on Ukraine and its people, with dire consequences for those who continue to stand for justice and tell the truth about its brutality.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) the secretary general of Hizballah, Hassan Nasrallah, said, that – threatened that that Iran could attack Israel directly and not through proxies. Do you have concerns over that, or how do you comment on this?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hiba, if we still have you, can you please repeat your question? The first part of your question was cut off.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Today the secretary general of Hizballah, Hassan Nasrallah, said in a speech that Iran could attack Israel directly and not through proxies. Do you have any comment on that? Do you have concerns also?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Hiba. We don’t have any particular response at this time. But if we have one soon, we’ll be sure to follow up.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Mariana Sanchez.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for taking my questions. Can you hear me well?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Mariana.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-brazil"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Perfect. So this last week there was this high level with State Department visit in Brazil, and on that I would like to ask some questions. Could you confirm that Brazilian authorities requested help from the Americans with the American nuclear submarine technology, and what the U.S. officials answered concerning this matter?</p>
<p>And the second question, the U.S. authorities said that they are following the electoral process in Brazil and they trust the institutions there. Two days ago the Brazilian president said that the military should be directly involved in counting the votes for the next presidential election. Is the U.S. following these new events, and would the State Department provide any comments on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Mariana. So I won’t get into too much of the specifics of the discussions, but I will reiterate that we did have principals recently in the region, our Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and our Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose Fernandez.</p>
<p>What I will say from here is that shared goals were discussed to protect the environment, mitigation of effects of climate change, recovery from COVID-19, and ways to build supply chain resilience. We also reinforced our cooperation in security and defense, and promoting peace and the rule of law, as well as our appreciation for the vibrant partnership that the United States does share with Brazil.</p>
<p>And as far as your second question on elections, we have nothing specific to offer on – at that time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Endale Getahun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Good afternoon, Jalina. Happy Friday to you. I hope you can hear me.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, thank you. Happy Friday to you as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ethiopiaeritrea"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. Thanks so much. I was just wondering if you have read the statement that was made by the Congress Bradley Sherman regarding – based on his tweet that said that he was waiting for the Secretary of State’s promise that he would probably publicly come up and determine for the – regarding the genocide take place in Tigray, Ethiopia or any statement that would be – because said he’s waiting, that the Secretary promised but so far has not made that publicly yet. And so do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>My also second questions: Do you have any reaction to the Eritrean Government, which has still occupied the western Tigray, including the neighboring Amhara troops or groups in western Tigray? But Eritreans-appointed officials has visited Russia. Possibly there is a negotiation for new military arms for Eritrea and possibly also, according to sources, that the Russians, possibly a warship, could be docked in Red Sea close to Eritrea. As you know, Eritrea is still occupied with Ethiopian authorities and Amhara regime in western Tigray. What’s your reaction on that and if you have those – those are two questions that I have, and thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So Endale, to your second question, I just don’t have anything to offer on that.</p>
<p>What I would say to your first question on the determination, on the atrocity determination, our position hasn’t changed and we are following the situation in Tigray as well as across northern Ethiopia very closely. We’re also deeply concerned by reported human rights abuses and violations.</p>
<p>In response to these credible reports, we regularly issue statements condemning these incidents and also call for accountability. The Secretary acknowledged to Congressman Sherman on Thursday that the State Department, by law, has the prerogative to issue atrocity determinations and, as a matter of policy, will issue one if and when appropriate.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Can you hear me, Jalina?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thanks so much. I wanted to follow up both on Conor and Cindy’s questions.</p>
<p>On Conor’s, can you just confirm how many trips the embassy staff has taken into Ukraine this week? Has it just been the one-day trip or have there been multiple, and are they overnighting at this point yet?</p>
<p>And then I know the State Department doesn’t track the number of Americans who are abroad, but do you have a rough estimate of how many Americans have gone to Ukraine to fight on behalf of the Ukrainian forces there? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So we don’t have an exact number to preview as far as the trips to Ukraine and overnight. We’ll be happy to share that whenever we do.</p>
<p>And as far as Americans fighting in Ukraine, we don’t have anything to share today on that as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ROK"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Wonderful. I have two questions today.</p>
<p>South Korean NGO launched one million leaflets into North Korea by balloon this week, and South Korean Government said it will enforce the anti-leaflet law which bans sending leaflets across the border. What is the State Department’s position on South Korean NGO’s efforts to send leaflets into North Korea?</p>
<p>And then my second question: U.S. think tanks this week released analysis that North Korea is continuing work to restore its nuclear test site. What is State Department’s reaction to North Korea’s continued preparations for a nuclear test? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So we are aware of reports that the DPRK may be preparing to conduct a nuclear test in the coming months. And such an action not only would be dangerous but it would also be deeply destabilizing to the region. It would blatantly violate international law as set out in multiple resolutions of the UN Security Council. It would also undermine the global nonproliferation regime.</p>
<p>The DPRK has already launched 13 ballistic missiles this year, including at least three ICBMs, and we urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activity and instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>As far as leaflets, we don’t have anything to share at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Alex Raufoglu.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-ukraine4"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, thank you, Jalina, and Happy Friday. Couple of questions here, and let me start with the – your early statement on fallen journalist Vira Hyrych, who worked for a U.S.-backed outlet. Will the State Department be willing to lead the investigation around her death, as well as the deaths of other reporters during this war – be investigated as a war crime?</p>
<p>And my second question is about November G20 summit, whose hosts received confirmation today that President Putin plans to attend. Do you have anything on how Washington will approach that event?</p>
<p>And lastly, any result on meetings at the State Department with Belarus president elect Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Alex, to your first question, broadly speaking, so evidence of criminality is mounting, and those who have unleashed, perpetrated, and ordered crimes must be held to account. We strongly condemn apparent atrocities by the Kremlin forces across Ukraine. And we’ve assessed that members of Russia’s forces have committed war crimes, and we continue to monitor atrocities being committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>To your second question on the G20, the United States continues to believe that it can’t be business as usual with regards to Russia’s participation with the international community or international institutions. The G20 president, Indonesia, is responsible for all the invitations, and outside of that we don’t have anything further to announce.</p>
<p>To your last question, we have issued a readout that’s found on our website.</p>
<p>We’ll take our last question from Hyejun So.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m not sure if you called my name, but did you call me? Hyejun So?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes. Hyejun So.</p>
<p><a id="post-339666-rokdprk"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Thank you for taking my question. My question is very similar to the previous one from our colleague on North Korea, but it’s a – I saw a report that South Korean military authorities are closely monitoring North Korean military movement, judging from the assessment that there is a high chance of another test firing of missiles, possibly one of the ones that North Korea showed off at their military parade on the 25th. And I’m wondering if this kind of discussion or this kind of South Korean military authority assessment was discussed with U.S. in advance. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>What I would say from here is that we continue to closely monitor the situation on the Korean peninsula, and I’ll just underscore that we urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activity and instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s briefing. Thank you so much for joining. I hope you have a great weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Travel to South Africa, Angola, Gabon, and France</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-south-africa-angola-gabon-and-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 20:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will travel to South Africa, Angola, Gabon, and France from May 2 to 7. Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs Molly Phee and National Security Council Senior Director for Africa Dana Banks will join the Deputy Secretary’s delegation.</p>
<p>In South Africa, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Cape Town, Johannesburg, and Pretoria from May 2 to 4 and meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Alvin Botes and other senior government officials to discuss furthering U.S.-South African cooperation on a range of issues, including global and regional peace and security, trade and investment, sustainable infrastructure, health security, and the climate crisis. She will meet with business leaders and entrepreneurs to discuss strengthening the important trade and investment relationship between the U.S. and South Africa. The Deputy Secretary will also present the International Women of Courage Award during a discussion with women leaders promoting human rights for marginalized communities.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will then travel to Luanda, Angola from May 4 to 5 to meet with President João Lourenço, Foreign Minister Tete Antonio, and other senior Angolan officials to discuss our shared interests, including regional security and defense cooperation, economic prosperity, good governance, support for Angola’s COVID-19 vaccination effort, and cooperation on shared maritime law enforcement as well as economic, and climate-related challenges in the Atlantic Basin. She will also hold discussions with business leaders, and Mandela Washington Fellowship alumni who are working to promote women’s entrepreneurship and youth engagement.</p>
<p>From May 5 to 6, the Deputy Secretary will travel to Libreville, Gabon, where she will meet with President Ali Bongo Ondimba, Foreign Minister Michael Moussa-Adamo, and Minister of Defense Félicité Ongouori Ngoubili to engage on our shared priorities including promoting environmental protection, addressing the climate crisis, and furthering security cooperation. The Deputy Secretary will also visit Raponda Walker Arboretum to learn about Gabon’s work in forest conservation leadership to combat the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Finally, on May 7, the Deputy Secretary will meet in Paris, France, with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly to discuss our ongoing, close coordination to respond to Putin’s brutal, unprovoked war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will travel to South Africa, Angola, Gabon, and France from May 2 to 7. Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs Molly Phee and National Security Council Senior Director for Africa Dana Banks will join the Deputy Secretary’s delegation.</p>
<p>In South Africa, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Cape Town, Johannesburg, and Pretoria from May 2 to 4 and meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Alvin Botes and other senior government officials to discuss furthering U.S.-South African cooperation on a range of issues, including global and regional peace and security, trade and investment, sustainable infrastructure, health security, and the climate crisis. She will meet with business leaders and entrepreneurs to discuss strengthening the important trade and investment relationship between the U.S. and South Africa. The Deputy Secretary will also present the International Women of Courage Award during a discussion with women leaders promoting human rights for marginalized communities.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will then travel to Luanda, Angola from May 4 to 5 to meet with President João Lourenço, Foreign Minister Tete Antonio, and other senior Angolan officials to discuss our shared interests, including regional security and defense cooperation, economic prosperity, good governance, support for Angola’s COVID-19 vaccination effort, and cooperation on shared maritime law enforcement as well as economic, and climate-related challenges in the Atlantic Basin. She will also hold discussions with business leaders, and Mandela Washington Fellowship alumni who are working to promote women’s entrepreneurship and youth engagement.</p>
<p>From May 5 to 6, the Deputy Secretary will travel to Libreville, Gabon, where she will meet with President Ali Bongo Ondimba, Foreign Minister Michael Moussa-Adamo, and Minister of Defense Félicité Ongouori Ngoubili to engage on our shared priorities including promoting environmental protection, addressing the climate crisis, and furthering security cooperation. The Deputy Secretary will also visit Raponda Walker Arboretum to learn about Gabon’s work in forest conservation leadership to combat the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Finally, on May 7, the Deputy Secretary will meet in Paris, France, with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly to discuss our ongoing, close coordination to respond to Putin’s brutal, unprovoked war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Leader of the Democratic Opposition of Belarus Tsikhanouskaya</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-leader-of-the-democratic-opposition-of-belarus-tsikhanouskaya/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met yesterday with Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, leader of the democratic opposition of Belarus.  They discussed the Lukashenka regime’s continued support of Russia’s unprovoked war against Ukraine and U.S. efforts to hold the regime accountable for its complicity, as well as for its sustained crackdown on human rights and democratic freedoms. Secretary of State Antony Blinken joined the group for part of the meeting.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, together with Ms. Tsikhanouskaya, called for an end to the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing crackdown on democratic voices and for the unconditional release of all political prisoners in Belarus and emphasized the United States’ enduring support for the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met yesterday with Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, leader of the democratic opposition of Belarus.  They discussed the Lukashenka regime’s continued support of Russia’s unprovoked war against Ukraine and U.S. efforts to hold the regime accountable for its complicity, as well as for its sustained crackdown on human rights and democratic freedoms. Secretary of State Antony Blinken joined the group for part of the meeting.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, together with Ms. Tsikhanouskaya, called for an end to the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing crackdown on democratic voices and for the unconditional release of all political prisoners in Belarus and emphasized the United States’ enduring support for the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel J. Kritenbrink’s Travel to Cambodia and Laos</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-of-state-for-east-asian-and-pacific-affairs-daniel-j-kritenbrinks-travel-to-cambodia-and-laos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 17:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel J. Kritenbrink will travel to Cambodia and Laos May 1-7.  The visits will highlight U.S. commitment to two of the youngest and most dynamic societies in the region, reinforcing ASEAN centrality, underscoring the United States’ commitment to the Mekong-U.S. Partnership to address transboundary challenges, and promoting a secure, open and prosperous Mekong sub-region.</p>
<p>In Cambodia, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will meet with Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn and other senior officials, and youth and civil society leaders to discuss our bilateral relationship and U.S. support for Cambodia’s year as ASEAN Chair.</p>
<p>In Laos, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will lead the U.S.-Laos Comprehensive Bilateral Dialogue to discuss closer U.S.-Laos cooperation and forge deeper connection with Laos as the 2022 Mekong-U.S. Partnership co-chair.  He will meet with Foreign Minister Saleumxay Kommasith, Vice Foreign Minister Thongphane Savanphet, and officials from the Mekong River Commission.  The Assistant Secretary will also engage with alumni of Department of State exchange programs.</p>
<p>In both countries, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will discuss the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit that President Biden will host in Washington May 12-13.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel J. Kritenbrink will travel to Cambodia and Laos May 1-7.  The visits will highlight U.S. commitment to two of the youngest and most dynamic societies in the region, reinforcing ASEAN centrality, underscoring the United States’ commitment to the Mekong-U.S. Partnership to address transboundary challenges, and promoting a secure, open and prosperous Mekong sub-region.</p>
<p>In Cambodia, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will meet with Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn and other senior officials, and youth and civil society leaders to discuss our bilateral relationship and U.S. support for Cambodia’s year as ASEAN Chair.</p>
<p>In Laos, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will lead the U.S.-Laos Comprehensive Bilateral Dialogue to discuss closer U.S.-Laos cooperation and forge deeper connection with Laos as the 2022 Mekong-U.S. Partnership co-chair.  He will meet with Foreign Minister Saleumxay Kommasith, Vice Foreign Minister Thongphane Savanphet, and officials from the Mekong River Commission.  The Assistant Secretary will also engage with alumni of Department of State exchange programs.</p>
<p>In both countries, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will discuss the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit that President Biden will host in Washington May 12-13.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twenty-fifth Anniversary of the Chemical Weapons Convention’s Entry into Force</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/twenty-fifth-anniversary-of-the-chemical-weapons-conventions-entry-into-force/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today marks the twenty-fifth anniversary of the entry into force of the Chemical Weapons Convention (CWC).  For a quarter of a century, the United States has worked with its Allies and partners to help rid the world of chemical weapons and deter their use by anyone, anywhere, and under any circumstances.  Our collective goal is to exclude completely the possibility of the use of chemical weapons, which are abhorrent tools of war.  On this anniversary, we renew our commitment to upholding the CWC and note the Convention’s important role in contributing to U.S. national security.  Unfortunately, this anniversary reminds us that the world continues to be threatened by the specter of these weapons.</p>
<p>In recent years, the world has witnessed chemical weapons use that challenges the CWC’s core prohibitions: by the Assad regime and ISIS in Syria, by Russian government operatives against the Skripals in the UK and Aleksey Navalny in Russia, and by the DPRK against Kim Jong Nam in Malaysia.  Syria remains in noncompliance with the CWC, and we will continue to work to hold the Assad regime accountable for its repeated use of chemical weapons against its own people.  We will also continue our efforts to hold the Kremlin accountable for its noncompliance with the CWC, repeated use of chemical weapons, and ongoing efforts to shield the Assad regime from accountability for its CW use.  Further, we have made very clear that the Russian government would face profound consequences were it to use chemical weapons in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Despite these challenges, the Convention, which President Biden has championed since his time in the U.S. Senate, has shown time and again its utility, demonstrated by the commitment of the majority of States Parties to compliance and their willingness to take actions to uphold it and hold accountable those who violate it.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today marks the twenty-fifth anniversary of the entry into force of the Chemical Weapons Convention (CWC).  For a quarter of a century, the United States has worked with its Allies and partners to help rid the world of chemical weapons and deter their use by anyone, anywhere, and under any circumstances.  Our collective goal is to exclude completely the possibility of the use of chemical weapons, which are abhorrent tools of war.  On this anniversary, we renew our commitment to upholding the CWC and note the Convention’s important role in contributing to U.S. national security.  Unfortunately, this anniversary reminds us that the world continues to be threatened by the specter of these weapons.</p>
<p>In recent years, the world has witnessed chemical weapons use that challenges the CWC’s core prohibitions: by the Assad regime and ISIS in Syria, by Russian government operatives against the Skripals in the UK and Aleksey Navalny in Russia, and by the DPRK against Kim Jong Nam in Malaysia.  Syria remains in noncompliance with the CWC, and we will continue to work to hold the Assad regime accountable for its repeated use of chemical weapons against its own people.  We will also continue our efforts to hold the Kremlin accountable for its noncompliance with the CWC, repeated use of chemical weapons, and ongoing efforts to shield the Assad regime from accountability for its CW use.  Further, we have made very clear that the Russian government would face profound consequences were it to use chemical weapons in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Despite these challenges, the Convention, which President Biden has championed since his time in the U.S. Senate, has shown time and again its utility, demonstrated by the commitment of the majority of States Parties to compliance and their willingness to take actions to uphold it and hold accountable those who violate it.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
