<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 23:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Briefing with Deputy Secretary for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon and Afghanistan Task Force Director Ambassador Tracey Jacobson with On-Background Q&#038;A by Senior State Department Officials On Operation Allies Refuge</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-deputy-secretary-for-management-and-resources-brian-p-mckeon-and-afghanistan-task-force-director-ambassador-tracey-jacobson-with-on-background-qa-by-senior-state-department-officials-o/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p>July 21, 2021</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon, and thanks, everyone, for joining us for this call on Operation Allies Refuge, which, of course, is an effort President Biden announced earlier this month to support relocation flights for interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the United States in Afghanistan.  Just a reminder of the ground rules:  We will have opening remarks from Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian McKeon and Afghanistan Task Force Director Ambassador Tracey Jacobson.  Those will be on the record.  After their remarks, we’ll then open it up for Q&amp;A and we’ll do that on background to senior State Department officials, and I’ll provide more details on that in just a moment.</p>
<p>This call is embargoed until it is – until its conclusion.  As we always do, we’ll have a transcript available after the fact.  But with that, I will turn it over to Deputy Secretary McKeon.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  Thank you, Ned.  Good afternoon, everybody.  Last week, the President outlined the next steps in our efforts to honor the commitment to Afghans who worked side by side with Americans in Afghanistan over the years, including interpreters and translators.  We owe a great debt to those who have provided valuable and faithful service to the United States working alongside our military and diplomatic personnel, thereby putting their own lives at risk.</p>
<p>In recognition of our commitment, the United States will temporarily relocate these individuals and their families who feel threatened in Afghanistan so they can complete their Special Immigrant Visa processing outside of Afghanistan.  We’ve already accelerated the processing of SIVs in part by adding additional staff at U.S. Embassy Kabul to process applications and by using technology to improve efficiency and work flow.</p>
<p>In February, Embassy Kabul reopened for in-person immigrant visa services following an 11-month suspension due to the COVID-19 pandemic.  That backlog has since been cleared out and we’re working as fast possible to interview SIV applicants whose appointments were canceled during a recent COVID outbreak in Kabul.  Since January, we’ve already approved 2,500 Special Immigrant Visas.</p>
<p>Much work remains to be done.  That’s why Secretary Blinken asked three-time Ambassador Tracey Jacobson to lead our newly created Afghanistan coordination task force.  The task force will coordinate the U.S. Government’s efforts to bring qualified SIV applicants to the United States once their security vetting is complete.  The Department of State, Homeland Security, other U.S. Government departments and agencies involved in the SIV program are committed to helping the men and women who have taken significant risks to support our military and diplomatic personnel.</p>
<p>I want to thank Ambassador Jacobson, who’s here with us in the room, for standing up this task force and getting them going and for all they’ve been able to accomplish in just a few days since it started, and turn it over to her.</p>
<p><strong>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:</strong>  Thank you, Deputy Secretary.  My team and I are working to coordinate the U.S. Government’s efforts to relocate thousands of Afghans and their immediate families.  It’s hard work and a sacred duty to fill our commitment to these people.</p>
<p>Our first priority is to relocate to the United States some 750 Afghan SIV applicants and their immediate families who have completed the majority of the visa process, including a thorough security background check.  We are working to bring them to the United States starting next week.  They will be paroled into the United States and have their status adjusted by the Department of Homeland Security.  During this processing, they will be located at Fort Lee, Virginia, and when they leave Fort Lee, they will join 70,000 Afghans who have received SIVs and started new lives in the United States since 2008.</p>
<p>We are also working to relocate from Afghanistan those applicants who have received chief of mission approval but have not gone so far in their visa processing, including the full security screen.  This group includes about 4,000 principal applicants and their families.  We will take them to locations outside the United States where they can safely await the completion of their application processing, and we will provide them accommodation and other support during this period, which we are committed to making as short as possible.</p>
<p>I know many Americans will want to welcome and help these Afghans who dedicated themselves to the United States mission in Afghanistan.  We’ve already had inquiries from some of them, and we encourage people who are interested in assisting resettled Afghan special immigrants or any refugees to reach out to their local refugees resettlement agency to donate, volunteer, or even form community sponsorship teams.  There are many opportunities to be involved in welcoming Afghans as they come to the United States.</p>
<p>As President Biden said to these Afghans and their families, there is a home for you in the United States if you so choose, and we’ll stand with you just as you stood with us.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you both.  We now look forward to taking your questions, and we will do this on background.  You can attribute what you hear to senior State Department officials.  We will have  and  with us.  We will be joined by , we’ll have , and we’ll have .</p>
<p>And so, with that, operator, if you want to just repeat instructions for asking questions.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question today, please press 1 followed by 0.  We will announce your name and organization and put you – open your line.  And as a reminder, please wait until I let you know that your line is open before asking a question.  So again, please press 1, 0 at this time to ask a question.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR: </strong> Great.  We’ll start with Kylie Atwood.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you.  Kylie, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks, guys, for doing this.  I think we all have a bunch of questions.  I am wondering how long the administration plans to be doing these relocation efforts.  Do you expect this is something that will happen over the course of years given some SIV applicants have just applied recently given the U.S. troop withdrawal?</p>
<p>My second question is about safety for these Afghans.  What is the U.S. doing, what can the U.S. do to provide them with any safety when U.S. troops withdraw from the country, and how are they being transported to the airport?  Is there any support for them given threats from the Taliban?  And last question is:  How long are they expected to stay at Fort Lee in this final stage? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>So working backward, we don’t expect them to stay at Fort Lee for very often, or very long, excuse me.  We’ll try to work them through Fort Lee in 7 to 10 day is our hope and expectation.  The applicants need to get themselves to Kabul. We’re not going to talk about how they get in and around Kabul and to the airport for security reasons.</p>
<p>The SIV Program is – has eligibility standards, and we have authorized numbers from the U.S. Congress, and so long as we keep having those numbers provided to us by Congress, we’ll keep processing SIV applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We will go to the line of Andrea Mitchell, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  One moment.  Ms. Mitchell, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Can you talk about the others in the program and where else they might be going, and how long it will take to get what was originally estimated as as many as 70,000 people, including families, accommodated because obviously their lives are right now in danger?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>So the total number of applicants to the SIV Program number just over 20,000, but about half of those have not yet completed the initial stages of the application process, so we’re not in a position to move forward with their case until they do so.  So I’m not sure where the 70,000 number comes from.  The 4,000 number and their families, they would be targeted for the next phase of bringing people to third country locations, and that process in the third country would take longer because they’re not as far along in the screening process as those who we will bring to the United States.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Laura Seligman.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  I apologize, I do not see Laura’s name.  Laura, would you hit 1, 0 again?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  It looks like she just dropped out of the queue.  No problem.  We will move on then to the line of Nick Schifrin.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  Mr. Schifrin, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks, guys.  Let me follow up on what comes next.  Can you confirm that there’s the deal pretty much done to move, I don’t know if it’s the next round or the third round, some of these applicants to military bases in Kuwait and Qatar?  And can you talk about whether there’s a push on P-2 refugees, whether the number – sorry, the kind of aperture of the person who can apply, whether there’s a push to expand that aperture and including P-2 refugees.  And I know you don’t want to talk about some of the details on transport for security reasons, but can you give us any more details on how exactly they will get to Fort Lee this first round?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  I’m sorry, Nick, I was – I didn&#8217;t understand the last piece of the question.  I’m not sure we have many answers that we can give you.  We’re talking to third countries about the possibility of temporary relocation, but we’re not in a position to confirm any agreements with any of those third countries at this time.</p>
<p>On the transportation to Fort Lee, we will fly them into the country and bring them by vehicle to Fort Lee.  I assume it will be buses.</p>
<p>And what was the second question?  I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  P-2.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Oh.  On the question of the P-2 refugee program, we are looking at several options, including expanding pathways through the refugee program.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Ellen Knickmeyer.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  Ms. Knickmeyer, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi there.  Thank you for doing this.  Let’s see.  Is the – because the Afghan SIVs will fly out through the Kabul airport, has there been an agreement finalized to keep that operating under Turkey?  I don’t know if their relocations are all supposed to be completed by the time the U.S. withdraws or not.  And then you say you’re – do you not yet have any agreement from any other country to temporarily host the Afghan SIVs?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  On the second question, we don’t have agreement with any countries that we’re ready to announce here.</p>
<p>On the airport, obviously, we’ve said the airport needs to be open and functioning as part of a normal country, and we’re grateful for our conversations with our colleagues in Turkey.  The DOD is leading those conversations.  We’re optimistic that we’ll have the security package that we need at the airport in Kabul.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Dan Lamothe.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you, one moment.  Mr. Lamothe, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks for doing this today.  A couple follow-on questions just to clarify.  Before these individuals receive chief of mission approval, it sounds like they’ll be staying in Afghanistan?  Just wanted to check on that.</p>
<p>And then when it comes to these facilities in third countries, can you describe a bit what they’re going to look like, both in terms of living conditions and then also any kind of services?  It occurs to me you’re going to have children in play here with potentially months and months of waiting.</p>
<p>And then a third question, since there are a number of anecdotes of interpreters who have been denied SIV applications in the past, often for seemingly unclear and arbitrary reasons, what will be done to take care of individuals like that, especially if it comes down to paperwork from companies they’re not in touch with and things along those lines?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Thanks, Dan.  Working backwards, I mean, the third one – the last question is a tough one because we have applicants who have sought to enter the program who cannot find verification of their employment from their – say they worked for a DOD contractor many years ago.  We’re trying to help them.  The Department of Defense is trying to help with that part of it, but that is a critical first stage to prove eligibility.</p>
<p>On the conditions, I’m not really in a position to speak to that right now in the third countries.  Suffice to say we will house and feed them in safe and adequate facilities.</p>
<p>On your first question, we haven’t made any – we haven’t ruled anything in and out of what we’re doing.  We’re starting in these phases with people at the later stages of the program.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll take a couple additional questions.  We’ll go to the line of Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Mr. Finnegan, please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you for having this call.  A couple of follow-ups as well.  Can you say how many there are in total with this group of 4,000 principal applicants who will be moved to third countries?  If you include their families, what is that total number?</p>
<p>You said applicants will have to get themselves to Kabul.  For many of them, that journey would be dangerous if not impossible.  What would you say to the – to security concerns of folks trying to get to Kabul?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  So we don’t know for certain how many family members will be brought.  The principal applicant can choose to bring the ones that are eligible.  We’ve just been doing these rough extrapolations based on an average of three to five per principal applicant based on past practice.  In order to come on an evacuation flight, they would have to get themselves to Kabul.  Obviously, we don’t have substantial U.S. military presence.  We don’t have an ability to provide transportation for them.  If they’re, say, in the north of the country and they don’t feel safe staying in Afghanistan, they could go to a neighboring country and finish their SIV application process there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We will go to Meghann Myers, who I understand is together with Lara Seligman, so if you want to call on Meghann Myers, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  Ms. Myers, please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, thanks so much, .  This is Lara.  I’m wondering if you could tell us anything more about where else these 4,000 other applicants are going, and what is the timeline for this next batch to come over to the United States?  And then also, I’m wondering what happens to the other Afghans who risked their lives to help the U.S., these journalists, women’s rights activists, Afghan troops that don’t fall into the SIV category.  How are we helping them escape the Taliban?  Thank you.</p>
<p>And this is Meghann.  I’ll jump in after that answer.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Well, Meghann, why don’t you offer your question now?  We’ll take them together.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay, great.  So my question is about the 4,000 who are going to be going abroad to complete their processes.  Will they be able to fully complete everything from the third-party country, or will they need to come to Fort Lee to finish out that process?  And are you looking at any other domestic installations such as Fort Lee for applicants who are in the final stages to go to?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Lara, on your first questions, I don’t really have any more detail than I’ve previously given on the third country option.  On the 4,000 who will be going to third countries, we expect that we would complete the process within – in that third country, and then they would come to the United States and go to their ultimate destination.  We wouldn’t expect as of this time – maybe that could change – to put them onto a military base for any period of time.</p>
<p>As to whether we will use another facility besides Fort Lee, that’s really a question for the Department of Defense.  They were given the requirements by the State Department.  They selected Fort Lee as an option for this, this first phase that we’re doing here of evacuating the people at the later stage in the process.</p>
<p>And then, Lara, your other question about others who have helped the United States, I think I referenced that in response to an earlier question.  We’re looking at other options and pathways for people who’ve helped us.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>And we’ll conclude with the line of Nike Ching.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Thank you very much.  Nike, please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Good afternoon.  Thank you so much for the call.  Just a follow-up question on the Afghanistan fixers who have helped the U.S. press organizations.  Would you support the creation of a visa program for those Afghans, Afghans who helped with the U.S. media organizations and who are now seeking safety in the U.S.?  I’m asking this because a coalition of U.S. media organizations has sent a letter to the Congress requesting to create such visa program.  Would you like to weigh in?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:   </strong>Yes, thank you.  We’ve seen the letter from the news organizations and we’ll be responding in due course to them.  As I think I’ve responded previously to this question, in terms of other people in Afghanistan who have helped the United States or helped U.S. organizations, whether it’s NGOs or media organizations, we are looking at other options for providing safe options for them outside of Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Right, well, thank you very much, everyone.  Just a reminder:  The Q&amp;A was done on a background basis.  That was a senior State Department official.  And with that, the embargo is lifted and we’ll conclude the call.  Talk to you soon.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p>July 21, 2021</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon, and thanks, everyone, for joining us for this call on Operation Allies Refuge, which, of course, is an effort President Biden announced earlier this month to support relocation flights for interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the United States in Afghanistan.  Just a reminder of the ground rules:  We will have opening remarks from Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian McKeon and Afghanistan Task Force Director Ambassador Tracey Jacobson.  Those will be on the record.  After their remarks, we’ll then open it up for Q&amp;A and we’ll do that on background to senior State Department officials, and I’ll provide more details on that in just a moment.</p>
<p>This call is embargoed until it is – until its conclusion.  As we always do, we’ll have a transcript available after the fact.  But with that, I will turn it over to Deputy Secretary McKeon.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  Thank you, Ned.  Good afternoon, everybody.  Last week, the President outlined the next steps in our efforts to honor the commitment to Afghans who worked side by side with Americans in Afghanistan over the years, including interpreters and translators.  We owe a great debt to those who have provided valuable and faithful service to the United States working alongside our military and diplomatic personnel, thereby putting their own lives at risk.</p>
<p>In recognition of our commitment, the United States will temporarily relocate these individuals and their families who feel threatened in Afghanistan so they can complete their Special Immigrant Visa processing outside of Afghanistan.  We’ve already accelerated the processing of SIVs in part by adding additional staff at U.S. Embassy Kabul to process applications and by using technology to improve efficiency and work flow.</p>
<p>In February, Embassy Kabul reopened for in-person immigrant visa services following an 11-month suspension due to the COVID-19 pandemic.  That backlog has since been cleared out and we’re working as fast possible to interview SIV applicants whose appointments were canceled during a recent COVID outbreak in Kabul.  Since January, we’ve already approved 2,500 Special Immigrant Visas.</p>
<p>Much work remains to be done.  That’s why Secretary Blinken asked three-time Ambassador Tracey Jacobson to lead our newly created Afghanistan coordination task force.  The task force will coordinate the U.S. Government’s efforts to bring qualified SIV applicants to the United States once their security vetting is complete.  The Department of State, Homeland Security, other U.S. Government departments and agencies involved in the SIV program are committed to helping the men and women who have taken significant risks to support our military and diplomatic personnel.</p>
<p>I want to thank Ambassador Jacobson, who’s here with us in the room, for standing up this task force and getting them going and for all they’ve been able to accomplish in just a few days since it started, and turn it over to her.</p>
<p><strong>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:</strong>  Thank you, Deputy Secretary.  My team and I are working to coordinate the U.S. Government’s efforts to relocate thousands of Afghans and their immediate families.  It’s hard work and a sacred duty to fill our commitment to these people.</p>
<p>Our first priority is to relocate to the United States some 750 Afghan SIV applicants and their immediate families who have completed the majority of the visa process, including a thorough security background check.  We are working to bring them to the United States starting next week.  They will be paroled into the United States and have their status adjusted by the Department of Homeland Security.  During this processing, they will be located at Fort Lee, Virginia, and when they leave Fort Lee, they will join 70,000 Afghans who have received SIVs and started new lives in the United States since 2008.</p>
<p>We are also working to relocate from Afghanistan those applicants who have received chief of mission approval but have not gone so far in their visa processing, including the full security screen.  This group includes about 4,000 principal applicants and their families.  We will take them to locations outside the United States where they can safely await the completion of their application processing, and we will provide them accommodation and other support during this period, which we are committed to making as short as possible.</p>
<p>I know many Americans will want to welcome and help these Afghans who dedicated themselves to the United States mission in Afghanistan.  We’ve already had inquiries from some of them, and we encourage people who are interested in assisting resettled Afghan special immigrants or any refugees to reach out to their local refugees resettlement agency to donate, volunteer, or even form community sponsorship teams.  There are many opportunities to be involved in welcoming Afghans as they come to the United States.</p>
<p>As President Biden said to these Afghans and their families, there is a home for you in the United States if you so choose, and we’ll stand with you just as you stood with us.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you both.  We now look forward to taking your questions, and we will do this on background.  You can attribute what you hear to senior State Department officials.  We will have  and  with us.  We will be joined by , we’ll have , and we’ll have .</p>
<p>And so, with that, operator, if you want to just repeat instructions for asking questions.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question today, please press 1 followed by 0.  We will announce your name and organization and put you – open your line.  And as a reminder, please wait until I let you know that your line is open before asking a question.  So again, please press 1, 0 at this time to ask a question.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR: </strong> Great.  We’ll start with Kylie Atwood.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you.  Kylie, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks, guys, for doing this.  I think we all have a bunch of questions.  I am wondering how long the administration plans to be doing these relocation efforts.  Do you expect this is something that will happen over the course of years given some SIV applicants have just applied recently given the U.S. troop withdrawal?</p>
<p>My second question is about safety for these Afghans.  What is the U.S. doing, what can the U.S. do to provide them with any safety when U.S. troops withdraw from the country, and how are they being transported to the airport?  Is there any support for them given threats from the Taliban?  And last question is:  How long are they expected to stay at Fort Lee in this final stage? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>So working backward, we don’t expect them to stay at Fort Lee for very often, or very long, excuse me.  We’ll try to work them through Fort Lee in 7 to 10 day is our hope and expectation.  The applicants need to get themselves to Kabul. We’re not going to talk about how they get in and around Kabul and to the airport for security reasons.</p>
<p>The SIV Program is – has eligibility standards, and we have authorized numbers from the U.S. Congress, and so long as we keep having those numbers provided to us by Congress, we’ll keep processing SIV applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We will go to the line of Andrea Mitchell, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  One moment.  Ms. Mitchell, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Can you talk about the others in the program and where else they might be going, and how long it will take to get what was originally estimated as as many as 70,000 people, including families, accommodated because obviously their lives are right now in danger?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>So the total number of applicants to the SIV Program number just over 20,000, but about half of those have not yet completed the initial stages of the application process, so we’re not in a position to move forward with their case until they do so.  So I’m not sure where the 70,000 number comes from.  The 4,000 number and their families, they would be targeted for the next phase of bringing people to third country locations, and that process in the third country would take longer because they’re not as far along in the screening process as those who we will bring to the United States.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Laura Seligman.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  I apologize, I do not see Laura’s name.  Laura, would you hit 1, 0 again?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  It looks like she just dropped out of the queue.  No problem.  We will move on then to the line of Nick Schifrin.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  Mr. Schifrin, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks, guys.  Let me follow up on what comes next.  Can you confirm that there’s the deal pretty much done to move, I don’t know if it’s the next round or the third round, some of these applicants to military bases in Kuwait and Qatar?  And can you talk about whether there’s a push on P-2 refugees, whether the number – sorry, the kind of aperture of the person who can apply, whether there’s a push to expand that aperture and including P-2 refugees.  And I know you don’t want to talk about some of the details on transport for security reasons, but can you give us any more details on how exactly they will get to Fort Lee this first round?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  I’m sorry, Nick, I was – I didn&#8217;t understand the last piece of the question.  I’m not sure we have many answers that we can give you.  We’re talking to third countries about the possibility of temporary relocation, but we’re not in a position to confirm any agreements with any of those third countries at this time.</p>
<p>On the transportation to Fort Lee, we will fly them into the country and bring them by vehicle to Fort Lee.  I assume it will be buses.</p>
<p>And what was the second question?  I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  P-2.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Oh.  On the question of the P-2 refugee program, we are looking at several options, including expanding pathways through the refugee program.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Ellen Knickmeyer.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  Ms. Knickmeyer, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi there.  Thank you for doing this.  Let’s see.  Is the – because the Afghan SIVs will fly out through the Kabul airport, has there been an agreement finalized to keep that operating under Turkey?  I don’t know if their relocations are all supposed to be completed by the time the U.S. withdraws or not.  And then you say you’re – do you not yet have any agreement from any other country to temporarily host the Afghan SIVs?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  On the second question, we don’t have agreement with any countries that we’re ready to announce here.</p>
<p>On the airport, obviously, we’ve said the airport needs to be open and functioning as part of a normal country, and we’re grateful for our conversations with our colleagues in Turkey.  The DOD is leading those conversations.  We’re optimistic that we’ll have the security package that we need at the airport in Kabul.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Dan Lamothe.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you, one moment.  Mr. Lamothe, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks for doing this today.  A couple follow-on questions just to clarify.  Before these individuals receive chief of mission approval, it sounds like they’ll be staying in Afghanistan?  Just wanted to check on that.</p>
<p>And then when it comes to these facilities in third countries, can you describe a bit what they’re going to look like, both in terms of living conditions and then also any kind of services?  It occurs to me you’re going to have children in play here with potentially months and months of waiting.</p>
<p>And then a third question, since there are a number of anecdotes of interpreters who have been denied SIV applications in the past, often for seemingly unclear and arbitrary reasons, what will be done to take care of individuals like that, especially if it comes down to paperwork from companies they’re not in touch with and things along those lines?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Thanks, Dan.  Working backwards, I mean, the third one – the last question is a tough one because we have applicants who have sought to enter the program who cannot find verification of their employment from their – say they worked for a DOD contractor many years ago.  We’re trying to help them.  The Department of Defense is trying to help with that part of it, but that is a critical first stage to prove eligibility.</p>
<p>On the conditions, I’m not really in a position to speak to that right now in the third countries.  Suffice to say we will house and feed them in safe and adequate facilities.</p>
<p>On your first question, we haven’t made any – we haven’t ruled anything in and out of what we’re doing.  We’re starting in these phases with people at the later stages of the program.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll take a couple additional questions.  We’ll go to the line of Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Mr. Finnegan, please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you for having this call.  A couple of follow-ups as well.  Can you say how many there are in total with this group of 4,000 principal applicants who will be moved to third countries?  If you include their families, what is that total number?</p>
<p>You said applicants will have to get themselves to Kabul.  For many of them, that journey would be dangerous if not impossible.  What would you say to the – to security concerns of folks trying to get to Kabul?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  So we don’t know for certain how many family members will be brought.  The principal applicant can choose to bring the ones that are eligible.  We’ve just been doing these rough extrapolations based on an average of three to five per principal applicant based on past practice.  In order to come on an evacuation flight, they would have to get themselves to Kabul.  Obviously, we don’t have substantial U.S. military presence.  We don’t have an ability to provide transportation for them.  If they’re, say, in the north of the country and they don’t feel safe staying in Afghanistan, they could go to a neighboring country and finish their SIV application process there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We will go to Meghann Myers, who I understand is together with Lara Seligman, so if you want to call on Meghann Myers, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  Ms. Myers, please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, thanks so much, .  This is Lara.  I’m wondering if you could tell us anything more about where else these 4,000 other applicants are going, and what is the timeline for this next batch to come over to the United States?  And then also, I’m wondering what happens to the other Afghans who risked their lives to help the U.S., these journalists, women’s rights activists, Afghan troops that don’t fall into the SIV category.  How are we helping them escape the Taliban?  Thank you.</p>
<p>And this is Meghann.  I’ll jump in after that answer.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Well, Meghann, why don’t you offer your question now?  We’ll take them together.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay, great.  So my question is about the 4,000 who are going to be going abroad to complete their processes.  Will they be able to fully complete everything from the third-party country, or will they need to come to Fort Lee to finish out that process?  And are you looking at any other domestic installations such as Fort Lee for applicants who are in the final stages to go to?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Lara, on your first questions, I don’t really have any more detail than I’ve previously given on the third country option.  On the 4,000 who will be going to third countries, we expect that we would complete the process within – in that third country, and then they would come to the United States and go to their ultimate destination.  We wouldn’t expect as of this time – maybe that could change – to put them onto a military base for any period of time.</p>
<p>As to whether we will use another facility besides Fort Lee, that’s really a question for the Department of Defense.  They were given the requirements by the State Department.  They selected Fort Lee as an option for this, this first phase that we’re doing here of evacuating the people at the later stage in the process.</p>
<p>And then, Lara, your other question about others who have helped the United States, I think I referenced that in response to an earlier question.  We’re looking at other options and pathways for people who’ve helped us.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>And we’ll conclude with the line of Nike Ching.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Thank you very much.  Nike, please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Good afternoon.  Thank you so much for the call.  Just a follow-up question on the Afghanistan fixers who have helped the U.S. press organizations.  Would you support the creation of a visa program for those Afghans, Afghans who helped with the U.S. media organizations and who are now seeking safety in the U.S.?  I’m asking this because a coalition of U.S. media organizations has sent a letter to the Congress requesting to create such visa program.  Would you like to weigh in?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:   </strong>Yes, thank you.  We’ve seen the letter from the news organizations and we’ll be responding in due course to them.  As I think I’ve responded previously to this question, in terms of other people in Afghanistan who have helped the United States or helped U.S. organizations, whether it’s NGOs or media organizations, we are looking at other options for providing safe options for them outside of Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Right, well, thank you very much, everyone.  Just a reminder:  The Q&amp;A was done on a background basis.  That was a senior State Department official.  And with that, the embargo is lifted and we’ll conclude the call.  Talk to you soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Senior State Department Officials On European Energy Security</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-senior-state-department-officials-on-european-energy-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 22:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference </p>
<p>July 21, 2021</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thanks very much, and thanks, everyone, for joining us today for this call on European energy security.</p>
<p>Just a reminder this call is on background, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  As always, we’ll have a transcript available after the fact.</p>
<p>Just for your awareness and not for reporting, we will have two senior State Department officials on today’s call.  We’ll have  as well as .  They will be known as Senior State Department Officials One and Two for the purpose of this call.  First,  will give an overview of the action we are taking today, and both will then be in a position to take your questions.  Again, this call is on background and embargoed until the conclusion.</p>
<p>And so with that, I will turn it over to our first speaker.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Great.  Thanks, .  Good to be with all of you today.  Last week, the President and German Chancellor Angela Merkel affirmed in the July 15th Washington Declaration the United States’ and Germany’s commitment to close bilateral cooperation in promoting peace, security, and prosperity around the world.</p>
<p>This declaration, which demonstrates this administration’s success in turning the page on a difficult chapter in U.S.-German relations, reflects the importance of our alliance to addressing future challenges – from China to COVID to climate change – and is a reminder of why, even when we disagree, allies must resolve their differences in a spirit of pragmatism, friendship, and trust.</p>
<p>This is how we approached managing our profound differences over the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.  While the United States has consistently opposed the construction of the pipeline since the Obama administration, when President Biden took office in January, more than 90 percent of the pipeline had been completed.</p>
<p>Even after Congress passed bipartisan legislation aimed at stopping the pipeline via sanctions in both 2017 and in 2019, the previous administration did not apply sanctions related to the pipeline until its very last day in office, when it imposed sanctions on just one entity and one vessel involved in construction of the pipeline. The previous administration could have used a number of sanctions tools, including its authority under IEEPA, to sanction the pipeline, but it chose not to.</p>
<p>In contrast, in less than six months in office, the Biden administration has imposed sanctions on five entities and five vessels under PEESA, as amended, as well as on an additional nine vessels within the Nord Stream 2 fleet owned by a sanctioned entity.  These designations represent sanctions on a significant portion of the Nord Stream 2 fleet.  To repeat, there were two entities related to Nord Stream 2 sanctioned before January 20th; there have been 19 applied since.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, while we remain opposed to this pipeline, we reached the judgment that sanctions would not stop its construction and risked undermining a critical alliance with Germany, as well as with the EU and other European allies.</p>
<p>We therefore charted a course in line with the President’s commitment to rebuild relations with our allies and intended to create space for diplomacy with Germany to address the risks an operational Nord Stream 2 pipeline would pose to European energy security and to Ukraine and frontline NATO and EU countries.</p>
<p>That is why Germany came to the table to negotiate a package of measures designed to reduce the risk an operational Nord Stream 2 would pose to European energy security, Ukraine, and frontline NATO and EU countries.</p>
<p>This package is designed to address the root causes of those risks – Russia’s use of energy as a geopolitical weapon and the vulnerability of countries like Ukraine, which are dependent on Russian gas and transit fees, to Russian malign activities.</p>
<p>Throughout this process both we and our German partners have consulted closely with Ukraine and Poland as well as other countries that would be harmed by this project about their concerns, which we have taken into account.</p>
<p>Our joint statement sends a clear message that the United States and Germany will not tolerate Russia using energy as a geopolitical weapon in Europe or escalating its aggression against Ukraine.  We’re committed to working together with our allies and partners to impose significant costs on Russia, including in the areas of sanctions and energy flows, if it engages in these malign activities.</p>
<p>We also know that it will take significant time and resources for Ukraine to end its dependence on Russian energy.  That is why, in this statement, Germany has committed to appoint a special envoy and use all of its available leverage in the period before Nord Stream 2 becomes operational to help Ukraine negotiate an extension of its gas transit contract with Russia well beyond 2024.</p>
<p>This proposed extension, the negotiation of which the United States will actively support, would preserve gas flows and transit revenue that Ukraine would otherwise stand to lose once Nord Stream 2 becomes operational, postponing the negative impacts of the pipeline on Ukraine and other transit countries such as Slovakia.</p>
<p>To take full advantage of that time, Germany and the United States have proposed a number of measures to support Ukraine’s efforts toward a more secure and sustainable energy future, in which Ukraine is no longer dependent on Russian gas and transit fees for its energy or revenue.</p>
<p>First, as part of our U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership, Germany has committed to create and administer a billion-dollar Green Fund for Ukraine to support Ukraine’s energy transition, energy efficiency, and energy security.</p>
<p>The goals of the fund will be to promote the use of renewable energy; facilitate the development of hydrogen; increase energy efficiency; accelerate the transition from coal; and foster carbon neutrality.</p>
<p>As a way to jump start this fund, Germany will provide an initial donation of at least 150 million euros and will work toward extending that commitment in future budget years.</p>
<p>The United States will work with Germany to support the fund’s objectives with assistance programming and policy support, as well as helping to promote and support investments in the fund, including from other governments and third parties such as private-sector entities.</p>
<p>Second, Germany has also committed to a 60-million-euro Ukraine Resilience Package to support Ukraine’s energy security, including in such areas as safeguarding reverse flow, facilitating electrical grid integration, building cyber capacity for critical infrastructure, and supporting modernization of and reform to Ukraine’s energy sector.</p>
<p>Third, in light of the adverse effects Nord Stream 2 would have on Central and Eastern European EU member states, Germany will also enhance its engagement with the Three Seas Initiative, with an eye toward investing in projects related to – or part of the initiative.  This is in addition to the 1.5 billion euros Germany will invest in energy projects as part of the EU budget between 2021 and 2027.</p>
<p>Fourth, Germany has also committed to implement the letter and the spirit of the EU Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2, which will support the principles of diversity and security of supply within EU energy markets.</p>
<p>These measures will help to prevent the worst-case scenario – an operational Nord Stream 2 with no protection from its adverse effects for Ukraine, frontline NATO and EU countries, and European energy security as a whole.</p>
<p>Taken together, these measures represent a significant commitment by Germany, supported by the United States, to push back against Russian malign activities and to advance a more secure and sustainable energy future for Ukraine and other frontline NATO and EU countries.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  And just a logistical note: the joint statement that our speaker referred to will be out in just about half an hour, so that will be accessible to you all then.</p>
<p>Operator, if you want to repeat the instructions for questions, we’ll turn to them now.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  And once again, for questions or comments you may press 1 and then 0, 1 and then 0 for your questions or comments.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Great.  We’ll go to the line of Andrea Mitchell, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Andrea, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  There was a very contentious exchange at a hearing this morning, (inaudible) the question from Republican Senator Ted Cruz whether or not there was pressure on Ukraine, and also pointing out from his perspective that it may have been only 90 percent complete but that it was being held up until the decision was made to proceed with it, so that it couldn’t get to the 100 percent of completion without this decision.  So can you address that and his contention that this is the worst geopolitical mistake in a generation as far as enabling Russia.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure.  Thanks, Andrea.  So first let me just address this question of whether we pressured or threatened the Ukrainians – regarding this issue.  There were no threats.  Ukraine is a partner and we don’t threaten our partners.  We have engaged intensively with Ukraine throughout the course of our diplomatic efforts to ensure that Moscow is not able to weaponize the Nord Stream 2 pipeline, and we’ve done so at multiple levels.</p>
<p>We’ve shared details and ideas, including the text of this statement itself, that it remain deliberative and sensitive.  And so, of course, as we always do in the conduct of diplomacy, we have endeavored to keep those consultations private, but we have, as I said, engaged intensively with Ukraine and included its input and ideas in this statement, and we really look forward to continuing to do so as we look to implement the commitments in this statement and as we look forward to welcoming President Zelenskyy to the White House later this summer.</p>
<p>In terms of your next question, in terms of the completion of the pipeline, I would just say that this pipeline was over 90 percent completed when we came into office.  As I noted, this administration has put in place sanctions on 19 targets, and that is compared to only two in the previous administration, and so our opposition to the pipeline, our commitment to following the law, I think, is unquestionable.  And we agree that this is a Russian geopolitical project, but that is why for us the worst-case scenario was a completed pipeline, which we think, as the Secretary has said, that it is virtually a <em>fait accompli,</em> that the construction will be finished, but a completed pipeline and nothing to help Ukraine to reduce the risks that this pipeline poses to it.</p>
<p>So that’s why today we’re announcing with the Germans a total of more than 200 million euros in new funding to help Ukraine to reduce those risks, as well as other measures to support energy security across Europe and to really help Ukraine to pursue a more secure and sustainable energy future.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go the line of Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Simon, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Great, thank you.  You mentioned the commitment to oppose any Russian measures to weaponize energy.  I wonder, in the agreement, is there – is it clearly defined how – clearly spelled out how you and – the U.S. and Russia – sorry, U.S. and Germany will agree on occasions where that’s the case.  And there are – are there – is there a criteria to say this action represents Russia weaponizing its energy?  And further, what specifically is Germany committing to in terms of what sanctions and other measures they would take in that – if that – if it’s agreed that Russia has taken that kind of action?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks for that question.  I mean, I think there’s a clear commitment on the part of the United States and Germany in this statement that should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, that Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions to limit Russian export capabilities to Europe in the energy sector, and that includes gas and/or other economically relevant sectors.</p>
<p>And so with that, Germany has really committed to taking swift action.  As you heard from Chancellor Merkel last week during her visit to Washington, there are a number of tools that Germany and the EU have at their disposal to push back against Russian aggression or malign activities.  This is a strong commitment to do so, but I would say we elected not to provide Russia with a roadmap in terms of how they can evade that commitment to push back.</p>
<p>And so what you see is a commitment that we will move forward swiftly together along with the EU if we see these types of activities, and I think you heard that commitment as well from both the President and from Chancellor Merkel last week.  As the President said, we may have differences over Nord Stream 2, but we remain united in our commitment to pushing back against Russia’s use of energy as a weapon.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Lara, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Great, thank you.  I have a – I just need to clarify on the universe of sanctions that have been levied in relation to Nord Stream.  I think you mentioned 21 in total, 19 in the last six months, and two by the Trump administration.  I’m just confused, are those all now being lifted in order to assuage concerns with Germany, or are those – as I recall, one of them was against a German court that Germany was upset about in January, specifically.  So are most of those against Russians or – entities, or are they against German entities, or could you just give me the status of what’s going to happen with the sanctions that are currently in place?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL TWO:</strong>  Thank you, it’s  here.  What  was outlining were the designations that have already taken place previously with respect to Nord Stream 2.  So the previous administration, on the last day or maybe second-to-last day of the administration, designated one entity and a vessel that it had provided to the project under CAATSA Section 232, Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act.  And then the current administration in its regular reports to Congress under PEESA has identified five vessels and five entities as required, and thus imposed sanctions on those five entities, including listing the five vessels as blocked property.  And in our May report we identified another nine vessels as blocked property because they had been provided to the project by a designated entity.</p>
<p>So the 19 entities and vessels that  referenced are the number of targets that – on which the current administration has imposed sanctions, but those sanctions have already been imposed and continue in effect.</p>
<p>And I’m not – you mentioned something about a sanction with respect to a German court.  I’m not – that’s not something that – that’s not a sanction that we have imposed.  I’m not sure what you’re referring to on that one.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Matt, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, there.  Can you all hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, okay, great.  I just wanted to know, based on what Toria said on the Hill this morning and what Ned said in the briefing just now, are you guys really making the argument that the completion of this pipeline was the Trump – the fault of the Trump administration?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Thanks for the question, Matt.  I mean, I think we’ve been clear that this pipeline was over 90 percent complete when we came into office.  And I think we’ve explained our record in terms of the sanctions that we have imposed under PEESA, as amended.  We continue to oppose the pipeline as a bad deal for Ukraine and for Europe, and we’re committed to following the law.  None of that changes with this statement that we’re issuing today.  But certainly, we think that there is more that the previous administration could have done, but we – we’re making the best of a bad hand, and in doing so we’re trying to make sure that we protect our partner, Ukraine, and that that’s really our priority.</p>
<p>But I think we really want to focus our conversation here, again, on the root causes of this problem, which are Russia’s use of energy as a weapon and its aggression against Ukraine.  And so that’s really our focus here.  We understand the pipeline is a Russian geopolitical project.  We continue to oppose it, and that’s why we’re so focused on working with Germany, with Ukraine, with Poland, and all of our other partners to protect them from the risks that the pipeline poses and to strengthen European energy security.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Nick Schifrin.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks, .  Can I take you back to the punishment question?  I understand that you’re not going to provide Russia with a roadmap, as you said, but you can understand the skepticism, especially on the Hill.  Can you discuss any more about the guarantees that this agreement provides, or this threshold over which you and Germany would take punishment of Russia?  And separately, how are you going to get or will you get Ukraine some kind of guarantee for the 3 billion that it currently receives from transit fees on the overground transfers?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure, thanks for that.  I mean, first of all, in transit revenues, I mean, I think one really key point here is that by extending the transit agreement that Ukraine has with Russia, that means Ukraine isn’t losing any revenue.  And so our goal – and Germany is committing in writing to use all of its available leverage to negotiate that agreement, and we think they have considerable leverage, particularly in this period before Nord Stream 2 is operational, in order to negotiate that agreement.</p>
<p>So our goal is to prevent Ukraine from losing any transit revenues for as long as possible.  Right now they have an agreement through 2024, and so an extension would take them beyond that.  And so if we’re able to get an extension to the agreement, Ukraine isn’t losing any revenue and they’re gaining a billion-dollar fund to help them transition to a more sustainable and secure energy future as well as other programs to help them to support that effort.  So we think there’s certainly something positive here for Ukraine.</p>
<p>In terms of sanctions and other questions, I would just say again that this is a strong commitment, and we heard it last week from the President and Chancellor Merkel, to push back against Russia’s use of energy as a weapon.  We know that Russia does use pipeline energy flows and other tools related to energy to pursue its political ends, and we’re committed to pushing back against that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Francesco Fontemaggi.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And Francesco, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.  I just wanted to ask you again on sanctions.  So you confirmed there is absolutely no automatic sanctions in this agreement in the case of aggressive actions from Russia against Ukraine?  And if yes, why haven’t you seeked some automatic sanctions?  And also on the extension of the transit agreements, so, if I understand, you said that Germany has considerable leverage in this period before Nord Stream 2 is operational.  Do you mean that they committed to, like, say to Russia that they won’t make it operational if the transit agreement isn’t extended for 10 years?  Is that what they committed to?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>So on the question of leverage, Germany has committed to use all of its available leverage to negotiate an extension to the gas transit agreement.  That’s all I can say for now, but I think you heard from Chancellor Merkel last week that commitment.  She said that Ukraine will be a transit country beyond 2024 and that – and she committed future German governments to that as well.  So that is something that we look forward to supporting the German Government as they work with Ukraine to engage in those negotiations, just as we did when the transit agreement was extended previously in 2019.</p>
<p>On the sanctions question, again, this is something where automaticity – and perhaps my colleague  can talk about this a little bit more – is not something that we typically see in the sanctions world.  And so what we have is really a commitment on the part of both the United States and Germany to hold Russia accountable and to impose costs if it elects to use energy as a weapon or to commit aggressive acts against Ukraine.  And so that’s the headline here; that’s our commitment.  And you heard, again, from the President and Chancellor Merkel that that we are committed to following through on that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Dave Lawler, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And, Dave, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thanks.  Wanted to follow up on the comment that the goal of this was to protect Ukraine.  I think the early indications are that the Ukrainians don’t think this deal protects them, doesn’t address their security concerns.  And obviously, that’s being echoed by people on the Hill.  Are they wrong about that?  Are you confident that this does secure Ukraine and they just don’t possibly recognize the benefits?  What’s your position on the concerns that are still out there on the Ukrainian side?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>Yeah, thanks for that question.  So I think we believe that this agreement – sorry, that this statement and the commitments that are outlined in it will help us to reduce the risks that the pipeline would pose to Ukraine and European energy security.  And there are a lot of discussions that are part of our wider bilateral relationship with Ukraine.  One of the things that I think will be good and important about this agreement is that we hope that it will enable us to move forward with conversations in a number of other areas, including on security, rather than only talking about Nord Stream 2, because our relationship with Ukraine is incredibly important.</p>
<p>We are resolutely committed to the sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence, and Euro-Atlantic future of Ukraine, and we want to support Ukraine – Ukraine’s security, its reform process.  And certainly, working toward greater energy security and independence is a part of that, but there are a lot of other issues on our bilateral agenda and we are covering those issues, we’re discussing those issues in a number of different channels.  And so President Zelenskyy, when he visits Washington later this summer, will have an opportunity to discuss those security issues and many others with President Biden.  We’re really looking forward to that and we’re eagerly preparing the ground.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll take a couple final questions here.  We’ll go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And Jennifer, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thanks so much.  Do you have an estimate on when the pipeline will become operational?  And then, can you get into more specifics of how the U.S. intends to enforce this or follow the enforcement on Germany’s part with Merkel stepping down from power?  What happens if a pro-Russia party comes into power in Germany?  Do you expect this agreement to last?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>Thanks for the question.  So in terms of the completion of the pipeline, we understand that it is very, very close to being completed, over 95 precent complete in terms of construction.  That doesn’t mean that gas will start flowing through it immediately.  There are a number of additional steps that have to be completed in order for it to become operational, and so I would refer you to the German Government for questions about their regulatory processes, since this is – in several cases those steps are in the hands of an independent German regulator.</p>
<p>And on your second question, on the impact a new German government would have, I mean, so this is an agreement between the United States and Germany.  I think, again, you heard Chancellor Merkel commit future German governments to Ukraine remaining a transit country and to ensuring that this pipeline doesn’t negatively impact it.  I would also say that we really look forward to engaging with a future German government intensively on the implementation of these commitments.  I expect that we’ll be working very closely together on a trilateral basis with Germany and Ukraine for some time to come in terms of implementing this.</p>
<p>So we really view this as the first step in an intensive effort to support Ukraine’s energy security and sustainability, and so we look forward to working with the next German government on that.  And we also will certainly look to hold any future German government accountable for the commitments that they have made in this statement.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Rich, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  And Rich, please check your mute button.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello.  Sorry about that.  Hey, guys.  Are the U.S. and Germany in this agreement – are the U.S. and Germany just generally prepared for a case that this investment may not be enough for Ukraine, that it may require more support from the U.S. and Germany?</p>
<p>And secondly, if you could just speak to the timing of this in relation to the White House announcement today that President Zelenskyy will be visiting in August and as to why that was announced on the same day?  Is there any connection to that?  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure.  So in terms of the visit, I mean, that invitation was issued in early June, and so we have been working with the Ukrainians to identify a date for some time.  And so that announcement is not related to the issuance of this joint statement.</p>
<p>In terms of your other question, yeah, I would just say that the United States and Germany are the largest bilateral donors to Ukraine, and that has been the case since 2014.  And this is not the sum total of our assistance, nor is it the sum total of our assistance even related to energy.  My colleagues at USAID and the Department of Energy have programs underway to assist Ukraine in a number of these areas already and we’ll continue to work with the Ukrainians on many, many issues through our assistance, as will Germany, to help them on their reform path, to modernize their energy sector, to pursue sustainable, net zero fuels, et cetera.  And so we really look forward to working with Ukraine to help it to achieve its energy security and sustainability goals, and this is just part of that equation.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And we’ll conclude with the line of Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Laura, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Last question, no pressure.  I just want to be clear:  The U.S. is no longer standing in the way of Nord Stream 2 becoming operational?</p>
<p>And then if you could just maybe address the transit agreement one more time between Russia and Ukraine.  Can you give a ballpark for how long that transit agreement will be extended – 10, 20, 30, 100 years?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure.  So in terms of the transit agreement, I don’t think we can prejudge the results of those negotiations, but we certainly will do everything we can to support those negotiations and we look forward to Germany naming a special envoy in the coming weeks to get started on those talks.  And as I said, we look forward to supporting them.  We think the current German Government has been very clear on its intent to ensure that Ukraine is a transit country beyond 2024, and we will support that in any way that we can.</p>
<p>Oh, right.  And yeah, I mean, so this question of whether we’re dropping our opposition – I would just say emphatically that we still oppose Nord Stream 2.  We still believe it’s a Russian geopolitical malign influence project.  None of that has changed, and we are still committed to following the law.  And we have a report due to Congress in mid-August, and we will take a look at any potentially sanctionable activity that entities may be engaged in related to this project and make those decisions on a case-by-case basis.  So we – again, we remain opposed.  We think this is a bad deal for Ukraine and a bad deal for the rest of Europe, but we also are pragmatic, and with it over 95 percent complete, our focus really is on ensuring that we are prepared to push back against Russia’s use of energy as a weapon along with our partners and allies and that we’re doing everything we can to reduce the risk this pipeline poses to Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Well, thanks very much, everyone.  Thanks very much to our speakers.  Just a reminder, this call was on background.  You heard from senior State Department officials.  And with that, the embargo is now lifted.  Thanks, everyone.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference </p>
<p>July 21, 2021</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thanks very much, and thanks, everyone, for joining us today for this call on European energy security.</p>
<p>Just a reminder this call is on background, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  As always, we’ll have a transcript available after the fact.</p>
<p>Just for your awareness and not for reporting, we will have two senior State Department officials on today’s call.  We’ll have  as well as .  They will be known as Senior State Department Officials One and Two for the purpose of this call.  First,  will give an overview of the action we are taking today, and both will then be in a position to take your questions.  Again, this call is on background and embargoed until the conclusion.</p>
<p>And so with that, I will turn it over to our first speaker.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Great.  Thanks, .  Good to be with all of you today.  Last week, the President and German Chancellor Angela Merkel affirmed in the July 15th Washington Declaration the United States’ and Germany’s commitment to close bilateral cooperation in promoting peace, security, and prosperity around the world.</p>
<p>This declaration, which demonstrates this administration’s success in turning the page on a difficult chapter in U.S.-German relations, reflects the importance of our alliance to addressing future challenges – from China to COVID to climate change – and is a reminder of why, even when we disagree, allies must resolve their differences in a spirit of pragmatism, friendship, and trust.</p>
<p>This is how we approached managing our profound differences over the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.  While the United States has consistently opposed the construction of the pipeline since the Obama administration, when President Biden took office in January, more than 90 percent of the pipeline had been completed.</p>
<p>Even after Congress passed bipartisan legislation aimed at stopping the pipeline via sanctions in both 2017 and in 2019, the previous administration did not apply sanctions related to the pipeline until its very last day in office, when it imposed sanctions on just one entity and one vessel involved in construction of the pipeline. The previous administration could have used a number of sanctions tools, including its authority under IEEPA, to sanction the pipeline, but it chose not to.</p>
<p>In contrast, in less than six months in office, the Biden administration has imposed sanctions on five entities and five vessels under PEESA, as amended, as well as on an additional nine vessels within the Nord Stream 2 fleet owned by a sanctioned entity.  These designations represent sanctions on a significant portion of the Nord Stream 2 fleet.  To repeat, there were two entities related to Nord Stream 2 sanctioned before January 20th; there have been 19 applied since.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, while we remain opposed to this pipeline, we reached the judgment that sanctions would not stop its construction and risked undermining a critical alliance with Germany, as well as with the EU and other European allies.</p>
<p>We therefore charted a course in line with the President’s commitment to rebuild relations with our allies and intended to create space for diplomacy with Germany to address the risks an operational Nord Stream 2 pipeline would pose to European energy security and to Ukraine and frontline NATO and EU countries.</p>
<p>That is why Germany came to the table to negotiate a package of measures designed to reduce the risk an operational Nord Stream 2 would pose to European energy security, Ukraine, and frontline NATO and EU countries.</p>
<p>This package is designed to address the root causes of those risks – Russia’s use of energy as a geopolitical weapon and the vulnerability of countries like Ukraine, which are dependent on Russian gas and transit fees, to Russian malign activities.</p>
<p>Throughout this process both we and our German partners have consulted closely with Ukraine and Poland as well as other countries that would be harmed by this project about their concerns, which we have taken into account.</p>
<p>Our joint statement sends a clear message that the United States and Germany will not tolerate Russia using energy as a geopolitical weapon in Europe or escalating its aggression against Ukraine.  We’re committed to working together with our allies and partners to impose significant costs on Russia, including in the areas of sanctions and energy flows, if it engages in these malign activities.</p>
<p>We also know that it will take significant time and resources for Ukraine to end its dependence on Russian energy.  That is why, in this statement, Germany has committed to appoint a special envoy and use all of its available leverage in the period before Nord Stream 2 becomes operational to help Ukraine negotiate an extension of its gas transit contract with Russia well beyond 2024.</p>
<p>This proposed extension, the negotiation of which the United States will actively support, would preserve gas flows and transit revenue that Ukraine would otherwise stand to lose once Nord Stream 2 becomes operational, postponing the negative impacts of the pipeline on Ukraine and other transit countries such as Slovakia.</p>
<p>To take full advantage of that time, Germany and the United States have proposed a number of measures to support Ukraine’s efforts toward a more secure and sustainable energy future, in which Ukraine is no longer dependent on Russian gas and transit fees for its energy or revenue.</p>
<p>First, as part of our U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership, Germany has committed to create and administer a billion-dollar Green Fund for Ukraine to support Ukraine’s energy transition, energy efficiency, and energy security.</p>
<p>The goals of the fund will be to promote the use of renewable energy; facilitate the development of hydrogen; increase energy efficiency; accelerate the transition from coal; and foster carbon neutrality.</p>
<p>As a way to jump start this fund, Germany will provide an initial donation of at least 150 million euros and will work toward extending that commitment in future budget years.</p>
<p>The United States will work with Germany to support the fund’s objectives with assistance programming and policy support, as well as helping to promote and support investments in the fund, including from other governments and third parties such as private-sector entities.</p>
<p>Second, Germany has also committed to a 60-million-euro Ukraine Resilience Package to support Ukraine’s energy security, including in such areas as safeguarding reverse flow, facilitating electrical grid integration, building cyber capacity for critical infrastructure, and supporting modernization of and reform to Ukraine’s energy sector.</p>
<p>Third, in light of the adverse effects Nord Stream 2 would have on Central and Eastern European EU member states, Germany will also enhance its engagement with the Three Seas Initiative, with an eye toward investing in projects related to – or part of the initiative.  This is in addition to the 1.5 billion euros Germany will invest in energy projects as part of the EU budget between 2021 and 2027.</p>
<p>Fourth, Germany has also committed to implement the letter and the spirit of the EU Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2, which will support the principles of diversity and security of supply within EU energy markets.</p>
<p>These measures will help to prevent the worst-case scenario – an operational Nord Stream 2 with no protection from its adverse effects for Ukraine, frontline NATO and EU countries, and European energy security as a whole.</p>
<p>Taken together, these measures represent a significant commitment by Germany, supported by the United States, to push back against Russian malign activities and to advance a more secure and sustainable energy future for Ukraine and other frontline NATO and EU countries.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  And just a logistical note: the joint statement that our speaker referred to will be out in just about half an hour, so that will be accessible to you all then.</p>
<p>Operator, if you want to repeat the instructions for questions, we’ll turn to them now.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  And once again, for questions or comments you may press 1 and then 0, 1 and then 0 for your questions or comments.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Great.  We’ll go to the line of Andrea Mitchell, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Andrea, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  There was a very contentious exchange at a hearing this morning, (inaudible) the question from Republican Senator Ted Cruz whether or not there was pressure on Ukraine, and also pointing out from his perspective that it may have been only 90 percent complete but that it was being held up until the decision was made to proceed with it, so that it couldn’t get to the 100 percent of completion without this decision.  So can you address that and his contention that this is the worst geopolitical mistake in a generation as far as enabling Russia.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure.  Thanks, Andrea.  So first let me just address this question of whether we pressured or threatened the Ukrainians – regarding this issue.  There were no threats.  Ukraine is a partner and we don’t threaten our partners.  We have engaged intensively with Ukraine throughout the course of our diplomatic efforts to ensure that Moscow is not able to weaponize the Nord Stream 2 pipeline, and we’ve done so at multiple levels.</p>
<p>We’ve shared details and ideas, including the text of this statement itself, that it remain deliberative and sensitive.  And so, of course, as we always do in the conduct of diplomacy, we have endeavored to keep those consultations private, but we have, as I said, engaged intensively with Ukraine and included its input and ideas in this statement, and we really look forward to continuing to do so as we look to implement the commitments in this statement and as we look forward to welcoming President Zelenskyy to the White House later this summer.</p>
<p>In terms of your next question, in terms of the completion of the pipeline, I would just say that this pipeline was over 90 percent completed when we came into office.  As I noted, this administration has put in place sanctions on 19 targets, and that is compared to only two in the previous administration, and so our opposition to the pipeline, our commitment to following the law, I think, is unquestionable.  And we agree that this is a Russian geopolitical project, but that is why for us the worst-case scenario was a completed pipeline, which we think, as the Secretary has said, that it is virtually a <em>fait accompli,</em> that the construction will be finished, but a completed pipeline and nothing to help Ukraine to reduce the risks that this pipeline poses to it.</p>
<p>So that’s why today we’re announcing with the Germans a total of more than 200 million euros in new funding to help Ukraine to reduce those risks, as well as other measures to support energy security across Europe and to really help Ukraine to pursue a more secure and sustainable energy future.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go the line of Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Simon, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Great, thank you.  You mentioned the commitment to oppose any Russian measures to weaponize energy.  I wonder, in the agreement, is there – is it clearly defined how – clearly spelled out how you and – the U.S. and Russia – sorry, U.S. and Germany will agree on occasions where that’s the case.  And there are – are there – is there a criteria to say this action represents Russia weaponizing its energy?  And further, what specifically is Germany committing to in terms of what sanctions and other measures they would take in that – if that – if it’s agreed that Russia has taken that kind of action?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks for that question.  I mean, I think there’s a clear commitment on the part of the United States and Germany in this statement that should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, that Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions to limit Russian export capabilities to Europe in the energy sector, and that includes gas and/or other economically relevant sectors.</p>
<p>And so with that, Germany has really committed to taking swift action.  As you heard from Chancellor Merkel last week during her visit to Washington, there are a number of tools that Germany and the EU have at their disposal to push back against Russian aggression or malign activities.  This is a strong commitment to do so, but I would say we elected not to provide Russia with a roadmap in terms of how they can evade that commitment to push back.</p>
<p>And so what you see is a commitment that we will move forward swiftly together along with the EU if we see these types of activities, and I think you heard that commitment as well from both the President and from Chancellor Merkel last week.  As the President said, we may have differences over Nord Stream 2, but we remain united in our commitment to pushing back against Russia’s use of energy as a weapon.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Lara, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Great, thank you.  I have a – I just need to clarify on the universe of sanctions that have been levied in relation to Nord Stream.  I think you mentioned 21 in total, 19 in the last six months, and two by the Trump administration.  I’m just confused, are those all now being lifted in order to assuage concerns with Germany, or are those – as I recall, one of them was against a German court that Germany was upset about in January, specifically.  So are most of those against Russians or – entities, or are they against German entities, or could you just give me the status of what’s going to happen with the sanctions that are currently in place?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL TWO:</strong>  Thank you, it’s  here.  What  was outlining were the designations that have already taken place previously with respect to Nord Stream 2.  So the previous administration, on the last day or maybe second-to-last day of the administration, designated one entity and a vessel that it had provided to the project under CAATSA Section 232, Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act.  And then the current administration in its regular reports to Congress under PEESA has identified five vessels and five entities as required, and thus imposed sanctions on those five entities, including listing the five vessels as blocked property.  And in our May report we identified another nine vessels as blocked property because they had been provided to the project by a designated entity.</p>
<p>So the 19 entities and vessels that  referenced are the number of targets that – on which the current administration has imposed sanctions, but those sanctions have already been imposed and continue in effect.</p>
<p>And I’m not – you mentioned something about a sanction with respect to a German court.  I’m not – that’s not something that – that’s not a sanction that we have imposed.  I’m not sure what you’re referring to on that one.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Matt, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, there.  Can you all hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, okay, great.  I just wanted to know, based on what Toria said on the Hill this morning and what Ned said in the briefing just now, are you guys really making the argument that the completion of this pipeline was the Trump – the fault of the Trump administration?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Thanks for the question, Matt.  I mean, I think we’ve been clear that this pipeline was over 90 percent complete when we came into office.  And I think we’ve explained our record in terms of the sanctions that we have imposed under PEESA, as amended.  We continue to oppose the pipeline as a bad deal for Ukraine and for Europe, and we’re committed to following the law.  None of that changes with this statement that we’re issuing today.  But certainly, we think that there is more that the previous administration could have done, but we – we’re making the best of a bad hand, and in doing so we’re trying to make sure that we protect our partner, Ukraine, and that that’s really our priority.</p>
<p>But I think we really want to focus our conversation here, again, on the root causes of this problem, which are Russia’s use of energy as a weapon and its aggression against Ukraine.  And so that’s really our focus here.  We understand the pipeline is a Russian geopolitical project.  We continue to oppose it, and that’s why we’re so focused on working with Germany, with Ukraine, with Poland, and all of our other partners to protect them from the risks that the pipeline poses and to strengthen European energy security.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Nick Schifrin.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks, .  Can I take you back to the punishment question?  I understand that you’re not going to provide Russia with a roadmap, as you said, but you can understand the skepticism, especially on the Hill.  Can you discuss any more about the guarantees that this agreement provides, or this threshold over which you and Germany would take punishment of Russia?  And separately, how are you going to get or will you get Ukraine some kind of guarantee for the 3 billion that it currently receives from transit fees on the overground transfers?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure, thanks for that.  I mean, first of all, in transit revenues, I mean, I think one really key point here is that by extending the transit agreement that Ukraine has with Russia, that means Ukraine isn’t losing any revenue.  And so our goal – and Germany is committing in writing to use all of its available leverage to negotiate that agreement, and we think they have considerable leverage, particularly in this period before Nord Stream 2 is operational, in order to negotiate that agreement.</p>
<p>So our goal is to prevent Ukraine from losing any transit revenues for as long as possible.  Right now they have an agreement through 2024, and so an extension would take them beyond that.  And so if we’re able to get an extension to the agreement, Ukraine isn’t losing any revenue and they’re gaining a billion-dollar fund to help them transition to a more sustainable and secure energy future as well as other programs to help them to support that effort.  So we think there’s certainly something positive here for Ukraine.</p>
<p>In terms of sanctions and other questions, I would just say again that this is a strong commitment, and we heard it last week from the President and Chancellor Merkel, to push back against Russia’s use of energy as a weapon.  We know that Russia does use pipeline energy flows and other tools related to energy to pursue its political ends, and we’re committed to pushing back against that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Francesco Fontemaggi.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And Francesco, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.  I just wanted to ask you again on sanctions.  So you confirmed there is absolutely no automatic sanctions in this agreement in the case of aggressive actions from Russia against Ukraine?  And if yes, why haven’t you seeked some automatic sanctions?  And also on the extension of the transit agreements, so, if I understand, you said that Germany has considerable leverage in this period before Nord Stream 2 is operational.  Do you mean that they committed to, like, say to Russia that they won’t make it operational if the transit agreement isn’t extended for 10 years?  Is that what they committed to?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>So on the question of leverage, Germany has committed to use all of its available leverage to negotiate an extension to the gas transit agreement.  That’s all I can say for now, but I think you heard from Chancellor Merkel last week that commitment.  She said that Ukraine will be a transit country beyond 2024 and that – and she committed future German governments to that as well.  So that is something that we look forward to supporting the German Government as they work with Ukraine to engage in those negotiations, just as we did when the transit agreement was extended previously in 2019.</p>
<p>On the sanctions question, again, this is something where automaticity – and perhaps my colleague  can talk about this a little bit more – is not something that we typically see in the sanctions world.  And so what we have is really a commitment on the part of both the United States and Germany to hold Russia accountable and to impose costs if it elects to use energy as a weapon or to commit aggressive acts against Ukraine.  And so that’s the headline here; that’s our commitment.  And you heard, again, from the President and Chancellor Merkel that that we are committed to following through on that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Dave Lawler, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And, Dave, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thanks.  Wanted to follow up on the comment that the goal of this was to protect Ukraine.  I think the early indications are that the Ukrainians don’t think this deal protects them, doesn’t address their security concerns.  And obviously, that’s being echoed by people on the Hill.  Are they wrong about that?  Are you confident that this does secure Ukraine and they just don’t possibly recognize the benefits?  What’s your position on the concerns that are still out there on the Ukrainian side?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>Yeah, thanks for that question.  So I think we believe that this agreement – sorry, that this statement and the commitments that are outlined in it will help us to reduce the risks that the pipeline would pose to Ukraine and European energy security.  And there are a lot of discussions that are part of our wider bilateral relationship with Ukraine.  One of the things that I think will be good and important about this agreement is that we hope that it will enable us to move forward with conversations in a number of other areas, including on security, rather than only talking about Nord Stream 2, because our relationship with Ukraine is incredibly important.</p>
<p>We are resolutely committed to the sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence, and Euro-Atlantic future of Ukraine, and we want to support Ukraine – Ukraine’s security, its reform process.  And certainly, working toward greater energy security and independence is a part of that, but there are a lot of other issues on our bilateral agenda and we are covering those issues, we’re discussing those issues in a number of different channels.  And so President Zelenskyy, when he visits Washington later this summer, will have an opportunity to discuss those security issues and many others with President Biden.  We’re really looking forward to that and we’re eagerly preparing the ground.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll take a couple final questions here.  We’ll go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And Jennifer, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thanks so much.  Do you have an estimate on when the pipeline will become operational?  And then, can you get into more specifics of how the U.S. intends to enforce this or follow the enforcement on Germany’s part with Merkel stepping down from power?  What happens if a pro-Russia party comes into power in Germany?  Do you expect this agreement to last?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:  </strong>Thanks for the question.  So in terms of the completion of the pipeline, we understand that it is very, very close to being completed, over 95 precent complete in terms of construction.  That doesn’t mean that gas will start flowing through it immediately.  There are a number of additional steps that have to be completed in order for it to become operational, and so I would refer you to the German Government for questions about their regulatory processes, since this is – in several cases those steps are in the hands of an independent German regulator.</p>
<p>And on your second question, on the impact a new German government would have, I mean, so this is an agreement between the United States and Germany.  I think, again, you heard Chancellor Merkel commit future German governments to Ukraine remaining a transit country and to ensuring that this pipeline doesn’t negatively impact it.  I would also say that we really look forward to engaging with a future German government intensively on the implementation of these commitments.  I expect that we’ll be working very closely together on a trilateral basis with Germany and Ukraine for some time to come in terms of implementing this.</p>
<p>So we really view this as the first step in an intensive effort to support Ukraine’s energy security and sustainability, and so we look forward to working with the next German government on that.  And we also will certainly look to hold any future German government accountable for the commitments that they have made in this statement.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Rich, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  And Rich, please check your mute button.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello.  Sorry about that.  Hey, guys.  Are the U.S. and Germany in this agreement – are the U.S. and Germany just generally prepared for a case that this investment may not be enough for Ukraine, that it may require more support from the U.S. and Germany?</p>
<p>And secondly, if you could just speak to the timing of this in relation to the White House announcement today that President Zelenskyy will be visiting in August and as to why that was announced on the same day?  Is there any connection to that?  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure.  So in terms of the visit, I mean, that invitation was issued in early June, and so we have been working with the Ukrainians to identify a date for some time.  And so that announcement is not related to the issuance of this joint statement.</p>
<p>In terms of your other question, yeah, I would just say that the United States and Germany are the largest bilateral donors to Ukraine, and that has been the case since 2014.  And this is not the sum total of our assistance, nor is it the sum total of our assistance even related to energy.  My colleagues at USAID and the Department of Energy have programs underway to assist Ukraine in a number of these areas already and we’ll continue to work with the Ukrainians on many, many issues through our assistance, as will Germany, to help them on their reform path, to modernize their energy sector, to pursue sustainable, net zero fuels, et cetera.  And so we really look forward to working with Ukraine to help it to achieve its energy security and sustainability goals, and this is just part of that equation.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And we’ll conclude with the line of Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And Laura, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Last question, no pressure.  I just want to be clear:  The U.S. is no longer standing in the way of Nord Stream 2 becoming operational?</p>
<p>And then if you could just maybe address the transit agreement one more time between Russia and Ukraine.  Can you give a ballpark for how long that transit agreement will be extended – 10, 20, 30, 100 years?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</strong>  Sure.  So in terms of the transit agreement, I don’t think we can prejudge the results of those negotiations, but we certainly will do everything we can to support those negotiations and we look forward to Germany naming a special envoy in the coming weeks to get started on those talks.  And as I said, we look forward to supporting them.  We think the current German Government has been very clear on its intent to ensure that Ukraine is a transit country beyond 2024, and we will support that in any way that we can.</p>
<p>Oh, right.  And yeah, I mean, so this question of whether we’re dropping our opposition – I would just say emphatically that we still oppose Nord Stream 2.  We still believe it’s a Russian geopolitical malign influence project.  None of that has changed, and we are still committed to following the law.  And we have a report due to Congress in mid-August, and we will take a look at any potentially sanctionable activity that entities may be engaged in related to this project and make those decisions on a case-by-case basis.  So we – again, we remain opposed.  We think this is a bad deal for Ukraine and a bad deal for the rest of Europe, but we also are pragmatic, and with it over 95 percent complete, our focus really is on ensuring that we are prepared to push back against Russia’s use of energy as a weapon along with our partners and allies and that we’re doing everything we can to reduce the risk this pipeline poses to Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Well, thanks very much, everyone.  Thanks very much to our speakers.  Just a reminder, this call was on background.  You heard from senior State Department officials.  And with that, the embargo is now lifted.  Thanks, everyone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 21, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-21-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 22:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=261072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>1:05 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. A couple things at the top.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Norway"></a> We join Norwegians and others around the world in remembering the horrific July 22nd, 2011 attacks in Utoya and Oslo. On that day, Norway experienced its deadliest attack since World War II. And since then, our thoughts and prayers have been with the victims, as well as with their family, their friends, and the first responders as well.</p>
<p>These types of attacks remind us of the threat we all face from violent extremism and terrorism. The entire international community has a stake in preventing this kind of violent extremism and terror going forward.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-InvestmentCliamateStatements"></a> Next, the department released the 2021 Investment Climate Statements. These reports analyze the business climates of more than 170 countries and economies that are current or potential markets for American companies. U.S. businesses can use the Investment Climate Statements to inform their international investment decisions in any one of the covered economies. The Investment Climate Statements are, also, points of reference for foreign governments. looking to improve their business climates and attract U.S. investment.</p>
<p>The reports include information on barriers to investment U.S. companies are likely to encounter. They also highlight progress made on reducing these barriers and creating a fair, open, transparent market that’s attractive to foreign direct investors.</p>
<p>The Department of State works with our foreign government partners to build business environments that are not only economically sound, but also adhere to high standards such as protecting the environment and respecting human rights.</p>
<p>The Investment Climate Statements are one of the many ways in which the department connects our foreign policy work to the needs and the aspirations of the American people and U.S. companies as well.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Really? That’s it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You have nothing else to say? Okay. All right, well, I was going to start with Sesame Street and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Grover asked some hard-hitting questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My daughter – yes, exactly. My daughter &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You might want to take a cue.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My four-year-old daughter is an enormous fan, and I’m sure she’ll love to see it. But I won’t start with that, because there are other, more pressing matters.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I would welcome it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m sure you would. Toria, up on the Hill, just a while ago said that you guys have reached an agreement with the Germans on Nord Stream 2, and so I’m wondering if you – recognizing their – that this joint statement that she talked about hasn’t come out, yet/ I’m just wondering if there’s any more you can add to what she said ahead of the release of that statement.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-NordStream"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There is not more that I’m prepared to add right now. We talked about this some yesterday, and we talked about our rationale in approaching this challenge, and I made very clear yesterday, as did the President in his meeting with Chancellor Merkel earlier this month, that we continue to oppose Nord Stream 2. We continue to view it as a Kremlin geopolitical project whose goal is to expand Russia’s influence over Europe’s energy resources. We continue to believe it’s a bad deal for Germany, it’s a bad deal for Ukraine, it’s a bad deal for Europe and Europe’s broader energy security goals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And yet you’re prepared to allow it to go ahead without &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; without trying to – without trying to stop it, even at this late hour?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And to demonstrate that opposition, we have consistently applied sanctions and examined potentially sanctionable activity, and acted on that. And of course, we have in May imposed sanctions on 19 entities and vessels, and at the same time – as you’ve heard from the Secretary, as you’ve heard from the President – we have come to the conclusion, as any rational observer would, that sanctions are unlikely to stop, to stand in the way of the completion of the pipeline, to prevent the pipeline’s construction. And so, that is why this administration determined that it was not in our interest to significantly undermine, to weaken our bilateral relationship, our ally, the relationship we have with our ally, Germany, for a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, but it’s really – no need &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; but if I could just &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There’s no need to repeat everything that you said yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; no, no, no, but if I could just finish a couple points – for a pipeline whose construction would continue, nonetheless.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Germany"></a> Now, to your question – and I mentioned this yesterday, or I alluded to it – the Germans have put forward useful proposals, and we’ve been able to make progress on steps to achieve our shared goal, and that shared goal is very important. That shared goal is ensuring that this pipeline cannot be weaponized against Ukraine, against any other European partner. That is our goal in doing so. I do expect we’ll be able to share more details on this today.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But one other point I want to really emphasize here: We are committed to following the law; we are committed to continuing to examine entities that have engaged in potentially sanctionable activity. Any decisions on sanctions or sanctions-related decisions, those will be made on a case-by-case basis consistent with the law.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, just three very quick points. One. If you’re committed to following the law, then you would actually follow the law, right? Which says that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> And we have, correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I think that a lot of people think that’s debatable. The second thing is that you say “any rational observer” would realize that sanctions wouldn’t stop this. Well, are you saying that members of Congress, who are Democrats as well as Republicans, are irrational?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We have looked at this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you saying that Senator Shaheen is irrational, that Senator Menendez is irrational &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; because they think that this could actually be stopped?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ve looked at this issue very closely, and we have examined &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And they haven’t?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I’m speaking for us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, right. So you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I’m the spokesperson for the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you know more than they do? That’s the idea?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m saying I can speak to the Department of State, and what I can say is that we have looked at this issue very closely. We examined a range of options, a range of tools at our disposal. We came to the conclusion that for a pipeline that was 90 – more than 90 percent complete, on the day this administration assumed office, to potentially undermine our relationship with Germany, and to send a signal to our allies and to our partners the world over that the United States is willing to throw asunder important relationships, that’s not something that we were eager to do, certainly.</p>
<p>We also know that perhaps now more than ever we need our allies, we need our partners, across a range of challenges to confront a host of threats. And in this briefing room, we’ve discussed our cooperation with Germany on any number of fronts, from the PRC, to Afghanistan, to the climate crisis, to the shared values that we have more broadly.</p>
<p>I will also say that even as we came to this conclusion and going forward, we have shown that we are going to always follow the law. We enacted sanctions, as I said, in May on 19 entities and vessels. That is in contrast to two sanctions that were levied by the previous administration under which more than 90 percent of this pipeline was completed.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Russia"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. The last thing, and it’s kind of a minor thing, but you keep referring to this – to the pipeline as a Russian geopolitical project, as if in some way the phrase “geopolitical project” is pejorative. Why?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There are innumerable U.S. policies that are geopolitical projects.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Of course. Our &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So why do you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> No, no. I don’t – we have not intended the term “geopolitical project” to be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, you have. You use it constantly. It’s, like, in the talking points along with &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It is – to us, it is more than a pipeline.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It is more than a pipeline that carries &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, so is your campaign against Huawei and 5G, so is your campaign against any number of things.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I don’t think you’re going to find – I don’t think you’re going to find – I didn’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So “geopolitical project” is not intended to be a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> A geopolitical – a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; and not intended to be pejorative?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Oh, no, no, no. It is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’re not saying that Russia can’t have geopolitical projects because you don’t like them.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> States have geopolitical projects.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>This is a geopolitical &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s all.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> No, no, but you asked the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I did, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> This is a geopolitical project intended to exert, and to expand, Russia’s influence over Ukraine and other parts of Europe.</p>
<p>Other questions. Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Let me pursue that. One of the things that Toria mentioned was that there’s a pursuit of a tenure extension of – after 2024 of the transit rights in Ukraine. What’s the enforcement mechanism for that? I know you said at the beginning that you’re not going to get into the details, but if I can pursue that, what – how could this actually be enforced?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> There are a number of good questions about this. We are going to have an opportunity today to speak to this in some detail. I would expect today you will see an official release as well, so I’m going to reserve comment until we’re in a position to do that.</p>
<p>Other questions? Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Different topic. News reports say that the U.S. is putting pressure on the Israeli Government to stop all settlement activities in the Palestinian territories. Is that accurate, and do you have any time for the reopening of the U.S. consulate in Jerusalem?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Israel"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, when it comes to the reopening of the U.S. consulate, Secretary Blinken was clear on this when he visited Jerusalem and Ramallah, earlier this year. He noted then that the United States will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem and will do so as part of our effort to re-establish that partnership with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority precisely because it allows us to engage with them, it allows us to execute our assistance programs, it allows us to execute our public diplomacy mission, and to conduct the sort of diplomatic reporting that we need. I don’t have a timeframe to offer for you, but we’ll be happy to keep you posted.</p>
<p>When it comes to settlement activity, we have also been clear and consistent on that. We believe it’s critical to refrain from unilateral steps that increase tensions and make it more difficult to advance a negotiated two-state solution. This is a message we have conveyed in public, as I have just now, but also in private. And it has been the longstanding position, certainly the position of this administration and had been a longstanding position of prior administrations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could we go to a new topic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To Deputy Secretary Sherman’s visit to China that’s coming up. You’ve been saying in recent days that the United States will only – only goes ahead with a visit such as this one if there is a point to it, if it’s constructive, the lines that you’ve given on that.</p>
<p>So what made you think – what made the department think that it was the right time for her to go to China? Is there something that she – specifically she hopes to achieve there?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-DeputySecretaryTravel"></a><a id="post-261072-China"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. So as we announced this morning, and I’m sure you all have seen the announcement, the deputy will travel to the People’s Republic of China on July 25th. She will travel there after her stops in Tokyo and Seoul and Ulaanbaatar as well. In the PRC, she will take part in meetings in Tianjin where she will meet with PRC officials, including State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi. These discussions, as we’ve said, are part of an ongoing U.S. effort to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials, designed to advance U.S. interests and values; and overall to allow us to responsibly manage this incredibly consequential bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>We said earlier this week before we were in a position to confirm the trip that, as you alluded to, the deputy would be prepared to travel if her engagement there would be substantive, constructive; if it were indeed to be a forum and a venue for us to accomplish what we seek to accomplish, and that is to advance U.S. interests, to explore and to discuss how we can manage this relationship responsibly, and how we can address the competition and responsibly manage the competition &#8211; and the stiff competition, that we welcome with the PRC.</p>
<p>And so the PRC has confirmed an in-person meeting with State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi. We’ve said all along that we seek for our senior-level engagement with PRC officials to be substantive and constructive, and we believe this meeting has the potential to be just that.</p>
<p>Look, when – in the context of relationships that are complex, that are challenging, that are dynamic, we believe it’s important to maintain open lines of communication between high-level officials, and that includes in times of, as in the case with the PRC, sustained competition, even when the PRC is taking actions that challenge our interests, that challenge our values. And these are shared interests. These are shared values, And so, I think it’s important in that context to note that the deputy will be traveling to the PRC, after having visited Japan, after having visited the Republic of Korea, after having visited Mongolia as well. She’ll be traveling there, as we have said, from a position of strength, not unlike how Secretary Blinken met with Director Yang and other PRC officials in Anchorage on the way back from the Indo-Pacific region, where we had engaged in consultations with our Japanese and South Korean counterparts as well.</p>
<p>I think broadly speaking, the deputy intends for this engagement to show and to demonstrate to the PRC what responsible and healthy competition can look like. As I’ve said before, we know this relationship is going to be competitive. We welcome that competition. We welcome that stiff competition. But we also want to make sure that the playing field is level, and importantly, that competition doesn’t veer into conflict. We want to make sure that this is a relationship that has guard rails there – where there are clearly defined parameters to the relationship as well. And we believe, again, that engaging in practical, substantive, and a direct manner, as we expect this visit will be, will help us achieve those goals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just follow up on that quickly?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> When you talk about wanting responsible and healthy competition with the PRC, has there been any indication that they are interested in engaging in that kind of competition since President Biden has taken office or since Secretary of State met with Chinese officials earlier this year?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Much of what we’ve done in the early months of this administration is to test the – test various propositions. We want competition with China where we’re competing against one another. This is a relationship that is fundamentally predicated on competition, it’s fundamentally competitive at its core, in our estimation, but again, where the playing field is level, where the rules of the game are clearly defined and enforced, and where there are guard rails to ensure and to see to it that competition doesn’t spill over into something more dangerous, including, at worst, conflict.</p>
<p>So we have tested that proposition in a number of ways. The Secretary and National Security Advisor Sullivan met with Director Yang, met with other senior PRC officials in Anchorage, where we had our first senior-level engagement with the PRC. Of course, Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity to speak to Director Yang on a couple of occasions since then. President Biden, I would be remiss to add, has had an opportunity to speak to President Xi.</p>
<p>And so these open lines of communication are important in their own right because we believe – and especially at times of stiff competition – that we need dialogue. We need constructive dialogue, but it’s also important for us to – for the PRC to hear from us, and for us to hear from the PRC, perspectives on the relationship. And that will help us test the proposition, and arrive at a conclusion as to how we can most effectively ensure that the relationship is conducted on a level playing field, that those guardrails are there, and that it is managed responsibly.</p>
<p>So this is an ongoing endeavor for us. The deputy’s travel and engagement in PRC will be the next phase in that process.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, if I – UK-EU – you wanted to ask on the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I – just one more thing on the PRC? Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just briefly, the – you also mentioned – the State Department mentioned that she’s going on to Oman. Oman obviously has had a key role in indirect diplomacy with Iran. Is that one of the key elements there of going to Oman?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Oman has played an important mediating role in the region. We’ll have more on her travel and engagements in Oman as that gets closer, but certainly we’ve worked closely with Oman on a range of regional priorities. Iran is one of them, Yemen is another, and we’ll have a fuller description of that visit as the time comes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I just wanted to ask on the UK-EU agreement on Northern Ireland. The – Prime Minister Boris Johnson wants to renegotiate parts of that. The E.U. today has rejected that attempt at renegotiation, just saying that it imperiled the Good Friday Agreement, among other things. Just wanted to know where the U.S. stands. Are they – is the U.S. worried about the Good Friday Agreement or is the U.S. worried about the flow of goods between the UK and – between Northern Ireland and the rest of the UK – things like sausages, medicine, even seeing eye dogs – that London says have been obstructed by the current deal?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-NorthernIreland"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we have seen the reports of the UK’s command paper proposal on the Northern Ireland Protocol. We would refer you to the UK and to the E.U. for questions on the negotiations. Of course, the United States is not a direct party to them. But we do and we have encouraged all parties to prioritize political and economic stability in Northern Ireland in the context of these discussions.</p>
<p>To your question, President Biden has been nothing but unequivocal in his support for the Belfast and the Good Friday Agreement, which was an historic agreement at the time, remains significant and incredibly important. We support a close relationship between the UK and the EU, and between all communities in Northern Ireland as well. And we continue to encourage the parties to negotiate within existing mechanisms, and to avoid unilateral actions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just further to that, do you have any comments on how the implications of this might impact a future U.S.-UK trade deal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Look, I – what we’re going to focus on now is what we would like to see broadly, and that is we would encourage all the parties to prioritize political and economic stability in Northern Ireland in these discussions while continuing to negotiate within existing mechanisms and avoiding unilateral actions. I’m not going to entertain hypotheticals, what might happen. Right now, we’re focused on what is happening between the parties.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Varosha in Cyprus, are you planning to impose sanctions on Turkey after the steps that it has taken?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are looking at a number of steps, but let me just back up, and I’m sure you saw the statement from the Secretary that was released last night. In it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A little late last night.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, again, we operate under the assumption that you all like information at the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That we’re all awake at 10 o’clock? Okay, okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You like information at the speed of news, so we’re happy to hold things.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it was news about four hours earlier, so – or five. Just to point that out.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s – we think it’s news when the Secretary speaks.</p>
<p>The – as you heard last night, we condemn the announcement by the Turkish Cypriot leader Ersin Tatar and Turkish President Erdogan regarding the transfer of parts of Varosha to Cypriot – to Turkish Cypriot control. Such a move is clearly inconsistent with UN Security Council Resolutions 550 and 789, which are very explicit in their calls for Varosha to be administered by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Since last year, since October of 2020, Turkish Cypriots and Turkey have ignored calls from the international community and from the UN Security Council to reverse their steps on Varosha. The – we view Turkey – Turkish Cypriot actions in Varosha, which have the support of Turkey, as provocative, as unacceptable, and incompatible with their past commitments to engage constructively in settlement talks.</p>
<p>We continue to support efforts to refer this situation, which we deem to be very concerning, to the UN Security Council, and we will urge a strong response from the international community. Again, to go back to the basics, we support a Cypriot-led comprehensive settlement to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation to benefit all Cypriots and the wider region. We continue to encourage efforts to de-escalate tensions in the Eastern Mediterranean, and to call for the resolution of issues through dialogue and in accordance with international law, not unilateral action.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What about the sanctions at the UN and is the U.S. prepared to take such actions against Turkey too?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> As I – as you have heard us say before, we don’t preview policy actions, and certainly not any sanctions, but we do support efforts to refer this to the UN Security Council and we will urge the international community to muster a strong response. The United States would be certainly a part of that.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A Russian hacker named Peter Levashov was freed yesterday on time served for his hacking activities. There was some speculation that he could be part of a prisoner exchange for either Paul Whelan or Trevor Reed. Did the administration have any role in his sentencing and freeing, and is there a prisoner swap underway?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Conor, you won’t be surprised to hear that I don’t have anything for you on that. We have made very clear – and President Biden was clear with President Putin, Secretary Blinken was clear with Foreign Minister Lavrov, other U.S. officials at multiple levels have been unambiguous with their Russian counterparts – that Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed, their release from their unjustified detention is an absolute priority for us. We are working very hard and doing everything we can to see to it that they are reunited with their families as soon as is possible. They have been held against their will, of course, away from their families. They’ve missed birthdays; they have missed anniversaries. They have missed important life occasions and, importantly, their families have missed them. And so we will continue to do all we can. As you know, we don’t often speak publicly of our efforts to effect the release of Americans who are unjustly detained around the world, but we are always, always working on these cases.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So just no denial, then, that the administration maybe played a role in the judge’s decision here?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have anything for you on that. I’m just not entertaining the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. You speak publicly all the time. We just went through this on Monday, after you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; went after the Iranians for talking about &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well – no.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; about a prisoner swap.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What – and what I said on Monday is that we have made it a priority.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, but don’t say that you don’t talk about it, because you do.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We don’t detail it. We don’t detail it. I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, you talk about it all the time.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; Matt, you – I think, Matt, you would agree with that, that we do not detail our efforts to release – to seek the release, to effect the release of Americans who are unjustly detained around the world. And we don’t do that for the simple reason that their release, expeditious release, is our top priority. And we wouldn’t want to do anything that could complicate, that could delay their potential freedom.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Is there anything new on either Haiti or Cuba? And please don’t repeat the statement from last night or your comments yesterday about the Cuba review. I’m just asking, is there anything new that you can report to us today on either of those Caribbean situations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we did release a statement on the new &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Go ahead and read it for us, all 20 minutes of it.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-haiti"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I – well, I am not going to – I’m not going to read the statement. But I will just say very briefly that the formation of a new government in Haiti is a positive, it’s a necessary step to respond to the Haitian people’s needs and to begin Haiti – to begin restoring Haiti’s democratic institutions. We do welcome efforts by Haiti’s political leadership to come together in choosing an interim prime minister as well as a unity cabinet to chart a path forward in the wake of the assassination of President Moise, and we’re committed to working with Haiti’s new government to support its investigation into the assassination, to expand our COVID-19 vaccination efforts, and to promote security and the rule of law.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue, as we have done, to coordinate with Haitian and international partners to support efforts to establish the conditions necessary for Haitians, importantly, to vote in free and fair elections – in free and fair legislative elections and presidential elections as soon as possible.</p>
<p>We urge, in the meantime, members of Haiti’s new government to work with civil society to find solutions to the many pressing challenges facing Haiti and to facilitate that return to long-term stability and prosperity.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On the investigation, Haitian authorities said today that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You couldn’t not do it, could you? It was just impossible for you not to re-read the entire – okay, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, you’re good. The Haitian authorities said today that they arrest – that they have in mind three foreigners who they believe helped to fund the operation that assassinated the president. Is the U.S. Government aware whether or not any of those three are American citizens? And they asked again for further FBI help in tracking down those three potential suspects. What is the FBI doing? Can you provide any sort of update on the assistance?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are aware and we can confirm the detention of U.S. citizens in Haiti. We’re monitoring the situation closely. The Haitian Government has been cooperative in our requests for consular access to the detained U.S. citizens. Anywhere, anytime a U.S. citizen is detained overseas, the department works to provide all appropriate consular assistance. That has been the case here as well. I’m not able to go into further details given some of the privacy considerations.</p>
<p>In terms of the investigation, we have been very clear all along that, of course, this is a Haitian investigation. We’ve deferred investigative questions to Haitian authorities. We’ve also relayed to Haitian authorities and as well as publicly to all of you that in terms of our assistance, we do see the investigation as one area in which the United States can make potentially valuable contributions to this Haitian-led effort. DHS and the FBI have continued to do that. The State Department has provided other forms of assistance, as we’ve discussed previously, but I’m not in a position to detail where that is right now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And you have nothing – there’s nothing new on the Cuba remittances or the embassy staffing review, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Nothing I’m in a position to add today.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. And on the Iran prisoner thing, still – there’s nothing new on that either?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We were very clear on this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We spoke over the weekend; we spoke on Monday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sorry, on Cuba.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Assistant Secretary Julie Chung put out some tweets about Cuba, and one of them mentioned, “We are going to focus on applying hard-hitting sanctions on regime officials.” Could you tell us a bit more about, like, what kind of sanctions you’re considering? Is this going to be GLOMAG? Or is there – is there – there are other ways that you could do this? And then is this a situation where you think sanctioning officials is going to make a difference?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, so as not to repeat everything I said yesterday and to not face the ire &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The wrath.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; the wrath, I will just make the very brief point that we spoke yesterday of steps that we are studying and looking into that would support the Cuban people, but also steps that would seek to hold to account Cuban Government officials responsible for the repression, for the crackdown, for the violence in the context of these peaceful street protests.</p>
<p>When it comes to sanctions, the Treasury Department’s OFAC, the Office of Foreign Assets Control, is exploring designating Cuban officials responsible for violence, repression, human rights violations against those peaceful protesters. We’re also working diligently with the international community to condemn the violence and repression that the Cuban people have faced. This is, as is almost always the case, one of those areas where U.S. action will be meaningful, it will be, we expect, effective, but it will be all the more meaningful if we are able to speak with one voice with the international community and we are able to make clear that the international community does not abide the regimes repression, crackdown, deprivation of human rights and civil liberties for the Cuban people.</p>
<p>So as you can expect, I’m not in a position to detail now what any potential sanctions might look like, what authorities we might use, but we are certainly looking at ways that we can hold accountable those Cuban regime officials who have been responsible for what we’ve seen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So you don’t – there aren’t enough sanctions against Cuba already?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You feel there’s still more room?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, there – we are confident there is more room. There are broad sanctions imposed against Cuba, of course, with humanitarian carve-outs and tools we can use to ensure that much-needed humanitarian supplies can reach the Cuban people. But we are confident that we have policy tools available to us, to potentially include sanctions, that could be wielded against specific individuals who may be responsible for some of what we’ve seen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, what about helping the Cubans receive internet service? Do you have anything on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We discussed this yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m happy to give you the quick summary, but we are working with the private sector and with Congress to identify viable options to make the internet more accessible to the Cuban people. And when we talk about our collaboration with the private sector, we are actively collaborating to identify solutions and proposals that are creative and to seek to ensure that the Cuban people have access to that free flow of information. That’s so important to us in large part because we have seen the actions that the Cuban Government has taken in the context of these peaceful demonstrations &#8212; the internet crackdowns, the blockages, the efforts on the part of the regime to stifle the voice of the Cuban people, to stifle their access to information – and so we are exploring options with both Congress and the private sector to that effect.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Tanzania"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A different topic, Tanzania.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The opposition leader Freeman Mbowe was apparently arrested today. Does the United States have any comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We have seen these reports. We are looking into them. If confirmed, it would be very concerning. As you know, Secretary Blinken had an opportunity earlier this month on July 6th to speak with Tanzanian President Hassan, and Secretary Blinken, in the context of that conversation, reiterated and spoke about the importance of political rights, civil liberties, as well as the importance of ensuring a democratic, peaceful, free, and prosperous future for all Tanzanians. That is what we continue to hope to see, and so we’ll be looking into these reports.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just have one quick question? I understand we might get more information on this today, but do you have a figure for the number of SIV applicants that will be relocated before the U.S. troop withdrawal?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Afghanistan"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So what I can say is I can speak to the two groups that we have detailed to date. The first group is that group that has completed their security clearance – their security vetting procedures, the rigorous security vetting procedures, and that group, because they have completed that important stage in the process, will be relocated starting – flights will start later this month to Fort Lee in Virginia. And so there – we said there are 700 principal applicants along with their family members.</p>
<p>The other group of applicants entail applicants who have not yet completed that security vetting step. They will be relocated to third countries. And that group, if I have it here, I believe is 2,500 principal applicants and their families. But beyond that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Wait, wait, no. Is it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That was 4,000 &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, is it 4,000? Did it go down 1,500?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sorry, sorry. I’m sorry. It was 4,000, 4,000, 4,000, I’m sorry. You’re right, 4,000 principal applicants and their families. Thank you for catching that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So, I mean, previously you guys had been saying that the relocation effort would be complete before the U.S. military withdrawal. So does it just demonstrate how complicated this is, how grand this effort is that it may take a little bit longer, frankly? Because we’re talking about maybe 5,000 of these SIV applicants that you’re saying are in the works, but as we well know, there’s upwards of 10,000, maybe close to 20,000 who are in the full line here.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> That’s right. And we are working, as we have said, as quickly as we can to process as many of these SIV applicants as efficiently as we can, and we’ve done so consistent with the fact that this is a program that is written into law, it’s statutorily defined, more than a dozen steps that applicants need to go through, but we have surged resources, we have surged staff to help us process this. As I’ve said, we have increased the pace at which we are processing these applicants. And you see, if you look at the most recent quarterly report, a pretty marked increase between the early months of this year to mid this year in terms of what we are able to process.</p>
<p>The other important point, though, is that the SIV program will not come to a close when the military withdrawal is completed later this year, and that’s because the Department of State and our embassy intends to remain engaged on the ground. We intend to continue with our partnership with the Afghan Government, and in this case, importantly, with the Afghan people, and so we’ll continue to be in a position to process applicants.</p>
<p>I will add that last night we did begin notifying eligible SIV applicants and their families regarding the option they have to be relocated to Fort Lee in Virginia. This is the first of many steps the department is taking to honor the U.S. Government’s commitment to our Afghan SIV applicants, and it’s an important step in our effort to begin relocating them to the United States this month.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And on Iran, on the demonstrations over there &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I just want to – well, I guess maybe it can be answered in the – later on. But when you say 4,000 to these third countries, that’s the actual principal applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Principal applicants.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So once you factor in the families, do you have an estimate of the total number of people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It’s – it is a rough estimate.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I mean, if it’s 700 principal applicants for Fort Lee but that means 2,500 total, what does 4,000 – my math is from elementary or high school, middle school.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It’s – it’s – it’s an extrapolation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Exactly.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It’s an &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But does it work &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; if you do that extrapolation, like, the 700 over 2,500 and for &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’re not – when we talk about 2,500, obviously, that’s a round number. It’s not precise.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, yeah, yeah, obviously not exact. But is there an estimate of the total number of people who will be – who are in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, one, we have to see how many people take us up on that offer. As you heard from the President &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. But if everyone, if all of them took it up, how many people are we talking about, including family members?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So we have – we’ve talked about 2,500 for Fort Lee based on that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, not for Fort Lee. For the other, for the 4,000.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So the SIV program allows a principal applicant along with a spouse and dependent children to come to the United States. And so 2,500 is, of course, the extrapolation based on 750. You – I don’t have my calculator in front of me, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I just did it, but I – but I don’t – anyway. Whatever.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And of course, once we determine how many people, how many applicants do wish to take us up on this offer for relocation, we’ll have a precise figure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I have one quick follow-up on all of that too?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is this group, then, of 4,000 plus the 700 principal applicants – is that the total universe of people that you are willing to evacuate? Or are you going to do more down the line?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are looking at all potential contingencies. This is the group that we’re speaking to at the moment, the group that we’re – the groups that we’re actively making plans for. But we’re looking at all potential contingencies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So of the 10,000 principal applicants who are waiting for their cases to be adjudicated, is – are all of those people going to be evacuated at some point, or – out of the 20,000 that are in the pipeline, are all of those people going to be – like, we still don’t have a sense of the scale from the administration of how many people you’re willing to pull out.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are looking at all contingencies. We have a commitment and a special responsibility to those individuals who have applied and who are able to complete the SIV processing, and we’ll have more to share on what that looks like going forward.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Iran"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on the demonstrations in Iran, do you have any comment on the security forces crackdown?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I do. We are closely following reports of protests in Iran’s Khuzestan province, including reports that security forces have fired on these protesters. We support the rights of Iranians to peacefully assemble and to express themselves. Iranians, just like any other people, should enjoy without – should enjoy those rights without fear of violence, without fear of arbitrary detention by security forces. And so we’re monitoring this very closely.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Korea"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Going back to North Korean issue, Northeast Asia issue, during the deputy secretary’s visit to China, does she have a plan to ask any kind of cooperation regarding North Korea with China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll have more to say, I would expect, in the aftermath of the deputy’s visit to the PRC. I – what I would say broadly now is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The aftermath? That sounds like it’s not going to go well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The – after the deputy’s visit to the PRC. What I would say broadly now is that, as I’ve already alluded to, this is a relationship for us that is predicated principally on competition. There are elements of this relationship that are adversarial, but there are also going to be elements where our interests are aligned. And in cases where our interests are aligned, we do seek to explore the potential for cooperation. We’ve talked about that in the context of climate, for example. We’ve talked about that in the context of Afghanistan, potentially. We’ve also talked about that in the context of the DPRK.</p>
<p>It is in no one’s interest for the DPRK to be a threat to the region and potentially beyond. It is in no one’s interest to see a humanitarian catastrophe potentially unfold in the DPRK, and so I think it is safe to say that we do have some alignment of interests when it comes to the DPRK and we’ll be in a position to explore that.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, the last time he spoke with Director Yang, spent much of that conversation speaking to our DPRK policy review, which had recently been completed, knowing that the PRC does have influence and a relationship with the regime in the DPRK that perhaps few other countries do.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, will the U.S. and China discuss about any way to bring North Korea to a dialogue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t want to go any further into what they may discuss vis-a-vis the DPRK or any other issue. But they will certainly explore those areas where our interests are aligned because this visit is very much about advancing U.S. interests. It is about exploring ways in which – and areas in which we might cooperate, where that cooperation would be in service of U.S. and shared collective interests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Regarding that also, the deputy secretary said during the trilateral meeting between Korea and Japan and the U.S. that the cooperation among three countries would be the big message to North Korea. So what could be the message?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry, what – what would be the message to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, the – like, the meaning of the message.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the purpose of the trilateral meeting wasn’t so much to send a message to North Korea. It was to leverage the trilateral relationship. We know just how important the trilateral relationship is to that challenge. It is one that – it’s a relationship that we have sought to bolster and to reinforce over the years. Of course, when he was deputy secretary, then-Deputy Secretary Blinken spent quite a bit of time in the region seeking to strengthen this trilateral relationship. It was certainly – it’s precisely why Secretary Blinken met with his Japanese and South Korean counterparts in Europe not all that long ago as well.</p>
<p>We know across all these levels that a robust and effective trilateral relationship among these three countries is critical for our shared security and common interests in defending freedom and democracy, upholding human rights, championing women’s empowerment, combating climate change, promoting regional and global peace and security, and bolstering the rule of law and the rules-based international order throughout the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, just one more question. During the trilateral meeting, or before or after, did the deputy secretary make any suggestion for the improvement of Korean-Japan relationship?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We issued a readout of this, so I wouldn’t want to go beyond that readout. But just to reiterate the importance we attach to that trilateral relationship, not just in the context of the DPRK but also in the broader regional context as well.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 1:54 p.m.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>1:05 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. A couple things at the top.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Norway"></a> We join Norwegians and others around the world in remembering the horrific July 22nd, 2011 attacks in Utoya and Oslo. On that day, Norway experienced its deadliest attack since World War II. And since then, our thoughts and prayers have been with the victims, as well as with their family, their friends, and the first responders as well.</p>
<p>These types of attacks remind us of the threat we all face from violent extremism and terrorism. The entire international community has a stake in preventing this kind of violent extremism and terror going forward.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-InvestmentCliamateStatements"></a> Next, the department released the 2021 Investment Climate Statements. These reports analyze the business climates of more than 170 countries and economies that are current or potential markets for American companies. U.S. businesses can use the Investment Climate Statements to inform their international investment decisions in any one of the covered economies. The Investment Climate Statements are, also, points of reference for foreign governments. looking to improve their business climates and attract U.S. investment.</p>
<p>The reports include information on barriers to investment U.S. companies are likely to encounter. They also highlight progress made on reducing these barriers and creating a fair, open, transparent market that’s attractive to foreign direct investors.</p>
<p>The Department of State works with our foreign government partners to build business environments that are not only economically sound, but also adhere to high standards such as protecting the environment and respecting human rights.</p>
<p>The Investment Climate Statements are one of the many ways in which the department connects our foreign policy work to the needs and the aspirations of the American people and U.S. companies as well.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Really? That’s it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You have nothing else to say? Okay. All right, well, I was going to start with Sesame Street and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Grover asked some hard-hitting questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My daughter – yes, exactly. My daughter &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You might want to take a cue.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My four-year-old daughter is an enormous fan, and I’m sure she’ll love to see it. But I won’t start with that, because there are other, more pressing matters.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I would welcome it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m sure you would. Toria, up on the Hill, just a while ago said that you guys have reached an agreement with the Germans on Nord Stream 2, and so I’m wondering if you – recognizing their – that this joint statement that she talked about hasn’t come out, yet/ I’m just wondering if there’s any more you can add to what she said ahead of the release of that statement.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-NordStream"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There is not more that I’m prepared to add right now. We talked about this some yesterday, and we talked about our rationale in approaching this challenge, and I made very clear yesterday, as did the President in his meeting with Chancellor Merkel earlier this month, that we continue to oppose Nord Stream 2. We continue to view it as a Kremlin geopolitical project whose goal is to expand Russia’s influence over Europe’s energy resources. We continue to believe it’s a bad deal for Germany, it’s a bad deal for Ukraine, it’s a bad deal for Europe and Europe’s broader energy security goals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And yet you’re prepared to allow it to go ahead without &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; without trying to – without trying to stop it, even at this late hour?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And to demonstrate that opposition, we have consistently applied sanctions and examined potentially sanctionable activity, and acted on that. And of course, we have in May imposed sanctions on 19 entities and vessels, and at the same time – as you’ve heard from the Secretary, as you’ve heard from the President – we have come to the conclusion, as any rational observer would, that sanctions are unlikely to stop, to stand in the way of the completion of the pipeline, to prevent the pipeline’s construction. And so, that is why this administration determined that it was not in our interest to significantly undermine, to weaken our bilateral relationship, our ally, the relationship we have with our ally, Germany, for a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, but it’s really – no need &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; but if I could just &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There’s no need to repeat everything that you said yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; no, no, no, but if I could just finish a couple points – for a pipeline whose construction would continue, nonetheless.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Germany"></a> Now, to your question – and I mentioned this yesterday, or I alluded to it – the Germans have put forward useful proposals, and we’ve been able to make progress on steps to achieve our shared goal, and that shared goal is very important. That shared goal is ensuring that this pipeline cannot be weaponized against Ukraine, against any other European partner. That is our goal in doing so. I do expect we’ll be able to share more details on this today.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But one other point I want to really emphasize here: We are committed to following the law; we are committed to continuing to examine entities that have engaged in potentially sanctionable activity. Any decisions on sanctions or sanctions-related decisions, those will be made on a case-by-case basis consistent with the law.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, just three very quick points. One. If you’re committed to following the law, then you would actually follow the law, right? Which says that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> And we have, correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I think that a lot of people think that’s debatable. The second thing is that you say “any rational observer” would realize that sanctions wouldn’t stop this. Well, are you saying that members of Congress, who are Democrats as well as Republicans, are irrational?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We have looked at this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you saying that Senator Shaheen is irrational, that Senator Menendez is irrational &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; because they think that this could actually be stopped?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ve looked at this issue very closely, and we have examined &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And they haven’t?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I’m speaking for us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, right. So you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I’m the spokesperson for the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you know more than they do? That’s the idea?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m saying I can speak to the Department of State, and what I can say is that we have looked at this issue very closely. We examined a range of options, a range of tools at our disposal. We came to the conclusion that for a pipeline that was 90 – more than 90 percent complete, on the day this administration assumed office, to potentially undermine our relationship with Germany, and to send a signal to our allies and to our partners the world over that the United States is willing to throw asunder important relationships, that’s not something that we were eager to do, certainly.</p>
<p>We also know that perhaps now more than ever we need our allies, we need our partners, across a range of challenges to confront a host of threats. And in this briefing room, we’ve discussed our cooperation with Germany on any number of fronts, from the PRC, to Afghanistan, to the climate crisis, to the shared values that we have more broadly.</p>
<p>I will also say that even as we came to this conclusion and going forward, we have shown that we are going to always follow the law. We enacted sanctions, as I said, in May on 19 entities and vessels. That is in contrast to two sanctions that were levied by the previous administration under which more than 90 percent of this pipeline was completed.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Russia"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. The last thing, and it’s kind of a minor thing, but you keep referring to this – to the pipeline as a Russian geopolitical project, as if in some way the phrase “geopolitical project” is pejorative. Why?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There are innumerable U.S. policies that are geopolitical projects.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Of course. Our &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So why do you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> No, no. I don’t – we have not intended the term “geopolitical project” to be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, you have. You use it constantly. It’s, like, in the talking points along with &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It is – to us, it is more than a pipeline.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It is more than a pipeline that carries &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, so is your campaign against Huawei and 5G, so is your campaign against any number of things.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I don’t think you’re going to find – I don’t think you’re going to find – I didn’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So “geopolitical project” is not intended to be a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> A geopolitical – a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; and not intended to be pejorative?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Oh, no, no, no. It is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’re not saying that Russia can’t have geopolitical projects because you don’t like them.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> States have geopolitical projects.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>This is a geopolitical &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s all.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> No, no, but you asked the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I did, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> This is a geopolitical project intended to exert, and to expand, Russia’s influence over Ukraine and other parts of Europe.</p>
<p>Other questions. Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Let me pursue that. One of the things that Toria mentioned was that there’s a pursuit of a tenure extension of – after 2024 of the transit rights in Ukraine. What’s the enforcement mechanism for that? I know you said at the beginning that you’re not going to get into the details, but if I can pursue that, what – how could this actually be enforced?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> There are a number of good questions about this. We are going to have an opportunity today to speak to this in some detail. I would expect today you will see an official release as well, so I’m going to reserve comment until we’re in a position to do that.</p>
<p>Other questions? Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Different topic. News reports say that the U.S. is putting pressure on the Israeli Government to stop all settlement activities in the Palestinian territories. Is that accurate, and do you have any time for the reopening of the U.S. consulate in Jerusalem?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Israel"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, when it comes to the reopening of the U.S. consulate, Secretary Blinken was clear on this when he visited Jerusalem and Ramallah, earlier this year. He noted then that the United States will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem and will do so as part of our effort to re-establish that partnership with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority precisely because it allows us to engage with them, it allows us to execute our assistance programs, it allows us to execute our public diplomacy mission, and to conduct the sort of diplomatic reporting that we need. I don’t have a timeframe to offer for you, but we’ll be happy to keep you posted.</p>
<p>When it comes to settlement activity, we have also been clear and consistent on that. We believe it’s critical to refrain from unilateral steps that increase tensions and make it more difficult to advance a negotiated two-state solution. This is a message we have conveyed in public, as I have just now, but also in private. And it has been the longstanding position, certainly the position of this administration and had been a longstanding position of prior administrations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could we go to a new topic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To Deputy Secretary Sherman’s visit to China that’s coming up. You’ve been saying in recent days that the United States will only – only goes ahead with a visit such as this one if there is a point to it, if it’s constructive, the lines that you’ve given on that.</p>
<p>So what made you think – what made the department think that it was the right time for her to go to China? Is there something that she – specifically she hopes to achieve there?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-DeputySecretaryTravel"></a><a id="post-261072-China"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. So as we announced this morning, and I’m sure you all have seen the announcement, the deputy will travel to the People’s Republic of China on July 25th. She will travel there after her stops in Tokyo and Seoul and Ulaanbaatar as well. In the PRC, she will take part in meetings in Tianjin where she will meet with PRC officials, including State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi. These discussions, as we’ve said, are part of an ongoing U.S. effort to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials, designed to advance U.S. interests and values; and overall to allow us to responsibly manage this incredibly consequential bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>We said earlier this week before we were in a position to confirm the trip that, as you alluded to, the deputy would be prepared to travel if her engagement there would be substantive, constructive; if it were indeed to be a forum and a venue for us to accomplish what we seek to accomplish, and that is to advance U.S. interests, to explore and to discuss how we can manage this relationship responsibly, and how we can address the competition and responsibly manage the competition &#8211; and the stiff competition, that we welcome with the PRC.</p>
<p>And so the PRC has confirmed an in-person meeting with State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi. We’ve said all along that we seek for our senior-level engagement with PRC officials to be substantive and constructive, and we believe this meeting has the potential to be just that.</p>
<p>Look, when – in the context of relationships that are complex, that are challenging, that are dynamic, we believe it’s important to maintain open lines of communication between high-level officials, and that includes in times of, as in the case with the PRC, sustained competition, even when the PRC is taking actions that challenge our interests, that challenge our values. And these are shared interests. These are shared values, And so, I think it’s important in that context to note that the deputy will be traveling to the PRC, after having visited Japan, after having visited the Republic of Korea, after having visited Mongolia as well. She’ll be traveling there, as we have said, from a position of strength, not unlike how Secretary Blinken met with Director Yang and other PRC officials in Anchorage on the way back from the Indo-Pacific region, where we had engaged in consultations with our Japanese and South Korean counterparts as well.</p>
<p>I think broadly speaking, the deputy intends for this engagement to show and to demonstrate to the PRC what responsible and healthy competition can look like. As I’ve said before, we know this relationship is going to be competitive. We welcome that competition. We welcome that stiff competition. But we also want to make sure that the playing field is level, and importantly, that competition doesn’t veer into conflict. We want to make sure that this is a relationship that has guard rails there – where there are clearly defined parameters to the relationship as well. And we believe, again, that engaging in practical, substantive, and a direct manner, as we expect this visit will be, will help us achieve those goals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just follow up on that quickly?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> When you talk about wanting responsible and healthy competition with the PRC, has there been any indication that they are interested in engaging in that kind of competition since President Biden has taken office or since Secretary of State met with Chinese officials earlier this year?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Much of what we’ve done in the early months of this administration is to test the – test various propositions. We want competition with China where we’re competing against one another. This is a relationship that is fundamentally predicated on competition, it’s fundamentally competitive at its core, in our estimation, but again, where the playing field is level, where the rules of the game are clearly defined and enforced, and where there are guard rails to ensure and to see to it that competition doesn’t spill over into something more dangerous, including, at worst, conflict.</p>
<p>So we have tested that proposition in a number of ways. The Secretary and National Security Advisor Sullivan met with Director Yang, met with other senior PRC officials in Anchorage, where we had our first senior-level engagement with the PRC. Of course, Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity to speak to Director Yang on a couple of occasions since then. President Biden, I would be remiss to add, has had an opportunity to speak to President Xi.</p>
<p>And so these open lines of communication are important in their own right because we believe – and especially at times of stiff competition – that we need dialogue. We need constructive dialogue, but it’s also important for us to – for the PRC to hear from us, and for us to hear from the PRC, perspectives on the relationship. And that will help us test the proposition, and arrive at a conclusion as to how we can most effectively ensure that the relationship is conducted on a level playing field, that those guardrails are there, and that it is managed responsibly.</p>
<p>So this is an ongoing endeavor for us. The deputy’s travel and engagement in PRC will be the next phase in that process.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, if I – UK-EU – you wanted to ask on the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I – just one more thing on the PRC? Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just briefly, the – you also mentioned – the State Department mentioned that she’s going on to Oman. Oman obviously has had a key role in indirect diplomacy with Iran. Is that one of the key elements there of going to Oman?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Oman has played an important mediating role in the region. We’ll have more on her travel and engagements in Oman as that gets closer, but certainly we’ve worked closely with Oman on a range of regional priorities. Iran is one of them, Yemen is another, and we’ll have a fuller description of that visit as the time comes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I just wanted to ask on the UK-EU agreement on Northern Ireland. The – Prime Minister Boris Johnson wants to renegotiate parts of that. The E.U. today has rejected that attempt at renegotiation, just saying that it imperiled the Good Friday Agreement, among other things. Just wanted to know where the U.S. stands. Are they – is the U.S. worried about the Good Friday Agreement or is the U.S. worried about the flow of goods between the UK and – between Northern Ireland and the rest of the UK – things like sausages, medicine, even seeing eye dogs – that London says have been obstructed by the current deal?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-NorthernIreland"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we have seen the reports of the UK’s command paper proposal on the Northern Ireland Protocol. We would refer you to the UK and to the E.U. for questions on the negotiations. Of course, the United States is not a direct party to them. But we do and we have encouraged all parties to prioritize political and economic stability in Northern Ireland in the context of these discussions.</p>
<p>To your question, President Biden has been nothing but unequivocal in his support for the Belfast and the Good Friday Agreement, which was an historic agreement at the time, remains significant and incredibly important. We support a close relationship between the UK and the EU, and between all communities in Northern Ireland as well. And we continue to encourage the parties to negotiate within existing mechanisms, and to avoid unilateral actions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just further to that, do you have any comments on how the implications of this might impact a future U.S.-UK trade deal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Look, I – what we’re going to focus on now is what we would like to see broadly, and that is we would encourage all the parties to prioritize political and economic stability in Northern Ireland in these discussions while continuing to negotiate within existing mechanisms and avoiding unilateral actions. I’m not going to entertain hypotheticals, what might happen. Right now, we’re focused on what is happening between the parties.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Varosha in Cyprus, are you planning to impose sanctions on Turkey after the steps that it has taken?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are looking at a number of steps, but let me just back up, and I’m sure you saw the statement from the Secretary that was released last night. In it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A little late last night.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, again, we operate under the assumption that you all like information at the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That we’re all awake at 10 o’clock? Okay, okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You like information at the speed of news, so we’re happy to hold things.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it was news about four hours earlier, so – or five. Just to point that out.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s – we think it’s news when the Secretary speaks.</p>
<p>The – as you heard last night, we condemn the announcement by the Turkish Cypriot leader Ersin Tatar and Turkish President Erdogan regarding the transfer of parts of Varosha to Cypriot – to Turkish Cypriot control. Such a move is clearly inconsistent with UN Security Council Resolutions 550 and 789, which are very explicit in their calls for Varosha to be administered by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Since last year, since October of 2020, Turkish Cypriots and Turkey have ignored calls from the international community and from the UN Security Council to reverse their steps on Varosha. The – we view Turkey – Turkish Cypriot actions in Varosha, which have the support of Turkey, as provocative, as unacceptable, and incompatible with their past commitments to engage constructively in settlement talks.</p>
<p>We continue to support efforts to refer this situation, which we deem to be very concerning, to the UN Security Council, and we will urge a strong response from the international community. Again, to go back to the basics, we support a Cypriot-led comprehensive settlement to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation to benefit all Cypriots and the wider region. We continue to encourage efforts to de-escalate tensions in the Eastern Mediterranean, and to call for the resolution of issues through dialogue and in accordance with international law, not unilateral action.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What about the sanctions at the UN and is the U.S. prepared to take such actions against Turkey too?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> As I – as you have heard us say before, we don’t preview policy actions, and certainly not any sanctions, but we do support efforts to refer this to the UN Security Council and we will urge the international community to muster a strong response. The United States would be certainly a part of that.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A Russian hacker named Peter Levashov was freed yesterday on time served for his hacking activities. There was some speculation that he could be part of a prisoner exchange for either Paul Whelan or Trevor Reed. Did the administration have any role in his sentencing and freeing, and is there a prisoner swap underway?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Conor, you won’t be surprised to hear that I don’t have anything for you on that. We have made very clear – and President Biden was clear with President Putin, Secretary Blinken was clear with Foreign Minister Lavrov, other U.S. officials at multiple levels have been unambiguous with their Russian counterparts – that Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed, their release from their unjustified detention is an absolute priority for us. We are working very hard and doing everything we can to see to it that they are reunited with their families as soon as is possible. They have been held against their will, of course, away from their families. They’ve missed birthdays; they have missed anniversaries. They have missed important life occasions and, importantly, their families have missed them. And so we will continue to do all we can. As you know, we don’t often speak publicly of our efforts to effect the release of Americans who are unjustly detained around the world, but we are always, always working on these cases.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So just no denial, then, that the administration maybe played a role in the judge’s decision here?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have anything for you on that. I’m just not entertaining the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. You speak publicly all the time. We just went through this on Monday, after you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; went after the Iranians for talking about &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well – no.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; about a prisoner swap.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What – and what I said on Monday is that we have made it a priority.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, but don’t say that you don’t talk about it, because you do.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We don’t detail it. We don’t detail it. I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, you talk about it all the time.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; Matt, you – I think, Matt, you would agree with that, that we do not detail our efforts to release – to seek the release, to effect the release of Americans who are unjustly detained around the world. And we don’t do that for the simple reason that their release, expeditious release, is our top priority. And we wouldn’t want to do anything that could complicate, that could delay their potential freedom.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Is there anything new on either Haiti or Cuba? And please don’t repeat the statement from last night or your comments yesterday about the Cuba review. I’m just asking, is there anything new that you can report to us today on either of those Caribbean situations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we did release a statement on the new &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Go ahead and read it for us, all 20 minutes of it.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-haiti"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I – well, I am not going to – I’m not going to read the statement. But I will just say very briefly that the formation of a new government in Haiti is a positive, it’s a necessary step to respond to the Haitian people’s needs and to begin Haiti – to begin restoring Haiti’s democratic institutions. We do welcome efforts by Haiti’s political leadership to come together in choosing an interim prime minister as well as a unity cabinet to chart a path forward in the wake of the assassination of President Moise, and we’re committed to working with Haiti’s new government to support its investigation into the assassination, to expand our COVID-19 vaccination efforts, and to promote security and the rule of law.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue, as we have done, to coordinate with Haitian and international partners to support efforts to establish the conditions necessary for Haitians, importantly, to vote in free and fair elections – in free and fair legislative elections and presidential elections as soon as possible.</p>
<p>We urge, in the meantime, members of Haiti’s new government to work with civil society to find solutions to the many pressing challenges facing Haiti and to facilitate that return to long-term stability and prosperity.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On the investigation, Haitian authorities said today that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You couldn’t not do it, could you? It was just impossible for you not to re-read the entire – okay, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, you’re good. The Haitian authorities said today that they arrest – that they have in mind three foreigners who they believe helped to fund the operation that assassinated the president. Is the U.S. Government aware whether or not any of those three are American citizens? And they asked again for further FBI help in tracking down those three potential suspects. What is the FBI doing? Can you provide any sort of update on the assistance?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are aware and we can confirm the detention of U.S. citizens in Haiti. We’re monitoring the situation closely. The Haitian Government has been cooperative in our requests for consular access to the detained U.S. citizens. Anywhere, anytime a U.S. citizen is detained overseas, the department works to provide all appropriate consular assistance. That has been the case here as well. I’m not able to go into further details given some of the privacy considerations.</p>
<p>In terms of the investigation, we have been very clear all along that, of course, this is a Haitian investigation. We’ve deferred investigative questions to Haitian authorities. We’ve also relayed to Haitian authorities and as well as publicly to all of you that in terms of our assistance, we do see the investigation as one area in which the United States can make potentially valuable contributions to this Haitian-led effort. DHS and the FBI have continued to do that. The State Department has provided other forms of assistance, as we’ve discussed previously, but I’m not in a position to detail where that is right now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And you have nothing – there’s nothing new on the Cuba remittances or the embassy staffing review, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Nothing I’m in a position to add today.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. And on the Iran prisoner thing, still – there’s nothing new on that either?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We were very clear on this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We spoke over the weekend; we spoke on Monday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sorry, on Cuba.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Assistant Secretary Julie Chung put out some tweets about Cuba, and one of them mentioned, “We are going to focus on applying hard-hitting sanctions on regime officials.” Could you tell us a bit more about, like, what kind of sanctions you’re considering? Is this going to be GLOMAG? Or is there – is there – there are other ways that you could do this? And then is this a situation where you think sanctioning officials is going to make a difference?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, so as not to repeat everything I said yesterday and to not face the ire &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The wrath.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; the wrath, I will just make the very brief point that we spoke yesterday of steps that we are studying and looking into that would support the Cuban people, but also steps that would seek to hold to account Cuban Government officials responsible for the repression, for the crackdown, for the violence in the context of these peaceful street protests.</p>
<p>When it comes to sanctions, the Treasury Department’s OFAC, the Office of Foreign Assets Control, is exploring designating Cuban officials responsible for violence, repression, human rights violations against those peaceful protesters. We’re also working diligently with the international community to condemn the violence and repression that the Cuban people have faced. This is, as is almost always the case, one of those areas where U.S. action will be meaningful, it will be, we expect, effective, but it will be all the more meaningful if we are able to speak with one voice with the international community and we are able to make clear that the international community does not abide the regimes repression, crackdown, deprivation of human rights and civil liberties for the Cuban people.</p>
<p>So as you can expect, I’m not in a position to detail now what any potential sanctions might look like, what authorities we might use, but we are certainly looking at ways that we can hold accountable those Cuban regime officials who have been responsible for what we’ve seen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So you don’t – there aren’t enough sanctions against Cuba already?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You feel there’s still more room?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, there – we are confident there is more room. There are broad sanctions imposed against Cuba, of course, with humanitarian carve-outs and tools we can use to ensure that much-needed humanitarian supplies can reach the Cuban people. But we are confident that we have policy tools available to us, to potentially include sanctions, that could be wielded against specific individuals who may be responsible for some of what we’ve seen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, what about helping the Cubans receive internet service? Do you have anything on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We discussed this yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m happy to give you the quick summary, but we are working with the private sector and with Congress to identify viable options to make the internet more accessible to the Cuban people. And when we talk about our collaboration with the private sector, we are actively collaborating to identify solutions and proposals that are creative and to seek to ensure that the Cuban people have access to that free flow of information. That’s so important to us in large part because we have seen the actions that the Cuban Government has taken in the context of these peaceful demonstrations &#8212; the internet crackdowns, the blockages, the efforts on the part of the regime to stifle the voice of the Cuban people, to stifle their access to information – and so we are exploring options with both Congress and the private sector to that effect.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Tanzania"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A different topic, Tanzania.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The opposition leader Freeman Mbowe was apparently arrested today. Does the United States have any comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We have seen these reports. We are looking into them. If confirmed, it would be very concerning. As you know, Secretary Blinken had an opportunity earlier this month on July 6th to speak with Tanzanian President Hassan, and Secretary Blinken, in the context of that conversation, reiterated and spoke about the importance of political rights, civil liberties, as well as the importance of ensuring a democratic, peaceful, free, and prosperous future for all Tanzanians. That is what we continue to hope to see, and so we’ll be looking into these reports.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just have one quick question? I understand we might get more information on this today, but do you have a figure for the number of SIV applicants that will be relocated before the U.S. troop withdrawal?</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Afghanistan"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So what I can say is I can speak to the two groups that we have detailed to date. The first group is that group that has completed their security clearance – their security vetting procedures, the rigorous security vetting procedures, and that group, because they have completed that important stage in the process, will be relocated starting – flights will start later this month to Fort Lee in Virginia. And so there – we said there are 700 principal applicants along with their family members.</p>
<p>The other group of applicants entail applicants who have not yet completed that security vetting step. They will be relocated to third countries. And that group, if I have it here, I believe is 2,500 principal applicants and their families. But beyond that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Wait, wait, no. Is it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That was 4,000 &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, is it 4,000? Did it go down 1,500?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sorry, sorry. I’m sorry. It was 4,000, 4,000, 4,000, I’m sorry. You’re right, 4,000 principal applicants and their families. Thank you for catching that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So, I mean, previously you guys had been saying that the relocation effort would be complete before the U.S. military withdrawal. So does it just demonstrate how complicated this is, how grand this effort is that it may take a little bit longer, frankly? Because we’re talking about maybe 5,000 of these SIV applicants that you’re saying are in the works, but as we well know, there’s upwards of 10,000, maybe close to 20,000 who are in the full line here.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> That’s right. And we are working, as we have said, as quickly as we can to process as many of these SIV applicants as efficiently as we can, and we’ve done so consistent with the fact that this is a program that is written into law, it’s statutorily defined, more than a dozen steps that applicants need to go through, but we have surged resources, we have surged staff to help us process this. As I’ve said, we have increased the pace at which we are processing these applicants. And you see, if you look at the most recent quarterly report, a pretty marked increase between the early months of this year to mid this year in terms of what we are able to process.</p>
<p>The other important point, though, is that the SIV program will not come to a close when the military withdrawal is completed later this year, and that’s because the Department of State and our embassy intends to remain engaged on the ground. We intend to continue with our partnership with the Afghan Government, and in this case, importantly, with the Afghan people, and so we’ll continue to be in a position to process applicants.</p>
<p>I will add that last night we did begin notifying eligible SIV applicants and their families regarding the option they have to be relocated to Fort Lee in Virginia. This is the first of many steps the department is taking to honor the U.S. Government’s commitment to our Afghan SIV applicants, and it’s an important step in our effort to begin relocating them to the United States this month.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And on Iran, on the demonstrations over there &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I just want to – well, I guess maybe it can be answered in the – later on. But when you say 4,000 to these third countries, that’s the actual principal applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Principal applicants.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So once you factor in the families, do you have an estimate of the total number of people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It’s – it is a rough estimate.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I mean, if it’s 700 principal applicants for Fort Lee but that means 2,500 total, what does 4,000 – my math is from elementary or high school, middle school.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It’s – it’s – it’s an extrapolation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Exactly.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> It’s an &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But does it work &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; if you do that extrapolation, like, the 700 over 2,500 and for &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’re not – when we talk about 2,500, obviously, that’s a round number. It’s not precise.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, yeah, yeah, obviously not exact. But is there an estimate of the total number of people who will be – who are in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, one, we have to see how many people take us up on that offer. As you heard from the President &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. But if everyone, if all of them took it up, how many people are we talking about, including family members?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So we have – we’ve talked about 2,500 for Fort Lee based on that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, not for Fort Lee. For the other, for the 4,000.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So the SIV program allows a principal applicant along with a spouse and dependent children to come to the United States. And so 2,500 is, of course, the extrapolation based on 750. You – I don’t have my calculator in front of me, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I just did it, but I – but I don’t – anyway. Whatever.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And of course, once we determine how many people, how many applicants do wish to take us up on this offer for relocation, we’ll have a precise figure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I have one quick follow-up on all of that too?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is this group, then, of 4,000 plus the 700 principal applicants – is that the total universe of people that you are willing to evacuate? Or are you going to do more down the line?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are looking at all potential contingencies. This is the group that we’re speaking to at the moment, the group that we’re – the groups that we’re actively making plans for. But we’re looking at all potential contingencies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So of the 10,000 principal applicants who are waiting for their cases to be adjudicated, is – are all of those people going to be evacuated at some point, or – out of the 20,000 that are in the pipeline, are all of those people going to be – like, we still don’t have a sense of the scale from the administration of how many people you’re willing to pull out.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are looking at all contingencies. We have a commitment and a special responsibility to those individuals who have applied and who are able to complete the SIV processing, and we’ll have more to share on what that looks like going forward.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Iran"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on the demonstrations in Iran, do you have any comment on the security forces crackdown?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I do. We are closely following reports of protests in Iran’s Khuzestan province, including reports that security forces have fired on these protesters. We support the rights of Iranians to peacefully assemble and to express themselves. Iranians, just like any other people, should enjoy without – should enjoy those rights without fear of violence, without fear of arbitrary detention by security forces. And so we’re monitoring this very closely.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-261072-Korea"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Going back to North Korean issue, Northeast Asia issue, during the deputy secretary’s visit to China, does she have a plan to ask any kind of cooperation regarding North Korea with China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll have more to say, I would expect, in the aftermath of the deputy’s visit to the PRC. I – what I would say broadly now is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The aftermath? That sounds like it’s not going to go well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The – after the deputy’s visit to the PRC. What I would say broadly now is that, as I’ve already alluded to, this is a relationship for us that is predicated principally on competition. There are elements of this relationship that are adversarial, but there are also going to be elements where our interests are aligned. And in cases where our interests are aligned, we do seek to explore the potential for cooperation. We’ve talked about that in the context of climate, for example. We’ve talked about that in the context of Afghanistan, potentially. We’ve also talked about that in the context of the DPRK.</p>
<p>It is in no one’s interest for the DPRK to be a threat to the region and potentially beyond. It is in no one’s interest to see a humanitarian catastrophe potentially unfold in the DPRK, and so I think it is safe to say that we do have some alignment of interests when it comes to the DPRK and we’ll be in a position to explore that.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, the last time he spoke with Director Yang, spent much of that conversation speaking to our DPRK policy review, which had recently been completed, knowing that the PRC does have influence and a relationship with the regime in the DPRK that perhaps few other countries do.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, will the U.S. and China discuss about any way to bring North Korea to a dialogue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t want to go any further into what they may discuss vis-a-vis the DPRK or any other issue. But they will certainly explore those areas where our interests are aligned because this visit is very much about advancing U.S. interests. It is about exploring ways in which – and areas in which we might cooperate, where that cooperation would be in service of U.S. and shared collective interests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Regarding that also, the deputy secretary said during the trilateral meeting between Korea and Japan and the U.S. that the cooperation among three countries would be the big message to North Korea. So what could be the message?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry, what – what would be the message to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, the – like, the meaning of the message.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the purpose of the trilateral meeting wasn’t so much to send a message to North Korea. It was to leverage the trilateral relationship. We know just how important the trilateral relationship is to that challenge. It is one that – it’s a relationship that we have sought to bolster and to reinforce over the years. Of course, when he was deputy secretary, then-Deputy Secretary Blinken spent quite a bit of time in the region seeking to strengthen this trilateral relationship. It was certainly – it’s precisely why Secretary Blinken met with his Japanese and South Korean counterparts in Europe not all that long ago as well.</p>
<p>We know across all these levels that a robust and effective trilateral relationship among these three countries is critical for our shared security and common interests in defending freedom and democracy, upholding human rights, championing women’s empowerment, combating climate change, promoting regional and global peace and security, and bolstering the rule of law and the rules-based international order throughout the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, just one more question. During the trilateral meeting, or before or after, did the deputy secretary make any suggestion for the improvement of Korean-Japan relationship?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We issued a readout of this, so I wouldn’t want to go beyond that readout. But just to reiterate the importance we attach to that trilateral relationship, not just in the context of the DPRK but also in the broader regional context as well.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 1:54 p.m.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the United States and Germany on Support for Ukraine, European Energy Security, and our Climate Goals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-united-states-and-germany-on-support-for-ukraine-european-energy-security-and-our-climate-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 19:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Germany.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The United States and Germany are steadfast in their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence, and chosen European path. We recommit ourselves today to push back against Russian aggression and malign activities in Ukraine and beyond. The United States pledges to support Germany’s and France’s efforts to bring peace to eastern Ukraine via the Normandy Format. Germany will intensify its efforts within the Normandy Format to facilitate the implementation of the Minsk agreements. The United States and Germany affirm their commitment to tackling the climate crisis and taking decisive action to reduce emissions in the 2020s to keep a 1.5-degree Celsius temperature limit within reach.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their determination to hold Russia to account for its aggression and malign activities by imposing costs via sanctions and other tools. We commit to working together via the newly established U.S.-EU High Level Dialogue on Russia, and via bilateral channels, to ensure the United States and the EU remain prepared, including with appropriate tools and mechanisms, to respond together to Russian aggression and malign activities, including Russian efforts to use energy as a weapon. Should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions, to limit Russian export capabilities to Europe in the energy sector, including gas, and/or in other economically relevant sectors. This commitment is designed to ensure that Russia will not misuse any pipeline, including Nord Stream 2, to achieve aggressive political ends by using energy as a weapon.</p>
<p>We support the energy security of Ukraine and Central and Eastern Europe, including the key principles enshrined in the EU’s Third Energy Package of diversity and security of supply. Germany underscores that it will abide by both the letter and the spirit of the Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2 under German jurisdiction to ensure unbundling and third-party access. This includes an assessment of any risks posed by certification of the project operator to the security of energy supply of the EU.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their belief that it is in Ukraine’s and Europe’s interest for gas transit via Ukraine to continue beyond 2024. In line with this belief, Germany commits to utilize all available leverage to facilitate an extension of up to 10 years to Ukraine’s gas transit agreement with Russia, including appointing a special envoy to support those negotiations, to begin as soon as possible and no later than September 1. The United States commits to fully support these efforts.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are resolute in their commitment to the fight against climate change and ensuring the success of the Paris Agreement by reducing our own emissions in line with net-zero by 2050 at the latest, encouraging the strengthening of climate ambition of other major economies, and collaborating on the policies and technologies to accelerate the global net-zero transition. That is why we have launched the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership . The Partnership will foster U.S.-Germany collaboration on developing actionable roadmaps to reach our ambitious emission reduction targets; coordinating our domestic policies and priorities in sectoral decarbonization initiatives and multilateral fora; mobilizing investment in energy transition; and developing, demonstrating, and scaling critical energy technologies such as renewable energy and storage, hydrogen, energy efficiency, and electric mobility.</p>
<p>As part of the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership, we have decided to establish a pillar to support the energy transitions in emerging economies. This pillar will include a focus on supporting Ukraine and other countries in Central and Eastern Europe. These efforts will not only contribute to the fight against climate change but will support European energy security by reducing demand for Russian energy.</p>
<p>In line with these efforts, Germany commits to establish and administer a Green Fund for Ukraine to support Ukraine’s energy transition, energy efficiency, and energy security. Germany and the United States will endeavor to promote and support investments of at least $1 billion in the Green Fund for Ukraine, including from third parties such as private-sector entities. Germany will provide an initial donation to the fund of at least $175 million and will work toward extending its commitments in the coming budget years. The fund will promote the use of renewable energy; facilitate the development of hydrogen; increase energy efficiency; accelerate the transition from coal; and foster carbon neutrality. The United States plans to support the initiative via technical assistance and policy support consistent with the objectives of the fund, in addition to programs supporting market integration, regulatory reform, and renewables development in Ukraine’s energy sector.</p>
<p>In addition, Germany will continue to support bilateral energy projects with Ukraine, especially in the field of renewables and energy efficiency, as well as coal transition support, including the appointment of a special envoy with dedicated funding of $70 million. Germany is also ready to launch a Ukraine Resilience Package to support Ukraine’s energy security. This will include efforts to safeguard and increase the capacity for reverse flows of gas to Ukraine, with the aim of shielding Ukraine completely from potential future attempts by Russia to cut gas supplies to the country. It will also include technical assistance for Ukraine’s integration into the European electricity grid, building on and in coordination with the ongoing work by the EU and the U.S. Agency for International Development. In addition, Germany will facilitate Ukraine’s inclusion in Germany’s Cyber Capacity Building Facility, support efforts to reform Ukraine’s energy sector, and assist with identifying options to modernize Ukraine’s gas transmission systems.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany express their strong support for the Three Seas Initiative and its efforts to strengthen infrastructure connectivity and energy security in Central and Eastern Europe. Germany commits to expand its engagement with the initiative with an eye toward financially supporting projects of the Three Seas Initiative in the fields of regional energy security and renewable energy. In addition, Germany will support projects of common interest in the energy sector via the EU Budget, with contributions of up to $1.77 billion in 2021-2027. The United States remains committed to investing in the Three Seas Initiative and continues to encourage concrete investments by members and others.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Germany.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The United States and Germany are steadfast in their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence, and chosen European path. We recommit ourselves today to push back against Russian aggression and malign activities in Ukraine and beyond. The United States pledges to support Germany’s and France’s efforts to bring peace to eastern Ukraine via the Normandy Format. Germany will intensify its efforts within the Normandy Format to facilitate the implementation of the Minsk agreements. The United States and Germany affirm their commitment to tackling the climate crisis and taking decisive action to reduce emissions in the 2020s to keep a 1.5-degree Celsius temperature limit within reach.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their determination to hold Russia to account for its aggression and malign activities by imposing costs via sanctions and other tools. We commit to working together via the newly established U.S.-EU High Level Dialogue on Russia, and via bilateral channels, to ensure the United States and the EU remain prepared, including with appropriate tools and mechanisms, to respond together to Russian aggression and malign activities, including Russian efforts to use energy as a weapon. Should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions, to limit Russian export capabilities to Europe in the energy sector, including gas, and/or in other economically relevant sectors. This commitment is designed to ensure that Russia will not misuse any pipeline, including Nord Stream 2, to achieve aggressive political ends by using energy as a weapon.</p>
<p>We support the energy security of Ukraine and Central and Eastern Europe, including the key principles enshrined in the EU’s Third Energy Package of diversity and security of supply. Germany underscores that it will abide by both the letter and the spirit of the Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2 under German jurisdiction to ensure unbundling and third-party access. This includes an assessment of any risks posed by certification of the project operator to the security of energy supply of the EU.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their belief that it is in Ukraine’s and Europe’s interest for gas transit via Ukraine to continue beyond 2024. In line with this belief, Germany commits to utilize all available leverage to facilitate an extension of up to 10 years to Ukraine’s gas transit agreement with Russia, including appointing a special envoy to support those negotiations, to begin as soon as possible and no later than September 1. The United States commits to fully support these efforts.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are resolute in their commitment to the fight against climate change and ensuring the success of the Paris Agreement by reducing our own emissions in line with net-zero by 2050 at the latest, encouraging the strengthening of climate ambition of other major economies, and collaborating on the policies and technologies to accelerate the global net-zero transition. That is why we have launched the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership . The Partnership will foster U.S.-Germany collaboration on developing actionable roadmaps to reach our ambitious emission reduction targets; coordinating our domestic policies and priorities in sectoral decarbonization initiatives and multilateral fora; mobilizing investment in energy transition; and developing, demonstrating, and scaling critical energy technologies such as renewable energy and storage, hydrogen, energy efficiency, and electric mobility.</p>
<p>As part of the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership, we have decided to establish a pillar to support the energy transitions in emerging economies. This pillar will include a focus on supporting Ukraine and other countries in Central and Eastern Europe. These efforts will not only contribute to the fight against climate change but will support European energy security by reducing demand for Russian energy.</p>
<p>In line with these efforts, Germany commits to establish and administer a Green Fund for Ukraine to support Ukraine’s energy transition, energy efficiency, and energy security. Germany and the United States will endeavor to promote and support investments of at least $1 billion in the Green Fund for Ukraine, including from third parties such as private-sector entities. Germany will provide an initial donation to the fund of at least $175 million and will work toward extending its commitments in the coming budget years. The fund will promote the use of renewable energy; facilitate the development of hydrogen; increase energy efficiency; accelerate the transition from coal; and foster carbon neutrality. The United States plans to support the initiative via technical assistance and policy support consistent with the objectives of the fund, in addition to programs supporting market integration, regulatory reform, and renewables development in Ukraine’s energy sector.</p>
<p>In addition, Germany will continue to support bilateral energy projects with Ukraine, especially in the field of renewables and energy efficiency, as well as coal transition support, including the appointment of a special envoy with dedicated funding of $70 million. Germany is also ready to launch a Ukraine Resilience Package to support Ukraine’s energy security. This will include efforts to safeguard and increase the capacity for reverse flows of gas to Ukraine, with the aim of shielding Ukraine completely from potential future attempts by Russia to cut gas supplies to the country. It will also include technical assistance for Ukraine’s integration into the European electricity grid, building on and in coordination with the ongoing work by the EU and the U.S. Agency for International Development. In addition, Germany will facilitate Ukraine’s inclusion in Germany’s Cyber Capacity Building Facility, support efforts to reform Ukraine’s energy sector, and assist with identifying options to modernize Ukraine’s gas transmission systems.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany express their strong support for the Three Seas Initiative and its efforts to strengthen infrastructure connectivity and energy security in Central and Eastern Europe. Germany commits to expand its engagement with the initiative with an eye toward financially supporting projects of the Three Seas Initiative in the fields of regional energy security and renewable energy. In addition, Germany will support projects of common interest in the energy sector via the EU Budget, with contributions of up to $1.77 billion in 2021-2027. The United States remains committed to investing in the Three Seas Initiative and continues to encourage concrete investments by members and others.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2021 Investment Climate Statements Released</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/2021-investment-climate-statements-released/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 15:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today the Department of State released the 2021 Investment Climate Statements, which analyze the investment climates of more than 170 countries and economies that are current or potential markets for U.S. companies. The reports provide up-to-date information gathered by our economic officers in embassies and consulates around the world – helping U.S. companies make informed business decisions. They also serve as a reference in working with partner governments to create enabling environments that are not only economically sound but also adhere to high standards, like protecting the environment and respecting human rights, including worker rights. Readers can also access points of contact within each U.S. mission for additional follow-up and consultation.</p>
<p>The reports cover topics including: Openness to Investment, Legal and Regulatory Systems, Protection of Real and Intellectual Property Rights, Financial Sector, State-Owned Enterprises, Responsible Business Conduct, and Corruption.</p>
<p>Our posts overseas are working daily to address many of the barriers to U.S. investment highlighted by the Investment Climate Statements. Addressing these barriers can create opportunities for U.S. businesses and support their growth and expansion in the United States and in partner countries.</p>
<p>The reports can be viewed at the following link: <a href="https://www.state.gov/investment-climate-statements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjEuNDM1MDAxNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvaW52ZXN0bWVudC1jbGltYXRlLXN0YXRlbWVudHMvIn0.EeplJbZ3QPalW83Bp61BtwChcrox_x_Gb_c2sCXmtoI/s/1039202793/br/109682275679-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626967329646000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE71M3abyhI9iY0qCqE5iOGRu42XA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />investment-climate-statements/</a><wbr />.</p>
<p>The Investment Climate Statements also form a chapter of the Department of Commerce&#8217;s Country Commercial Guides and can be read together with those guides for a broad description of the investment and business environments in foreign economies (<a class="external-link" href="https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>).</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today the Department of State released the 2021 Investment Climate Statements, which analyze the investment climates of more than 170 countries and economies that are current or potential markets for U.S. companies. The reports provide up-to-date information gathered by our economic officers in embassies and consulates around the world – helping U.S. companies make informed business decisions. They also serve as a reference in working with partner governments to create enabling environments that are not only economically sound but also adhere to high standards, like protecting the environment and respecting human rights, including worker rights. Readers can also access points of contact within each U.S. mission for additional follow-up and consultation.</p>
<p>The reports cover topics including: Openness to Investment, Legal and Regulatory Systems, Protection of Real and Intellectual Property Rights, Financial Sector, State-Owned Enterprises, Responsible Business Conduct, and Corruption.</p>
<p>Our posts overseas are working daily to address many of the barriers to U.S. investment highlighted by the Investment Climate Statements. Addressing these barriers can create opportunities for U.S. businesses and support their growth and expansion in the United States and in partner countries.</p>
<p>The reports can be viewed at the following link: <a href="https://www.state.gov/investment-climate-statements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjEuNDM1MDAxNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvaW52ZXN0bWVudC1jbGltYXRlLXN0YXRlbWVudHMvIn0.EeplJbZ3QPalW83Bp61BtwChcrox_x_Gb_c2sCXmtoI/s/1039202793/br/109682275679-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626967329646000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE71M3abyhI9iY0qCqE5iOGRu42XA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />investment-climate-statements/</a><wbr />.</p>
<p>The Investment Climate Statements also form a chapter of the Department of Commerce&#8217;s Country Commercial Guides and can be read together with those guides for a broad description of the investment and business environments in foreign economies (<a class="external-link" href="https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Counselor Chollet’s Trip to Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/counselor-chollets-trip-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor of the Department Derek Chollet met with Ukrainian Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal, Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba, Head of Presidential Office Andriy Yermak, and Deputy Foreign Minister Yevhenii Yenin in Kyiv, Ukraine, on July 20-21. The Counselor and the senior Ukrainian officials discussed our shared concerns about the Nord Stream 2 pipeline and U.S. commitments to ensure Russia cannot use energy as a coercive tool against Ukraine or any other country in Europe. Counselor Chollet reiterated our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and Euro-Atlantic aspirations. The Counselor addressed Ukraine’s efforts to advance economic and rule of law reforms, with an emphasis on strengthening corporate governance and bolstering anti-corruption institutions.</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor Chollet also met with energy sector and corporate governance leaders to discuss Ukraine’s prosperity and energy security.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor of the Department Derek Chollet met with Ukrainian Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal, Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba, Head of Presidential Office Andriy Yermak, and Deputy Foreign Minister Yevhenii Yenin in Kyiv, Ukraine, on July 20-21. The Counselor and the senior Ukrainian officials discussed our shared concerns about the Nord Stream 2 pipeline and U.S. commitments to ensure Russia cannot use energy as a coercive tool against Ukraine or any other country in Europe. Counselor Chollet reiterated our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and Euro-Atlantic aspirations. The Counselor addressed Ukraine’s efforts to advance economic and rule of law reforms, with an emphasis on strengthening corporate governance and bolstering anti-corruption institutions.</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor Chollet also met with energy sector and corporate governance leaders to discuss Ukraine’s prosperity and energy security.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Japanese Defense Minister Kishi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-japanese-defense-minister-kishi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Japanese Defense Minister Kishi today in Tokyo. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Defense Minister Kishi reaffirmed that the U.S.-Japan Alliance remains the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted the United States’ unwavering commitment to the defense of Japan.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the Defense Minister underscored the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait and highlighted their shared commitment to working toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, including through trilateral cooperation among the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Japanese Defense Minister Kishi today in Tokyo. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Defense Minister Kishi reaffirmed that the U.S.-Japan Alliance remains the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted the United States’ unwavering commitment to the defense of Japan.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the Defense Minister underscored the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait and highlighted their shared commitment to working toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, including through trilateral cooperation among the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Travel to the People’s Republic of China and Oman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-the-peoples-republic-of-china-and-oman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 11:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to the People’s Republic of China (PRC) July 25-26 and to Oman July 27.</span></p>
<p>In the PRC, the Deputy Secretary will travel to Tianjin to meet with PRC officials, including State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi.  These discussions are part of ongoing U.S. efforts to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials to advance U.S. interests and values and to responsibly manage the relationship. The Deputy Secretary will discuss areas where we have serious concerns about PRC actions, as well as areas where our interests align.</p>
<p>In Oman, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Sheikh Khalifa Al Harthy to discuss advancing peace and security in the region and our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.- Oman bilateral relationship.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to the People’s Republic of China (PRC) July 25-26 and to Oman July 27.</span></p>
<p>In the PRC, the Deputy Secretary will travel to Tianjin to meet with PRC officials, including State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi.  These discussions are part of ongoing U.S. efforts to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials to advance U.S. interests and values and to responsibly manage the relationship. The Deputy Secretary will discuss areas where we have serious concerns about PRC actions, as well as areas where our interests align.</p>
<p>In Oman, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Sheikh Khalifa Al Harthy to discuss advancing peace and security in the region and our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.- Oman bilateral relationship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Belgium National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/belgium-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 04:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send my warm wishes to the people of the Kingdom of Belgium as you observe your National Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Belgium have a long and proud history of cooperation, and our close alliance is based on a shared commitment to democracy and human rights.  We fought side by side in two world wars to defend our shared values.  As founding members of NATO, we established the cornerstone of peace, prosperity, and stability the Transatlantic community has enjoyed since then.</p>
<p>The people of the United States mourn with you after the devastating loss of life and destruction from the recent floods.  We trust that Belgium will rebuild and persevere as it has done in the past.  Such perseverance has been evident as we face a global pandemic and continue to stand together.  The fruits of our scientific cooperation have benefited the world.  We are committed to using that same ingenuity in new avenues of partnership, such as working together to combat the climate crisis by reducing greenhouse gas emissions and developing green infrastructure.</p>
<p>I look forward to creating a more secure and prosperous future for our citizens in the coming year.  Best wishes to the people of Belgium on the occasion of your National Day.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send my warm wishes to the people of the Kingdom of Belgium as you observe your National Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Belgium have a long and proud history of cooperation, and our close alliance is based on a shared commitment to democracy and human rights.  We fought side by side in two world wars to defend our shared values.  As founding members of NATO, we established the cornerstone of peace, prosperity, and stability the Transatlantic community has enjoyed since then.</p>
<p>The people of the United States mourn with you after the devastating loss of life and destruction from the recent floods.  We trust that Belgium will rebuild and persevere as it has done in the past.  Such perseverance has been evident as we face a global pandemic and continue to stand together.  The fruits of our scientific cooperation have benefited the world.  We are committed to using that same ingenuity in new avenues of partnership, such as working together to combat the climate crisis by reducing greenhouse gas emissions and developing green infrastructure.</p>
<p>I look forward to creating a more secure and prosperous future for our citizens in the coming year.  Best wishes to the people of Belgium on the occasion of your National Day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcement of a Unity Government in Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/announcement-of-a-unity-government-in-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 02:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes efforts by Haiti’s political leadership to come together in choosing an interim Prime Minister and a unity cabinet to chart a path forward in the wake of the heinous assassination of Jovenel Moïse.  The formation of this interim government is a positive and necessary step to respond to the Haitian people’s needs and begin restoring Haiti’s democratic institutions.</p>
<p>The United States, together with the international community, urges Haiti’s political and civil society leaders to continue to work together to advance a broad and inclusive dialogue that responds to the needs of the Haitian people and lays the groundwork for long-term stability and prosperity.</p>
<p>We remain committed to supporting the Haitian government’s investigation into the assassination of Jovenel Moïse, expanding COVID-19 vaccination efforts, working with the Haitian National Police to promote security and the rule of law, and coordinating with the international community to establish the conditions necessary for Haitians to vote as soon as feasible.</p>
<p>We call on all Haitians to work together to maintain peace and will continue to support the Haitian people as they strive to build a stable, prosperous, and democratic country.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes efforts by Haiti’s political leadership to come together in choosing an interim Prime Minister and a unity cabinet to chart a path forward in the wake of the heinous assassination of Jovenel Moïse.  The formation of this interim government is a positive and necessary step to respond to the Haitian people’s needs and begin restoring Haiti’s democratic institutions.</p>
<p>The United States, together with the international community, urges Haiti’s political and civil society leaders to continue to work together to advance a broad and inclusive dialogue that responds to the needs of the Haitian people and lays the groundwork for long-term stability and prosperity.</p>
<p>We remain committed to supporting the Haitian government’s investigation into the assassination of Jovenel Moïse, expanding COVID-19 vaccination efforts, working with the Haitian National Police to promote security and the rule of law, and coordinating with the international community to establish the conditions necessary for Haitians to vote as soon as feasible.</p>
<p>We call on all Haitians to work together to maintain peace and will continue to support the Haitian people as they strive to build a stable, prosperous, and democratic country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
