<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 23:03:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the recent Taliban Decision to Deny Afghan Girls the Right to an Education</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-recent-taliban-decision-to-deny-afghan-girls-the-right-to-an-education/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 23:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is a statement from the Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Italy, Norway, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.  We are united in our condemnation of the Taliban’s decision not to re-open secondary schools to Afghan girls.</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>We are united in our condemnation of the Taliban’s decision on March 23 to deny so many Afghan girls the opportunity to finally go back to school.   The Taliban’s action contradicted its public assurances to the Afghan people and to the international community.  The decision came after months of work by the international community to support teacher stipends based on an expectation that schools would be open for all, with the higher interest of Afghan students and teachers in mind.  And sadly, it came as eager Afghan girls were walking to their schools for the first time in seven months.</p>
<p>We call on the Taliban urgently to reverse this decision, which will have consequences far beyond its harm to Afghan girls.  Unreversed, it will profoundly harm Afghanistan’s prospects for social cohesion and economic growth, its ambition to become a respected member in the community of nations, and the willingness of Afghans to return from overseas.  It will have an inevitable impact on the Taliban’s prospects of gaining political support and legitimacy either at home or abroad.  Every Afghan citizen, boy or girl, man or woman, has an equal right to an education at all levels, in all provinces of the country.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is a statement from the Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Italy, Norway, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.  We are united in our condemnation of the Taliban’s decision not to re-open secondary schools to Afghan girls.</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>We are united in our condemnation of the Taliban’s decision on March 23 to deny so many Afghan girls the opportunity to finally go back to school.   The Taliban’s action contradicted its public assurances to the Afghan people and to the international community.  The decision came after months of work by the international community to support teacher stipends based on an expectation that schools would be open for all, with the higher interest of Afghan students and teachers in mind.  And sadly, it came as eager Afghan girls were walking to their schools for the first time in seven months.</p>
<p>We call on the Taliban urgently to reverse this decision, which will have consequences far beyond its harm to Afghan girls.  Unreversed, it will profoundly harm Afghanistan’s prospects for social cohesion and economic growth, its ambition to become a respected member in the community of nations, and the willingness of Afghans to return from overseas.  It will have an inevitable impact on the Taliban’s prospects of gaining political support and legitimacy either at home or abroad.  Every Afghan citizen, boy or girl, man or woman, has an equal right to an education at all levels, in all provinces of the country.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Sanctions Under the Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act (INKSNA)</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/new-sanctions-under-the-iran-north-korea-and-syria-nonproliferation-act-inksna/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 22:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States today announced sanctions on five entities and individuals located in Russia and the DPRK and one entity in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for proliferation activities under the Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act (INKSNA).  As part of this action, we imposed sanctions against the Russian entities Ardis Group of Companies LLC (Ardis Group); PFK Profpodshipnik; LLC, and Russian individual Igor Aleksandrovich Michurin; as well as DPRK entity Second Academy of Natural Science Foreign Affairs Bureau (SANS FAB); and DPRK individual Ri Sung Chol (aka Ri Su’ng-ch’o’l) for transferring sensitive items to North Korea’s missile program.  These measures are part of our ongoing efforts to impede the DPRK’s ability to advance its missile program and they highlight the negative role Russia plays on the world stage as a proliferator to programs of concern.</p>
<p>We also are imposing sanctions against the PRC entity Zhengzhou Nanbei Instrument Equipment Co. Ltd for supplying Syria with equipment controlled by the Australia Group chemical and biological weapons nonproliferation regime.  The ongoing imposition of INKSNA sanctions against PRC entities calls attention to the role of PRC entities in proliferation and shortcomings in the PRC’s implementation of export controls and its nonproliferation track record.</p>
<p>These determinations underscore the continuing need for all countries to remain vigilant to efforts by North Korea and Syria to advance their proliferation programs of concern.  We will continue to work to impede these programs and use our sanctions authorities to spotlight the foreign suppliers, such as these entities in the PRC and Russia that provide sensitive materials and technology to the DPRK and Syria.  The sanctions announced today will be in effect for two years and include restrictions on U.S. government procurement, U.S. government assistance, and exports.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States today announced sanctions on five entities and individuals located in Russia and the DPRK and one entity in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for proliferation activities under the Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act (INKSNA).  As part of this action, we imposed sanctions against the Russian entities Ardis Group of Companies LLC (Ardis Group); PFK Profpodshipnik; LLC, and Russian individual Igor Aleksandrovich Michurin; as well as DPRK entity Second Academy of Natural Science Foreign Affairs Bureau (SANS FAB); and DPRK individual Ri Sung Chol (aka Ri Su’ng-ch’o’l) for transferring sensitive items to North Korea’s missile program.  These measures are part of our ongoing efforts to impede the DPRK’s ability to advance its missile program and they highlight the negative role Russia plays on the world stage as a proliferator to programs of concern.</p>
<p>We also are imposing sanctions against the PRC entity Zhengzhou Nanbei Instrument Equipment Co. Ltd for supplying Syria with equipment controlled by the Australia Group chemical and biological weapons nonproliferation regime.  The ongoing imposition of INKSNA sanctions against PRC entities calls attention to the role of PRC entities in proliferation and shortcomings in the PRC’s implementation of export controls and its nonproliferation track record.</p>
<p>These determinations underscore the continuing need for all countries to remain vigilant to efforts by North Korea and Syria to advance their proliferation programs of concern.  We will continue to work to impede these programs and use our sanctions authorities to spotlight the foreign suppliers, such as these entities in the PRC and Russia that provide sensitive materials and technology to the DPRK and Syria.  The sanctions announced today will be in effect for two years and include restrictions on U.S. government procurement, U.S. government assistance, and exports.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acting Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Yael Lempert  On the Secretary’s Upcoming Travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-for-near-eastern-affairs-yael-lempert-on-the-secretarys-upcoming-travel-to-israel-the-west-bank-morocco-and-algeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson, Yael  Lempert , Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Near Eastern Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 21:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Yael  Lempert , Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Near Eastern Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks very much and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for joining today’s call. Very pleased to have with us today Acting Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Yael Lempert.  She will preview the Secretary’s travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria.  The acting assistant secretary will speak today on the record.  This call is embargoed until its conclusion, and after the acting assistant secretary offers some opening remarks, she will have a couple minutes to answer questions.</p>
<p>So with that I will turn it over to Acting Assistant Secretary Lempert.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT</strong>:  Great.  Thank you so much, Ned.  Good afternoon, everybody.  Nice to be with you today.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken is going to travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria from March 26th to March 30th.  While there, he’s going to engage with our partners on a range of regional and global priorities, including Ukraine, Iran, the Abraham Accords and normalization agreements with Israel, preserving the prospects for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, and building support for the UN’s engagement on Western Sahara, among other topics.  Of course, this will be Secretary Blinken’s second visit to Israel and the West Bank as Secretary, but this will be his first visit to Morocco and Algeria since he became Secretary.</p>
<p>During his visit to Israel and the West Bank, the Secretary will underscore the United States’ ironclad commitment to Israeli security, coordination on Ukraine and Iran, and work to build upon the gains from the Abraham Accords.  While there, he will meet with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid, Defense Minister Benny Gantz, and also with Israeli President Isaac Herzog.  The Secretary will also meet with President Abbas of the Palestinian Authority in Ramallah as well as with representatives of Palestinian civil society.</p>
<p>During the visit, Secretary Blinken will affirm the commitment of the United States to a two-state solution, and to greater freedom, security, and prosperity for Palestinians and Israelis alike.  He will also underscore the importance of the upcoming month when major religious holidays across faiths will be celebrated, and reiterate the importance of actions to build trust, and enhance stability and security, and the need to avoid steps that can inflame tensions on the ground.</p>
<p>Turning to North Africa, the Secretary will first visit Morocco, where he will meet with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and other senior government officials to exchange views on regional issues and bilateral cooperation, and on advancing human rights and fundamental freedom, and he also will engage with Moroccan youth.  While in Rabat, the Secretary will also meet Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to discuss regional security and international developments.</p>
<p>The Secretary’s trip will culminate in Algiers, where he will meet President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and his counterpart Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, commercial cooperation, and advancing human rights and fundamental freedom.  The Secretary also will officially inaugurate the United States as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair – it’s the largest trade show of its kind in Africa – and he will meet with U.S. businesses.   During the course of this trip, the Secretary will emphasize to all the foreign leaders he meets with that the U.S. stands in solidarity and support with the government and people of Ukraine.  He will affirm the need for Vladimir Putin to end his premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>This region – the Middle East and North Africa – has seen the damaging effects of Russia’s military campaigns before:  In Syria and Libya and Mali, Russian military and paramilitary forces have exploited conflicts for Moscow’s own selfish interests, posing grave threats to regional stability and global commerce.</p>
<p>Putin’s invasion is already causing food prices – especially wheat – to rise, just as our economies recover from the COVID pandemic.  We know this pain is keenly felt in the Middle East and North Africa, where most countries import at least half of their wheat.  Egypt, Lebanon, Libya, Qatar, and Tunisia import at least a quarter of their wheat specifically from Ukraine.</p>
<p>Putin’s reckless war will only continue to increase the price of basic staples like bread in the region, taking money from the pockets of the hardest working and most vulnerable families as he invades a sovereign country without provocation.</p>
<p>This war must stop, and we will work hand-in-hand with our partners the world over to get there.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE</strong>:  Terrific.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  And again, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone.  Again, that’s 1-0.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Let’s start with the line of Jennifer Hansler of CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Great.  Thank you.  I was wondering whether the Secretary intends to bring up with President Bennett their – his outreach to President Putin, whether the U.S. finds these efforts helpful, if there’s going to be any effort to get on the same page in Bennett’s diplomacy with Putin.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Thank you.  Yes, we do anticipate that we’ll be discussing Ukraine in Israel and elsewhere as well, but in Israel we’ll be discussing Israel’s efforts.  We appreciate Israel’s role.  So that will be on the agenda.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Humeyra Pamuk of Reuters.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks for doing this.  Just a couple of quick ones.  Just to follow up from Jennifer, how much of this trip do you think will be about Russia, Ukraine, given Israel’s emerging role as a potential mediator?  Because the Iran deal is also a big topic.  Like how – which one is going to dominate?</p>
<p>And a quick question on Secretary’s meeting with Abu Dhabi crown prince.  The relationship has not been at its best, to say the least, and there seems to be an expectation on the Emirati side for concrete proposals.  Will the Secretary have those in his suitcase, and what will those be?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Great.  Thanks for that question.  In terms of our engagement on Ukraine and discussing Russia’s invasion and war against Ukraine, that will be a topic I’m sure at all of our stops, as well, I anticipate, Iran, which as you know is an issue that is of great interest to all of our partners in the region.  So it’s difficult for me to predict at this moment what will dominate.  What I can predict with assurance is that both of those are going to be really at the top of the agenda in terms of our discussions.</p>
<p>In terms of the meeting with the crown prince, look, we’re taking advantage of the opportunity during the Secretary’s visit to Morocco to meet with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed and really have a strategic conversation about the full range of regional, international issues before us.  This is a valued and really important strategic relationship for us, and it’s an opportune moment for this meeting.  There’s a lot to discuss.  So we’re pleased to have this chance to sit down, the Secretary is, with the crown prince as strategic partners and discuss the full range of issues before us.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to John Hudson of <em>The Washington Post</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is the Secretary going to push the consulate issue while he’s in Israel?  Is that a campaign promise that’s just basically falling by the wayside in wake of Israeli opposition?</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  That will certainly be a topic of discussion in his meetings in both Israel and the West Bank.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Nahal Toosi.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hey, guys.  Thanks for doing this.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Halley, you are – I think we’ve lost you.  Unless we can get you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I’m here.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We can now.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sorry about that.  Former Secretary of State Pompeo issued a ruling for –  decision that said that the U.S. did not see the Israeli settlements in the West Bank as being illegal.  And to my knowledge, Secretary of State Blinken has not reversed that position.  Now, tell me if I’m wrong.  But is it the Biden administration’s policy that the Israeli settlements are not illegal under their – our version of international law?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  I have no update for you on that particular topic.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Paul Handley.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) tell us what those issues are.  Can you go through the list?  What are the priorities to discuss, because there’s a lot of things I could name, but why don’t you – can you just talk about them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Paul, we missed the top of your question.  What was your whole question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The question is could you go – you said there’s a whole list of things to talk about with Mohammed bin Zayed.  Can you go through that list, please?  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you.  Sorry.  Yes, there’s a wide range of issues, ranging from Iran to Yemen, Syria, global energy markets, and Ethiopia.  We have a range of topics that we’ll be discussing, as well as the Abraham Accords and what we can do to strengthen those further.  We have seen tremendous and tangible results in terms of the UAE-Israel relationship.  It’s really blossomed.  Tourism is thriving; direct flights are ferrying numbers of tourists back and forth.  Trade is booming.  And we anticipate that that will be a big topic of discussion as well.  We’ll probably also touch briefly on the Expo, which has really been a tremendous success, closing soon in Dubai.  That’s just a sampling.  I mean, we have just a wide array of shared interests and topics that we want to cover.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We have time for a final question or two.  Let’s go to Yuna Leibzon of Channel 12.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I do want to focus on Israel.  You talked about priorities in different countries.  But can you say what would be the first priority on the visit and the meeting in Israel?  Would it be Iran, or the Russia-Ukraine negotiations, or Palestinian issues, if you could focus that specifically, please?</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Look, our relationship with Israel is so broad and so deep, it’s difficult to choose just one issue and say that’s going to be the priority.  As I mentioned previously on this call, we’ll be certainly discussing Iran, as we have had close consultations on that topic since the beginning of the administration; Russia-Ukraine, no doubt; again, Abraham Accords and what we can do to try and strengthen and broaden them; and of course, Israeli-Palestinian issues and what we can do in terms of helping to lower tensions and see movement forward on that front, in addition to a range of other bilateral topics.  So it will be a broad and wide-ranging discussion.  There’s no doubt in my mind.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  And we’ll conclude with the line of Said Arikat, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) Madam Assistant Secretary.  Very quickly, I want to follow up on John Hudson’s question on the consulate.  Now, last year Secretary Blinken stated in no uncertain terms that the consulate will be reopened.  Are we likely to hear anything that is as strong in terms of a commitment to the consulate this time around?</p>
<p>And my second question regarding the village of Al-Walaja that is slated to be demolished, will the Secretary of State express that his opposition or – his clear opposition to the demolition of this particular Palestinian village?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Thank you.  Look, as I mentioned before, the issue of our consulate general in Jerusalem will undoubtedly be a topic of discussion in the Secretary’s meetings both in Israel and the West Bank, and he’ll be speaking to it there.</p>
<p>In terms of your question about demolitions, I think that that will be among the topics that is discussed.  I will say that the State Department has made the administration’s view clear.  We believe it is critical for Israel and the Palestinian Authority to refrain from unilateral steps that exacerbate tensions and undercut efforts to advance a negotiated two-state solution.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.  Thank you very much, Acting Assistant Secretary Lempert.  Appreciate everyone’s time.  Again, this call was on the record, and we will be seeing many of you on the ground during the trip.  Talk to you then.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Yael  Lempert , Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Near Eastern Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks very much and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for joining today’s call. Very pleased to have with us today Acting Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Yael Lempert.  She will preview the Secretary’s travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria.  The acting assistant secretary will speak today on the record.  This call is embargoed until its conclusion, and after the acting assistant secretary offers some opening remarks, she will have a couple minutes to answer questions.</p>
<p>So with that I will turn it over to Acting Assistant Secretary Lempert.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT</strong>:  Great.  Thank you so much, Ned.  Good afternoon, everybody.  Nice to be with you today.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken is going to travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria from March 26th to March 30th.  While there, he’s going to engage with our partners on a range of regional and global priorities, including Ukraine, Iran, the Abraham Accords and normalization agreements with Israel, preserving the prospects for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, and building support for the UN’s engagement on Western Sahara, among other topics.  Of course, this will be Secretary Blinken’s second visit to Israel and the West Bank as Secretary, but this will be his first visit to Morocco and Algeria since he became Secretary.</p>
<p>During his visit to Israel and the West Bank, the Secretary will underscore the United States’ ironclad commitment to Israeli security, coordination on Ukraine and Iran, and work to build upon the gains from the Abraham Accords.  While there, he will meet with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid, Defense Minister Benny Gantz, and also with Israeli President Isaac Herzog.  The Secretary will also meet with President Abbas of the Palestinian Authority in Ramallah as well as with representatives of Palestinian civil society.</p>
<p>During the visit, Secretary Blinken will affirm the commitment of the United States to a two-state solution, and to greater freedom, security, and prosperity for Palestinians and Israelis alike.  He will also underscore the importance of the upcoming month when major religious holidays across faiths will be celebrated, and reiterate the importance of actions to build trust, and enhance stability and security, and the need to avoid steps that can inflame tensions on the ground.</p>
<p>Turning to North Africa, the Secretary will first visit Morocco, where he will meet with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and other senior government officials to exchange views on regional issues and bilateral cooperation, and on advancing human rights and fundamental freedom, and he also will engage with Moroccan youth.  While in Rabat, the Secretary will also meet Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to discuss regional security and international developments.</p>
<p>The Secretary’s trip will culminate in Algiers, where he will meet President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and his counterpart Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, commercial cooperation, and advancing human rights and fundamental freedom.  The Secretary also will officially inaugurate the United States as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair – it’s the largest trade show of its kind in Africa – and he will meet with U.S. businesses.   During the course of this trip, the Secretary will emphasize to all the foreign leaders he meets with that the U.S. stands in solidarity and support with the government and people of Ukraine.  He will affirm the need for Vladimir Putin to end his premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>This region – the Middle East and North Africa – has seen the damaging effects of Russia’s military campaigns before:  In Syria and Libya and Mali, Russian military and paramilitary forces have exploited conflicts for Moscow’s own selfish interests, posing grave threats to regional stability and global commerce.</p>
<p>Putin’s invasion is already causing food prices – especially wheat – to rise, just as our economies recover from the COVID pandemic.  We know this pain is keenly felt in the Middle East and North Africa, where most countries import at least half of their wheat.  Egypt, Lebanon, Libya, Qatar, and Tunisia import at least a quarter of their wheat specifically from Ukraine.</p>
<p>Putin’s reckless war will only continue to increase the price of basic staples like bread in the region, taking money from the pockets of the hardest working and most vulnerable families as he invades a sovereign country without provocation.</p>
<p>This war must stop, and we will work hand-in-hand with our partners the world over to get there.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE</strong>:  Terrific.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Thank you.  And again, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone.  Again, that’s 1-0.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Let’s start with the line of Jennifer Hansler of CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Great.  Thank you.  I was wondering whether the Secretary intends to bring up with President Bennett their – his outreach to President Putin, whether the U.S. finds these efforts helpful, if there’s going to be any effort to get on the same page in Bennett’s diplomacy with Putin.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Thank you.  Yes, we do anticipate that we’ll be discussing Ukraine in Israel and elsewhere as well, but in Israel we’ll be discussing Israel’s efforts.  We appreciate Israel’s role.  So that will be on the agenda.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Humeyra Pamuk of Reuters.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks for doing this.  Just a couple of quick ones.  Just to follow up from Jennifer, how much of this trip do you think will be about Russia, Ukraine, given Israel’s emerging role as a potential mediator?  Because the Iran deal is also a big topic.  Like how – which one is going to dominate?</p>
<p>And a quick question on Secretary’s meeting with Abu Dhabi crown prince.  The relationship has not been at its best, to say the least, and there seems to be an expectation on the Emirati side for concrete proposals.  Will the Secretary have those in his suitcase, and what will those be?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Great.  Thanks for that question.  In terms of our engagement on Ukraine and discussing Russia’s invasion and war against Ukraine, that will be a topic I’m sure at all of our stops, as well, I anticipate, Iran, which as you know is an issue that is of great interest to all of our partners in the region.  So it’s difficult for me to predict at this moment what will dominate.  What I can predict with assurance is that both of those are going to be really at the top of the agenda in terms of our discussions.</p>
<p>In terms of the meeting with the crown prince, look, we’re taking advantage of the opportunity during the Secretary’s visit to Morocco to meet with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed and really have a strategic conversation about the full range of regional, international issues before us.  This is a valued and really important strategic relationship for us, and it’s an opportune moment for this meeting.  There’s a lot to discuss.  So we’re pleased to have this chance to sit down, the Secretary is, with the crown prince as strategic partners and discuss the full range of issues before us.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to John Hudson of <em>The Washington Post</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is the Secretary going to push the consulate issue while he’s in Israel?  Is that a campaign promise that’s just basically falling by the wayside in wake of Israeli opposition?</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  That will certainly be a topic of discussion in his meetings in both Israel and the West Bank.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Nahal Toosi.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hey, guys.  Thanks for doing this.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Halley, you are – I think we’ve lost you.  Unless we can get you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I’m here.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We can now.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sorry about that.  Former Secretary of State Pompeo issued a ruling for –  decision that said that the U.S. did not see the Israeli settlements in the West Bank as being illegal.  And to my knowledge, Secretary of State Blinken has not reversed that position.  Now, tell me if I’m wrong.  But is it the Biden administration’s policy that the Israeli settlements are not illegal under their – our version of international law?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  I have no update for you on that particular topic.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Paul Handley.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) tell us what those issues are.  Can you go through the list?  What are the priorities to discuss, because there’s a lot of things I could name, but why don’t you – can you just talk about them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Paul, we missed the top of your question.  What was your whole question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The question is could you go – you said there’s a whole list of things to talk about with Mohammed bin Zayed.  Can you go through that list, please?  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you.  Sorry.  Yes, there’s a wide range of issues, ranging from Iran to Yemen, Syria, global energy markets, and Ethiopia.  We have a range of topics that we’ll be discussing, as well as the Abraham Accords and what we can do to strengthen those further.  We have seen tremendous and tangible results in terms of the UAE-Israel relationship.  It’s really blossomed.  Tourism is thriving; direct flights are ferrying numbers of tourists back and forth.  Trade is booming.  And we anticipate that that will be a big topic of discussion as well.  We’ll probably also touch briefly on the Expo, which has really been a tremendous success, closing soon in Dubai.  That’s just a sampling.  I mean, we have just a wide array of shared interests and topics that we want to cover.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We have time for a final question or two.  Let’s go to Yuna Leibzon of Channel 12.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I do want to focus on Israel.  You talked about priorities in different countries.  But can you say what would be the first priority on the visit and the meeting in Israel?  Would it be Iran, or the Russia-Ukraine negotiations, or Palestinian issues, if you could focus that specifically, please?</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Look, our relationship with Israel is so broad and so deep, it’s difficult to choose just one issue and say that’s going to be the priority.  As I mentioned previously on this call, we’ll be certainly discussing Iran, as we have had close consultations on that topic since the beginning of the administration; Russia-Ukraine, no doubt; again, Abraham Accords and what we can do to try and strengthen and broaden them; and of course, Israeli-Palestinian issues and what we can do in terms of helping to lower tensions and see movement forward on that front, in addition to a range of other bilateral topics.  So it will be a broad and wide-ranging discussion.  There’s no doubt in my mind.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  And we’ll conclude with the line of Said Arikat, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) Madam Assistant Secretary.  Very quickly, I want to follow up on John Hudson’s question on the consulate.  Now, last year Secretary Blinken stated in no uncertain terms that the consulate will be reopened.  Are we likely to hear anything that is as strong in terms of a commitment to the consulate this time around?</p>
<p>And my second question regarding the village of Al-Walaja that is slated to be demolished, will the Secretary of State express that his opposition or – his clear opposition to the demolition of this particular Palestinian village?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS LEMPERT:</strong>  Thank you.  Look, as I mentioned before, the issue of our consulate general in Jerusalem will undoubtedly be a topic of discussion in the Secretary’s meetings both in Israel and the West Bank, and he’ll be speaking to it there.</p>
<p>In terms of your question about demolitions, I think that that will be among the topics that is discussed.  I will say that the State Department has made the administration’s view clear.  We believe it is critical for Israel and the Palestinian Authority to refrain from unilateral steps that exacerbate tensions and undercut efforts to advance a negotiated two-state solution.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.  Thank you very much, Acting Assistant Secretary Lempert.  Appreciate everyone’s time.  Again, this call was on the record, and we will be seeing many of you on the ground during the trip.  Talk to you then.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Military Presence at the Doha Defense Show</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/iran-military-presence-at-the-doha-defense-show/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327800</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are deeply disappointed and troubled by the presence of Iranian military officials and reportedly Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps officers at the Doha Defense Show in Qatar. We utterly reject their presence at the show and its maritime defense exhibit, as it is Iran that is biggest threat to maritime stability in the Gulf region. Transactions related to Iranian weapons are generally sanctionable under multiple U.S. authorities, including sanctions related to terrorism and weapons of mass destruction.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are deeply disappointed and troubled by the presence of Iranian military officials and reportedly Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps officers at the Doha Defense Show in Qatar. We utterly reject their presence at the show and its maritime defense exhibit, as it is Iran that is biggest threat to maritime stability in the Gulf region. Transactions related to Iranian weapons are generally sanctionable under multiple U.S. authorities, including sanctions related to terrorism and weapons of mass destruction.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-israel-the-west-bank-morocco-and-algeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria March 26-30 to consult with partners on a range of regional and global priorities, including the Russian government’s war on Ukraine, Iran’s destabilizing activities, the Abraham Accords and normalization agreements with Israel, Israeli-Palestinian relations, and preserving the possibility of a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, among other topics.</p>
<p>The Secretary will start his trip in Israel and the West Bank.  There, he will meet with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid, Defense Minister Benny Gantz, and Israeli President Isaac Herzog.  The Secretary will underscore the unwavering U.S. commitment to Israel’s security, engage on Israeli-Palestinian issues, and discuss regional and global challenges with his counterparts in the Israeli government.  The Secretary will also meet with President Mahmoud Abbas in Ramallah as well as with representatives of Palestinian civil society.  In these meetings, the Secretary will emphasize the importance of strengthening U.S.-Palestinian relations, and advancing freedom, security and prosperity for the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>In Morocco, he will meet with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and other senior government officials to exchange views on regional issues and bilateral cooperation, as well as advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will also meet with exceptional Moroccan alumnae of U.S.-sponsored exchange programs.</p>
<p>While in Rabat, the Secretary will also meet Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to discuss regional security and international developments.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Algiers, Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, commercial cooperation, advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, and other areas of mutual concern.  The Secretary will also officially inaugurate the United States as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa. He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p>During the course of his trip, the Secretary will emphasize to all of the foreign leaders he meets that the United States stands in solidarity with the government and people of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression.  We will continue to work closely with our allies and partners to impose further costs on Putin and his enablers if Putin does not change course.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria March 26-30 to consult with partners on a range of regional and global priorities, including the Russian government’s war on Ukraine, Iran’s destabilizing activities, the Abraham Accords and normalization agreements with Israel, Israeli-Palestinian relations, and preserving the possibility of a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, among other topics.</p>
<p>The Secretary will start his trip in Israel and the West Bank.  There, he will meet with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid, Defense Minister Benny Gantz, and Israeli President Isaac Herzog.  The Secretary will underscore the unwavering U.S. commitment to Israel’s security, engage on Israeli-Palestinian issues, and discuss regional and global challenges with his counterparts in the Israeli government.  The Secretary will also meet with President Mahmoud Abbas in Ramallah as well as with representatives of Palestinian civil society.  In these meetings, the Secretary will emphasize the importance of strengthening U.S.-Palestinian relations, and advancing freedom, security and prosperity for the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>In Morocco, he will meet with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and other senior government officials to exchange views on regional issues and bilateral cooperation, as well as advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will also meet with exceptional Moroccan alumnae of U.S.-sponsored exchange programs.</p>
<p>While in Rabat, the Secretary will also meet Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to discuss regional security and international developments.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Algiers, Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, commercial cooperation, advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, and other areas of mutual concern.  The Secretary will also officially inaugurate the United States as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa. He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p>During the course of his trip, the Secretary will emphasize to all of the foreign leaders he meets that the United States stands in solidarity with the government and people of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression.  We will continue to work closely with our allies and partners to impose further costs on Putin and his enablers if Putin does not change course.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sanctioning Additional Members of Russia’s Duma, Russian Elites, Bank Board Members, and Defense Entities</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/sanctioning-additional-members-of-russias-duma-russian-elites-bank-board-members-and-defense-entities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 14:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Putin’s war continues to inflict horror and widespread suffering on the people of Ukraine.  At the same time, in Russia, the State Duma continues to use its legislative power to target domestic dissenters and political opponents, disrupt the free flow of information, and restrict the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the citizens of Russia.  The United States today is designating 328 members of the Russian State Duma, in addition to the 12 members designated on March 11.  These members supported the Kremlin’s violations of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, including through treaties recognizing the self-proclaimed independence of Russian-proxy controlled areas of eastern Ukraine, the so-called Donetsk People’s Republic (DNR) and Luhansk People’s Republic (LNR).</p>
<p>The United States is also designating the Russian State Duma in its entirety, as well as Herman Gref, the head of Sberbank and a close ally of Putin.  Today’s actions are taken pursuant to Executive Order 14024, which authorizes sanctions against Russia for its harmful foreign activities.  These actions complement the ongoing efforts of our allies and partners to hold to account enablers of this unconscionable war of choice against Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>As part of this action, we are also targeting multiple Russian elites to include their properties and family members.  Notably, this will include 17 members of the board of PJSC Sovcombank, a designated entity.  These executives join the growing list of individuals associated with blocked Russian financial institutions that now also find themselves subject to U.S. sanctions.  Additionally, OOO Volga Group is being re-designated for having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy.  As a result, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, the owner of OOO Volga Group, will also be re-designated along with OOO Transoil, which Timchenko owns.  Timchenko’s wife, Elena Petrovna Timchenko, and daughter, Natalya Browning, will now also be designated along with Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, a board member of OOO Transoil and her spouse Gleb Sergeevich Frank.</p>
<p>Additionally, the United States is taking action to impose additional severe costs on Russia’s defense establishment.  This includes designating multiple defense-related entities and one associated individual.  An important component of today’s action is designating Russian defense companies that are part of Russia’s defense-industrial base and that produce weapons that have been used in Russia’s war of aggression.  By cutting off dozens of Russian defense companies from the U.S. financial system, today’s action will have a deep and long-lasting effect on Russia’s defense-industrial base.  We are targeting, and will continue to target, the suppliers of Russia’s war effort and, in turn, their supply chain.</p>
<p>With our partners and allies, the United States aims to strike the heart of Russia’s ability to engage in warfare and carry out aggression against other countries, including Ukraine.  We will continue to impose costs until Putin ends this unprovoked war against Ukraine.  We call on those closest to Putin to cease and publicly condemn this cold-blooded war, which has caused the unconscionable death of hundreds of civilians, including children, and the largest humanitarian catastrophe in Europe since the Second World War.</p>
<p>At the same time, we continue to support Ukraine, including through an additional $800 million in security assistance, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in the past two weeks and more than $2 billion since last March.  The United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  We stand with the brave people of Ukraine who are demonstrating incredible courage and fierce determination in defending their country against the Kremlin’s aggression.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of State <a href="https://www.state.gov/targeting-elites-of-the-russian-federation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjQuNTUzODUzNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdGFyZ2V0aW5nLWVsaXRlcy1vZi10aGUtcnVzc2lhbi1mZWRlcmF0aW9uLyJ9.KrvJ1UrgUvrd-WX5rkiryY6WVkQwUFL1jDgyv2xd2kk/s/1006560560/br/128587650881-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648215944405000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0lNcuXrCzLv4RkpfaqfLWR">Fact Sheet</a> and the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0677" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Putin’s war continues to inflict horror and widespread suffering on the people of Ukraine.  At the same time, in Russia, the State Duma continues to use its legislative power to target domestic dissenters and political opponents, disrupt the free flow of information, and restrict the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the citizens of Russia.  The United States today is designating 328 members of the Russian State Duma, in addition to the 12 members designated on March 11.  These members supported the Kremlin’s violations of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, including through treaties recognizing the self-proclaimed independence of Russian-proxy controlled areas of eastern Ukraine, the so-called Donetsk People’s Republic (DNR) and Luhansk People’s Republic (LNR).</p>
<p>The United States is also designating the Russian State Duma in its entirety, as well as Herman Gref, the head of Sberbank and a close ally of Putin.  Today’s actions are taken pursuant to Executive Order 14024, which authorizes sanctions against Russia for its harmful foreign activities.  These actions complement the ongoing efforts of our allies and partners to hold to account enablers of this unconscionable war of choice against Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>As part of this action, we are also targeting multiple Russian elites to include their properties and family members.  Notably, this will include 17 members of the board of PJSC Sovcombank, a designated entity.  These executives join the growing list of individuals associated with blocked Russian financial institutions that now also find themselves subject to U.S. sanctions.  Additionally, OOO Volga Group is being re-designated for having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy.  As a result, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, the owner of OOO Volga Group, will also be re-designated along with OOO Transoil, which Timchenko owns.  Timchenko’s wife, Elena Petrovna Timchenko, and daughter, Natalya Browning, will now also be designated along with Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, a board member of OOO Transoil and her spouse Gleb Sergeevich Frank.</p>
<p>Additionally, the United States is taking action to impose additional severe costs on Russia’s defense establishment.  This includes designating multiple defense-related entities and one associated individual.  An important component of today’s action is designating Russian defense companies that are part of Russia’s defense-industrial base and that produce weapons that have been used in Russia’s war of aggression.  By cutting off dozens of Russian defense companies from the U.S. financial system, today’s action will have a deep and long-lasting effect on Russia’s defense-industrial base.  We are targeting, and will continue to target, the suppliers of Russia’s war effort and, in turn, their supply chain.</p>
<p>With our partners and allies, the United States aims to strike the heart of Russia’s ability to engage in warfare and carry out aggression against other countries, including Ukraine.  We will continue to impose costs until Putin ends this unprovoked war against Ukraine.  We call on those closest to Putin to cease and publicly condemn this cold-blooded war, which has caused the unconscionable death of hundreds of civilians, including children, and the largest humanitarian catastrophe in Europe since the Second World War.</p>
<p>At the same time, we continue to support Ukraine, including through an additional $800 million in security assistance, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in the past two weeks and more than $2 billion since last March.  The United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  We stand with the brave people of Ukraine who are demonstrating incredible courage and fierce determination in defending their country against the Kremlin’s aggression.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of State <a href="https://www.state.gov/targeting-elites-of-the-russian-federation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjQuNTUzODUzNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdGFyZ2V0aW5nLWVsaXRlcy1vZi10aGUtcnVzc2lhbi1mZWRlcmF0aW9uLyJ9.KrvJ1UrgUvrd-WX5rkiryY6WVkQwUFL1jDgyv2xd2kk/s/1006560560/br/128587650881-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648215944405000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0lNcuXrCzLv4RkpfaqfLWR">Fact Sheet</a> and the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0677" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Elites of the Russian Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-elites-of-the-russian-federation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the Department of State and the Department of the Treasury have taken additional sweeping actions as part of our response, together with our allies and partners, to the Russian Federation’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.  We are steadfast in our commitment to ensuring Russia pays a severe economic and diplomatic price for its further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Department of State is targeting elites close to Putin, along with their property, holdings, and family members.  Today, the Department has designated:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dmitry Vladimirovich Gusev, Mikhail Lvovich Kuchment, Anatoly Alexandrovich Bravverman, Ilya Borisovich Brodskiy, Aleksey Leonidovich Fisun, Dmitry Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Sergey Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Mikhail Vasilyevich Klyukin, Mikhal Olegovich Avtukhov, Albert Alexandrovich Boris, Dmitry Vladimirovich Beryshnikov, Elena Alexandrovna Cherstvova, Sergey Nikolaevich Bondarovich, Oleg Alexandrovich Mashtalyar, Alexey Valeryevich Panferov, Irina Nikoalyevna Kashina, and Joel Raymon Lautier
<ul>
<li>These individuals are each being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of PJSC Sovcombank, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group is being designated for operating or having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy, pursuant to Section 1(a)(i) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Volga Group, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil is being designated for being owned or controlled by, or having acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to section 1(a)(vii) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Transoil, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank is being designated for being the spouse of Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning are each being designated for being a spouse or adult child of Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena </em>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena</em> is property in which Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko has an interest and is therefore blocked property.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SANCTIONS IMPLICATIONS </strong></p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will add the individuals, entities, and property above to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons.  As a result of today’s action, all property and interests in property of the individuals and entities above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to OFAC.  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more, by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the Department of State and the Department of the Treasury have taken additional sweeping actions as part of our response, together with our allies and partners, to the Russian Federation’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.  We are steadfast in our commitment to ensuring Russia pays a severe economic and diplomatic price for its further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Department of State is targeting elites close to Putin, along with their property, holdings, and family members.  Today, the Department has designated:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dmitry Vladimirovich Gusev, Mikhail Lvovich Kuchment, Anatoly Alexandrovich Bravverman, Ilya Borisovich Brodskiy, Aleksey Leonidovich Fisun, Dmitry Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Sergey Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Mikhail Vasilyevich Klyukin, Mikhal Olegovich Avtukhov, Albert Alexandrovich Boris, Dmitry Vladimirovich Beryshnikov, Elena Alexandrovna Cherstvova, Sergey Nikolaevich Bondarovich, Oleg Alexandrovich Mashtalyar, Alexey Valeryevich Panferov, Irina Nikoalyevna Kashina, and Joel Raymon Lautier
<ul>
<li>These individuals are each being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of PJSC Sovcombank, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group is being designated for operating or having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy, pursuant to Section 1(a)(i) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Volga Group, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil is being designated for being owned or controlled by, or having acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to section 1(a)(vii) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Transoil, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank is being designated for being the spouse of Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning are each being designated for being a spouse or adult child of Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena </em>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena</em> is property in which Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko has an interest and is therefore blocked property.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SANCTIONS IMPLICATIONS </strong></p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will add the individuals, entities, and property above to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons.  As a result of today’s action, all property and interests in property of the individuals and entities above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to OFAC.  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more, by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea&#8217;s Ballistic Missile Launch</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-koreas-ballistic-missile-launch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 12:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>The United States condemns the DPRK&#8217;s ballistic missile launch. Like the DPRK&#8217;s other escalatory tests this year, including at least two intercontinental ballistic missiles, this launch is a clear violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions, and demonstrates the threat the DPRK&#8217;s unlawful weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs pose to the DPRK&#8217;s neighbors and the region as a whole. We stand with the international community to call on the DPRK to refrain from further provocations and engage in sustained and substantive dialogue. Our commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan remains ironclad. We have been and will continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners to address the threats posed by the DPRK, and to advance our shared objective of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>The United States condemns the DPRK&#8217;s ballistic missile launch. Like the DPRK&#8217;s other escalatory tests this year, including at least two intercontinental ballistic missiles, this launch is a clear violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions, and demonstrates the threat the DPRK&#8217;s unlawful weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs pose to the DPRK&#8217;s neighbors and the region as a whole. We stand with the international community to call on the DPRK to refrain from further provocations and engage in sustained and substantive dialogue. Our commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan remains ironclad. We have been and will continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners to address the threats posed by the DPRK, and to advance our shared objective of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with South African Foreign Minister Pandor</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-south-african-foreign-minister-pandor-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 01:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with South African Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Naledi Pandor about the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and the negative ripple effects it is already causing to food security and prices for essential commodities in Africa.  The Secretary underscored U.S. views on the need for a clear, unified international response to President Putin’s invasion to put a swift end to this crisis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with South African Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Naledi Pandor about the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and the negative ripple effects it is already causing to food security and prices for essential commodities in Africa.  The Secretary underscored U.S. views on the need for a clear, unified international response to President Putin’s invasion to put a swift end to this crisis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women and Girls’ Education in Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/women-and-girls-education-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Education is a human right, and the United States rejects the Taliban’s excuses for reversing their commitment to the people of Afghanistan that all Afghans would be able to return to school at all levels today.  As many girls and women were returning to secondary classrooms across the country, they were told to go home until further notice.  We stand with Afghan girls and their families, who see education as a path to realizing the full potential of Afghanistan&#8217;s society and economy.</p>
<p>This decision by the Taliban, if it is not swiftly reversed, will profoundly harm the Afghan people, the country’s prospects for economic growth, and the Taliban’s ambition to improve their relations with the international community.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Education is a human right, and the United States rejects the Taliban’s excuses for reversing their commitment to the people of Afghanistan that all Afghans would be able to return to school at all levels today.  As many girls and women were returning to secondary classrooms across the country, they were told to go home until further notice.  We stand with Afghan girls and their families, who see education as a path to realizing the full potential of Afghanistan&#8217;s society and economy.</p>
<p>This decision by the Taliban, if it is not swiftly reversed, will profoundly harm the Afghan people, the country’s prospects for economic growth, and the Taliban’s ambition to improve their relations with the international community.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
