<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 20:55:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks to the Press on the Announcement of a U.S. Refugee Admissions Program Priority 2 Designation for Afghan Nationals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-to-the-press-on-the-announcement-of-a-u-s-refugee-admissions-program-priority-2-designation-for-afghan-nationals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 20:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room </p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon.  Happy Monday.  As you all can see, we have a special guest with us today.  Secretary Blinken will offer some remarks at the top.  He’ll have time for a question or two, at which point we will resume with our regularly scheduled programming.  So without further ado, Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Ned, thanks very much.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good to see everyone here.</p>
<p>Before I turn to today’s announcement, I want to take a moment to address a few urgent matters.</p>
<p>First, I want to condemn again the attack on Friday against the commercial ship the Mercer Street, which was peacefully transiting through the north Arabian Sea in international waters when it was targeted by a drone laden with explosives, killing two people.</p>
<p>We’ve conducted a thorough review, and we are confident that Iran carried out this attack.</p>
<p>It follows a pattern of similar attacks by Iran, including past incidents with explosive drones.</p>
<p>There is no justification for this attack on a peaceful vessel on a commercial mission in international waters.</p>
<p>Iran’s action is a direct threat to freedom of navigation and commerce.</p>
<p>It took the lives of innocent sailors.</p>
<p>We’re currently coordinating with our partners and consulting with governments in the region.</p>
<p>And we join others around the world in sending our deepest condolences to the families of the British and Romanian crew members who were killed.</p>
<p>Second, on Friday, the White House announced two outstanding public servants who, with the consent of the Senate, will be joining our team here at the State Department.</p>
<p>Rashad Hussain is the President’s nominee for ambassador at large for international religious freedom.</p>
<p>He previously served as special envoy to the Organization of Islamic Cooperation, among other key roles in the Obama administration, and he’s currently director for partnerships and global engagement at the National Security Council.</p>
<p>Deborah Lipstadt is the President’s nominee for special envoy to monitor and combat anti-Semitism.</p>
<p>She’s a scholar of modern Jewish history and Holocaust studies who fights relentlessly against Holocaust denialism, including in a landmark London trial when she was sued for libel by a Holocaust denier, resulting in an overwhelming victory for Deborah and all those fighting Holocaust denialism.</p>
<p>She was also a two-term member of the United States Holocaust Memorial Council and represented our country at the 60th anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz.</p>
<p>We’re eager for Rashad and Deborah to be confirmed and to get to work, because this is a critical moment.</p>
<p>According to the Pew Center, 56 countries – home to a majority of the world’s people – have high or severe restrictions on religious freedom.</p>
<p>Here in the United States, as in many parts of the world, we have seen a rise in anti-Semitism and anti-Muslim hatred in recent years.</p>
<p>This hits painfully close to home.</p>
<p>As you know, there was an anti-Semitic incident here in this building last week.</p>
<p>That was deeply disturbing – not only because it was a deliberate act of hate toward many of our employees, but because this is the State Department.</p>
<p>And at our best, the State Department leads the fight for the dignity and freedom of people everywhere, and we’re resolute in the fight against anti-Semitism.</p>
<p>So that swastika wasn’t only a threat directed at Jewish people in this building.</p>
<p>It was also an insult to our global mission and our national ideals.</p>
<p>There’s just one response that we’ll make to that kind of hatred, and that’s to become even more committed to the fight against anti-Semitism.</p>
<p>Deborah and Rashad will help us do that.</p>
<p>The investigation into that incident is ongoing.</p>
<p>We’ll share new information as it becomes available.</p>
<p>While I’m on the topic of nominees, the State Department now has more than 65 nominees who have been formally nominated and are awaiting confirmation.</p>
<p>Within the next week, we’re hopeful that a third of those – 25 nominees – will be pending a vote in the full Senate.</p>
<p>These are critical national security positions.</p>
<p>They include overseeing security at our embassies and facilities around the world and helping clear the passport application backlog caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The American people need these services.</p>
<p>The nominees also include those who would lead our diplomacy in vital regions of the world, including Latin America, Asia, Europe, and Africa.</p>
<p>The American people need these nominees in place.</p>
<p>So we urge the Senate to confirm these individuals expeditiously, before the August recess.</p>
<p>Now let me turn to another urgent matter.</p>
<p>Even as we withdraw our forces from Afghanistan, the United States and our partners remain deeply engaged.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to work toward an Afghanistan where all Afghans can live in safety and security, and we will continue our support for Afghan institutions and for the gains that the Afghan people have made over the past 20 years.</p>
<p>Our partnership with the people of Afghanistan will endure long after our service members have departed.</p>
<p>We will keep engaging intensely in diplomacy to advance negotiations between the Afghan Government and the Taliban with the goal of a political solution, which we believe is the only path to lasting peace.</p>
<p>And we’ll keep working closely with countries in the region, which all have a stake in a stable, peaceful, democratic Afghanistan.</p>
<p>At the same time, Afghans who worked with the United States or the International Security Assistance Force at some point since 2001 are facing acute fears of persecution or retribution that will likely grow as coalition forces leave the country.</p>
<p>We have a special responsibility to these individuals.</p>
<p>They stood with us.</p>
<p>We will stand with them.</p>
<p>Over the past 13 years, the State Department has issued more than 73,000 Special Immigrant Visas to eligible Afghans who have helped the United States and also to their families.</p>
<p>Last year alone, we issued nearly 8,000 of those visas.</p>
<p>Now we have accelerated and expanded the program.  Congress recently increased the cap by another 8,000 visas.</p>
<p>The first flight of Operation Allies Refuge arrived in the United States on Friday, the second flight arrived early this morning, together transporting around 400 people, and those flights will continue.</p>
<p>We’re now focused on relocating a group of more than 1,000 applicants and their families who have nearly completed processing – around 4,000 people in total.</p>
<p>Additionally, we’re pursuing third-country agreements, so eligible Afghans can be quickly relocated to wait safely in another country while we finish elements of this rigorous vetting process.</p>
<p>Getting to this point was not a simple matter.</p>
<p>Earlier today, I visited the interagency task force located here at the State Department responsible for executing this 24/7 operation.  I conveyed to them how grateful we are that they’re giving their all to this tremendously important and also meaningful mission.</p>
<p>Now, as you know, the Special Immigrant Visa Program is defined carefully by statute.</p>
<p>And we know that there are Afghans who don’t qualify but who helped us and deserve our help.</p>
<p>Some may not have the qualifying employment for the special immigrant visa – for example, they worked for a project funded by the U.S. Government, but not for the government itself.</p>
<p>Some may not have met the minimum time-in-service requirement – for example, employees who began working for us more recently.</p>
<p>And some were employed by American media organizations or NGOs, doing vital work to support democratic progress in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>So today, the State Department is announcing a new resettlement program for Afghans who assisted the United States but who do not qualify for Special Immigrant Visas.</p>
<p>We’ve created a Priority-2, or P-2, designation, granting access to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program for many of these Afghans and their family members.</p>
<p>A great deal of hard work has gone into this already, but even more lies ahead.</p>
<p>There is a significant diplomatic, logistical, and bureaucratic challenge.</p>
<p>We take our responsibility to our Afghan partners deeply seriously, and we know the American people do as well.</p>
<p>We have a long history in the United States of welcoming refugees into our country.</p>
<p>And helping them resettle into new homes and new communities is the work of a huge network of state and local governments, NGOs, faith-based groups, advocacy groups, tens of thousands of volunteers.</p>
<p>It’s a powerful demonstration of American friendship and generosity.</p>
<p>Many Americans are asking how they can help Afghan refugees in their communities get resettled.</p>
<p>The answer is to reach out to your local refugee resettlement agency.</p>
<p>There are national websites with state-by-state phone numbers.</p>
<p>These agencies are always looking for extra hands and will be grateful for the help.</p>
<p>Again, I want to emphasize that although U.S. troops are leaving, the United States remains deeply engaged.  We will continue to support Afghanistan through security assistance, humanitarian development aid, and diplomatic support for the peace process.</p>
<p>The Afghan people deserve a just and lasting peace, and the security and opportunity that peace makes possible.</p>
<p>We will do all that we can to advance that goal.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to welcome Afghan immigrants and refugees as our neighbors, in gratitude for helping us despite the danger.</p>
<p>We won’t forget it.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Nazira.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Mr. Secretary, first of all, thank you so much.  I am Afghan woman.  I suffered a lot.  I know about the Afghan people also.  I represent them today.  Thank you very much for your service.</p>
<p>But still, Afghan people have suffered a lot, like especially Afghan journalists, especially women.  They are under a lot of risk in Afghanistan.  Any good news for them, too?</p>
<p>And the second question &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; is Taliban is still increasing their attack, and today, U.S. embassy and British embassy in Kabul said that Taliban kill innocent people in Spin Boldak, Kandahar.  Any reaction, although they sign agreement with you guys in Doha, Qatar?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So with regard to Afghans who may fear persecution, may fear violence, and who may not qualify either for the Special Immigrant Visa Program or what I just announced today, the P-2 program, they can also avail themselves of their right to seek refugee status in the United States and apply for that.  Now, to be clear, you have to do that from outside of Afghanistan, from a third country.  But they can go to the UNHCR, for example, and seek refugee status.</p>
<p>We’ve seen the reports of atrocities being committed by the Taliban in various places where they are on the offensive, and these reports are deeply disturbing and totally unacceptable.  And I think it speaks to a larger issue, which is this:  The Taliban has repeatedly said that they seek in the future a number of things – international recognition, international support; they want their leaders to be able to travel freely around the world; they would like sanctions lifted on them.  And none of those things are going to be possible if the Taliban seeks to take the country by force and commits the kind of atrocities that have been reported.  An Afghanistan, as I’ve said before, that does not respect the basic rights of its people, that does not have a representative and inclusive government, that does not abide by the main gains of the last 20 years is an Afghanistan that will be a pariah state, certainly for the United States, and I believe for the international community.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>If I may follow up on my colleague here from Afghanistan, how do these people under the P-1 program even get to third countries?  You’re asking that Turkey and other neighboring countries – Iran – open their borders.  How can they get from here to there past Taliban checkpoints?  They’ve got targets on their backs.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And if I might follow up also on the Mercer fleet, how do you interpret this action that you are attributing to Iran?  If this is correct, do you view this as an indication of the new government’s policy?  What action is going to be taken either by us, by Israel, or in some way a combination?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, Andrea.  So with regard first to Afghans who seek to leave the country and seek to avail themselves of the refugee programs, et cetera, you’re right:  This is incredibly hard.  It is hard on so many levels.  It’s hard to pick up and leave everything you know, potentially family, friends, community, culture, language.  It’s – and it’s hard to get yourself to a place where you can take advantage of what opportunities exist to seek to apply for refugee status.  And we recognize that.  This is, alas, the case for millions of people around the world who find themselves in very difficult situations, and particularly in Afghanistan now, especially a group of people who may have worked for us, worked for NGOs, media organizations, women and girls, and others who feel an acute sense of threat and fear with – for the future.</p>
<p>And so, as we see again and again, people have to do very difficult things to make sure that they can find safety and security, and we will do everything we can to help them, including making these different avenues of arrival to the United States for this group of people possible.  We are also dedicating very significant assistance, humanitarian assistance, not only in Afghanistan itself, but to neighboring countries to enable them to support those who come to their countries, again, seeking potentially, refugee status somewhere or immigrant status somewhere.</p>
<p>So that support, I think, makes it a little bit easier.  But I don&#8217;t want to deny the challenge and the difficulty.  It is indeed a hard thing.  Our obligation, I believe, is in the first instance to make sure that we are making good on our commitments to those who, in particular, put themselves on the line, put their families on the line to help us, whether it was, again, working directly for the United States Government, for our embassy, for our military, for the international security force, or whether it was working for NGOs, media organizations, and others.</p>
<p>And, of course, as we just discussed, some Afghans who are not – don’t fit into any of those categories but may feel particularly at risk, we also have the principal refugee program available for them.</p>
<p>With regard to Iran, so we have seen a series of actions taken by Iran over many months, including against shipping.  So I’m not sure that this particular action is anything new or augers anything one way or another for the new government.  But what it does say is that Iran continues to act with tremendous irresponsibility when it comes to, in this instance, threats to navigation, to commerce, to innocent sailors who are simply engaged in commercial transit in international waters.  And as I noted, we are in very close contact and coordination with the United Kingdom, Israel, Romania, and other countries, and there will be a collective response.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room </p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon.  Happy Monday.  As you all can see, we have a special guest with us today.  Secretary Blinken will offer some remarks at the top.  He’ll have time for a question or two, at which point we will resume with our regularly scheduled programming.  So without further ado, Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Ned, thanks very much.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good to see everyone here.</p>
<p>Before I turn to today’s announcement, I want to take a moment to address a few urgent matters.</p>
<p>First, I want to condemn again the attack on Friday against the commercial ship the Mercer Street, which was peacefully transiting through the north Arabian Sea in international waters when it was targeted by a drone laden with explosives, killing two people.</p>
<p>We’ve conducted a thorough review, and we are confident that Iran carried out this attack.</p>
<p>It follows a pattern of similar attacks by Iran, including past incidents with explosive drones.</p>
<p>There is no justification for this attack on a peaceful vessel on a commercial mission in international waters.</p>
<p>Iran’s action is a direct threat to freedom of navigation and commerce.</p>
<p>It took the lives of innocent sailors.</p>
<p>We’re currently coordinating with our partners and consulting with governments in the region.</p>
<p>And we join others around the world in sending our deepest condolences to the families of the British and Romanian crew members who were killed.</p>
<p>Second, on Friday, the White House announced two outstanding public servants who, with the consent of the Senate, will be joining our team here at the State Department.</p>
<p>Rashad Hussain is the President’s nominee for ambassador at large for international religious freedom.</p>
<p>He previously served as special envoy to the Organization of Islamic Cooperation, among other key roles in the Obama administration, and he’s currently director for partnerships and global engagement at the National Security Council.</p>
<p>Deborah Lipstadt is the President’s nominee for special envoy to monitor and combat anti-Semitism.</p>
<p>She’s a scholar of modern Jewish history and Holocaust studies who fights relentlessly against Holocaust denialism, including in a landmark London trial when she was sued for libel by a Holocaust denier, resulting in an overwhelming victory for Deborah and all those fighting Holocaust denialism.</p>
<p>She was also a two-term member of the United States Holocaust Memorial Council and represented our country at the 60th anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz.</p>
<p>We’re eager for Rashad and Deborah to be confirmed and to get to work, because this is a critical moment.</p>
<p>According to the Pew Center, 56 countries – home to a majority of the world’s people – have high or severe restrictions on religious freedom.</p>
<p>Here in the United States, as in many parts of the world, we have seen a rise in anti-Semitism and anti-Muslim hatred in recent years.</p>
<p>This hits painfully close to home.</p>
<p>As you know, there was an anti-Semitic incident here in this building last week.</p>
<p>That was deeply disturbing – not only because it was a deliberate act of hate toward many of our employees, but because this is the State Department.</p>
<p>And at our best, the State Department leads the fight for the dignity and freedom of people everywhere, and we’re resolute in the fight against anti-Semitism.</p>
<p>So that swastika wasn’t only a threat directed at Jewish people in this building.</p>
<p>It was also an insult to our global mission and our national ideals.</p>
<p>There’s just one response that we’ll make to that kind of hatred, and that’s to become even more committed to the fight against anti-Semitism.</p>
<p>Deborah and Rashad will help us do that.</p>
<p>The investigation into that incident is ongoing.</p>
<p>We’ll share new information as it becomes available.</p>
<p>While I’m on the topic of nominees, the State Department now has more than 65 nominees who have been formally nominated and are awaiting confirmation.</p>
<p>Within the next week, we’re hopeful that a third of those – 25 nominees – will be pending a vote in the full Senate.</p>
<p>These are critical national security positions.</p>
<p>They include overseeing security at our embassies and facilities around the world and helping clear the passport application backlog caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The American people need these services.</p>
<p>The nominees also include those who would lead our diplomacy in vital regions of the world, including Latin America, Asia, Europe, and Africa.</p>
<p>The American people need these nominees in place.</p>
<p>So we urge the Senate to confirm these individuals expeditiously, before the August recess.</p>
<p>Now let me turn to another urgent matter.</p>
<p>Even as we withdraw our forces from Afghanistan, the United States and our partners remain deeply engaged.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to work toward an Afghanistan where all Afghans can live in safety and security, and we will continue our support for Afghan institutions and for the gains that the Afghan people have made over the past 20 years.</p>
<p>Our partnership with the people of Afghanistan will endure long after our service members have departed.</p>
<p>We will keep engaging intensely in diplomacy to advance negotiations between the Afghan Government and the Taliban with the goal of a political solution, which we believe is the only path to lasting peace.</p>
<p>And we’ll keep working closely with countries in the region, which all have a stake in a stable, peaceful, democratic Afghanistan.</p>
<p>At the same time, Afghans who worked with the United States or the International Security Assistance Force at some point since 2001 are facing acute fears of persecution or retribution that will likely grow as coalition forces leave the country.</p>
<p>We have a special responsibility to these individuals.</p>
<p>They stood with us.</p>
<p>We will stand with them.</p>
<p>Over the past 13 years, the State Department has issued more than 73,000 Special Immigrant Visas to eligible Afghans who have helped the United States and also to their families.</p>
<p>Last year alone, we issued nearly 8,000 of those visas.</p>
<p>Now we have accelerated and expanded the program.  Congress recently increased the cap by another 8,000 visas.</p>
<p>The first flight of Operation Allies Refuge arrived in the United States on Friday, the second flight arrived early this morning, together transporting around 400 people, and those flights will continue.</p>
<p>We’re now focused on relocating a group of more than 1,000 applicants and their families who have nearly completed processing – around 4,000 people in total.</p>
<p>Additionally, we’re pursuing third-country agreements, so eligible Afghans can be quickly relocated to wait safely in another country while we finish elements of this rigorous vetting process.</p>
<p>Getting to this point was not a simple matter.</p>
<p>Earlier today, I visited the interagency task force located here at the State Department responsible for executing this 24/7 operation.  I conveyed to them how grateful we are that they’re giving their all to this tremendously important and also meaningful mission.</p>
<p>Now, as you know, the Special Immigrant Visa Program is defined carefully by statute.</p>
<p>And we know that there are Afghans who don’t qualify but who helped us and deserve our help.</p>
<p>Some may not have the qualifying employment for the special immigrant visa – for example, they worked for a project funded by the U.S. Government, but not for the government itself.</p>
<p>Some may not have met the minimum time-in-service requirement – for example, employees who began working for us more recently.</p>
<p>And some were employed by American media organizations or NGOs, doing vital work to support democratic progress in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>So today, the State Department is announcing a new resettlement program for Afghans who assisted the United States but who do not qualify for Special Immigrant Visas.</p>
<p>We’ve created a Priority-2, or P-2, designation, granting access to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program for many of these Afghans and their family members.</p>
<p>A great deal of hard work has gone into this already, but even more lies ahead.</p>
<p>There is a significant diplomatic, logistical, and bureaucratic challenge.</p>
<p>We take our responsibility to our Afghan partners deeply seriously, and we know the American people do as well.</p>
<p>We have a long history in the United States of welcoming refugees into our country.</p>
<p>And helping them resettle into new homes and new communities is the work of a huge network of state and local governments, NGOs, faith-based groups, advocacy groups, tens of thousands of volunteers.</p>
<p>It’s a powerful demonstration of American friendship and generosity.</p>
<p>Many Americans are asking how they can help Afghan refugees in their communities get resettled.</p>
<p>The answer is to reach out to your local refugee resettlement agency.</p>
<p>There are national websites with state-by-state phone numbers.</p>
<p>These agencies are always looking for extra hands and will be grateful for the help.</p>
<p>Again, I want to emphasize that although U.S. troops are leaving, the United States remains deeply engaged.  We will continue to support Afghanistan through security assistance, humanitarian development aid, and diplomatic support for the peace process.</p>
<p>The Afghan people deserve a just and lasting peace, and the security and opportunity that peace makes possible.</p>
<p>We will do all that we can to advance that goal.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to welcome Afghan immigrants and refugees as our neighbors, in gratitude for helping us despite the danger.</p>
<p>We won’t forget it.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Nazira.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Mr. Secretary, first of all, thank you so much.  I am Afghan woman.  I suffered a lot.  I know about the Afghan people also.  I represent them today.  Thank you very much for your service.</p>
<p>But still, Afghan people have suffered a lot, like especially Afghan journalists, especially women.  They are under a lot of risk in Afghanistan.  Any good news for them, too?</p>
<p>And the second question &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; is Taliban is still increasing their attack, and today, U.S. embassy and British embassy in Kabul said that Taliban kill innocent people in Spin Boldak, Kandahar.  Any reaction, although they sign agreement with you guys in Doha, Qatar?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So with regard to Afghans who may fear persecution, may fear violence, and who may not qualify either for the Special Immigrant Visa Program or what I just announced today, the P-2 program, they can also avail themselves of their right to seek refugee status in the United States and apply for that.  Now, to be clear, you have to do that from outside of Afghanistan, from a third country.  But they can go to the UNHCR, for example, and seek refugee status.</p>
<p>We’ve seen the reports of atrocities being committed by the Taliban in various places where they are on the offensive, and these reports are deeply disturbing and totally unacceptable.  And I think it speaks to a larger issue, which is this:  The Taliban has repeatedly said that they seek in the future a number of things – international recognition, international support; they want their leaders to be able to travel freely around the world; they would like sanctions lifted on them.  And none of those things are going to be possible if the Taliban seeks to take the country by force and commits the kind of atrocities that have been reported.  An Afghanistan, as I’ve said before, that does not respect the basic rights of its people, that does not have a representative and inclusive government, that does not abide by the main gains of the last 20 years is an Afghanistan that will be a pariah state, certainly for the United States, and I believe for the international community.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>If I may follow up on my colleague here from Afghanistan, how do these people under the P-1 program even get to third countries?  You’re asking that Turkey and other neighboring countries – Iran – open their borders.  How can they get from here to there past Taliban checkpoints?  They’ve got targets on their backs.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And if I might follow up also on the Mercer fleet, how do you interpret this action that you are attributing to Iran?  If this is correct, do you view this as an indication of the new government’s policy?  What action is going to be taken either by us, by Israel, or in some way a combination?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, Andrea.  So with regard first to Afghans who seek to leave the country and seek to avail themselves of the refugee programs, et cetera, you’re right:  This is incredibly hard.  It is hard on so many levels.  It’s hard to pick up and leave everything you know, potentially family, friends, community, culture, language.  It’s – and it’s hard to get yourself to a place where you can take advantage of what opportunities exist to seek to apply for refugee status.  And we recognize that.  This is, alas, the case for millions of people around the world who find themselves in very difficult situations, and particularly in Afghanistan now, especially a group of people who may have worked for us, worked for NGOs, media organizations, women and girls, and others who feel an acute sense of threat and fear with – for the future.</p>
<p>And so, as we see again and again, people have to do very difficult things to make sure that they can find safety and security, and we will do everything we can to help them, including making these different avenues of arrival to the United States for this group of people possible.  We are also dedicating very significant assistance, humanitarian assistance, not only in Afghanistan itself, but to neighboring countries to enable them to support those who come to their countries, again, seeking potentially, refugee status somewhere or immigrant status somewhere.</p>
<p>So that support, I think, makes it a little bit easier.  But I don&#8217;t want to deny the challenge and the difficulty.  It is indeed a hard thing.  Our obligation, I believe, is in the first instance to make sure that we are making good on our commitments to those who, in particular, put themselves on the line, put their families on the line to help us, whether it was, again, working directly for the United States Government, for our embassy, for our military, for the international security force, or whether it was working for NGOs, media organizations, and others.</p>
<p>And, of course, as we just discussed, some Afghans who are not – don’t fit into any of those categories but may feel particularly at risk, we also have the principal refugee program available for them.</p>
<p>With regard to Iran, so we have seen a series of actions taken by Iran over many months, including against shipping.  So I’m not sure that this particular action is anything new or augers anything one way or another for the new government.  But what it does say is that Iran continues to act with tremendous irresponsibility when it comes to, in this instance, threats to navigation, to commerce, to innocent sailors who are simply engaged in commercial transit in international waters.  And as I noted, we are in very close contact and coordination with the United Kingdom, Israel, Romania, and other countries, and there will be a collective response.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Senior State Department Officials On the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program Priority 2 (P-2) Designation for Afghan Nationals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-senior-state-department-officials-on-the-u-s-refugee-admissions-program-priority-2-p-2-designation-for-afghan-nationals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 16:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today for this call to discuss the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program Priority 2 Designation for Afghan Nationals.</p>
<p>This call, as you know, is on background. For reporting purposes, our briefers should be referred to as senior State Department officials.</p>
<p>Just for your knowledge, and again, not for reporting, our briefing today will begin with remarks from , , and  will also be on the line to take your questions after ’s opening remarks.</p>
<p>All contents of this call are embargoed until the conclusion. As you’ll hear from the operator, you can enter the question queue at any time by dialing 1 and then 0.</p>
<p>And with that, I will turn it over to our first speaker. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks so much, , and thank you all very much for joining us this morning. I’ll start with just some brief opening remarks and then we all look forward to taking your questions.</p>
<p>So today, the State Department is announcing a Priority 2, or as we call it, a P-2 designation granting U.S. Refugee Admissions Program access to certain Afghan nationals and their eligible family members.</p>
<p>The U.S. objective remains a peaceful and secure Afghanistan. As part of the President’s efforts to assist Afghans who have supported the U.S. Government’s efforts in Afghanistan, we are working to provide certain Afghans, including those who worked with and for the United States, the opportunity for refugee resettlement in the United States. Cases referred to this program will be processed in third countries, once the applicants are outside of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Those eligible for referral include:</p>
<p>One: U.S. Government, including U.S. Forces Afghanistan employees and contractors, including interpreters and translators, who do not have the minimum time in service to qualify for a Special Immigrant Visa or SIV.</p>
<p>Second: International Security Assistance Force employees, including interpreters and translators, who do not have the minimum time in service for an SIV.</p>
<p>Resolute Support employees and contractors, including interpreters and translators, who do not have the minimum time in service for an SIV.</p>
<p>Four: Afghans who work or worked for a U.S. Government-funded program or project in Afghanistan supported through a U.S. Government grant or cooperative agreement.</p>
<p>And lastly, Afghans who are or were employed in Afghanistan by a U.S.-based nongovernmental or media organization that does not require U.S. Government funding.</p>
<p>Many thousands of Afghans and their immediate family members are at risk due to these U.S. affiliations and are not eligible for a Special Immigrant Visa because either they did not have qualifying employment, or they have not met the time-in-service requirement to become eligible; however, they may be eligible for a P-2 referral, and thus, to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</p>
<p>As noted, this P-2 designation also expands eligibility to Afghans who are or were employed in Afghanistan by a U.S.-based media organization or nongovernmental organization. Referral information for how these U.S.-based media organizations or NGOs can be found at WRAPSNET.org. That’s wraps with a W, W-R-A-P-S, dot O-R-G.</p>
<p>Once we begin processing these cases, we will work with our resettlement partners in the United States to welcome these Afghan refugees to their new communities. Refugee resettlement would not be possible without the support of state and local governments, our resettlement partners and affiliates, nongovernmental organizations, faith-based organizations, advocacy groups, and the tens of thousands of volunteers across the United States who participate in this program.</p>
<p>Similar to the Afghans who are eligible for or have received a Special Immigrant Visa, the P-2 designation expands the United States commitment to honor those who served alongside our military and diplomats on the ground. Their support was essential to our operations. Our continued support for and humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan includes offering this unique form of protection to those who are particularly vulnerable as a result of their affiliation with the United States, and maintains our promise to show our gratitude for their extraordinary service.</p>
<p>I thank you, and we now look forward to your questions. Over.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Ladies and gentlemen, as a reminder, if you would like to ask a question, press 1, then 0 on your touchtone phone. You will hear an indication you’ve been placed into the queue and you may remove yourself from the queue by repeating the 1 then 0 command. We ask that you please pick up your handset and make sure that your phone is unmuted when you – before you press any buttons. Again, for questions, press 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll start with the line of Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you for doing this. I was wondering if you could give us a timeline of how quickly you anticipate processing all of these referrals. Will it be done before the end of the month when the military withdrawal is complete? Do you have an estimate of how many people might be eligible for these referrals? And was there a particular impetus for announcing this now rather than when you announced Operations Allies Refuge? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks so much, Jennifer. Let me see if I can remember all of them. So the first is the time horizon for how quickly we can process. So the first step in this process is really referrals and we would hope that that can start immediately.</p>
<p>The next thing that’s going to determine the time horizon is how quickly people – or how – when they make the decision to actually leave Afghanistan. We have to wait until they are outside of the country in order to begin processing. From that point on, it is a regular refugee resettlement program, and it is a somewhat lengthy process because there is a lot of security screening that goes on as part of the refugee program in itself. That can take anywhere from 12 to 14 months. So that’s the time horizon.</p>
<p>The question on – I’m trying to remember the other two. One was the timing of this announcement. Nothing special in it, just that this takes quite a lot of time to set up, and our first priority had been to really focus on getting the Afghan Special Immigrant Visa processing and relocation started because these are people that are particularly affiliated with us, and so that relocation effort really took a lot of time. But concurrently we were setting this one up, so no special timing.</p>
<p>And I think you may have had a third question that I forgot, and I apologize.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> It might have been the number of people potentially eligible for this.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Thanks so much for the clarification. We don’t have an estimate yet. We’ll have to wait and see how many referrals we get for the program. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll go to the line of Missy Ryan, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you. I just want to clarify something that I didn’t quite catch. So did you say that the people need to apply for this outside of Afghanistan, and are these people going to be relocated like the SIV individuals are? And it would be helpful for me if you would be able to just maybe walk through what the steps would be for any particular former employee – how and where do they apply, and then what the steps are, and then when they can actually come to the United States. Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks very much. So to your first question, just to clarify, people are not going to be applying once they get outside the country. What’s going to happen – the process is that individuals can be referred by their employer – not directly, but through their employer – to us through that website that I gave you. Once that happens, they are in our system and we will contact the individual via email to let them know they are now in the system and – for us.</p>
<p>Once they get themselves out of Afghanistan, they alert us that they are now outside of the country, tell us where they are, and then we can begin the processing of their caseload to be presented to the Department of Homeland Security for adjudication. So that is the process of how it works.</p>
<p>I’m going to turn it over to  now, , to talk a little bit in more detail about how the former employees can access the program.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL TWO:</b> I think – hi, this is . So as – I think as  said, that the organization itself would need to make the referral, so that would be true of a former or a current employee. Again, this is a requirement we’ve put in place so that we can really verify the employment up front and kind of avoid, I think, some of the issues in terms of trying to determine whether or not there was verifiable and – employment through an organization. So again, you should have lists or other NGOs or media organizations should have lists of their former employees and they would be welcome to submit that through the WRAPSNET.org site.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> And it’s  again. I realized there was one other question about relocation. As I said, Afghans really – they need to be outside of Afghanistan for us to begin the processing. At this time, we do not anticipate relocating P-2 applicants prior to or during the application process. However, we continue to review the situation on the ground, and we continue to examine all options to protect those who served with or for us. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Thanks very much. We’ll go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi. Thanks very much. So just two questions. To be clear on that last point, it is the responsibility of the potential applicants themselves to get out of Afghanistan?</p>
<p>And then second, could you give us sort of a bigger, 3,000-foot view of what this says about the U.S. project in Afghanistan, that after 20 years anyone who has an affiliation or previous affiliation with a U.S. entity is under so much threat that they would likely have to seek refugee status in the United States to remain safe from the Taliban? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thank you. So, first, just to confirm, yes, it is the responsibility of the applicant to get themselves out of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>On your last question, I would just note what the President said on July 30, that although U.S. troops are leaving, we will continue to support Afghanistan through our security assistance to Afghan forces, as well as humanitarian and development assistance to the Afghan people. Obviously, I’m from the Bureau for Population, Refugees, and Migration, so my focus is on that – the humanitarian piece, and I would just like to add that the U.S. is the largest single donor of humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan. And just as recently as June 4, we announced an additional $266 million in new humanitarian assistance to help Afghans both inside the country and those who have left. Our total for humanitarian assistance now reaches nearly $3.9 billion since 2002. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I’m driving right now, so I’m not sure if you can hear me. Can &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ve got you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> We can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Yeah, okay. So, look, one of my questions was kind of already answered, and that is you really have no idea what the universe of – it says “many thousands” in the fact sheet, but are we talking hundreds of thousands, tens of thousands? You must have some idea.</p>
<p>And then just secondly, I mean, on the surface of this, this sounds – this is wonderful. It sounds like it’s a great idea. It meets or it would appear to meet concerns that have been expressed by members of Congress and others about people with U.S. affiliations. But if they have to get out of Afghanistan on their own to apply or – not to be referred but to actually start the process, that doesn’t – that seems problematic to me, and I’m not sure how you expect people who might not be able to afford the – are there any countries that they might get to where they couldn’t do this, like Iran, for example? I just am not sure what exactly – it looks good on paper, but realistically, I don’t see how this is going to be a significant thing. If they have to pay for getting out and then do they – can only one person in a family leave the country to apply for an entire family or do they have to get an entire family of five or six out and then pay – not just pay for them to get out but pay for them to live for 12 to 14 months, I think is what you said, somewhere else? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks very much, Matt. So on the universe of people, we really don’t want to project because we don’t know how many referrals. So we did say many thousands because we think it’ll be in the tens of thousands, but we don’t know how much more than that. So we are – because it is a very individual case, right, of individuals making a tough decision to leave their homeland and become a refugee. And so we will wait and see what the referrals bring us now that we’ve announced this program.</p>
<p>I take your point about the difficulty of people getting out and having to get out on their own. This is – this program is meant to expand the aperture of people who have an opportunity to be resettled in the United States beyond the SIVs. So it is our attempt to try and offer an option for people. At this – as I said earlier, at this point in time, unfortunately, we do not anticipate relocating them, but we will continue to examine all the options to protect those who have served with – or for us. And we will review the situation on the ground and our planning will continue to evolve. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll go to the line of Francesco Fontemaggi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi. Yeah, I was about to ask about that since it seems to me that the process you described – those people having to be referred and then having to leave the country by their own means – means that they won’t be out of Afghanistan, for most of them, when the U.S. forces leave in one month. So if you can give more details about what you plan to do to protect them while in Afghanistan. And then, also, if you plan to expand this program to others like – who are not U.S.-affiliated, like minorities, the Azaras or women activists or others who may be threatened by the Taliban? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks very much for the question. So maybe I’ll start with the last one first, in terms of those Afghans who are not U.S.-affiliated in any way or worked for any U.S.-based organizations. There is an existing program as part of the U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program that is known as our Priority 1, or P-1, program that is specifically designed for people such as those you have described. There are two ways in which somebody can access the U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program through its – the P-1 referral. One is if they are well-known to our embassy; our embassy can refer them directly. The other option is for anyone who is fleeing the country and outside the country. They can present themselves to UNHCR, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, for referral to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program. So there are options for other Afghans at risk through the P-1 referral process.</p>
<p>I think I neglected to answer a question about family members. I will say the whole family doesn’t have to leave all at once, but they – the family needs to be outside the country for us to process them. That is correct. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll take a final question or two here. We will go to the line of Joel Gehrke.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you for doing this.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you for doing this. I just wanted to follow up on my colleagues’ questions about these people getting themselves out of the country and that process. I’m wondering: Afghanistan’s passport is one of the weakest passports in the world. Are you doing anything to coordinate with allies or partner countries so that – is there anything about being in this program that would lead those other countries to treat these people who show up without a visa as being eligible for refugee status? In that very limited number of countries where they do have visa-free travel, are you doing anything to coordinate with those countries? Because we can probably anticipate that they’ll be getting a lot of people suddenly. And do you anticipate that what might be analogous – I guess we could call it uncontrolled migration – would put any pressure on your ability to get countries to accept this parallel group of people who you’re trying to evacuate for the SIV program?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks, Joel. That’s a really great question. And there’s a lot to unpack there. So let me start, but then I’m going to turn to my colleagues  and  to add on. So as we have – as we see in – generally around the world with refugee crises, there is a possibility that large movements of people will seek to find safety by fleeing and crossing borders. This is not unique to Afghanistan; we’ve seen it many times over. There is a process in place by which people who are fleeing and flee with limited documentation have the ability to present what they have, and us, through our case work as well as U.S. Department of Homeland Security interviews, to address those issues. But I’m going turn to  and  to see what more they want to add about this issue of people crossing borders. Over.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL THREE: </b>This is . I’ll just add that in a typical refugee outflow, when refugees arrive at the border they would present themselves also to UNHCR, which is our primary partner on the ground. And they would be providing the international protection in addition to whatever protection might be provided by the government in which the refugee is seeking asylum.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL TWO: </b>Yeah, and this is . I’ll just add one other thing, and that is that we’ve already been in discussions with neighboring countries as well as UNHCR to be prepared for potential outflows. So in a place like Pakistan, it’ll be important that their borders remain open. Obviously, if people go north or if they go via Iran to Turkey – we&#8217;ve already seen some arrivals in Turkey – that people have an opportunity both to enter the country as well as to register with either the government or with UNHCR.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>We will go to Courtney Kube.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b>Your line is open. Go ahead, please. I’m sorry, I opened the wrong line. One moment, please. Courtney, your line is open. Go ahead, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you very much. Two quick clarifications. So just to be clear, the 12 to 14 months, that is from the time someone is referred until potentially accepted? Is that correct? Number two, you mentioned – sorry I’m out of breath, I’m running – you mentioned that these – these other countries that they could go to. Are there any countries where you’ll provide them any housing or any kind of support? And three, you just mentioned that you’ve already seen an influx into Turkey. Can you give us any sense of how many people have gone to Turkey who may be eligible or applying for this new visa? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Thanks, Courtney. So first question on the time horizon, no, it’s not 12 to 14 months from the time they’re referred. The clock really doesn’t start ticking until somebody has left Afghanistan and we can begin their case processing. So the time horizon is really dependent on when they get out and when we can start the processing of their case.</p>
<p>In terms of assistance in other countries, as in any other refugee situation where people are fleeing the country and showing up in other countries, as I believe my colleague  mentioned, there is an international response for that that is organized through the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, where people can present themselves either to the government or to UNHCR to seek international protection while they wait for our program. And as part of that protection that is offered it oftentimes includes humanitarian assistance, and so that would be the mechanism by which we would look to have us and other donors support people who are fleeing.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t have numbers on Turkey. I would say we haven’t seen major large outflows of people yet, but we have seen some numbers of people crossing, but not large numbers yet.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>And we’ll take a final question from Quill Lawrence.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b>Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you so much for this. I have one question about – so you’re saying that their employee – their employer, rather, the NGO or the contractor or media organization, is going to refer them through this website. And then what sort of certification, what piece of paper or digital form will they have that tells them, okay, it’s now a sensible thing for me to flee to a third country where I will have a decent chance of getting this status? And will any of that be – will the third countries where the SIVs are being processed, is there any idea that they – that some of this processing might also take place in those countries, although they’re not bordering?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Thanks so much, Quill. So on the first question regarding paperwork and documentation, so there is a form that the employing organization needs to fill out and submit. It’s pretty – it just provides some basic bio data for us. And that information is on the website. Once that is received and we confirm that we have all the necessary information we need to open the case, one of the pieces of information we need is a point of contact for the principal applicant himself or herself, an email address by which we can reach them. We will then reach out via email to say that their case has now been referred to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program and to let them know how to reach us once they have gotten out of the country so that we can start their casework. So they will basically have an email from us saying that we’re ready to receive them whenever they move.</p>
<p>In terms of your question about, I think it was third – I’m looking – third countries – sorry, I’m drawing a blank. Can – , can somebody remind me what the second question is?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Yes. Will you help processing within the third countries?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Oh, thank you. Yes, yes. So right now, the plan for processing through – in the third countries for SIV is a separate program than the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program. So right now, the anticipation is that we won’t be relocating them to third countries to process, we will process them where they get themselves to and go from there. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Well, thank you very much to our speakers. Thank you very much for all of you for dialing in, and the embargo is now lifted. Have a good day.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today for this call to discuss the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program Priority 2 Designation for Afghan Nationals.</p>
<p>This call, as you know, is on background. For reporting purposes, our briefers should be referred to as senior State Department officials.</p>
<p>Just for your knowledge, and again, not for reporting, our briefing today will begin with remarks from , , and  will also be on the line to take your questions after ’s opening remarks.</p>
<p>All contents of this call are embargoed until the conclusion. As you’ll hear from the operator, you can enter the question queue at any time by dialing 1 and then 0.</p>
<p>And with that, I will turn it over to our first speaker. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks so much, , and thank you all very much for joining us this morning. I’ll start with just some brief opening remarks and then we all look forward to taking your questions.</p>
<p>So today, the State Department is announcing a Priority 2, or as we call it, a P-2 designation granting U.S. Refugee Admissions Program access to certain Afghan nationals and their eligible family members.</p>
<p>The U.S. objective remains a peaceful and secure Afghanistan. As part of the President’s efforts to assist Afghans who have supported the U.S. Government’s efforts in Afghanistan, we are working to provide certain Afghans, including those who worked with and for the United States, the opportunity for refugee resettlement in the United States. Cases referred to this program will be processed in third countries, once the applicants are outside of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Those eligible for referral include:</p>
<p>One: U.S. Government, including U.S. Forces Afghanistan employees and contractors, including interpreters and translators, who do not have the minimum time in service to qualify for a Special Immigrant Visa or SIV.</p>
<p>Second: International Security Assistance Force employees, including interpreters and translators, who do not have the minimum time in service for an SIV.</p>
<p>Resolute Support employees and contractors, including interpreters and translators, who do not have the minimum time in service for an SIV.</p>
<p>Four: Afghans who work or worked for a U.S. Government-funded program or project in Afghanistan supported through a U.S. Government grant or cooperative agreement.</p>
<p>And lastly, Afghans who are or were employed in Afghanistan by a U.S.-based nongovernmental or media organization that does not require U.S. Government funding.</p>
<p>Many thousands of Afghans and their immediate family members are at risk due to these U.S. affiliations and are not eligible for a Special Immigrant Visa because either they did not have qualifying employment, or they have not met the time-in-service requirement to become eligible; however, they may be eligible for a P-2 referral, and thus, to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</p>
<p>As noted, this P-2 designation also expands eligibility to Afghans who are or were employed in Afghanistan by a U.S.-based media organization or nongovernmental organization. Referral information for how these U.S.-based media organizations or NGOs can be found at WRAPSNET.org. That’s wraps with a W, W-R-A-P-S, dot O-R-G.</p>
<p>Once we begin processing these cases, we will work with our resettlement partners in the United States to welcome these Afghan refugees to their new communities. Refugee resettlement would not be possible without the support of state and local governments, our resettlement partners and affiliates, nongovernmental organizations, faith-based organizations, advocacy groups, and the tens of thousands of volunteers across the United States who participate in this program.</p>
<p>Similar to the Afghans who are eligible for or have received a Special Immigrant Visa, the P-2 designation expands the United States commitment to honor those who served alongside our military and diplomats on the ground. Their support was essential to our operations. Our continued support for and humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan includes offering this unique form of protection to those who are particularly vulnerable as a result of their affiliation with the United States, and maintains our promise to show our gratitude for their extraordinary service.</p>
<p>I thank you, and we now look forward to your questions. Over.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Ladies and gentlemen, as a reminder, if you would like to ask a question, press 1, then 0 on your touchtone phone. You will hear an indication you’ve been placed into the queue and you may remove yourself from the queue by repeating the 1 then 0 command. We ask that you please pick up your handset and make sure that your phone is unmuted when you – before you press any buttons. Again, for questions, press 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll start with the line of Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you for doing this. I was wondering if you could give us a timeline of how quickly you anticipate processing all of these referrals. Will it be done before the end of the month when the military withdrawal is complete? Do you have an estimate of how many people might be eligible for these referrals? And was there a particular impetus for announcing this now rather than when you announced Operations Allies Refuge? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks so much, Jennifer. Let me see if I can remember all of them. So the first is the time horizon for how quickly we can process. So the first step in this process is really referrals and we would hope that that can start immediately.</p>
<p>The next thing that’s going to determine the time horizon is how quickly people – or how – when they make the decision to actually leave Afghanistan. We have to wait until they are outside of the country in order to begin processing. From that point on, it is a regular refugee resettlement program, and it is a somewhat lengthy process because there is a lot of security screening that goes on as part of the refugee program in itself. That can take anywhere from 12 to 14 months. So that’s the time horizon.</p>
<p>The question on – I’m trying to remember the other two. One was the timing of this announcement. Nothing special in it, just that this takes quite a lot of time to set up, and our first priority had been to really focus on getting the Afghan Special Immigrant Visa processing and relocation started because these are people that are particularly affiliated with us, and so that relocation effort really took a lot of time. But concurrently we were setting this one up, so no special timing.</p>
<p>And I think you may have had a third question that I forgot, and I apologize.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> It might have been the number of people potentially eligible for this.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Thanks so much for the clarification. We don’t have an estimate yet. We’ll have to wait and see how many referrals we get for the program. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll go to the line of Missy Ryan, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you. I just want to clarify something that I didn’t quite catch. So did you say that the people need to apply for this outside of Afghanistan, and are these people going to be relocated like the SIV individuals are? And it would be helpful for me if you would be able to just maybe walk through what the steps would be for any particular former employee – how and where do they apply, and then what the steps are, and then when they can actually come to the United States. Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks very much. So to your first question, just to clarify, people are not going to be applying once they get outside the country. What’s going to happen – the process is that individuals can be referred by their employer – not directly, but through their employer – to us through that website that I gave you. Once that happens, they are in our system and we will contact the individual via email to let them know they are now in the system and – for us.</p>
<p>Once they get themselves out of Afghanistan, they alert us that they are now outside of the country, tell us where they are, and then we can begin the processing of their caseload to be presented to the Department of Homeland Security for adjudication. So that is the process of how it works.</p>
<p>I’m going to turn it over to  now, , to talk a little bit in more detail about how the former employees can access the program.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL TWO:</b> I think – hi, this is . So as – I think as  said, that the organization itself would need to make the referral, so that would be true of a former or a current employee. Again, this is a requirement we’ve put in place so that we can really verify the employment up front and kind of avoid, I think, some of the issues in terms of trying to determine whether or not there was verifiable and – employment through an organization. So again, you should have lists or other NGOs or media organizations should have lists of their former employees and they would be welcome to submit that through the WRAPSNET.org site.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> And it’s  again. I realized there was one other question about relocation. As I said, Afghans really – they need to be outside of Afghanistan for us to begin the processing. At this time, we do not anticipate relocating P-2 applicants prior to or during the application process. However, we continue to review the situation on the ground, and we continue to examine all options to protect those who served with or for us. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Thanks very much. We’ll go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi. Thanks very much. So just two questions. To be clear on that last point, it is the responsibility of the potential applicants themselves to get out of Afghanistan?</p>
<p>And then second, could you give us sort of a bigger, 3,000-foot view of what this says about the U.S. project in Afghanistan, that after 20 years anyone who has an affiliation or previous affiliation with a U.S. entity is under so much threat that they would likely have to seek refugee status in the United States to remain safe from the Taliban? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thank you. So, first, just to confirm, yes, it is the responsibility of the applicant to get themselves out of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>On your last question, I would just note what the President said on July 30, that although U.S. troops are leaving, we will continue to support Afghanistan through our security assistance to Afghan forces, as well as humanitarian and development assistance to the Afghan people. Obviously, I’m from the Bureau for Population, Refugees, and Migration, so my focus is on that – the humanitarian piece, and I would just like to add that the U.S. is the largest single donor of humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan. And just as recently as June 4, we announced an additional $266 million in new humanitarian assistance to help Afghans both inside the country and those who have left. Our total for humanitarian assistance now reaches nearly $3.9 billion since 2002. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I’m driving right now, so I’m not sure if you can hear me. Can &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ve got you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> We can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Yeah, okay. So, look, one of my questions was kind of already answered, and that is you really have no idea what the universe of – it says “many thousands” in the fact sheet, but are we talking hundreds of thousands, tens of thousands? You must have some idea.</p>
<p>And then just secondly, I mean, on the surface of this, this sounds – this is wonderful. It sounds like it’s a great idea. It meets or it would appear to meet concerns that have been expressed by members of Congress and others about people with U.S. affiliations. But if they have to get out of Afghanistan on their own to apply or – not to be referred but to actually start the process, that doesn’t – that seems problematic to me, and I’m not sure how you expect people who might not be able to afford the – are there any countries that they might get to where they couldn’t do this, like Iran, for example? I just am not sure what exactly – it looks good on paper, but realistically, I don’t see how this is going to be a significant thing. If they have to pay for getting out and then do they – can only one person in a family leave the country to apply for an entire family or do they have to get an entire family of five or six out and then pay – not just pay for them to get out but pay for them to live for 12 to 14 months, I think is what you said, somewhere else? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks very much, Matt. So on the universe of people, we really don’t want to project because we don’t know how many referrals. So we did say many thousands because we think it’ll be in the tens of thousands, but we don’t know how much more than that. So we are – because it is a very individual case, right, of individuals making a tough decision to leave their homeland and become a refugee. And so we will wait and see what the referrals bring us now that we’ve announced this program.</p>
<p>I take your point about the difficulty of people getting out and having to get out on their own. This is – this program is meant to expand the aperture of people who have an opportunity to be resettled in the United States beyond the SIVs. So it is our attempt to try and offer an option for people. At this – as I said earlier, at this point in time, unfortunately, we do not anticipate relocating them, but we will continue to examine all the options to protect those who have served with – or for us. And we will review the situation on the ground and our planning will continue to evolve. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll go to the line of Francesco Fontemaggi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi. Yeah, I was about to ask about that since it seems to me that the process you described – those people having to be referred and then having to leave the country by their own means – means that they won’t be out of Afghanistan, for most of them, when the U.S. forces leave in one month. So if you can give more details about what you plan to do to protect them while in Afghanistan. And then, also, if you plan to expand this program to others like – who are not U.S.-affiliated, like minorities, the Azaras or women activists or others who may be threatened by the Taliban? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks very much for the question. So maybe I’ll start with the last one first, in terms of those Afghans who are not U.S.-affiliated in any way or worked for any U.S.-based organizations. There is an existing program as part of the U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program that is known as our Priority 1, or P-1, program that is specifically designed for people such as those you have described. There are two ways in which somebody can access the U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program through its – the P-1 referral. One is if they are well-known to our embassy; our embassy can refer them directly. The other option is for anyone who is fleeing the country and outside the country. They can present themselves to UNHCR, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, for referral to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program. So there are options for other Afghans at risk through the P-1 referral process.</p>
<p>I think I neglected to answer a question about family members. I will say the whole family doesn’t have to leave all at once, but they – the family needs to be outside the country for us to process them. That is correct. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> We’ll take a final question or two here. We will go to the line of Joel Gehrke.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you for doing this.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, thank you for doing this. I just wanted to follow up on my colleagues’ questions about these people getting themselves out of the country and that process. I’m wondering: Afghanistan’s passport is one of the weakest passports in the world. Are you doing anything to coordinate with allies or partner countries so that – is there anything about being in this program that would lead those other countries to treat these people who show up without a visa as being eligible for refugee status? In that very limited number of countries where they do have visa-free travel, are you doing anything to coordinate with those countries? Because we can probably anticipate that they’ll be getting a lot of people suddenly. And do you anticipate that what might be analogous – I guess we could call it uncontrolled migration – would put any pressure on your ability to get countries to accept this parallel group of people who you’re trying to evacuate for the SIV program?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE:</b> Thanks, Joel. That’s a really great question. And there’s a lot to unpack there. So let me start, but then I’m going to turn to my colleagues  and  to add on. So as we have – as we see in – generally around the world with refugee crises, there is a possibility that large movements of people will seek to find safety by fleeing and crossing borders. This is not unique to Afghanistan; we’ve seen it many times over. There is a process in place by which people who are fleeing and flee with limited documentation have the ability to present what they have, and us, through our case work as well as U.S. Department of Homeland Security interviews, to address those issues. But I’m going turn to  and  to see what more they want to add about this issue of people crossing borders. Over.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL THREE: </b>This is . I’ll just add that in a typical refugee outflow, when refugees arrive at the border they would present themselves also to UNHCR, which is our primary partner on the ground. And they would be providing the international protection in addition to whatever protection might be provided by the government in which the refugee is seeking asylum.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL TWO: </b>Yeah, and this is . I’ll just add one other thing, and that is that we’ve already been in discussions with neighboring countries as well as UNHCR to be prepared for potential outflows. So in a place like Pakistan, it’ll be important that their borders remain open. Obviously, if people go north or if they go via Iran to Turkey – we&#8217;ve already seen some arrivals in Turkey – that people have an opportunity both to enter the country as well as to register with either the government or with UNHCR.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>We will go to Courtney Kube.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b>Your line is open. Go ahead, please. I’m sorry, I opened the wrong line. One moment, please. Courtney, your line is open. Go ahead, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you very much. Two quick clarifications. So just to be clear, the 12 to 14 months, that is from the time someone is referred until potentially accepted? Is that correct? Number two, you mentioned – sorry I’m out of breath, I’m running – you mentioned that these – these other countries that they could go to. Are there any countries where you’ll provide them any housing or any kind of support? And three, you just mentioned that you’ve already seen an influx into Turkey. Can you give us any sense of how many people have gone to Turkey who may be eligible or applying for this new visa? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Thanks, Courtney. So first question on the time horizon, no, it’s not 12 to 14 months from the time they’re referred. The clock really doesn’t start ticking until somebody has left Afghanistan and we can begin their case processing. So the time horizon is really dependent on when they get out and when we can start the processing of their case.</p>
<p>In terms of assistance in other countries, as in any other refugee situation where people are fleeing the country and showing up in other countries, as I believe my colleague  mentioned, there is an international response for that that is organized through the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, where people can present themselves either to the government or to UNHCR to seek international protection while they wait for our program. And as part of that protection that is offered it oftentimes includes humanitarian assistance, and so that would be the mechanism by which we would look to have us and other donors support people who are fleeing.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t have numbers on Turkey. I would say we haven’t seen major large outflows of people yet, but we have seen some numbers of people crossing, but not large numbers yet.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>And we’ll take a final question from Quill Lawrence.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b>Your line is open. Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you so much for this. I have one question about – so you’re saying that their employee – their employer, rather, the NGO or the contractor or media organization, is going to refer them through this website. And then what sort of certification, what piece of paper or digital form will they have that tells them, okay, it’s now a sensible thing for me to flee to a third country where I will have a decent chance of getting this status? And will any of that be – will the third countries where the SIVs are being processed, is there any idea that they – that some of this processing might also take place in those countries, although they’re not bordering?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Thanks so much, Quill. So on the first question regarding paperwork and documentation, so there is a form that the employing organization needs to fill out and submit. It’s pretty – it just provides some basic bio data for us. And that information is on the website. Once that is received and we confirm that we have all the necessary information we need to open the case, one of the pieces of information we need is a point of contact for the principal applicant himself or herself, an email address by which we can reach them. We will then reach out via email to say that their case has now been referred to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program and to let them know how to reach us once they have gotten out of the country so that we can start their casework. So they will basically have an email from us saying that we’re ready to receive them whenever they move.</p>
<p>In terms of your question about, I think it was third – I’m looking – third countries – sorry, I’m drawing a blank. Can – , can somebody remind me what the second question is?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Yes. Will you help processing within the third countries?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL ONE: </b>Oh, thank you. Yes, yes. So right now, the plan for processing through – in the third countries for SIV is a separate program than the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program. So right now, the anticipation is that we won’t be relocating them to third countries to process, we will process them where they get themselves to and go from there. Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Well, thank you very much to our speakers. Thank you very much for all of you for dialing in, and the embargo is now lifted. Have a good day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virtual Summit of the Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/virtual-summit-of-the-mandela-washington-fellowship-for-young-african-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 14:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The U.S. Department of State will host the virtual </span><span class="s2">Mandela Washington Fellowship Summit</span><span class="s1"> on August 3-4.  The Summit brings together 700 of Sub-Saharan Africa’s most promising young leaders to expand their capacity and network with each other and U.S. government, private sector, and civil society representatives.  </span><span class="s2">The event is an opportunity for Fellows to build the foundations of long-term partnerships with U.S. professionals and each other and explore ways to continue their leadership journey after the Fellowship.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Summit will feature a welcome message from Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, remarks from U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield, a Partnership Expo where U.S. organizations will highlight their engagement with Africa, and TED Talk-style Ignite Talks presented by Fellows.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Summit follows six weeks of virtual academic study and leadership development for the 700 Fellows hosted by 26 U.S. higher education institutions as part of the <a href="https://www.mandelawashingtonfellowship.org/"><span class="s3">Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders</span></a>.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Alumni of the Fellowship are playing a role in enhancing peace and security, spurring economic growth, and strengthening democratic institutions in the United States and countries across Sub-Saharan Africa.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Interested media can complete <a href="https://www.surveygizmo.com/s3/6428782/Mandela-Washington-Fellowship-Summit-Press-RSVP"><span class="s3">this online form</span></a> to request access to open-press events.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s4">The Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders is the flagship program of the <a href="https://yali.state.gov/"><span class="s5">Young African Leaders Initiative</span></a> (YALI).  </span><span class="s1">YALI is the U.S. government&#8217;s signature effort to invest in young African leaders, and it offers four continent-based Regional Leadership Centers and an online YALI Network with more than 700,000 members.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">The Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders is a program of the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs and is administered by IREX.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For more information about the Mandela Washington Fellowship, visit <a href="https://www.mandelawashingtonfellowship.org/"><span class="s6">www.mandelawashingtonfellowship.org</span></a>. For questions please contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov"><span class="s6">ECA-Press@state.gov</span></a>.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The U.S. Department of State will host the virtual </span><span class="s2">Mandela Washington Fellowship Summit</span><span class="s1"> on August 3-4.  The Summit brings together 700 of Sub-Saharan Africa’s most promising young leaders to expand their capacity and network with each other and U.S. government, private sector, and civil society representatives.  </span><span class="s2">The event is an opportunity for Fellows to build the foundations of long-term partnerships with U.S. professionals and each other and explore ways to continue their leadership journey after the Fellowship.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Summit will feature a welcome message from Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, remarks from U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield, a Partnership Expo where U.S. organizations will highlight their engagement with Africa, and TED Talk-style Ignite Talks presented by Fellows.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Summit follows six weeks of virtual academic study and leadership development for the 700 Fellows hosted by 26 U.S. higher education institutions as part of the <a href="https://www.mandelawashingtonfellowship.org/"><span class="s3">Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders</span></a>.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Alumni of the Fellowship are playing a role in enhancing peace and security, spurring economic growth, and strengthening democratic institutions in the United States and countries across Sub-Saharan Africa.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Interested media can complete <a href="https://www.surveygizmo.com/s3/6428782/Mandela-Washington-Fellowship-Summit-Press-RSVP"><span class="s3">this online form</span></a> to request access to open-press events.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s4">The Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders is the flagship program of the <a href="https://yali.state.gov/"><span class="s5">Young African Leaders Initiative</span></a> (YALI).  </span><span class="s1">YALI is the U.S. government&#8217;s signature effort to invest in young African leaders, and it offers four continent-based Regional Leadership Centers and an online YALI Network with more than 700,000 members.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">The Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders is a program of the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs and is administered by IREX.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For more information about the Mandela Washington Fellowship, visit <a href="https://www.mandelawashingtonfellowship.org/"><span class="s6">www.mandelawashingtonfellowship.org</span></a>. For questions please contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov"><span class="s6">ECA-Press@state.gov</span></a>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Refugee Admissions Program Priority 2 Designation for Afghan Nationals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-refugee-admissions-program-priority-2-designation-for-afghan-nationals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 10:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the Department of State is announcing a Priority 2 (P-2) designation granting U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) access for certain Afghan nationals and their eligible family members.</p>
<p>The U.S. objective remains a peaceful, secure Afghanistan. However, in light of increased levels of Taliban violence, the U.S. government is working to provide certain Afghans, including those who worked with the United States, the opportunity for refugee resettlement to the United States. This designation expands the opportunity to permanently resettle in the United States to many thousands of Afghans and their immediate family members who may be at risk due to their U.S. affiliation but who are not eligible for a Special Immigrant Visa (SIV) because they did not have qualifying employment, or because they have not met the time-in-service requirement to become eligible. Access to the USRAP is a critical mechanism to provide protection for these individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Individuals Eligible for the P-2 Program:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Afghans who do not meet the minimum time-in-service for a SIV but who work or worked as employees of contractors,  locally-employed staff, interpreters/translators for the U.S. Government, United States Forces Afghanistan (USFOR-A), International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), or Resolute Support;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Afghans who work or worked for a U.S. government-funded program or project in Afghanistan supported through a U.S. government grant or cooperative agreement<sup>1</sup>;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Afghans who are or were employed in Afghanistan by a U.S.-based media organization or non-governmental organization.</li>
</ul>
<p>Afghans and their eligible family members (spouse and children of any age, whether married or unmarried) can be referred to the P-2 program by a U.S. government agency.  For non-governmental organizations (NGO) and media organizations that were not funded by the U.S. government, but are headquartered in the United States, the senior-most U.S. citizen employee of that organization may make a referral.</p>
<p><strong>P-2 Program for Afghan Nationals: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Department of State has designated certain categories of Afghan nationals as having access to the USRAP by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>To manage the P-2 program for Afghan nationals, the State Department’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) created a USRAP Afghan Referrals Workgroup comprised of federal agencies to refer individuals directly to the USRAP.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>If an individual is not eligible for the P-2 program, he or she may be eligible for the Priority 1 (P-1) program by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.  Individuals may be referred to the P-1 program by the UN High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), a U.S. Embassy, or a designated NGO.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Background on the USRAP:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) is managed by PRM in cooperation with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Office of Refugee Resettlement (ORR).</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>There are currently three categories of individuals who may access the USRAP, known as “priorities.” Once cases receive access to the USRAP, they undergo the same processing steps, including extensive security vetting.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Priority 1:  Individual cases referred by designated entities (an Embassy, designated NGO or the UNHCR) to the program by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Priority 2:  Groups of special concern designated by the Department of State as having access to the program by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Priority 3:  Individual cases granted access for purposes of reunification with family members already in the United States.</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, please visit <a class="external-link" href="https://www.wrapsnet.org/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.wrapsnet.org</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p> *<em>Note: Afghans who work/worked for sub-contractors and sub-grantees do not qualify for the P-2 program, though they may have access to USRAP through a P-1 Embassy referral (if well-known to an Embassy direct-hire American ) or through a referral from UNHCR or a designated NGO.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the Department of State is announcing a Priority 2 (P-2) designation granting U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) access for certain Afghan nationals and their eligible family members.</p>
<p>The U.S. objective remains a peaceful, secure Afghanistan. However, in light of increased levels of Taliban violence, the U.S. government is working to provide certain Afghans, including those who worked with the United States, the opportunity for refugee resettlement to the United States. This designation expands the opportunity to permanently resettle in the United States to many thousands of Afghans and their immediate family members who may be at risk due to their U.S. affiliation but who are not eligible for a Special Immigrant Visa (SIV) because they did not have qualifying employment, or because they have not met the time-in-service requirement to become eligible. Access to the USRAP is a critical mechanism to provide protection for these individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Individuals Eligible for the P-2 Program:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Afghans who do not meet the minimum time-in-service for a SIV but who work or worked as employees of contractors,  locally-employed staff, interpreters/translators for the U.S. Government, United States Forces Afghanistan (USFOR-A), International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), or Resolute Support;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Afghans who work or worked for a U.S. government-funded program or project in Afghanistan supported through a U.S. government grant or cooperative agreement<sup>1</sup>;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Afghans who are or were employed in Afghanistan by a U.S.-based media organization or non-governmental organization.</li>
</ul>
<p>Afghans and their eligible family members (spouse and children of any age, whether married or unmarried) can be referred to the P-2 program by a U.S. government agency.  For non-governmental organizations (NGO) and media organizations that were not funded by the U.S. government, but are headquartered in the United States, the senior-most U.S. citizen employee of that organization may make a referral.</p>
<p><strong>P-2 Program for Afghan Nationals: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Department of State has designated certain categories of Afghan nationals as having access to the USRAP by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>To manage the P-2 program for Afghan nationals, the State Department’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) created a USRAP Afghan Referrals Workgroup comprised of federal agencies to refer individuals directly to the USRAP.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>If an individual is not eligible for the P-2 program, he or she may be eligible for the Priority 1 (P-1) program by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.  Individuals may be referred to the P-1 program by the UN High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), a U.S. Embassy, or a designated NGO.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Background on the USRAP:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) is managed by PRM in cooperation with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Office of Refugee Resettlement (ORR).</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>There are currently three categories of individuals who may access the USRAP, known as “priorities.” Once cases receive access to the USRAP, they undergo the same processing steps, including extensive security vetting.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Priority 1:  Individual cases referred by designated entities (an Embassy, designated NGO or the UNHCR) to the program by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Priority 2:  Groups of special concern designated by the Department of State as having access to the program by virtue of their circumstances and apparent need for resettlement.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Priority 3:  Individual cases granted access for purposes of reunification with family members already in the United States.</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, please visit <a class="external-link" href="https://www.wrapsnet.org/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.wrapsnet.org</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p> *<em>Note: Afghans who work/worked for sub-contractors and sub-grantees do not qualify for the P-2 program, though they may have access to USRAP through a P-1 Embassy referral (if well-known to an Embassy direct-hire American ) or through a referral from UNHCR or a designated NGO.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Nuland’s Travel to South Africa, Botswana, Tanzania, and Niger</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-nulands-travel-to-south-africa-botswana-tanzania-and-niger/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 18:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel to South Africa, Botswana, Tanzania, and Niger from July 31 to August 6.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In South Africa, the Under Secretary will meet with senior South African officials and co-chair the Working Group on African and Global Issues to advance shared priorities. She will welcome the United States’ donation of 5.66 million COVID-19 vaccine doses to South Africa, and meet with civil society and business leaders.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Botswana, the Under Secretary will meet with President Mokgweetsi Masisi to advance our partnership on democracy, the climate crisis, economic prosperity, and security in southern Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Tanzania, the Under Secretary will meet with President Samia Suluhu Hassan and hold a roundtable with opposition leaders. Her discussions will focus on strengthening democracy, combatting COVID-19, and enhancing security and prosperity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Niger, the Under Secretary will meet with President Mohamed Bazoum to discuss ways to improve security in the Sahel, strengthen governance, and advance inclusive economic growth.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel to South Africa, Botswana, Tanzania, and Niger from July 31 to August 6.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In South Africa, the Under Secretary will meet with senior South African officials and co-chair the Working Group on African and Global Issues to advance shared priorities. She will welcome the United States’ donation of 5.66 million COVID-19 vaccine doses to South Africa, and meet with civil society and business leaders.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Botswana, the Under Secretary will meet with President Mokgweetsi Masisi to advance our partnership on democracy, the climate crisis, economic prosperity, and security in southern Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Tanzania, the Under Secretary will meet with President Samia Suluhu Hassan and hold a roundtable with opposition leaders. Her discussions will focus on strengthening democracy, combatting COVID-19, and enhancing security and prosperity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Niger, the Under Secretary will meet with President Mohamed Bazoum to discuss ways to improve security in the Sahel, strengthen governance, and advance inclusive economic growth.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Attack on Mercer Street Vessel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/attack-on-mercer-street-vessel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 17:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We join our partners and allies in our strong condemnation of the attack against the Mercer Street, a commercial ship that was peacefully transiting through the north Arabian Sea in international waters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upon review of the available information, we are confident that Iran conducted this attack, which killed two innocent people, using one-way explosive UAVs, a lethal capability it is increasingly employing throughout the region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is no justification for this attack, which follows a pattern of attacks and other belligerent behavior. These actions threaten freedom of navigation through this crucial waterway, international shipping and commerce, and the lives of those on the vessels involved.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are working with our partners to consider our next steps and consulting with governments inside the region and beyond on an appropriate response, which will be forthcoming. We once again offer our condolences to the families of the victims.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We join our partners and allies in our strong condemnation of the attack against the Mercer Street, a commercial ship that was peacefully transiting through the north Arabian Sea in international waters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upon review of the available information, we are confident that Iran conducted this attack, which killed two innocent people, using one-way explosive UAVs, a lethal capability it is increasingly employing throughout the region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is no justification for this attack, which follows a pattern of attacks and other belligerent behavior. These actions threaten freedom of navigation through this crucial waterway, international shipping and commerce, and the lives of those on the vessels involved.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are working with our partners to consider our next steps and consulting with governments inside the region and beyond on an appropriate response, which will be forthcoming. We once again offer our condolences to the families of the victims.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swiss Confederation National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/swiss-confederation-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 04:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264070</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I wish a heartfelt congratulations to the people of Switzerland as you celebrate your National Day on August 1.</p>
<p>The United States and Switzerland share an unwavering commitment to advancing human rights, promoting democratic values, achieving global health goals, and fostering peace and security around the world.  We also remain strong partners and advocates in promoting dialogue and diplomacy.  We will continue to work closely with Switzerland to expand economic growth and prosperity, collaborate in research and technological innovation, strengthen our cooperation in cyber defense, and partner to address the climate crisis.  I want to thank the Swiss government for serving as our Protecting Power and for representing our interests in Iran.  I witnessed firsthand Switzerland’s dedication to dialogue and diplomacy in June when I joined President Biden in Geneva.</p>
<p>Best wishes on this important day, and I look forward to advancing our exceptional partnership in the years ahead.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I wish a heartfelt congratulations to the people of Switzerland as you celebrate your National Day on August 1.</p>
<p>The United States and Switzerland share an unwavering commitment to advancing human rights, promoting democratic values, achieving global health goals, and fostering peace and security around the world.  We also remain strong partners and advocates in promoting dialogue and diplomacy.  We will continue to work closely with Switzerland to expand economic growth and prosperity, collaborate in research and technological innovation, strengthen our cooperation in cyber defense, and partner to address the climate crisis.  I want to thank the Swiss government for serving as our Protecting Power and for representing our interests in Iran.  I witnessed firsthand Switzerland’s dedication to dialogue and diplomacy in June when I joined President Biden in Geneva.</p>
<p>Best wishes on this important day, and I look forward to advancing our exceptional partnership in the years ahead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Lapid</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-israeli-foreign-minister-and-alternate-prime-minister-lapid/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 01:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid today. Secretary Blinken and FM Lapid discussed the attack on the Mercer Street, a commercial ship which was peacefully transiting through the north Arabian Sea. They agreed to work with the United Kingdom, Romania, and other international partners to investigate the facts, provide support, and consider the appropriate next steps.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid today. Secretary Blinken and FM Lapid discussed the attack on the Mercer Street, a commercial ship which was peacefully transiting through the north Arabian Sea. They agreed to work with the United Kingdom, Romania, and other international partners to investigate the facts, provide support, and consider the appropriate next steps.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States and Canada Forge Ahead on Critical Minerals Cooperation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-and-canada-forge-ahead-on-critical-minerals-cooperation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 13:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Canada hosted the third U.S.-Canada Critical Minerals Working Group meeting on July 28, co-chaired by U.S. Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs, Laura Lochman, and Assistant Deputy Minister of the Land and Minerals Sector of Natural Resources Canada, Jeff Labonté.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The working group discussed implementation of President Biden and Prime Minister Trudeau’s commitment to strengthen cooperation on critical minerals supply chains as outlined in the Roadmap for a Renewed U.S.-Canada Partnership. Participants discussed ways to strengthen the Joint Action Plan for Critical Minerals to target a net-zero industrial transformation, and to support clean energy deployment, including batteries for zero-emissions vehicles, as well as stationary energy storage. They also shared perspectives on strengthening supply chains that utilize critical minerals, and reviewed President Biden’s </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzEuNDM5NTM0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdi9icmllZmluZy1yb29tL3ByZXNpZGVudGlhbC1hY3Rpb25zLzIwMjEvMDIvMjQvZXhlY3V0aXZlLW9yZGVyLW9uLWFtZXJpY2FzLXN1cHBseS1jaGFpbnMvIn0.FI3sA2E_p8k1s-tVfP6cJ5EXx38BwK6rasS8sbl0ALE/s/1250718950/br/110208428522-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Executive Order on America’s Supply Chains</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the related </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzEuNDM5NTM0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdi9icmllZmluZy1yb29tL3N0YXRlbWVudHMtcmVsZWFzZXMvMjAyMS8wNi8wOC9mYWN0LXNoZWV0LWJpZGVuLWhhcnJpcy1hZG1pbmlzdHJhdGlvbi1hbm5vdW5jZXMtc3VwcGx5LWNoYWluLWRpc3J1cHRpb25zLXRhc2stZm9yY2UtdG8tYWRkcmVzcy1zaG9ydC10ZXJtLXN1cHBseS1jaGFpbi1kaXNjb250aW51aXRpZXMvIn0.1c60d5gfCVyqX4uCCbgW1fnNTGBYwdRO7FeTb-jWbQY/s/1250718950/br/110208428522-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">100-day supply chain review</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of critical minerals and materials and other key sectors issued in June.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Canada hosted the third U.S.-Canada Critical Minerals Working Group meeting on July 28, co-chaired by U.S. Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs, Laura Lochman, and Assistant Deputy Minister of the Land and Minerals Sector of Natural Resources Canada, Jeff Labonté.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The working group discussed implementation of President Biden and Prime Minister Trudeau’s commitment to strengthen cooperation on critical minerals supply chains as outlined in the Roadmap for a Renewed U.S.-Canada Partnership. Participants discussed ways to strengthen the Joint Action Plan for Critical Minerals to target a net-zero industrial transformation, and to support clean energy deployment, including batteries for zero-emissions vehicles, as well as stationary energy storage. They also shared perspectives on strengthening supply chains that utilize critical minerals, and reviewed President Biden’s </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzEuNDM5NTM0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdi9icmllZmluZy1yb29tL3ByZXNpZGVudGlhbC1hY3Rpb25zLzIwMjEvMDIvMjQvZXhlY3V0aXZlLW9yZGVyLW9uLWFtZXJpY2FzLXN1cHBseS1jaGFpbnMvIn0.FI3sA2E_p8k1s-tVfP6cJ5EXx38BwK6rasS8sbl0ALE/s/1250718950/br/110208428522-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Executive Order on America’s Supply Chains</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the related </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzEuNDM5NTM0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdi9icmllZmluZy1yb29tL3N0YXRlbWVudHMtcmVsZWFzZXMvMjAyMS8wNi8wOC9mYWN0LXNoZWV0LWJpZGVuLWhhcnJpcy1hZG1pbmlzdHJhdGlvbi1hbm5vdW5jZXMtc3VwcGx5LWNoYWluLWRpc3J1cHRpb25zLXRhc2stZm9yY2UtdG8tYWRkcmVzcy1zaG9ydC10ZXJtLXN1cHBseS1jaGFpbi1kaXNjb250aW51aXRpZXMvIn0.1c60d5gfCVyqX4uCCbgW1fnNTGBYwdRO7FeTb-jWbQY/s/1250718950/br/110208428522-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">100-day supply chain review</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of critical minerals and materials and other key sectors issued in June.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Lenderking’s Return from Saudi Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-for-yemen-lenderkings-return-from-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 23:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=264007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking returned from travel to Saudi Arabia today. Lenderking met with senior officials from the Republic of Yemen and Saudi governments, the Gulf Cooperation Council, the international community, and the UN Special Envoy’s Office.</p>
<p>During this trip, Lenderking called for an end to the stalemated fighting in Marib and across Yemen, which have only increased the suffering of the Yemeni people. He expressed concern that the Houthis continue to refuse to engage meaningfully on a ceasefire and political talks and stressed that only through a durable agreement between the Yemeni parties can the dire humanitarian crisis in the country be reversed.</p>
<p>During his meetings, Lenderking called for the Republic of Yemen Government and Southern Transitional Council to come together to improve services and stabilize the economy. A critical first step is ensuring the conditions necessary for the return of the cabinet to Aden. He also discussed immediate actions that must be taken to ease the humanitarian and economic crisis, including increasing fuel imports, ending manipulation of fuel and prices, and mobilizing additional economic and humanitarian aid for the country.</p>
<p>For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzAuNDM5NDQ5NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL1N0YXRlRGVwdF9ORUEjX2JsYW5rIn0.3H5uKX764U6iPcrFsm82MnmJRR4GI_iyrL6hzVMn-N8/s/1250718950/br/110198339537-l">@StateDept_NEA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking returned from travel to Saudi Arabia today. Lenderking met with senior officials from the Republic of Yemen and Saudi governments, the Gulf Cooperation Council, the international community, and the UN Special Envoy’s Office.</p>
<p>During this trip, Lenderking called for an end to the stalemated fighting in Marib and across Yemen, which have only increased the suffering of the Yemeni people. He expressed concern that the Houthis continue to refuse to engage meaningfully on a ceasefire and political talks and stressed that only through a durable agreement between the Yemeni parties can the dire humanitarian crisis in the country be reversed.</p>
<p>During his meetings, Lenderking called for the Republic of Yemen Government and Southern Transitional Council to come together to improve services and stabilize the economy. A critical first step is ensuring the conditions necessary for the return of the cabinet to Aden. He also discussed immediate actions that must be taken to ease the humanitarian and economic crisis, including increasing fuel imports, ending manipulation of fuel and prices, and mobilizing additional economic and humanitarian aid for the country.</p>
<p>For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MzAuNDM5NDQ5NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL1N0YXRlRGVwdF9ORUEjX2JsYW5rIn0.3H5uKX764U6iPcrFsm82MnmJRR4GI_iyrL6hzVMn-N8/s/1250718950/br/110198339537-l">@StateDept_NEA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
