<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 21:07:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, Indian Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar and Indian Minister of Defense Rajnath Singh Opening Remarks at the U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-secretary-of-defense-lloyd-austin-indian-minister-of-external-affairs-dr-s-jaishankar-and-indian-minister-of-defense-rajnath-singh-opening-remarks-at-the-u-s-india-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense, Dr. S. Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs, Rajnath Singh, Indian Minister of Defense]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 21:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense</p>
<p>Dr. S. Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Rajnath Singh, Indian Minister of Defense</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b> Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Minister Jaishankar, Minister Singh, I am honored to be able to host you here at the State Department for the fourth 2+2 U.S.-India foreign and defense ministerial, alongside my friend and colleague the Secretary of Defense, Lloyd Austin.</p>
<p>As President Biden said when he hosted Prime Minister Modi in September of 2021, the relationship between the oldest and biggest democracies in the world is destined to be stronger, closer, more meaningful.  And those were sentiments that I believe both the President and Prime Minister reiterated today when they spoke via videoconference.</p>
<p>These 2+2 meetings have already played a key role in strengthening our bilateral relationship.  This is the core whole-of-government dialogue in our strategic partnership framework.  Today’s discussions will build upon the previous productive meetings that we’ve had.</p>
<p>This is a momentous moment in global affairs, and I think as a result this partnership is even more consequential and more vital.  Today we’ll discuss pressing issues, shared global challenges, including Russia’s war against Ukraine, ending the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, upholding a free, open, democratic, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region where the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is assured.  We’ll also talk about improving our counterterrorism cooperation and strengthening the bonds between our higher education institutions.  So, this covers a wide range of different aspects in our relationship.  And I’m also looking forward to talking about our defense and security cooperation in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Finally, we’ll have an opportunity to sign the Space Situational Awareness Agreement a little bit later today.  This is a demonstration of our growing technology partnership which we believe has virtually limitless potential for exploration, for discovery, for achievement, to the benefit of people in both of our countries and indeed around the world.</p>
<p>This year, as has been noted, marks India’s 75th year of independence, 75 years of our own relationship.  We look very much forward to continuing to build a stronger future for both of our countries, both of our peoples through our defense and security cooperation, through our deeply connected economies, through our shared values and common bonds, and to do so for many, many decades to come.</p>
<p>With that, it’s a pleasure to turn over the microphone to my friend, Minister Jaishankar.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER JAISHANKAR: </b> Thank you.  My senior colleague, Defense Minister Rajnath Singh-ji, Secretary of State Blinken, Secretary of Defense Austin, it’s a great pleasure to participate in the fourth India-U.S. 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  This morning we have had separate meetings with our State and Defense counterparts respectively.  We have of course benefitted from the guidance provided by Prime Minister Modi and President Biden through the virtual summit, at which we were all present.</p>
<p>The 2+2 format is intended to promote a more integrated approach to our partnership, and this has become increasingly relevant as the scope and intensity of our engagement steadily increases.  We can truly assert that there’s virtually no domain on which we are not cooperating with each other.  The nature of our opportunities and challenges are such that they are more effectively addressed through a cross-cutting dialogue.</p>
<p>As we meet for the fourth time, we can take satisfaction at the extent of progress that we have made, whether it is a $160 billion trade account, our 200,000 students, our highest recorded investment levels, or our rapidly growing energy trade.  The yardsticks to measure our growing closeness tell their own story.  The defense minister would be similarly highlighting the transformation in that domain.</p>
<p>Our collaboration has grown well beyond its bilateral scope and now has a visible impact on global issues, as well.  It could be addressing the COVID challenge, taking climate action, ensuring maritime security, or promoting critical technologies.  What India and the U.S. do together will make a difference.</p>
<p>A significant focus of our engagement pertains to the Indo-Pacific.  We have seen, particularly over the last year, both an elevation and an intensification of the Quad.  Our achievements in this regard have a larger resonance.</p>
<p>Today we will be reviewing all these matters and more.  We will also be discussing contemporary developments, including, obviously, Ukraine; also, Afghanistan, the Gulf, and the Indian subcontinent.  I thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Austin for receiving us today, and look forward to our talks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY AUSTIN:</b>  Okay.  Secretary Blinken, Minister Singh, Minister Jaishankar, it is a privilege to be here with you today for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  It’s been nearly two decades since we signed our first defense framework, and we’ve built a partnership that is now a cornerstone of security in the Indo-Pacific.  Today, we are positioning the U.S. and Indian militaries to operate and coordinate closely together across all domains and increasingly across the wider Indo-Pacific, all in support of the rule of law, freedom of the seas, and regional peace and security.</p>
<p>Those are vital principles, and now, more than ever, democracies must stand together to defend the values that we all share.  We all understand the challenges that we face in the Indo-Pacific.  The People’s Republic of China is seeking to refashion the region and the international system more broadly in ways that serve its authoritarian interests.  But as we operationalize our defense agreements and take our cooperation to the next level, I believe that we can sustain and strengthen a favorable balance of power in the region.</p>
<p>So, I’m looking forward to discussing a range of bilateral defense priorities, including deeper information sharing and industrial cooperation.  All this will help to ensure that our militaries are ready to meet any challenge.</p>
<p>Now, a strong U.S.-Indian partnership is a critical building block in a more resilient, regional security architecture, and so today’s 2+2 is an opportunity to discuss ways to strengthen our cooperation with like-minded partners from East and Southeast Asia to Europe and beyond.</p>
<p>So, we’ve got an ambitious agenda today.  It reflects our combined vision for our partnership and our shared conviction that we can shape the course of history for the better and preserve a free and open Indo-Pacific at peace with itself and the world.</p>
<p>Ministers, I know that you’ve had a long trip to Washington and thank you for making it here for this important dialogue.  I am truly grateful for your vision, your commitment, and your leadership, as we work together to build one of the most consequential partnerships of our time.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I’ll now turn it over to Minister Singh.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER SINGH:</b>  Excellencies; Mr. Antony Blinken; Mr. Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense; my esteemed colleague, Dr. Jaishankar-ji; distinguished members of delegations:  Thank you, Secretary Blinken and to Secretary Austin, for your (inaudible) in Washington, D.C.  India places the highest priority upon the strategic partnership with USA.  (Inaudible) and for ensuring peace and sustained economic growth in our region.  Major defense partnership is one of the most important pillars of India-U.S. strategic relations.</p>
<p>As the largest country and the center to Indian Ocean, and as a democracy, India has critical roles to play in the Indian Ocean region and in the wider Indo-Pacific following the Act East and the Neighborhood First policy.  India played preeminent role in the region, from the tsunami in 2004 and during the COVID pandemic.  We have signed eight different defense-related agreements between our two countries in last few years, including a Space Situational Awareness Agreement for unclassified domain, which is being signed today.</p>
<p>Despite the pandemic, India-USA military engagements increased with higher capability in communication, closer information sharing, and enhanced mutual logistic support. This is a reflection of our – the growing depth and scale of our defense partnership.</p>
<p>In a decade, our defense suppliers from USA rose from negligible to a cumulative around of over $20 billion U.S.  We look forward to U.S. companies investing in India and support the Make In India program.</p>
<p>We look forward to further enhancing the depth and the scope of our defense cooperation to give effect to our shared vision of a free, open, inclusive, and a rules-bound Indo-Pacific and the Indian Ocean region.</p>
<p>We are working with the U.S. to double up capabilities across conventional and emerging defense domains.  We have made good progress in a number of defense cooperation activities since the visit of Secretary Austin to India in March 2021.  I look forward to discussing some of these and the way forward.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, colleagues, and I think we’ll allow our colleagues from the press to exit.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense</p>
<p>Dr. S. Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Rajnath Singh, Indian Minister of Defense</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b> Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Minister Jaishankar, Minister Singh, I am honored to be able to host you here at the State Department for the fourth 2+2 U.S.-India foreign and defense ministerial, alongside my friend and colleague the Secretary of Defense, Lloyd Austin.</p>
<p>As President Biden said when he hosted Prime Minister Modi in September of 2021, the relationship between the oldest and biggest democracies in the world is destined to be stronger, closer, more meaningful.  And those were sentiments that I believe both the President and Prime Minister reiterated today when they spoke via videoconference.</p>
<p>These 2+2 meetings have already played a key role in strengthening our bilateral relationship.  This is the core whole-of-government dialogue in our strategic partnership framework.  Today’s discussions will build upon the previous productive meetings that we’ve had.</p>
<p>This is a momentous moment in global affairs, and I think as a result this partnership is even more consequential and more vital.  Today we’ll discuss pressing issues, shared global challenges, including Russia’s war against Ukraine, ending the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, upholding a free, open, democratic, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region where the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is assured.  We’ll also talk about improving our counterterrorism cooperation and strengthening the bonds between our higher education institutions.  So, this covers a wide range of different aspects in our relationship.  And I’m also looking forward to talking about our defense and security cooperation in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Finally, we’ll have an opportunity to sign the Space Situational Awareness Agreement a little bit later today.  This is a demonstration of our growing technology partnership which we believe has virtually limitless potential for exploration, for discovery, for achievement, to the benefit of people in both of our countries and indeed around the world.</p>
<p>This year, as has been noted, marks India’s 75th year of independence, 75 years of our own relationship.  We look very much forward to continuing to build a stronger future for both of our countries, both of our peoples through our defense and security cooperation, through our deeply connected economies, through our shared values and common bonds, and to do so for many, many decades to come.</p>
<p>With that, it’s a pleasure to turn over the microphone to my friend, Minister Jaishankar.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER JAISHANKAR: </b> Thank you.  My senior colleague, Defense Minister Rajnath Singh-ji, Secretary of State Blinken, Secretary of Defense Austin, it’s a great pleasure to participate in the fourth India-U.S. 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  This morning we have had separate meetings with our State and Defense counterparts respectively.  We have of course benefitted from the guidance provided by Prime Minister Modi and President Biden through the virtual summit, at which we were all present.</p>
<p>The 2+2 format is intended to promote a more integrated approach to our partnership, and this has become increasingly relevant as the scope and intensity of our engagement steadily increases.  We can truly assert that there’s virtually no domain on which we are not cooperating with each other.  The nature of our opportunities and challenges are such that they are more effectively addressed through a cross-cutting dialogue.</p>
<p>As we meet for the fourth time, we can take satisfaction at the extent of progress that we have made, whether it is a $160 billion trade account, our 200,000 students, our highest recorded investment levels, or our rapidly growing energy trade.  The yardsticks to measure our growing closeness tell their own story.  The defense minister would be similarly highlighting the transformation in that domain.</p>
<p>Our collaboration has grown well beyond its bilateral scope and now has a visible impact on global issues, as well.  It could be addressing the COVID challenge, taking climate action, ensuring maritime security, or promoting critical technologies.  What India and the U.S. do together will make a difference.</p>
<p>A significant focus of our engagement pertains to the Indo-Pacific.  We have seen, particularly over the last year, both an elevation and an intensification of the Quad.  Our achievements in this regard have a larger resonance.</p>
<p>Today we will be reviewing all these matters and more.  We will also be discussing contemporary developments, including, obviously, Ukraine; also, Afghanistan, the Gulf, and the Indian subcontinent.  I thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Austin for receiving us today, and look forward to our talks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY AUSTIN:</b>  Okay.  Secretary Blinken, Minister Singh, Minister Jaishankar, it is a privilege to be here with you today for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  It’s been nearly two decades since we signed our first defense framework, and we’ve built a partnership that is now a cornerstone of security in the Indo-Pacific.  Today, we are positioning the U.S. and Indian militaries to operate and coordinate closely together across all domains and increasingly across the wider Indo-Pacific, all in support of the rule of law, freedom of the seas, and regional peace and security.</p>
<p>Those are vital principles, and now, more than ever, democracies must stand together to defend the values that we all share.  We all understand the challenges that we face in the Indo-Pacific.  The People’s Republic of China is seeking to refashion the region and the international system more broadly in ways that serve its authoritarian interests.  But as we operationalize our defense agreements and take our cooperation to the next level, I believe that we can sustain and strengthen a favorable balance of power in the region.</p>
<p>So, I’m looking forward to discussing a range of bilateral defense priorities, including deeper information sharing and industrial cooperation.  All this will help to ensure that our militaries are ready to meet any challenge.</p>
<p>Now, a strong U.S.-Indian partnership is a critical building block in a more resilient, regional security architecture, and so today’s 2+2 is an opportunity to discuss ways to strengthen our cooperation with like-minded partners from East and Southeast Asia to Europe and beyond.</p>
<p>So, we’ve got an ambitious agenda today.  It reflects our combined vision for our partnership and our shared conviction that we can shape the course of history for the better and preserve a free and open Indo-Pacific at peace with itself and the world.</p>
<p>Ministers, I know that you’ve had a long trip to Washington and thank you for making it here for this important dialogue.  I am truly grateful for your vision, your commitment, and your leadership, as we work together to build one of the most consequential partnerships of our time.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I’ll now turn it over to Minister Singh.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER SINGH:</b>  Excellencies; Mr. Antony Blinken; Mr. Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense; my esteemed colleague, Dr. Jaishankar-ji; distinguished members of delegations:  Thank you, Secretary Blinken and to Secretary Austin, for your (inaudible) in Washington, D.C.  India places the highest priority upon the strategic partnership with USA.  (Inaudible) and for ensuring peace and sustained economic growth in our region.  Major defense partnership is one of the most important pillars of India-U.S. strategic relations.</p>
<p>As the largest country and the center to Indian Ocean, and as a democracy, India has critical roles to play in the Indian Ocean region and in the wider Indo-Pacific following the Act East and the Neighborhood First policy.  India played preeminent role in the region, from the tsunami in 2004 and during the COVID pandemic.  We have signed eight different defense-related agreements between our two countries in last few years, including a Space Situational Awareness Agreement for unclassified domain, which is being signed today.</p>
<p>Despite the pandemic, India-USA military engagements increased with higher capability in communication, closer information sharing, and enhanced mutual logistic support. This is a reflection of our – the growing depth and scale of our defense partnership.</p>
<p>In a decade, our defense suppliers from USA rose from negligible to a cumulative around of over $20 billion U.S.  We look forward to U.S. companies investing in India and support the Make In India program.</p>
<p>We look forward to further enhancing the depth and the scope of our defense cooperation to give effect to our shared vision of a free, open, inclusive, and a rules-bound Indo-Pacific and the Indian Ocean region.</p>
<p>We are working with the U.S. to double up capabilities across conventional and emerging defense domains.  We have made good progress in a number of defense cooperation activities since the visit of Secretary Austin to India in March 2021.  I look forward to discussing some of these and the way forward.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, colleagues, and I think we’ll allow our colleagues from the press to exit.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Noyes Travel to Moldova and Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-noyes-travel-to-moldova-and-poland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes will travel to Chisinau, Moldova and Warsaw, Poland April 12-15.</p>
<p>In Chisinau, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with government officials to recognize Moldova’s role in hosting tens of thousands of refugees who have fled Ukraine due to Russia’s unprovoked invasion. She will also visit a refugee hosting center to meet with refugees as well as humanitarian organization staff and volunteers assisting them.</p>
<p>In Warsaw, she will meet with Polish and UN officials to discuss the ongoing humanitarian crisis response. Assistant Secretary Noyes will also meet with NGOs delivering critical humanitarian assistance for refugees in Poland.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes will travel to Chisinau, Moldova and Warsaw, Poland April 12-15.</p>
<p>In Chisinau, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with government officials to recognize Moldova’s role in hosting tens of thousands of refugees who have fled Ukraine due to Russia’s unprovoked invasion. She will also visit a refugee hosting center to meet with refugees as well as humanitarian organization staff and volunteers assisting them.</p>
<p>In Warsaw, she will meet with Polish and UN officials to discuss the ongoing humanitarian crisis response. Assistant Secretary Noyes will also meet with NGOs delivering critical humanitarian assistance for refugees in Poland.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with UK Minister for Europe and North America Cleverly</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-uk-minister-for-europe-and-north-america-cleverly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 17:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly today in Washington. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Cleverly continued close U.S.-UK coordination to hold the Kremlin accountable for its brutal atrocities in Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. The Deputy Secretary and Minister Cleverly also discussed bilateral cooperation to support South Caucasus peace and reconciliation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly today in Washington. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Cleverly continued close U.S.-UK coordination to hold the Kremlin accountable for its brutal atrocities in Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. The Deputy Secretary and Minister Cleverly also discussed bilateral cooperation to support South Caucasus peace and reconciliation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burma New Year 2022 – Thingyan Festival</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/burma-new-year-2022-thingyan-festival/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 13:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend best wishes to the people of Burma on the occasion of Burma’s New Year, Thingyan.</p>
<p>Thingyan is an opportunity to wash away the previous year’s tribulations. Since the military coup, the people of Burma have endured unimaginable suffering and shown incredible courage and resilience in opposition to the military regime. The United States will continue to stand by the people of Burma and to promote accountability in connection with the coup and the violence perpetrated by the regime. The United States is unwavering in its commitment to help restore Burma’s path to inclusive democracy and achieve lasting peace.</p>
<p>In these difficult times, please accept our warmest regards for the people of Burma.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend best wishes to the people of Burma on the occasion of Burma’s New Year, Thingyan.</p>
<p>Thingyan is an opportunity to wash away the previous year’s tribulations. Since the military coup, the people of Burma have endured unimaginable suffering and shown incredible courage and resilience in opposition to the military regime. The United States will continue to stand by the people of Burma and to promote accountability in connection with the coup and the violence perpetrated by the regime. The United States is unwavering in its commitment to help restore Burma’s path to inclusive democracy and achieve lasting peace.</p>
<p>In these difficult times, please accept our warmest regards for the people of Burma.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Violence and Threats to Free Speech in El Salvador</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/violence-and-threats-to-free-speech-in-el-salvador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States government is concerned about violence in El Salvador and the passage and implementation of the April 5 Criminal Code amendment by the Legislative Assembly criminalizing reporting on certain gang activities. The law lends itself to attempts to censor the media, prevent reporting on corruption and other matters of public interest, and silence critics of the Salvadoran government.</p>
<p>Journalists must have the freedom to do their jobs without fear of violence, threats, or unjust detention.</p>
<p>We continue to support El Salvador in its efforts to reduce the proliferation of gangs. Since 2008, we have invested $411 million to improve citizen security and help the Salvadoran government combat gang violence. Examples include the construction of a state-of-the-art forensics lab in Nuevo Cuscatlan, and assistance to reclaim and renovate public spaces such as Parque Cuscatlan.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the spike in violence and homicides committed by the MS-13 and the Barrio 18 gangs in El Salvador on March 25, 26, and 27.</p>
<p>Gangs pose a threat to the national security of El Salvador and the United States. We urge El Salvador to address this threat while also protecting vital civil liberties, including freedom of the press, due process, and freedom of speech.</p>
<p>Now more than ever it is essential to extradite gang leaders to face justice in the United States.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States government is concerned about violence in El Salvador and the passage and implementation of the April 5 Criminal Code amendment by the Legislative Assembly criminalizing reporting on certain gang activities. The law lends itself to attempts to censor the media, prevent reporting on corruption and other matters of public interest, and silence critics of the Salvadoran government.</p>
<p>Journalists must have the freedom to do their jobs without fear of violence, threats, or unjust detention.</p>
<p>We continue to support El Salvador in its efforts to reduce the proliferation of gangs. Since 2008, we have invested $411 million to improve citizen security and help the Salvadoran government combat gang violence. Examples include the construction of a state-of-the-art forensics lab in Nuevo Cuscatlan, and assistance to reclaim and renovate public spaces such as Parque Cuscatlan.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the spike in violence and homicides committed by the MS-13 and the Barrio 18 gangs in El Salvador on March 25, 26, and 27.</p>
<p>Gangs pose a threat to the national security of El Salvador and the United States. We urge El Salvador to address this threat while also protecting vital civil liberties, including freedom of the press, due process, and freedom of speech.</p>
<p>Now more than ever it is essential to extradite gang leaders to face justice in the United States.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – April 8, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-april-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=333088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. I have one update at the top, and then I’ll start with taking your questions. I<a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia"></a> would like to start off by addressing the missile strike by Russia’s forces that reportedly killed at least 50 civilians and injured many more at the Kramatorsk railway station in eastern Ukraine, where thousands of civilians were on a platform waiting to be evacuated. I want to express our deep condolences to the families of those killed or injured, and to the people of Ukraine who continue to suffer terribly from the Russian Government’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war.</p>
<p>We are horrified by this latest atrocity, but we can no longer be surprised by the Kremlin’s repugnant disregard for human life. This is just yet another example of the Russian Government’s unjustified, brutal war sowing senseless death and destruction in Ukraine, and unraveling the fabric of normal life on schools, on homes, on hospitals, and on workplaces. Civilians are killed when they stay in their homes, and they’re killed when they tried to leave. Actions like these demonstrate why Russia did not belong on the UN Human Rights Council, and they also reinforced the U.S. assessment that members of Russian – Russia’s forces are committing war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This tragedy has also further increased our resolve to do everything we can to assist those investigating potential war crimes, see those responsible held accountable for atrocities, and support the people of Ukraine in their just cause: the defense of their country, their democracy, and their free and sovereign future.</p>
<p>Let’s first go to the line of Cindy Saine, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you. Jalina, Prime Minister – Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan just spoke to the nation, and he has renewed allegations that the U.S. encouraged the no-confidence vote, saying that he has a cable to prove it. Could you please comment? And thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Cindy. <a id="post-333088-Pakistan"></a>Let me just say very bluntly there is absolutely no truth to these allegations. Of course, we continue to follow these developments, and we respect and support Pakistan’s constitutional process and rule of law. But again, these allegations are absolutely not true.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And next we’ll go to the line of Endale Getahun with KETO FM International. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much. Good morning. Good morning, everyone, and a Happy Friday. Thank you for taking my call. I am asking regarding the situation, as you know, that’s in East Africa, Ethiopia. I don’t know if you know, but there was – a meeting took place between the second in command on Ethiopian military and Eritrean. And so do you know any information or have you heard on – or do you want to comment on regarding the general who visited Eritrea with the state – given the statements on state media and Ethiopian TV that they are preparing to do a second phase there to invade Tigray, as we speak? Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>The second one I have: Have you seen the Human Rights and Amnesty International released about the (inaudible) was taken based on their statements, ethnic cleansing and what have you, on – for the neighboring state, for Amhara militants or vigilantes, and they were – and western Tigray, which is still occupied by Eritreans and by the – with the Amhara? So what is your comments on that statement and also on the general, the second in command in Ethiopia, that made the statements on they are heading to the second phase, even as there’s a ceasefire according to Ethiopian Government, and also on the human – that was my question, but if you have any comments on World Food Program. They’re still having issues for delivering food. Only 26 trucks head on to Tigray. What’s your comment on that too? And thank you so much, appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for all of those robust questions. <a id="post-333088-Ethiopia"></a>I’ll do my best to give you an overview of what we have from here. I’ll just start off by saying that we certainly welcome the humanitarian truce in Tigray.</p>
<p>Second, to your question on the joint Human Rights report and Amnesty International report, we’re certainly aware of these reports on ethnically motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in the western Tigray and in Ethiopia, and we also reiterate our grave concerns over findings in this report, which we will carefully review. In fact, we have some principals in the building, including Under Secretary Zeya, who is our Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights, along with our Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and a couple other principals in our department are actually meeting with representatives of Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International today to hear more about this report.</p>
<p>I’ll also say that the U.S. has consistently called out human rights abuses by all armed actors in this conflict, and we will continue to do this. Victims deserve justice, and those responsible for these abuses must be held accountable through transparent and inclusive processes.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Secretary Blinken on I believe it was March 23rd said that the State Department determined the Russians had committed war crimes in Ukraine. When do you intend to release those assessments of specific determinations of war crimes?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Laura. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia2"></a>Well, we certainly don’t have a timeline for this. But I’ll say that we continue to investigate Russia’s ongoing and unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine. But we have no – nothing to preview as far as timelines.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. The nominee for ambassador to South Korea, Ambassador Phillip Goldberg, at the Senate nomination hearing yesterday said comprehensive, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization are goals in – when it comes to North Korea. So is comprehensible, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization the Biden administration’s official term for describing the goal in negotiations with North Korea? Is the Biden administration officially replacing “complete” with “comprehensive” in defining this goal?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks for your question, Eunjong. <a id="post-333088-Koreas"></a>We have no change – the Biden-Harris administration has no change in our policy, and we continue to urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activities and of course instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Jenny Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for calling on me. The Ukrainian foreign minister just called for Russia to be expelled from the OSCE, saying that if the OSCE lacks an appropriate suspension mechanism, then they should set up a process to get them out. Does the U.S. support suspending Russia from the OSCE or creating a mechanism to do so?</p>
<p>And then secondly, do you have an update on the American citizens detained in Russia? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Jenny. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia3"></a>To your first question on the OSCE, I’m learning about that in real time so we don’t have anything to respond to at the moment.</p>
<p>But what I will say about – to your second question, of course, is our top priority is and has always been the safety and the security of Americans overseas, and we continue to engage the Russian Government on cases of Americans who are currently detained.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, Jalina. Two questions on – just following up on what you said at the top about the strike on the train station in Kramatorsk. First, you said it reinforces the assessment that Russia is committing war crimes. Are you calling this strike a war crime?</p>
<p>And then second, you attributed it to Russia. The Kremlin has obviously denied responsibility. Just wondering if you will respond to their denial. Any more information you can provide on why you are attributing it to them? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. I’ll say, to your question on the war crime question, assessing individual criminal liability in specific cases is the responsibility of courts as well as other investigatory bodies. But as the Secretary, Secretary Blinken, has said, those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine will be held to account. We won’t make any public comments on our war crimes assessment of specific acts or reports, nor discuss any information that’s reviewed at this time.</p>
<p>And then to your second question on a response – yeah, we just don’t have a response to give at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Joseph Akbush.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for this. Two questions. One, is there any comment on the two attacks which targeted U.S. servicemembers in Syria and Iraq over the last two days, I guess? And on that note, any updates to the Vienna talks?</p>
<p>And then my second question is on Ukraine. And are there still – is the U.S. still concerned about China providing military support to Russia or circumventing international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So for your first question, I would have to refer you to the DOD. To your second question on any updates in – on <a id="post-333088-Iran"></a>the status of talks and Iran, we don’t have any updates to share at this time other than it’s obviously been a significant process, but an agreement is neither imminent nor certain at this time.</p>
<p>And to your last question on <a id="post-333088-ChinaRussiaUkraine"></a>Chinese military to assist the Russians, I think we’ve been pretty clear on our stance when it comes to any support in this activity, and that hasn’t changed at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. One follow-up for you on Iran. Can you say whether the Biden administration shares General Milley’s view that the IRGC’s Qods Force specifically should remain on the U.S. list of terror organizations?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Elizabeth. <a id="post-333088-Iran2"></a>I’d say that the President shares the chairman’s view that IRGC Qods Forces are terrorists, and beyond that we aren’t going to comment on any of the topics in the nuclear talks. But what I would say is out of the 107 Biden administration designations in relation to Iran, 86 have specifically targeted the IRGC-related persons as well as affiliates.</p>
<p>Thank you all so much for joining today. That concludes today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a good weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:19 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. I have one update at the top, and then I’ll start with taking your questions. I<a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia"></a> would like to start off by addressing the missile strike by Russia’s forces that reportedly killed at least 50 civilians and injured many more at the Kramatorsk railway station in eastern Ukraine, where thousands of civilians were on a platform waiting to be evacuated. I want to express our deep condolences to the families of those killed or injured, and to the people of Ukraine who continue to suffer terribly from the Russian Government’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war.</p>
<p>We are horrified by this latest atrocity, but we can no longer be surprised by the Kremlin’s repugnant disregard for human life. This is just yet another example of the Russian Government’s unjustified, brutal war sowing senseless death and destruction in Ukraine, and unraveling the fabric of normal life on schools, on homes, on hospitals, and on workplaces. Civilians are killed when they stay in their homes, and they’re killed when they tried to leave. Actions like these demonstrate why Russia did not belong on the UN Human Rights Council, and they also reinforced the U.S. assessment that members of Russian – Russia’s forces are committing war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This tragedy has also further increased our resolve to do everything we can to assist those investigating potential war crimes, see those responsible held accountable for atrocities, and support the people of Ukraine in their just cause: the defense of their country, their democracy, and their free and sovereign future.</p>
<p>Let’s first go to the line of Cindy Saine, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you. Jalina, Prime Minister – Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan just spoke to the nation, and he has renewed allegations that the U.S. encouraged the no-confidence vote, saying that he has a cable to prove it. Could you please comment? And thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Cindy. <a id="post-333088-Pakistan"></a>Let me just say very bluntly there is absolutely no truth to these allegations. Of course, we continue to follow these developments, and we respect and support Pakistan’s constitutional process and rule of law. But again, these allegations are absolutely not true.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And next we’ll go to the line of Endale Getahun with KETO FM International. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much. Good morning. Good morning, everyone, and a Happy Friday. Thank you for taking my call. I am asking regarding the situation, as you know, that’s in East Africa, Ethiopia. I don’t know if you know, but there was – a meeting took place between the second in command on Ethiopian military and Eritrean. And so do you know any information or have you heard on – or do you want to comment on regarding the general who visited Eritrea with the state – given the statements on state media and Ethiopian TV that they are preparing to do a second phase there to invade Tigray, as we speak? Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>The second one I have: Have you seen the Human Rights and Amnesty International released about the (inaudible) was taken based on their statements, ethnic cleansing and what have you, on – for the neighboring state, for Amhara militants or vigilantes, and they were – and western Tigray, which is still occupied by Eritreans and by the – with the Amhara? So what is your comments on that statement and also on the general, the second in command in Ethiopia, that made the statements on they are heading to the second phase, even as there’s a ceasefire according to Ethiopian Government, and also on the human – that was my question, but if you have any comments on World Food Program. They’re still having issues for delivering food. Only 26 trucks head on to Tigray. What’s your comment on that too? And thank you so much, appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for all of those robust questions. <a id="post-333088-Ethiopia"></a>I’ll do my best to give you an overview of what we have from here. I’ll just start off by saying that we certainly welcome the humanitarian truce in Tigray.</p>
<p>Second, to your question on the joint Human Rights report and Amnesty International report, we’re certainly aware of these reports on ethnically motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in the western Tigray and in Ethiopia, and we also reiterate our grave concerns over findings in this report, which we will carefully review. In fact, we have some principals in the building, including Under Secretary Zeya, who is our Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights, along with our Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and a couple other principals in our department are actually meeting with representatives of Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International today to hear more about this report.</p>
<p>I’ll also say that the U.S. has consistently called out human rights abuses by all armed actors in this conflict, and we will continue to do this. Victims deserve justice, and those responsible for these abuses must be held accountable through transparent and inclusive processes.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Secretary Blinken on I believe it was March 23rd said that the State Department determined the Russians had committed war crimes in Ukraine. When do you intend to release those assessments of specific determinations of war crimes?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Laura. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia2"></a>Well, we certainly don’t have a timeline for this. But I’ll say that we continue to investigate Russia’s ongoing and unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine. But we have no – nothing to preview as far as timelines.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. The nominee for ambassador to South Korea, Ambassador Phillip Goldberg, at the Senate nomination hearing yesterday said comprehensive, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization are goals in – when it comes to North Korea. So is comprehensible, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization the Biden administration’s official term for describing the goal in negotiations with North Korea? Is the Biden administration officially replacing “complete” with “comprehensive” in defining this goal?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks for your question, Eunjong. <a id="post-333088-Koreas"></a>We have no change – the Biden-Harris administration has no change in our policy, and we continue to urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activities and of course instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Jenny Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for calling on me. The Ukrainian foreign minister just called for Russia to be expelled from the OSCE, saying that if the OSCE lacks an appropriate suspension mechanism, then they should set up a process to get them out. Does the U.S. support suspending Russia from the OSCE or creating a mechanism to do so?</p>
<p>And then secondly, do you have an update on the American citizens detained in Russia? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Jenny. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia3"></a>To your first question on the OSCE, I’m learning about that in real time so we don’t have anything to respond to at the moment.</p>
<p>But what I will say about – to your second question, of course, is our top priority is and has always been the safety and the security of Americans overseas, and we continue to engage the Russian Government on cases of Americans who are currently detained.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, Jalina. Two questions on – just following up on what you said at the top about the strike on the train station in Kramatorsk. First, you said it reinforces the assessment that Russia is committing war crimes. Are you calling this strike a war crime?</p>
<p>And then second, you attributed it to Russia. The Kremlin has obviously denied responsibility. Just wondering if you will respond to their denial. Any more information you can provide on why you are attributing it to them? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. I’ll say, to your question on the war crime question, assessing individual criminal liability in specific cases is the responsibility of courts as well as other investigatory bodies. But as the Secretary, Secretary Blinken, has said, those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine will be held to account. We won’t make any public comments on our war crimes assessment of specific acts or reports, nor discuss any information that’s reviewed at this time.</p>
<p>And then to your second question on a response – yeah, we just don’t have a response to give at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Joseph Akbush.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for this. Two questions. One, is there any comment on the two attacks which targeted U.S. servicemembers in Syria and Iraq over the last two days, I guess? And on that note, any updates to the Vienna talks?</p>
<p>And then my second question is on Ukraine. And are there still – is the U.S. still concerned about China providing military support to Russia or circumventing international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So for your first question, I would have to refer you to the DOD. To your second question on any updates in – on <a id="post-333088-Iran"></a>the status of talks and Iran, we don’t have any updates to share at this time other than it’s obviously been a significant process, but an agreement is neither imminent nor certain at this time.</p>
<p>And to your last question on <a id="post-333088-ChinaRussiaUkraine"></a>Chinese military to assist the Russians, I think we’ve been pretty clear on our stance when it comes to any support in this activity, and that hasn’t changed at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. One follow-up for you on Iran. Can you say whether the Biden administration shares General Milley’s view that the IRGC’s Qods Force specifically should remain on the U.S. list of terror organizations?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Elizabeth. <a id="post-333088-Iran2"></a>I’d say that the President shares the chairman’s view that IRGC Qods Forces are terrorists, and beyond that we aren’t going to comment on any of the topics in the nuclear talks. But what I would say is out of the 107 Biden administration designations in relation to Iran, 86 have specifically targeted the IRGC-related persons as well as affiliates.</p>
<p>Thank you all so much for joining today. That concludes today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a good weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:19 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Palau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerry-and-assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-palau/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Palau April 12-15 to lead the U.S. delegation to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>, co-hosted by the United States and the Republic of Palau.  He will be joined by Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina, who will travel to Palau April 10-16.</p>
<p>The Our Ocean Conference, taking place April 13-14, will focus on combating climate change, promoting sustainable fisheries, creating sustainable blue economies, advancing marine protected areas, achieving a safe and secure ocean, and confronting marine pollution.  The importance of ocean-based climate solutions and the centrality of a healthy ocean to small island developing states – and all places where the ocean is a primary source of sustenance – will be cross-cutting themes.</p>
<p>At the conference, Secretary Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina will engage with government counterparts, private sector actors, and civil society partners to advance efforts related to ocean conservation and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Palau April 12-15 to lead the U.S. delegation to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>, co-hosted by the United States and the Republic of Palau.  He will be joined by Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina, who will travel to Palau April 10-16.</p>
<p>The Our Ocean Conference, taking place April 13-14, will focus on combating climate change, promoting sustainable fisheries, creating sustainable blue economies, advancing marine protected areas, achieving a safe and secure ocean, and confronting marine pollution.  The importance of ocean-based climate solutions and the centrality of a healthy ocean to small island developing states – and all places where the ocean is a primary source of sustenance – will be cross-cutting themes.</p>
<p>At the conference, Secretary Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina will engage with government counterparts, private sector actors, and civil society partners to advance efforts related to ocean conservation and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Counselor Chollet’s Meeting with NUG Representatives</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/counselor-chollets-meeting-with-nug-representatives-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 19:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Counselor Derek Chollet met today with NUG representatives Aung Myo Min and Moe Zaw Oo.  The Counselor expressed deep sympathy for the victims of the military regime’s brutal atrocities across Burma.  He pledged the United States’ strong support for the people of Burma and discussed ways to step up assistance to the people, promote a return to Burma’s path of democratic transition, and advance peaceful resolution to the ongoing human rights and humanitarian crises the military caused by its February 2021 military coup.  In addition, the Counselor voiced appreciation for the NUG’s robust leadership and its efforts to promote respect for the human rights of all individuals in Burma, regardless of ethnicity or religion.  They also discussed Secretary Blinken’s recent announcement of the U.S. determination that members of the military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya and exchanged views on ways to further promote accountability and justice for the military’s atrocities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Counselor Derek Chollet met today with NUG representatives Aung Myo Min and Moe Zaw Oo.  The Counselor expressed deep sympathy for the victims of the military regime’s brutal atrocities across Burma.  He pledged the United States’ strong support for the people of Burma and discussed ways to step up assistance to the people, promote a return to Burma’s path of democratic transition, and advance peaceful resolution to the ongoing human rights and humanitarian crises the military caused by its February 2021 military coup.  In addition, the Counselor voiced appreciation for the NUG’s robust leadership and its efforts to promote respect for the human rights of all individuals in Burma, regardless of ethnicity or religion.  They also discussed Secretary Blinken’s recent announcement of the U.S. determination that members of the military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya and exchanged views on ways to further promote accountability and justice for the military’s atrocities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reports of Mass Atrocities in Western Tigray</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/reports-of-mass-atrocities-in-western-tigray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 17:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its grave concern over continuing reports of ethnically-motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in western Tigray, Ethiopia, including those described in the recent joint report by Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International.  In particular, we are deeply troubled by the report’s finding that these acts amount to ethnic cleansing.</p>
<p>We note with the utmost alarm that thousands of Ethiopians of Tigrayan ethnicity reportedly continue to be detained arbitrarily in life-threatening conditions in western Tigray.  We urge the immediate release of any such remaining detainees and call on relevant authorities to grant international monitors access to all detention facilities. It remains our firm position that there must be credible investigations into and accountability for atrocities committed by any party to the conflict as part of any lasting solution to the crisis.  We urge the Government of Ethiopia to cooperate with the UN Commission of Experts on Human Rights in Ethiopia.</p>
<p>Continued reports of atrocities underscore the urgency of ending the military conflict.  We strongly support the declarations of a cessation of hostilities by the Government of Ethiopia and the Tigray regional authority and welcome the news that they have been followed by initial convoys of life-saving assistance.  In keeping with these declarations, we renew our call on all armed actors to renounce and end human rights abuses and violence against civilians.  The United States reiterates its call for all foreign forces to withdraw from Ethiopia as well as for the regional state authorities to remove their security forces from neighboring regions.</p>
<p>We continue to urge all parties to take necessary steps to ensure the cessation of hostilities, unhindered and sustained humanitarian access, transparent investigations into human rights abuses and violations by all actors, and a negotiated resolution to the conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its grave concern over continuing reports of ethnically-motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in western Tigray, Ethiopia, including those described in the recent joint report by Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International.  In particular, we are deeply troubled by the report’s finding that these acts amount to ethnic cleansing.</p>
<p>We note with the utmost alarm that thousands of Ethiopians of Tigrayan ethnicity reportedly continue to be detained arbitrarily in life-threatening conditions in western Tigray.  We urge the immediate release of any such remaining detainees and call on relevant authorities to grant international monitors access to all detention facilities. It remains our firm position that there must be credible investigations into and accountability for atrocities committed by any party to the conflict as part of any lasting solution to the crisis.  We urge the Government of Ethiopia to cooperate with the UN Commission of Experts on Human Rights in Ethiopia.</p>
<p>Continued reports of atrocities underscore the urgency of ending the military conflict.  We strongly support the declarations of a cessation of hostilities by the Government of Ethiopia and the Tigray regional authority and welcome the news that they have been followed by initial convoys of life-saving assistance.  In keeping with these declarations, we renew our call on all armed actors to renounce and end human rights abuses and violence against civilians.  The United States reiterates its call for all foreign forces to withdraw from Ethiopia as well as for the regional state authorities to remove their security forces from neighboring regions.</p>
<p>We continue to urge all parties to take necessary steps to ensure the cessation of hostilities, unhindered and sustained humanitarian access, transparent investigations into human rights abuses and violations by all actors, and a negotiated resolution to the conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary McKeon’s Meeting with World Health Organization Director-General Ghebreyesus</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-mckeons-meeting-with-world-health-organization-director-general-ghebreyesus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 15:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brain P. McKeon met with World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Dr. Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus to discuss WHO sustainable financing and reform priorities. Deputy Secretary McKeon also expressed commitment to the pandemic instrument process, the continued efforts on amendments to the International Health Regulations, ongoing studies of COVID-19 origins, and Taiwan’s inclusion as an observer to the World Health Assembly.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brain P. McKeon met with World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Dr. Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus to discuss WHO sustainable financing and reform priorities. Deputy Secretary McKeon also expressed commitment to the pandemic instrument process, the continued efforts on amendments to the International Health Regulations, ongoing studies of COVID-19 origins, and Taiwan’s inclusion as an observer to the World Health Assembly.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
