<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 23:11:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Honoring the Legacies of Natalya Estemirova and Paul Klebnikov</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/honoring-the-legacies-of-natalya-estemirova-and-paul-klebnikov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 23:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>This month, the United States honors slain journalists Natalya Estemirova and Paul Klebnikov.  Klebnikov, a <em>Forbes</em> magazine journalist and U.S. citizen, investigated and exposed corruption in post-Soviet Russia.  On July 9, 2004, he was shot and killed in Moscow, likely in retaliation for his work.  Estemirova exposed the egregious human rights violations committed during the Second Chechen War as a human rights activist and journalist for <em>Novaya Gazeta.</em>  Estemirova was abducted in Grozny, Chechnya and killed on July 15, 2009.</p>
<p>The organizers and perpetrators of these heinous murders were never brought to justice, and violence and pressure against journalists continues with impunity in Russia.  The United States condemns the Russian government’s ongoing crackdown on independent media and stands in solidarity with independent Russian journalists and human rights defenders.</p>
<p>Estemirova’s and Klebnikov’s legacies will live on in their work, in the next generation of brave reporters they have inspired, and in the fight for human rights and against corruption in Russia.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>This month, the United States honors slain journalists Natalya Estemirova and Paul Klebnikov.  Klebnikov, a <em>Forbes</em> magazine journalist and U.S. citizen, investigated and exposed corruption in post-Soviet Russia.  On July 9, 2004, he was shot and killed in Moscow, likely in retaliation for his work.  Estemirova exposed the egregious human rights violations committed during the Second Chechen War as a human rights activist and journalist for <em>Novaya Gazeta.</em>  Estemirova was abducted in Grozny, Chechnya and killed on July 15, 2009.</p>
<p>The organizers and perpetrators of these heinous murders were never brought to justice, and violence and pressure against journalists continues with impunity in Russia.  The United States condemns the Russian government’s ongoing crackdown on independent media and stands in solidarity with independent Russian journalists and human rights defenders.</p>
<p>Estemirova’s and Klebnikov’s legacies will live on in their work, in the next generation of brave reporters they have inspired, and in the fight for human rights and against corruption in Russia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry&#8217;s Call with Russian President Putin During Meetings in Moscow, Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-john-kerrys-call-with-russian-president-putin-during-meetings-in-moscow-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',sans-serif; color: black;">Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry had a phone call on July 14 with Russian President Vladimir Putin to discuss U.S.-Russia cooperation on combatting the climate crisis.  Special Presidential Envoy Kerry emphasized that the United States and Russia have important roles to play, including on reducing greenhouse gas emissions in this critical decade, aiming for net-zero emissions in the long term, eliminating emissions from coal, and working to address Arctic-related climate issues under Russia’s chairmanship of the Arctic Council.  President Putin concurred about the need to redouble international climate efforts and affirmed Russia’s intention to address its own emissions, including in the forest sector, among other actions.  Recognizing recent extreme weather events and other climate impacts, as well as the urgency to act, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry and President Putin underscored the importance of the United States and Russia working together across a range of climate issues.  They also affirmed the importance of working toward a successful COP 26 in Glasgow, UK.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',sans-serif; color: black;">Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry had a phone call on July 14 with Russian President Vladimir Putin to discuss U.S.-Russia cooperation on combatting the climate crisis.  Special Presidential Envoy Kerry emphasized that the United States and Russia have important roles to play, including on reducing greenhouse gas emissions in this critical decade, aiming for net-zero emissions in the long term, eliminating emissions from coal, and working to address Arctic-related climate issues under Russia’s chairmanship of the Arctic Council.  President Putin concurred about the need to redouble international climate efforts and affirmed Russia’s intention to address its own emissions, including in the forest sector, among other actions.  Recognizing recent extreme weather events and other climate impacts, as well as the urgency to act, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry and President Putin underscored the importance of the United States and Russia working together across a range of climate issues.  They also affirmed the importance of working toward a successful COP 26 in Glasgow, UK.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Deputy Assistant Secretary for Passport Services Rachel Arndt, Bureau of Consular Affairs On the State Department’s Passport Services</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-deputy-assistant-secretary-for-passport-services-rachel-arndt-bureau-of-consular-affairs-on-the-state-departments-passport-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rachel Arndt, Deputy Assistant Secretary for Passport Services Bureau of Consular Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 17:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rachel Arndt, Deputy Assistant Secretary for Passport Services Bureau of Consular Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining the State Department’s press briefing on the status of our passport services. Joining us today is Deputy Assistant Secretary for Passport Services Rachel Arndt from the department’s Bureau of Consular Affairs. Deputy Assistant Secretary Arndt oversees and directs the department’s passports operations here in Washington, as well as its network of passport agencies and centers across the United States.</p>
<p>Today’s briefing is on the record; however, the contents will be embargoed until the end of the call. Deputy Assistant Secretary Arndt will begin with a brief opening statement, and then we’ll take your questions. With that, I’ll hand it over to you, DAS Arndt.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Good morning. Thank you for joining us today. As noted, I’m here to talk to you about the status of the State Department’s passport services. We as a department continue to recover from the effects of COVID-19 while we work to meet passport demand as U.S. citizens increasingly seek to travel overseas again. The success of the U.S. Government’s COVID-19 vaccination program means Americans will be able to get back to normal in many ways this summer. However, the pandemic’s disruptions continue to have a ripple effect on all steps of the passport process, including the amount of time it currently takes us to process a passport application.</p>
<p>We are surging staff, both adjudicators and contractors, back into the office at agencies across the country as COVID restrictions ease. But it will take time for our wait times to fall from the current 12 to 18 weeks to pre-pandemic levels. This means people who submit new passport applications right now will not get their new passport until well into the fall. Last-minute passport appointments are extremely limited. U.S. citizens who wish to travel overseas this summer and do not currently have a passport may need to make alternate travel plans.</p>
<p>We also want to remind U.S. citizens many parts of the world are experiencing additional waves of COVID-19, and they may have their travel plans unexpectedly interrupted due to the health situation in their destination. We’ve been doing and continue to do everything we can to serve the American public while prioritizing the health and safety of our staff and of our customers.</p>
<p>As we bring more staff back into the office, we will continue to be as transparent as possible in updating the American public on how long it will take to get a passport.</p>
<p>With that, I will take your questions. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Once again, for questions press 1-0, please. You will hear acknowledgment that you’ve been placed in queue. Just listen for your name on the line.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Let’s go to Christina Ruffini.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, good morning. I’m wondering, you said you’re surging staff back into the office, and contractors. When you say that, is that pre-pandemic levels? Are you seeking to add more staff in order to deal with the backlog? And what is the process for someone who needs an emergency passport or absolutely has to travel? Is there any way to expedite, and what are the odds of that happening? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Thank you, yes. We are ramping up our staffing, as noted. This summer we’re going to have over 150 staff returning to 21 agencies across the country, and that will increase our capacity to process applications more quickly. We are looking at surging back to pre-pandemic staffing levels and additional staff for both government and contractor staff.</p>
<p>The – as far as the second part of your question, for getting service right now, you can go online and make – get the application form for your passport and submit it by mail, if you’re eligible. And if you have to travel urgently and still need the passport, we do have extremely limited appointments for customers who have urgent international travel in the next 72 hours, or three business days, for reasons other than life-and-death emergencies. So that, you would need to go online to our online appointment system to make an appointment, and that appointment would have to be within three business days of the international travel. One caveat is if you need a foreign visa for your travel, the date of your appointment can be within 10 business days of your international travel.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi. Sorry. Sorry, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Okay, thanks. Sorry, I missed it just at the beginning. You said the wait times will be 12 to 18 weeks? And then also, can you address the issue of staff who are working on visas for foreigners looking to come into the United States? Do you have any sense of when the travel restrictions or the – for foreigners from Schengen countries and other nations like India and Brazil will be lifted? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT: </b>Let me address the second part of your question by saying that visa services are certainly outside of my swim lane. However, I will say that COVID-19 has been a disruptive force across the globe, and I know that many of our operations are impacted by that.</p>
<p>As far as – to go back to the routine passport processing times, currently our wait time for both new and renewal routine passport applications can be up to 18 weeks, and that includes our processing time, the initial internal intake of the applications, and mailing. Customers can pay an additional $60 to expedite their applications, and the wait times for the expedited applications are currently up to 12 weeks, and again, depending on the mailing time. We really encourage folks to apply for or renew their passport at least six months ahead of when you’ll need one to avoid any of those last-minute problems.</p>
<p>I would also note that when checking your expiration date, folks should also check the dates of their children’s passports as those are valid for only five years instead of the adults’, which are 10 years, and we find that people run into some difficulties if they don’t check their children’s passports. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Let’s go to Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you. We’ve heard from some travelers who have been unable to even get through on the renewal lines or the passport agency phone lines. They’ve cited long hold times followed by disconnections, and I’m wondering if your staffing surge also improves – includes improvements to those systems.</p>
<p>And then separately, the chairman and ranking member of the House Foreign Affairs Committee wrote to Secretary Blinken urging acceleration of processing and asking how Congress could potentially assist with resources or other steps, and I’m just wondering whether the department intends to respond by their Friday deadline. Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT: </b>Yes, thank you. I am certain that we have received that letter and will respond promptly. As to the call center, we note that the majority of the callers are actually requesting information on the status of their pending applications, which you can find that online at <a href="http://passportstatus.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://passportstatus.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626368951320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFqMdqSkcFodUv99qVA7qnruZvyMg">passportstatus.state.gov</a>. Representatives will not be able to provide the status updates by phone as they’re prioritizing life-or-death emergency appointments and expedite service upgrades. So it may take weeks for that status to be available as we are processing and intaking applications.</p>
<p>The passport information center, or our call center, is experiencing just unprecedented call volumes for many of the same reasons that our wait times are increasing. So we are addressing this by bringing on more staff to answer calls, as local conditions permit, and then working with our contractor for the call center to increase their staffing levels, and they are doing this with some aggressive hiring also, so also trying to surge on the call center staffing. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Let’s go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thanks for doing the call. Obviously, you know there’s huge interest in this issue. Two questions. One, what is the backlog, the current backlog of passports right now? I know you’ve mentioned the wait time, but how does that equate into actual applications that are sitting and waiting? And then secondly, I was curious. You mentioned that parents should also be looking at their children’s passports since they expire within a five-year period as opposed to a 10-year period. But as you know, children are required when they reapply to do it in-person – both parents need to be there. Quite an onerous process as opposed to just mailing it in, which is what you&#8217;re recommending for adults to do. Has there been any consideration of waiving those in-person requirements or those two-parent requirements for children to allow them to renew their passports online as well? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT: </b>Thank you. Yes, our backlog currently is somewhere in the range of a million and a half to 2 million applications. That is somewhat higher than what we would normally expect to see. However, that was really because as the travelers were ramping up with the vaccinations availability, the workload started coming in faster than we had – we would normally see. And you&#8217;re correct that we do require for the children’s passports to – and all first-time applicants actually must apply in person. And when we say “apply in person,” we can use a passport acceptance facility such as the post office, clerks of court, libraries, local government offices, and we do have information on <a href="http://travel.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://travel.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626368951320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGlCcSLQBfTgkRbazLCA_7nt49l8A">travel.state.gov</a> where people can locate the nearest location for that. And many of those facilities are also ramping back up their appointment availabilities similar to what we are doing. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Let’s go to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hey, thanks for doing this. Can you say how many, if any, of the regional passport offices are fully reopened? And if some of them are in cities that are fully reopened otherwise in accordance with their local restrictions, why aren’t these offices now fully reopened and fully restaffed so that they can take more appointments, more walk-in appointments, more emergency appointments? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes, as of July 12th, we had passport agencies where staff was returning, all of the staff was returning in 16 – I’m sorry, 17 cities. We have an additional five that we are anticipating approval to move to be completely open with all staff back in the office. What we are doing with the limited appointments, and those are available, again, on a first-come, first-served basis, is we are trying to address all of our workflow streams, and that means we have the majority of our work comes in through the mail. It takes four to five times longer to assist a customer at a counter than in the back room looking at the documentation, so what we’re doing to ensure that we get through all of the applications as quickly as possible is to continue to focus on those that are pending that people have applied for in the past several months. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Let’s go to Eric Katz.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you. I wanted to ask, first of all, how important is it to have workers in person? There’s in-person application process that you’ve gone over, but to what extent can sort of normal passport processing happen when the staff is working remotely? And secondly, when you talked about surging up offices, is there any actual new hiring taking place, or is this just returning employees who had been remote back to the office and adding contractors? I – just to add on to that – sorry – I know there was this – the department told the IG in 2019 that there was a critical shortage of passport specialists, so has that been addressed, and are you trying to add on to the that? Are you still trying to get back to sort of the normal level?</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes. So our – actually, passport specialists need to be physically present in the office to process the passports. They are not processing remotely or from home. What we have for our issuance process, we require a connectivity to systems and databases that are currently only accessible from within our facilities. So we’re trying to adjudicate on site to help us safeguard the customers’ personally identifiable information and to ensure the integrity of the entire application process. So we’re maintaining very high standards of security and privacy protection for the customers, and we’re securing their sensitive documents like their birth certificates and naturalization certificates in our offices. And, of course, the physical printing and mailing of the passport books and cards occurs from our facility.</p>
<p>As to the hiring, we are doing dual-track, as you noted, bringing back additional folks who had been out of the office and we are also ramping up and surging to meet the higher demand levels. It does take some time to hire staff, but we – in the interim, we have – in addition to surging our staff for both contract and government, we are expanding our overtime work at all locations and we are continuing to increase the number of appointments available at all of our public passport agencies and centers. And then we are also working with our partners to expand staffing capacity at the front end for processing at our lockbox facilities where they open the mail and enter – data enter the information into the system so it’s accessible to us. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you for doing the call. What about the U.S. citizens who are abroad and they need to renew their passports? Do they have to wait between 12 and 18 weeks too?</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes, our embassies and consulates are currently providing emergency passport services and in some cases routine passport services to U.S. citizens overseas. That is dependent upon the particular location. So anyone who needs passport services abroad, the U.S. citizen should contact the U.S. embassy or consulate that’s closest to them, and they can find information on the services and the operations available on each of the embassies’ or consulates’ webpage. And – that information is updated weekly. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Let’s take our last question from Ted Daniel, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, good morning. Is State aware that people are selling passport appointments online and is anything being done to stop that?</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes, we are aware of the issues and we are working to prevent them. The Department of State does not charge a fee to solely book an emergency appointment at one of our agencies or centers, so if anyone receives a request for payment for scheduling a U.S. passport appointment, that should be considered fraudulent. You can go online and see the full schedule of passport fees, again, on <a href="http://travel.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://travel.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626368951320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGlCcSLQBfTgkRbazLCA_7nt49l8A">travel.state.gov</a> if anyone is interested in that.</p>
<p>And I’d also like to say that the department is not affiliated with any third-party appointment booking services, and we’ve seen numerous instances of falsified appointment bookings through these vendors. And unfortunately, we may not be able to honor appointments booked via third party, so we are aware and are working to try to rectify that situation. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> It looks like we have Courtney McBride of <i>Wall Street Journal</i> back in the queue. Courtney, if you’re with us, we’ll actually take you as the last question.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you so much. The department has attributed some of these extended turnaround times not just to staffing but to delays with the postal service, and for its part, USPS expressed some surprise when we talked to them about this estimate of six weeks’ mailing time between the consumer and the processing facilities. I’m just wondering if you can explain how you arrived at that number and where the discrepancy might lie.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Thank you. Yes, we have – that part of the process is not something, obviously, that we can control. So what we are relying on that is the – some anecdotal evidence from when passport applicants have identified that they have submitted their application and when it is received at our processing or intake processing facility. And it’s only when it’s received at our processing facility that we can actually track it and then only when it’s data entered that we will be able to provide a status update to the applicant on their passport.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Thank you all for joining this morning’s press briefing. That concludes the contents of the briefing. The embargo is now lifted. Have a wonderful rest of your day.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rachel Arndt, Deputy Assistant Secretary for Passport Services Bureau of Consular Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining the State Department’s press briefing on the status of our passport services. Joining us today is Deputy Assistant Secretary for Passport Services Rachel Arndt from the department’s Bureau of Consular Affairs. Deputy Assistant Secretary Arndt oversees and directs the department’s passports operations here in Washington, as well as its network of passport agencies and centers across the United States.</p>
<p>Today’s briefing is on the record; however, the contents will be embargoed until the end of the call. Deputy Assistant Secretary Arndt will begin with a brief opening statement, and then we’ll take your questions. With that, I’ll hand it over to you, DAS Arndt.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Good morning. Thank you for joining us today. As noted, I’m here to talk to you about the status of the State Department’s passport services. We as a department continue to recover from the effects of COVID-19 while we work to meet passport demand as U.S. citizens increasingly seek to travel overseas again. The success of the U.S. Government’s COVID-19 vaccination program means Americans will be able to get back to normal in many ways this summer. However, the pandemic’s disruptions continue to have a ripple effect on all steps of the passport process, including the amount of time it currently takes us to process a passport application.</p>
<p>We are surging staff, both adjudicators and contractors, back into the office at agencies across the country as COVID restrictions ease. But it will take time for our wait times to fall from the current 12 to 18 weeks to pre-pandemic levels. This means people who submit new passport applications right now will not get their new passport until well into the fall. Last-minute passport appointments are extremely limited. U.S. citizens who wish to travel overseas this summer and do not currently have a passport may need to make alternate travel plans.</p>
<p>We also want to remind U.S. citizens many parts of the world are experiencing additional waves of COVID-19, and they may have their travel plans unexpectedly interrupted due to the health situation in their destination. We’ve been doing and continue to do everything we can to serve the American public while prioritizing the health and safety of our staff and of our customers.</p>
<p>As we bring more staff back into the office, we will continue to be as transparent as possible in updating the American public on how long it will take to get a passport.</p>
<p>With that, I will take your questions. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b> Once again, for questions press 1-0, please. You will hear acknowledgment that you’ve been placed in queue. Just listen for your name on the line.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Let’s go to Christina Ruffini.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, good morning. I’m wondering, you said you’re surging staff back into the office, and contractors. When you say that, is that pre-pandemic levels? Are you seeking to add more staff in order to deal with the backlog? And what is the process for someone who needs an emergency passport or absolutely has to travel? Is there any way to expedite, and what are the odds of that happening? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Thank you, yes. We are ramping up our staffing, as noted. This summer we’re going to have over 150 staff returning to 21 agencies across the country, and that will increase our capacity to process applications more quickly. We are looking at surging back to pre-pandemic staffing levels and additional staff for both government and contractor staff.</p>
<p>The – as far as the second part of your question, for getting service right now, you can go online and make – get the application form for your passport and submit it by mail, if you’re eligible. And if you have to travel urgently and still need the passport, we do have extremely limited appointments for customers who have urgent international travel in the next 72 hours, or three business days, for reasons other than life-and-death emergencies. So that, you would need to go online to our online appointment system to make an appointment, and that appointment would have to be within three business days of the international travel. One caveat is if you need a foreign visa for your travel, the date of your appointment can be within 10 business days of your international travel.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi. Sorry. Sorry, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Okay, thanks. Sorry, I missed it just at the beginning. You said the wait times will be 12 to 18 weeks? And then also, can you address the issue of staff who are working on visas for foreigners looking to come into the United States? Do you have any sense of when the travel restrictions or the – for foreigners from Schengen countries and other nations like India and Brazil will be lifted? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT: </b>Let me address the second part of your question by saying that visa services are certainly outside of my swim lane. However, I will say that COVID-19 has been a disruptive force across the globe, and I know that many of our operations are impacted by that.</p>
<p>As far as – to go back to the routine passport processing times, currently our wait time for both new and renewal routine passport applications can be up to 18 weeks, and that includes our processing time, the initial internal intake of the applications, and mailing. Customers can pay an additional $60 to expedite their applications, and the wait times for the expedited applications are currently up to 12 weeks, and again, depending on the mailing time. We really encourage folks to apply for or renew their passport at least six months ahead of when you’ll need one to avoid any of those last-minute problems.</p>
<p>I would also note that when checking your expiration date, folks should also check the dates of their children’s passports as those are valid for only five years instead of the adults’, which are 10 years, and we find that people run into some difficulties if they don’t check their children’s passports. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Let’s go to Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Thank you. We’ve heard from some travelers who have been unable to even get through on the renewal lines or the passport agency phone lines. They’ve cited long hold times followed by disconnections, and I’m wondering if your staffing surge also improves – includes improvements to those systems.</p>
<p>And then separately, the chairman and ranking member of the House Foreign Affairs Committee wrote to Secretary Blinken urging acceleration of processing and asking how Congress could potentially assist with resources or other steps, and I’m just wondering whether the department intends to respond by their Friday deadline. Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT: </b>Yes, thank you. I am certain that we have received that letter and will respond promptly. As to the call center, we note that the majority of the callers are actually requesting information on the status of their pending applications, which you can find that online at <a href="http://passportstatus.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://passportstatus.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626368951320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFqMdqSkcFodUv99qVA7qnruZvyMg">passportstatus.state.gov</a>. Representatives will not be able to provide the status updates by phone as they’re prioritizing life-or-death emergency appointments and expedite service upgrades. So it may take weeks for that status to be available as we are processing and intaking applications.</p>
<p>The passport information center, or our call center, is experiencing just unprecedented call volumes for many of the same reasons that our wait times are increasing. So we are addressing this by bringing on more staff to answer calls, as local conditions permit, and then working with our contractor for the call center to increase their staffing levels, and they are doing this with some aggressive hiring also, so also trying to surge on the call center staffing. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b>Let’s go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thanks for doing the call. Obviously, you know there’s huge interest in this issue. Two questions. One, what is the backlog, the current backlog of passports right now? I know you’ve mentioned the wait time, but how does that equate into actual applications that are sitting and waiting? And then secondly, I was curious. You mentioned that parents should also be looking at their children’s passports since they expire within a five-year period as opposed to a 10-year period. But as you know, children are required when they reapply to do it in-person – both parents need to be there. Quite an onerous process as opposed to just mailing it in, which is what you&#8217;re recommending for adults to do. Has there been any consideration of waiving those in-person requirements or those two-parent requirements for children to allow them to renew their passports online as well? Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT: </b>Thank you. Yes, our backlog currently is somewhere in the range of a million and a half to 2 million applications. That is somewhat higher than what we would normally expect to see. However, that was really because as the travelers were ramping up with the vaccinations availability, the workload started coming in faster than we had – we would normally see. And you&#8217;re correct that we do require for the children’s passports to – and all first-time applicants actually must apply in person. And when we say “apply in person,” we can use a passport acceptance facility such as the post office, clerks of court, libraries, local government offices, and we do have information on <a href="http://travel.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://travel.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626368951320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGlCcSLQBfTgkRbazLCA_7nt49l8A">travel.state.gov</a> where people can locate the nearest location for that. And many of those facilities are also ramping back up their appointment availabilities similar to what we are doing. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Let’s go to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hey, thanks for doing this. Can you say how many, if any, of the regional passport offices are fully reopened? And if some of them are in cities that are fully reopened otherwise in accordance with their local restrictions, why aren’t these offices now fully reopened and fully restaffed so that they can take more appointments, more walk-in appointments, more emergency appointments? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes, as of July 12th, we had passport agencies where staff was returning, all of the staff was returning in 16 – I’m sorry, 17 cities. We have an additional five that we are anticipating approval to move to be completely open with all staff back in the office. What we are doing with the limited appointments, and those are available, again, on a first-come, first-served basis, is we are trying to address all of our workflow streams, and that means we have the majority of our work comes in through the mail. It takes four to five times longer to assist a customer at a counter than in the back room looking at the documentation, so what we’re doing to ensure that we get through all of the applications as quickly as possible is to continue to focus on those that are pending that people have applied for in the past several months. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Let’s go to Eric Katz.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you. I wanted to ask, first of all, how important is it to have workers in person? There’s in-person application process that you’ve gone over, but to what extent can sort of normal passport processing happen when the staff is working remotely? And secondly, when you talked about surging up offices, is there any actual new hiring taking place, or is this just returning employees who had been remote back to the office and adding contractors? I – just to add on to that – sorry – I know there was this – the department told the IG in 2019 that there was a critical shortage of passport specialists, so has that been addressed, and are you trying to add on to the that? Are you still trying to get back to sort of the normal level?</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes. So our – actually, passport specialists need to be physically present in the office to process the passports. They are not processing remotely or from home. What we have for our issuance process, we require a connectivity to systems and databases that are currently only accessible from within our facilities. So we’re trying to adjudicate on site to help us safeguard the customers’ personally identifiable information and to ensure the integrity of the entire application process. So we’re maintaining very high standards of security and privacy protection for the customers, and we’re securing their sensitive documents like their birth certificates and naturalization certificates in our offices. And, of course, the physical printing and mailing of the passport books and cards occurs from our facility.</p>
<p>As to the hiring, we are doing dual-track, as you noted, bringing back additional folks who had been out of the office and we are also ramping up and surging to meet the higher demand levels. It does take some time to hire staff, but we – in the interim, we have – in addition to surging our staff for both contract and government, we are expanding our overtime work at all locations and we are continuing to increase the number of appointments available at all of our public passport agencies and centers. And then we are also working with our partners to expand staffing capacity at the front end for processing at our lockbox facilities where they open the mail and enter – data enter the information into the system so it’s accessible to us. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you for doing the call. What about the U.S. citizens who are abroad and they need to renew their passports? Do they have to wait between 12 and 18 weeks too?</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes, our embassies and consulates are currently providing emergency passport services and in some cases routine passport services to U.S. citizens overseas. That is dependent upon the particular location. So anyone who needs passport services abroad, the U.S. citizen should contact the U.S. embassy or consulate that’s closest to them, and they can find information on the services and the operations available on each of the embassies’ or consulates’ webpage. And – that information is updated weekly. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Let’s take our last question from Ted Daniel, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi, good morning. Is State aware that people are selling passport appointments online and is anything being done to stop that?</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Yes, we are aware of the issues and we are working to prevent them. The Department of State does not charge a fee to solely book an emergency appointment at one of our agencies or centers, so if anyone receives a request for payment for scheduling a U.S. passport appointment, that should be considered fraudulent. You can go online and see the full schedule of passport fees, again, on <a href="http://travel.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://travel.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626368951320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGlCcSLQBfTgkRbazLCA_7nt49l8A">travel.state.gov</a> if anyone is interested in that.</p>
<p>And I’d also like to say that the department is not affiliated with any third-party appointment booking services, and we’ve seen numerous instances of falsified appointment bookings through these vendors. And unfortunately, we may not be able to honor appointments booked via third party, so we are aware and are working to try to rectify that situation. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> It looks like we have Courtney McBride of <i>Wall Street Journal</i> back in the queue. Courtney, if you’re with us, we’ll actually take you as the last question.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you so much. The department has attributed some of these extended turnaround times not just to staffing but to delays with the postal service, and for its part, USPS expressed some surprise when we talked to them about this estimate of six weeks’ mailing time between the consumer and the processing facilities. I’m just wondering if you can explain how you arrived at that number and where the discrepancy might lie.</p>
<p><b>MS ARNDT:</b> Thank you. Yes, we have – that part of the process is not something, obviously, that we can control. So what we are relying on that is the – some anecdotal evidence from when passport applicants have identified that they have submitted their application and when it is received at our processing or intake processing facility. And it’s only when it’s received at our processing facility that we can actually track it and then only when it’s data entered that we will be able to provide a status update to the applicant on their passport.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b> Thank you all for joining this morning’s press briefing. That concludes the contents of the briefing. The embargo is now lifted. Have a wonderful rest of your day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Armenian Acting Prime Minister Pashinyan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-armenian-acting-prime-minister-pashinyan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259097</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Armenian acting Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan of Armenia.  The Secretary offered hearty congratulations to the people of Armenia following the June 20 elections, in which the OSCE’s Office for Democratic Institutions and Human Rights found that voters’ fundamental rights and freedoms were generally respected, and contestants were able to campaign freely.  He urged continued democratic reforms.</p>
<p>The Secretary highlighted U.S. support for the Minsk Group Co-Chairs process aimed at a lasting political settlement to the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.  He encouraged Armenia to engage constructively at the OSCE.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed his support for the expeditious return of all Armenian detainees from Azerbaijan to Armenia.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Armenian acting Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan of Armenia.  The Secretary offered hearty congratulations to the people of Armenia following the June 20 elections, in which the OSCE’s Office for Democratic Institutions and Human Rights found that voters’ fundamental rights and freedoms were generally respected, and contestants were able to campaign freely.  He urged continued democratic reforms.</p>
<p>The Secretary highlighted U.S. support for the Minsk Group Co-Chairs process aimed at a lasting political settlement to the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.  He encouraged Armenia to engage constructively at the OSCE.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed his support for the expeditious return of all Armenian detainees from Azerbaijan to Armenia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Canadian Foreign Minister Garneau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-canadian-foreign-minister-garneau-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259094</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The below is attributable to State Department Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Canadian Minister of Foreign Affairs Marc Garneau today to discuss collaboration between the United States and Canada to defeat the COVID-19 pandemic and the Foreign Minister’s trip to the Middle East.  Noting our shared democratic values, they also discussed efforts to promote democracy and security throughout the Western Hemisphere.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Garneau also reviewed progress towards the goals as outlined in the Roadmap for a Renewed U.S.-Canada Partnership.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The below is attributable to State Department Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Canadian Minister of Foreign Affairs Marc Garneau today to discuss collaboration between the United States and Canada to defeat the COVID-19 pandemic and the Foreign Minister’s trip to the Middle East.  Noting our shared democratic values, they also discussed efforts to promote democracy and security throughout the Western Hemisphere.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Garneau also reviewed progress towards the goals as outlined in the Roadmap for a Renewed U.S.-Canada Partnership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Mozambican President Nyusi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-mozambican-president-nyusi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mozambican President Filipe Nyusi.  The Secretary and President reaffirmed the strength and importance of U.S.-Mozambique relations and our joint commitment to countering ISIS.  The Secretary underscored U.S. support for Mozambique’s efforts against COVID-19, building on our long-standing investments in the country’s health sector.  The Secretary expressed a desire for further collaboration on economic development and governance.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mozambican President Filipe Nyusi.  The Secretary and President reaffirmed the strength and importance of U.S.-Mozambique relations and our joint commitment to countering ISIS.  The Secretary underscored U.S. support for Mozambique’s efforts against COVID-19, building on our long-standing investments in the country’s health sector.  The Secretary expressed a desire for further collaboration on economic development and governance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bastille Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/bastille-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 04:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I send my warm wishes to the people of France as they celebrate their national day.</p>
<p>We have an enduring and close relationship with France, our oldest Ally.  In the spirit of “Liberté, Égalité, and Fraternité,” the United States cherishes its relationship with France, defined by our shared values and belief in democracy and human rights.  We fought side by side through two World Wars and worked together in the aftermath to create a more prosperous and secure Europe.  We recognize and appreciate French contributions to global security, including in Africa and in the Middle East, and applaud French leadership on climate, including the Paris Agreement.  The United States is committed to working with France to combat the climate crisis and to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic.  Our nations’ partnership is extensive and multifaceted, and we highly value France’s contributions to creating a more peaceful and prosperous world.</p>
<p>Best wishes to the people of France for a joyous national day and a successful year ahead.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I send my warm wishes to the people of France as they celebrate their national day.</p>
<p>We have an enduring and close relationship with France, our oldest Ally.  In the spirit of “Liberté, Égalité, and Fraternité,” the United States cherishes its relationship with France, defined by our shared values and belief in democracy and human rights.  We fought side by side through two World Wars and worked together in the aftermath to create a more prosperous and secure Europe.  We recognize and appreciate French contributions to global security, including in Africa and in the Middle East, and applaud French leadership on climate, including the Paris Agreement.  The United States is committed to working with France to combat the climate crisis and to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic.  Our nations’ partnership is extensive and multifaceted, and we highly value France’s contributions to creating a more peaceful and prosperous world.</p>
<p>Best wishes to the people of France for a joyous national day and a successful year ahead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with ASEAN Foreign Ministers and the ASEAN Secretary General</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-asean-foreign-ministers-and-the-asean-secretary-general/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 03:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with foreign ministers of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the ASEAN Secretary General during the Special ASEAN-U.S. Foreign Ministerial Meeting. The Secretary reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to ASEAN centrality and underscored ASEAN’s essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture. The Secretary and the ASEAN foreign ministers pledged to continue building the ASEAN-U.S. strategic partnership based on human rights and fundamental freedoms, economic prosperity, and strong people-to-people ties.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken stressed the U.S. commitment to working with ASEAN and international partners to combat the COVID-19 pandemic. He also emphasized the importance of taking bold action to address the climate crisis. The Secretary underscored the United States’ rejection of the PRC’s unlawful maritime claims in the South China Sea and reiterated that the United States stands with Southeast Asian claimants in the face of PRC coercion. He pledged continued U.S. support for a free and open Mekong region under the Mekong-U.S. Partnership.</p>
<p>Expressing deep concerns about the military coup in Burma, Secretary Blinken recalled the principles of the ASEAN Charter related to the rule of law, good governance, democracy, and human rights. He called on ASEAN to take joint action to urge the end of violence, the restoration of Burma’s democratic transition, and the release of all those unjustly detained. The Secretary said that ASEAN’s five-point consensus is an important step forward and urged ASEAN to take immediate action to hold the Burmese regime accountable to the consensus and to appoint a special envoy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with foreign ministers of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the ASEAN Secretary General during the Special ASEAN-U.S. Foreign Ministerial Meeting. The Secretary reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to ASEAN centrality and underscored ASEAN’s essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture. The Secretary and the ASEAN foreign ministers pledged to continue building the ASEAN-U.S. strategic partnership based on human rights and fundamental freedoms, economic prosperity, and strong people-to-people ties.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken stressed the U.S. commitment to working with ASEAN and international partners to combat the COVID-19 pandemic. He also emphasized the importance of taking bold action to address the climate crisis. The Secretary underscored the United States’ rejection of the PRC’s unlawful maritime claims in the South China Sea and reiterated that the United States stands with Southeast Asian claimants in the face of PRC coercion. He pledged continued U.S. support for a free and open Mekong region under the Mekong-U.S. Partnership.</p>
<p>Expressing deep concerns about the military coup in Burma, Secretary Blinken recalled the principles of the ASEAN Charter related to the rule of law, good governance, democracy, and human rights. He called on ASEAN to take joint action to urge the end of violence, the restoration of Burma’s democratic transition, and the release of all those unjustly detained. The Secretary said that ASEAN’s five-point consensus is an important step forward and urged ASEAN to take immediate action to hold the Burmese regime accountable to the consensus and to appoint a special envoy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Leadership on Human Rights and Ending Systemic Racism</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-leadership-on-human-rights-and-ending-systemic-racism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This Administration is deeply dedicated to addressing racial injustice and inequities at home and abroad. On the global stage, the United States is leading by example.</p>
<p>Last month, the UN’s High Commissioner for Human Rights released a report on racism and police brutality against Africans and people of African descent at the hands of law enforcement around the world, which includes examination of such cases in the United States. As the President has repeatedly made clear, great nations such as ours do not hide from our shortcomings; they acknowledge them openly and strive to improve with transparency. In so doing, we not only work to set the standard for national responses to these challenges, we also strengthen our democracy, and give new hope and motivation to human rights defenders across the globe.</p>
<p>It is in this context that the United States intends to issue a formal, standing invitation to all UN experts who report and advise on thematic human rights issues. As a first step, we have reached out to offer an official visit by the UN Special Rapporteur on contemporary forms of racism and the UN Special Rapporteur on minority issues. I also welcome the UN Human Rights Council’s adoption today in Geneva of a resolution to address systemic racism against Africans and people of African descent in the context of law enforcement. I look forward to engaging with the new mechanism to advance racial justice and equity.</p>
<p>Responsible nations must not shrink from scrutiny of their human rights record; rather, they should acknowledge it with the intent to improve. I urge all UN member states to join the United States in this effort, and confront the scourge of racism, racial discrimination, and xenophobia. Because when all people – regardless of their race or ethnicity – are free to live up to their full potential, our collective security is strengthened.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This Administration is deeply dedicated to addressing racial injustice and inequities at home and abroad. On the global stage, the United States is leading by example.</p>
<p>Last month, the UN’s High Commissioner for Human Rights released a report on racism and police brutality against Africans and people of African descent at the hands of law enforcement around the world, which includes examination of such cases in the United States. As the President has repeatedly made clear, great nations such as ours do not hide from our shortcomings; they acknowledge them openly and strive to improve with transparency. In so doing, we not only work to set the standard for national responses to these challenges, we also strengthen our democracy, and give new hope and motivation to human rights defenders across the globe.</p>
<p>It is in this context that the United States intends to issue a formal, standing invitation to all UN experts who report and advise on thematic human rights issues. As a first step, we have reached out to offer an official visit by the UN Special Rapporteur on contemporary forms of racism and the UN Special Rapporteur on minority issues. I also welcome the UN Human Rights Council’s adoption today in Geneva of a resolution to address systemic racism against Africans and people of African descent in the context of law enforcement. I look forward to engaging with the new mechanism to advance racial justice and equity.</p>
<p>Responsible nations must not shrink from scrutiny of their human rights record; rather, they should acknowledge it with the intent to improve. I urge all UN member states to join the United States in this effort, and confront the scourge of racism, racial discrimination, and xenophobia. Because when all people – regardless of their race or ethnicity – are free to live up to their full potential, our collective security is strengthened.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence’s (NSCAI) Global Emerging Technology Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-national-security-commission-on-artificial-intelligences-nscai-global-emerging-technology-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 23:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Mayflower Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you all very, very much.  It is actually wonderful to be in a room with real people – (laughter) – with friends, with colleagues and without masks too.  So in and of itself, that’s a very positive thing.</p>
<p>But there is a lot to be positive about today, and it starts with the remarkable work of the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence, especially the work of my friend Eric Schmidt, another friend and close colleague Bob Work, who I haven’t seen yet but hopefully is here, and – Bob, there you are – and the executive director Ylli Bajraktari.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for this remarkable effort.  I am in your debt, and quite frankly the country is going to be in your debt for the work that you’ve done.  I’m going to put this down.</p>
<p>And I really want to thank the members of Congress who have come together across party lines to launch this enterprise at what is a pivotal moment for our country, and I think for the world at large.</p>
<p>Today, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Defense, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Commerce, the National Security Advisor, the director of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy.</p>
<p>In and of itself, that is testament to how seriously the administration takes these issues.  And again, that’s in no small part due to the work of this commission.</p>
<p>You have helped clarify the links among AI, the broader set of emerging technologies, strategic competition, and our national security and prosperity.</p>
<p>And you have made crystal clear that our country needs to play catch-up and to do it fast.  And not just our country.  Countries around the world.  And I’ll come to that.</p>
<p>We’re moving quickly, because we want to ensure that as AI and related technologies transform how we live, how we work, how we compete, how we defend ourselves, that we’re staying ahead of change, indeed that we are shaping change and, critically, making sure it delivers for our people.</p>
<p>My colleagues, I think, have very capably covered the administration’s work on these issues as it relates to our domestic renewal, our economy, and our defense.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do today is to focus on the State Department’s distinct role, because diplomacy will be critical.</p>
<p>Working with partners and allies to develop and deploy technology is going to help us tackle the most urgent challenges we face, from pandemics to the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Diplomacy will also be essential to mitigating risks, from preventing cyber attacks that target our businesses, to regulating technology that threatens our privacy, to defending our democratic values and way of life.</p>
<p>And let me just pause for a second on that last point, because I think it deserves emphasis.  It’s fundamentally what’s at stake here.</p>
<p>More than anything else, our task is to put forth and carry out a compelling vision for how to use technology in a way that serves our people, protects our interests and upholds our democratic values.  It’s not enough to highlight the horrors of techno-authoritarianism, to point to what countries like China and Russia are doing, and say that it’s wrong and dangerous, even as it is.  We’ve also got to make the positive case for our own approach, and then we’ve got to deliver.  That is the challenge before us.</p>
<p>We need the United States and we need its partners to remain the world’s innovative leaders and standard setters, to ensure that universal rights and democratic values remain at the center of all the innovation that’s to come, and that it delivers real benefits in people’s lives.  That fundamentally is the test that we have to pass, and it’s a test I think you’ve heard President Biden allude to.</p>
<p>In short, democracies have to pass the tech test together.  And diplomacy, I believe, has a big role to play in that.</p>
<p>Now, any time you hear someone from the State Department talking, we’re likely to throw in pillars and frameworks and tranches, so I can’t be any different today.  We have to have our pillars, so let me walk you through six of them – (laughter) – that cover the approach to these issues.  I know you’d be disappointed without it.</p>
<p>The first is reducing the national security risks posed by malicious cyber activities and emerging technologies.</p>
<p>This is the most basic thing our diplomacy has to do: protect our people, protect our networks, prevent conflict, and establish standards of responsible conduct in cyberspace.</p>
<p>Already, we’ve brought countries together around an approach that recognizes international law to make it clear that countries are governed in cyberspace just like they are offline and that defines norms that apply not only in wartime but in peacetime too, because we’re now dealing with significant cyber incidents outside the context of war.</p>
<p>We’ve also called for practical confidence-building measures; for example, steps as simple as establishing points of contact, so that in the event of a major cyber incident we actually know who to call.  Under American leadership, UN member-states have come together repeatedly to reaffirm this basic framework.</p>
<p>Now we’re working to bring allies and partners along to respond collectively when others engage in malicious cyber activity.  That’s what happened after the SolarWinds intrusion.  We attributed it to Russia; 22 countries, the European Union, NATO quickly supported that conclusion.  And that’s important, because when we speak with one voice, we can more effectively deter future bad acts.</p>
<p>Last month, as some of you will have noted, at the NATO summit, NATO reaffirmed that a cyber attack could trigger Article V – “an attack on one is an attack on all” – and that’s an important step too in deterring those attacks and protecting our national security in the cyber age.</p>
<p>We’re also treating ransomware not only as a law enforcement issue but also as a national security issue.  Ransomware and other cyber crimes affect all of us – our businesses, local governments; our most critical infrastructure, from power grids to hospitals.  As you know, one in four Americans has been the victim of a cyber crime, at a cost of more than $4 billion every single year.  That’s a direct threat to the safety, to the well-being of our people, and so it’s at the top of our diplomatic agenda.</p>
<p>And it’s also why we’re elevating ransomware in our engagements with Russia.  Our message is clear:  Countries that harbor cyber criminals have a responsibility to take action.  If they don’t, we will.  We’re strengthening our diplomatic and foreign assistance tools to fight transnational cyber criminals, and we’re working to expand membership in the global cyber crime treaty known as the Budapest Convention.</p>
<p>We’ll launch similar efforts on AI and other emerging technologies.  If they’re going to be used as part of our national defense, we want the world to have a shared understanding of how to do that responsibly, in the same way that we’ve hammered out rules for how to use conventional and nuclear weapons.  That’s how we reduce the risk of proliferation.  It’s how we prevent escalation or unintended incidents.</p>
<p>The second pillar is ensuring that our leadership in the fierce strategic technology competition that’s now underway not only continues but grows and strengthens.</p>
<p>We know China is determined to become the world’s technology leader.  And they have a well-resourced and comprehensive plan to achieve those ambitions.</p>
<p>We must preserve our competitive and comparative advantages.</p>
<p>That means building resilient, diverse, and secure supply chains for critical technologies.  Our proposed investments in semiconductor manufacturing here at home is an important part of that.  And again, I really want to underscore the very important work that was done on a bipartisan basis in Congress to help allow us to do that.</p>
<p>But I think you know this too:  We can’t onshore everything.  We don’t need to.  We’ll work with partners to “friend-shore” and “near-shore” our supply chains, and that will make all of us more resilient.</p>
<p>We’ll protect information communications technologies.  The Biden-Harris administration is committed to 5G security.  And we’re promoting the use of trusted and diverse vendors, including American companies, and advocating in multilateral settings for high standards for security and for trust.</p>
<p>We’re taking a fresh look at tools like export controls, investment screening, visa screening, to make sure our strategic competitors are not exploiting our own innovative ecosystems to gain military or national security advantage.</p>
<p>Today we also know that it’s harder to ensure that American innovations are used for commercial purposes only.  Countries like China don’t differentiate between civilian and military in the same way, and emerging technologies, including AI applications, blur that line too.  So we’ve got to think differently about how to protect our innovation and industries against that kind of misuse.</p>
<p>And of course, we need to do this at the same time that we’re growing our talent pipelines.  Perhaps more than any other factor, having the right people will determine whether we win the competition for the future.  We’ve got to recruit, we’ve got to retain the top talent, including talent from around the world, so that the best and the brightest study here, stay here, feel welcome here.</p>
<p>The third pillar: defending an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet.</p>
<p>We’ve been fighting for this vision of the internet for a long, long time.  Many of you in this room have been engaged in that effort.  These principles created the conditions that allowed the internet to grow into the transformative force that it’s become: an extraordinary resource for learning, for connection, for economic growth.</p>
<p>But the hard truth is that the internet is also growing more closed, more insecure, more fractured every single day.</p>
<p>We see country after country putting up firewalls, controlling speech, targeting activists, shutting down the internet to squelch dissent.  And while authoritarian regimes deny access to their networks, they actively reach into others and into ours, taking advantage and meddling in more open societies.  It’s no wonder that some countries are asking whether the principles around which we’ve organized the internet are still relevant, are still tenable.</p>
<p>In many ways, we are at an inflection point, some would say even a tipping point.  And our choice is between giving up on our vision for the internet or stepping up the fight.  We will step up the fight.</p>
<p>We’ll defend the principles of an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet across the full spectrum of our engagement – from trade agreements to governance to hardware.  We’ll use our diplomacy to unite governments and the private sector more firmly behind these efforts.  The work we do today will determine what the internet looks like just a few years from now.  That’s a responsibility we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>The fourth pillar I want to talk about is setting technical standards and creating norms for emerging technologies.</p>
<p>Technical standards help ensure quality, protect consumer health and safety, facilitate global interoperability.  They also help overcome trade barriers and expand market access.</p>
<p>We believe in a transparent, consensus-based, and private sector-led approach to developing standards for emerging technologies.  That’s how we’ll arrive at standards that are technologically sound, have earned people’s trust, reflect our values, and help American companies compete on a level playing field.</p>
<p>And norms, of course, are standards of another kind.  We’ll work with partners to ensure that technologies are developed and deployed in ethical ways that respect people’s rights.</p>
<p>That’s what we did at the UN International Telecommunications Union just a few months ago.  Some countries proposed norms that would allow the use, for example, of facial recognition technology in ways that could threaten human rights.  We brought governments and businesses together to stop it.</p>
<p>Whenever rules and norms that affect American lives are being debated and decided, American diplomats won’t be just – won’t just be in the room; we will be leading the charge.</p>
<p>The fifth pillar is this:  It’s making technology work for democracy.</p>
<p>Some of the leading threats to democracies today are playing out, as you all know, in cyberspace. We have to be leading the world’s efforts, and particularly the world’s democracies, in responding to those threats – fighting back against disinformation, standing up for internet freedom, reducing the misuse of surveillance technology.</p>
<p>We’ve got to make sure that our companies are not inadvertently fueling authoritarian practices, whether it’s in China or anywhere else.</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve released “surveillance due diligence guidance” to try to help American companies prevent their products from being misused.</p>
<p>Technology is also disrupting democracies from within – challenging the ways we think about privacy, free speech, the power of government, and corporations.  President Biden will take on these issues here at home.  For example, his new executive order on promoting competition in the U.S. economy asks the FTC to establish rules for companies on surveillance and how to treat personal data.</p>
<p>But democracies have to work together on these issues as well.  We need to close the gaps in regulatory and legal frameworks so that democracies can collaborate more easily on issues like privacy, content moderation, data sharing, and on digital trade.</p>
<p>You all know very well these are incredibly complicated issues.  The world’s democracies are not all on the same page on every single one of them.  But at heart we do share the same principles, and I have confidence that we can work together through the differences that we have.  I can tell you this:  It is a diplomatic priority for the United States to do that.</p>
<p>So is advancing trustworthy AI.  We need be able to reassure our citizens that AI is secure, that it does not have bias embedded in it, that it can be used safely.  And here, we’re grateful for a lot of good work happening in some critical organizations, including at the OECD and the Global Partnership on AI.  This is very important, too.</p>
<p>We’re interested in increasing access to shared public data sets for AI training and testing, while still preserving privacy – especially in sectors like health, climate, and energy, where AI could create transformational breakthroughs.</p>
<p>Finally, the sixth pillar is promoting cooperation.</p>
<p>Yes, our work in this space is about protecting ourselves and our allies from threats.  And yes, it’s about competition.  But more than anything, we want and we need to bring a spirit of cooperation to tech diplomacy.  Because the bottom-line truth is this:  The United States cannot deliver on these pillars on our own.  We need partners.</p>
<p>And this may be in some ways, I think, the most fundamental imperative of our time.  And it, of course, extends beyond technology.  If you think about virtually any challenge that we have to face as a country, as a society, challenges that have a direct impact on the lives of our citizens, whether it’s dealing with this pandemic, whether it’s climate change, whether it is emerging technologies, we know that not a single one can be fully and effectively addressed by any one country acting alone, even the United States.  Now, more than ever before in my lifetime, there is an imperative for cooperation.</p>
<p>So we are building technology into nearly all of our diplomatic engagements – tech by tech, issue by issue, bilaterally, multilaterally, always looking to assemble the right configurations of allies and partners to get things done.</p>
<p>And as we see it, this agenda has to start with our democratic partners.</p>
<p>And I think we’ve already gotten some good work under our belts.  We’ve been developing shared principles at the G7.  I think you saw some of that emerge just a few weeks ago with President Biden.  We’ve created a new U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council that’s going to be an important vehicle for advancing this agenda.  We’re starting a new science and technology partnership with the UK.  We’re launching cooperative agreements with Korea and Japan on emerging technologies.  We created a Critical and Emerging Tech Working Group with the Quad countries – with Japan, Australia, India.  We’re working with G7 partners through Build Back Better World to mobilize private capital and government finance to build digital infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries.</p>
<p>Our goal is strong networks – plural – of countries, companies, universities connected by shared values and a shared commitment to design and deploy technology for the benefit of all people, to strengthen open and interoperable systems, to encourage freedom of thought and expression, which are the heart of innovation, to defend each other against those who are intent on taking technologies that could be used for good and using them for harm.</p>
<p>To deliver on all of this, we need a State Department and a diplomatic corps that treats cyber and technology like the central issues that they are.</p>
<p>I’ve asked the two deputy secretaries of state, Wendy Sherman and Brian McKeon, to take the lead on delivering recommendations for how to elevate and institutionalize cyber and tech diplomacy across the department.  And I am committed to driving this forward in full partnership with Congress.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure the State Department is organized for the task at hand because the issues before us really bear little relationship to borders on a map or the current organizational chart of the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll build more expertise among our workforce in science, in technology, in innovation.  And here’s a request:  Help us spread the word.  We’re looking for outstanding people, for talent who want to make the leap to government, spend some time in government.  Now is a great time to put those skills to use, leveraging tech for the good of our country and for the good of the world.</p>
<p>In the coming weeks, the State Department will be releasing our first ever data strategy to help us use data more effectively and more creatively for diplomacy.  If Netflix can predict what TV show my wife and I might choose to watch next, I think data can also help us and help the department predict maybe the next civil conflict, the next famine, the next economic crisis, and how we can respond more effectively.</p>
<p>I intend to leave my successor at the State Department with strong capabilities in cyber and tech diplomacy, with clear leadership, lines of authority, organizational homes, and talent at every level.  We need to become much better at anticipating the foreign policy implications of the next wave of innovation, and the wave after that.  I want to shape the strategic tech landscape, not just react to it.</p>
<p>And at the same time, we have to find ways to put tech and innovation to the task of solving the concrete problems that we’re facing, whether that’s verifying an arms control agreement or preventing the next pandemic.  I’ve been in and out of government for the better part of 25 years, and the last time I was serving with Bob and others, we’d be in that Situation Room in the White House looking at one of the many challenges that would somehow wind up in our inbox, and I think it became clearer and clearer to all of us that for virtually every single one, there was some technological component to the solution.  Part of the problem is that many of us who are engaged in these issues are not brought up on these disciplines.  Bob is an exception to that, but many of us come from the humanities, from law.  It’s not our first knowledge.  It’s not our first instinct.</p>
<p>And I got to the point when I had the responsibility of chairing some of these meetings to thinking that I needed scientists and technologists in the room just to tell me whether I needed scientists and technologists in the room – (laughter) – to help identify the problems and help identify some of the solutions.  And I became more and more convinced that virtually everything on our agenda has some tech or science or innovative component to the solution.  So we need to do a better job bringing that knowledge, that expertise, that focus into the department and to everything we do.</p>
<p>We started to do that a few years ago when I was last here.  We actually set up our first-ever office in Silicon Valley.  Some of the other agencies of government were ahead of us.  We developed partnerships with leading institutions.  One of my very strong and positive memories was spending some time out at Stanford, we had started working with a class called Hacking for Diplomacy where 20 bureaus of the State Department sent this class problems that we were trying to solve.  And these remarkable students over the course of a semester or even a year worked to solve them.  And bringing that approach, bringing that perspective brought forward answers that I don’t think we would have come to doing it on our own in Washington.  So we need to make this shift too, and the changes we’re making at State I think will help us to do that.</p>
<p>If there’s one thing I want to leave you with today, it’s this:  For the Biden-Harris administration, this is not a standalone diplomatic issue.  It’s not just another line of effort.  We’re weaving cyber and technology diplomacy into our work across the board.  Nothing is more consequential to our competitiveness, to our security, and ultimately, to our democracy.</p>
<p>We’re in the early days of this endeavor.  All of us in the national security community have a tremendous amount to learn and even more to do.  We intend to secure American leadership.  We intend to get results for the American people.  And as we do, we will build upon the work of this commission and continue to work in partnership with you.</p>
<p>Thank you so much for listening.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Mayflower Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you all very, very much.  It is actually wonderful to be in a room with real people – (laughter) – with friends, with colleagues and without masks too.  So in and of itself, that’s a very positive thing.</p>
<p>But there is a lot to be positive about today, and it starts with the remarkable work of the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence, especially the work of my friend Eric Schmidt, another friend and close colleague Bob Work, who I haven’t seen yet but hopefully is here, and – Bob, there you are – and the executive director Ylli Bajraktari.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for this remarkable effort.  I am in your debt, and quite frankly the country is going to be in your debt for the work that you’ve done.  I’m going to put this down.</p>
<p>And I really want to thank the members of Congress who have come together across party lines to launch this enterprise at what is a pivotal moment for our country, and I think for the world at large.</p>
<p>Today, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Defense, you’ve heard from the Secretary of Commerce, the National Security Advisor, the director of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy.</p>
<p>In and of itself, that is testament to how seriously the administration takes these issues.  And again, that’s in no small part due to the work of this commission.</p>
<p>You have helped clarify the links among AI, the broader set of emerging technologies, strategic competition, and our national security and prosperity.</p>
<p>And you have made crystal clear that our country needs to play catch-up and to do it fast.  And not just our country.  Countries around the world.  And I’ll come to that.</p>
<p>We’re moving quickly, because we want to ensure that as AI and related technologies transform how we live, how we work, how we compete, how we defend ourselves, that we’re staying ahead of change, indeed that we are shaping change and, critically, making sure it delivers for our people.</p>
<p>My colleagues, I think, have very capably covered the administration’s work on these issues as it relates to our domestic renewal, our economy, and our defense.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do today is to focus on the State Department’s distinct role, because diplomacy will be critical.</p>
<p>Working with partners and allies to develop and deploy technology is going to help us tackle the most urgent challenges we face, from pandemics to the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Diplomacy will also be essential to mitigating risks, from preventing cyber attacks that target our businesses, to regulating technology that threatens our privacy, to defending our democratic values and way of life.</p>
<p>And let me just pause for a second on that last point, because I think it deserves emphasis.  It’s fundamentally what’s at stake here.</p>
<p>More than anything else, our task is to put forth and carry out a compelling vision for how to use technology in a way that serves our people, protects our interests and upholds our democratic values.  It’s not enough to highlight the horrors of techno-authoritarianism, to point to what countries like China and Russia are doing, and say that it’s wrong and dangerous, even as it is.  We’ve also got to make the positive case for our own approach, and then we’ve got to deliver.  That is the challenge before us.</p>
<p>We need the United States and we need its partners to remain the world’s innovative leaders and standard setters, to ensure that universal rights and democratic values remain at the center of all the innovation that’s to come, and that it delivers real benefits in people’s lives.  That fundamentally is the test that we have to pass, and it’s a test I think you’ve heard President Biden allude to.</p>
<p>In short, democracies have to pass the tech test together.  And diplomacy, I believe, has a big role to play in that.</p>
<p>Now, any time you hear someone from the State Department talking, we’re likely to throw in pillars and frameworks and tranches, so I can’t be any different today.  We have to have our pillars, so let me walk you through six of them – (laughter) – that cover the approach to these issues.  I know you’d be disappointed without it.</p>
<p>The first is reducing the national security risks posed by malicious cyber activities and emerging technologies.</p>
<p>This is the most basic thing our diplomacy has to do: protect our people, protect our networks, prevent conflict, and establish standards of responsible conduct in cyberspace.</p>
<p>Already, we’ve brought countries together around an approach that recognizes international law to make it clear that countries are governed in cyberspace just like they are offline and that defines norms that apply not only in wartime but in peacetime too, because we’re now dealing with significant cyber incidents outside the context of war.</p>
<p>We’ve also called for practical confidence-building measures; for example, steps as simple as establishing points of contact, so that in the event of a major cyber incident we actually know who to call.  Under American leadership, UN member-states have come together repeatedly to reaffirm this basic framework.</p>
<p>Now we’re working to bring allies and partners along to respond collectively when others engage in malicious cyber activity.  That’s what happened after the SolarWinds intrusion.  We attributed it to Russia; 22 countries, the European Union, NATO quickly supported that conclusion.  And that’s important, because when we speak with one voice, we can more effectively deter future bad acts.</p>
<p>Last month, as some of you will have noted, at the NATO summit, NATO reaffirmed that a cyber attack could trigger Article V – “an attack on one is an attack on all” – and that’s an important step too in deterring those attacks and protecting our national security in the cyber age.</p>
<p>We’re also treating ransomware not only as a law enforcement issue but also as a national security issue.  Ransomware and other cyber crimes affect all of us – our businesses, local governments; our most critical infrastructure, from power grids to hospitals.  As you know, one in four Americans has been the victim of a cyber crime, at a cost of more than $4 billion every single year.  That’s a direct threat to the safety, to the well-being of our people, and so it’s at the top of our diplomatic agenda.</p>
<p>And it’s also why we’re elevating ransomware in our engagements with Russia.  Our message is clear:  Countries that harbor cyber criminals have a responsibility to take action.  If they don’t, we will.  We’re strengthening our diplomatic and foreign assistance tools to fight transnational cyber criminals, and we’re working to expand membership in the global cyber crime treaty known as the Budapest Convention.</p>
<p>We’ll launch similar efforts on AI and other emerging technologies.  If they’re going to be used as part of our national defense, we want the world to have a shared understanding of how to do that responsibly, in the same way that we’ve hammered out rules for how to use conventional and nuclear weapons.  That’s how we reduce the risk of proliferation.  It’s how we prevent escalation or unintended incidents.</p>
<p>The second pillar is ensuring that our leadership in the fierce strategic technology competition that’s now underway not only continues but grows and strengthens.</p>
<p>We know China is determined to become the world’s technology leader.  And they have a well-resourced and comprehensive plan to achieve those ambitions.</p>
<p>We must preserve our competitive and comparative advantages.</p>
<p>That means building resilient, diverse, and secure supply chains for critical technologies.  Our proposed investments in semiconductor manufacturing here at home is an important part of that.  And again, I really want to underscore the very important work that was done on a bipartisan basis in Congress to help allow us to do that.</p>
<p>But I think you know this too:  We can’t onshore everything.  We don’t need to.  We’ll work with partners to “friend-shore” and “near-shore” our supply chains, and that will make all of us more resilient.</p>
<p>We’ll protect information communications technologies.  The Biden-Harris administration is committed to 5G security.  And we’re promoting the use of trusted and diverse vendors, including American companies, and advocating in multilateral settings for high standards for security and for trust.</p>
<p>We’re taking a fresh look at tools like export controls, investment screening, visa screening, to make sure our strategic competitors are not exploiting our own innovative ecosystems to gain military or national security advantage.</p>
<p>Today we also know that it’s harder to ensure that American innovations are used for commercial purposes only.  Countries like China don’t differentiate between civilian and military in the same way, and emerging technologies, including AI applications, blur that line too.  So we’ve got to think differently about how to protect our innovation and industries against that kind of misuse.</p>
<p>And of course, we need to do this at the same time that we’re growing our talent pipelines.  Perhaps more than any other factor, having the right people will determine whether we win the competition for the future.  We’ve got to recruit, we’ve got to retain the top talent, including talent from around the world, so that the best and the brightest study here, stay here, feel welcome here.</p>
<p>The third pillar: defending an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet.</p>
<p>We’ve been fighting for this vision of the internet for a long, long time.  Many of you in this room have been engaged in that effort.  These principles created the conditions that allowed the internet to grow into the transformative force that it’s become: an extraordinary resource for learning, for connection, for economic growth.</p>
<p>But the hard truth is that the internet is also growing more closed, more insecure, more fractured every single day.</p>
<p>We see country after country putting up firewalls, controlling speech, targeting activists, shutting down the internet to squelch dissent.  And while authoritarian regimes deny access to their networks, they actively reach into others and into ours, taking advantage and meddling in more open societies.  It’s no wonder that some countries are asking whether the principles around which we’ve organized the internet are still relevant, are still tenable.</p>
<p>In many ways, we are at an inflection point, some would say even a tipping point.  And our choice is between giving up on our vision for the internet or stepping up the fight.  We will step up the fight.</p>
<p>We’ll defend the principles of an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet across the full spectrum of our engagement – from trade agreements to governance to hardware.  We’ll use our diplomacy to unite governments and the private sector more firmly behind these efforts.  The work we do today will determine what the internet looks like just a few years from now.  That’s a responsibility we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>The fourth pillar I want to talk about is setting technical standards and creating norms for emerging technologies.</p>
<p>Technical standards help ensure quality, protect consumer health and safety, facilitate global interoperability.  They also help overcome trade barriers and expand market access.</p>
<p>We believe in a transparent, consensus-based, and private sector-led approach to developing standards for emerging technologies.  That’s how we’ll arrive at standards that are technologically sound, have earned people’s trust, reflect our values, and help American companies compete on a level playing field.</p>
<p>And norms, of course, are standards of another kind.  We’ll work with partners to ensure that technologies are developed and deployed in ethical ways that respect people’s rights.</p>
<p>That’s what we did at the UN International Telecommunications Union just a few months ago.  Some countries proposed norms that would allow the use, for example, of facial recognition technology in ways that could threaten human rights.  We brought governments and businesses together to stop it.</p>
<p>Whenever rules and norms that affect American lives are being debated and decided, American diplomats won’t be just – won’t just be in the room; we will be leading the charge.</p>
<p>The fifth pillar is this:  It’s making technology work for democracy.</p>
<p>Some of the leading threats to democracies today are playing out, as you all know, in cyberspace. We have to be leading the world’s efforts, and particularly the world’s democracies, in responding to those threats – fighting back against disinformation, standing up for internet freedom, reducing the misuse of surveillance technology.</p>
<p>We’ve got to make sure that our companies are not inadvertently fueling authoritarian practices, whether it’s in China or anywhere else.</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve released “surveillance due diligence guidance” to try to help American companies prevent their products from being misused.</p>
<p>Technology is also disrupting democracies from within – challenging the ways we think about privacy, free speech, the power of government, and corporations.  President Biden will take on these issues here at home.  For example, his new executive order on promoting competition in the U.S. economy asks the FTC to establish rules for companies on surveillance and how to treat personal data.</p>
<p>But democracies have to work together on these issues as well.  We need to close the gaps in regulatory and legal frameworks so that democracies can collaborate more easily on issues like privacy, content moderation, data sharing, and on digital trade.</p>
<p>You all know very well these are incredibly complicated issues.  The world’s democracies are not all on the same page on every single one of them.  But at heart we do share the same principles, and I have confidence that we can work together through the differences that we have.  I can tell you this:  It is a diplomatic priority for the United States to do that.</p>
<p>So is advancing trustworthy AI.  We need be able to reassure our citizens that AI is secure, that it does not have bias embedded in it, that it can be used safely.  And here, we’re grateful for a lot of good work happening in some critical organizations, including at the OECD and the Global Partnership on AI.  This is very important, too.</p>
<p>We’re interested in increasing access to shared public data sets for AI training and testing, while still preserving privacy – especially in sectors like health, climate, and energy, where AI could create transformational breakthroughs.</p>
<p>Finally, the sixth pillar is promoting cooperation.</p>
<p>Yes, our work in this space is about protecting ourselves and our allies from threats.  And yes, it’s about competition.  But more than anything, we want and we need to bring a spirit of cooperation to tech diplomacy.  Because the bottom-line truth is this:  The United States cannot deliver on these pillars on our own.  We need partners.</p>
<p>And this may be in some ways, I think, the most fundamental imperative of our time.  And it, of course, extends beyond technology.  If you think about virtually any challenge that we have to face as a country, as a society, challenges that have a direct impact on the lives of our citizens, whether it’s dealing with this pandemic, whether it’s climate change, whether it is emerging technologies, we know that not a single one can be fully and effectively addressed by any one country acting alone, even the United States.  Now, more than ever before in my lifetime, there is an imperative for cooperation.</p>
<p>So we are building technology into nearly all of our diplomatic engagements – tech by tech, issue by issue, bilaterally, multilaterally, always looking to assemble the right configurations of allies and partners to get things done.</p>
<p>And as we see it, this agenda has to start with our democratic partners.</p>
<p>And I think we’ve already gotten some good work under our belts.  We’ve been developing shared principles at the G7.  I think you saw some of that emerge just a few weeks ago with President Biden.  We’ve created a new U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council that’s going to be an important vehicle for advancing this agenda.  We’re starting a new science and technology partnership with the UK.  We’re launching cooperative agreements with Korea and Japan on emerging technologies.  We created a Critical and Emerging Tech Working Group with the Quad countries – with Japan, Australia, India.  We’re working with G7 partners through Build Back Better World to mobilize private capital and government finance to build digital infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries.</p>
<p>Our goal is strong networks – plural – of countries, companies, universities connected by shared values and a shared commitment to design and deploy technology for the benefit of all people, to strengthen open and interoperable systems, to encourage freedom of thought and expression, which are the heart of innovation, to defend each other against those who are intent on taking technologies that could be used for good and using them for harm.</p>
<p>To deliver on all of this, we need a State Department and a diplomatic corps that treats cyber and technology like the central issues that they are.</p>
<p>I’ve asked the two deputy secretaries of state, Wendy Sherman and Brian McKeon, to take the lead on delivering recommendations for how to elevate and institutionalize cyber and tech diplomacy across the department.  And I am committed to driving this forward in full partnership with Congress.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure the State Department is organized for the task at hand because the issues before us really bear little relationship to borders on a map or the current organizational chart of the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll build more expertise among our workforce in science, in technology, in innovation.  And here’s a request:  Help us spread the word.  We’re looking for outstanding people, for talent who want to make the leap to government, spend some time in government.  Now is a great time to put those skills to use, leveraging tech for the good of our country and for the good of the world.</p>
<p>In the coming weeks, the State Department will be releasing our first ever data strategy to help us use data more effectively and more creatively for diplomacy.  If Netflix can predict what TV show my wife and I might choose to watch next, I think data can also help us and help the department predict maybe the next civil conflict, the next famine, the next economic crisis, and how we can respond more effectively.</p>
<p>I intend to leave my successor at the State Department with strong capabilities in cyber and tech diplomacy, with clear leadership, lines of authority, organizational homes, and talent at every level.  We need to become much better at anticipating the foreign policy implications of the next wave of innovation, and the wave after that.  I want to shape the strategic tech landscape, not just react to it.</p>
<p>And at the same time, we have to find ways to put tech and innovation to the task of solving the concrete problems that we’re facing, whether that’s verifying an arms control agreement or preventing the next pandemic.  I’ve been in and out of government for the better part of 25 years, and the last time I was serving with Bob and others, we’d be in that Situation Room in the White House looking at one of the many challenges that would somehow wind up in our inbox, and I think it became clearer and clearer to all of us that for virtually every single one, there was some technological component to the solution.  Part of the problem is that many of us who are engaged in these issues are not brought up on these disciplines.  Bob is an exception to that, but many of us come from the humanities, from law.  It’s not our first knowledge.  It’s not our first instinct.</p>
<p>And I got to the point when I had the responsibility of chairing some of these meetings to thinking that I needed scientists and technologists in the room just to tell me whether I needed scientists and technologists in the room – (laughter) – to help identify the problems and help identify some of the solutions.  And I became more and more convinced that virtually everything on our agenda has some tech or science or innovative component to the solution.  So we need to do a better job bringing that knowledge, that expertise, that focus into the department and to everything we do.</p>
<p>We started to do that a few years ago when I was last here.  We actually set up our first-ever office in Silicon Valley.  Some of the other agencies of government were ahead of us.  We developed partnerships with leading institutions.  One of my very strong and positive memories was spending some time out at Stanford, we had started working with a class called Hacking for Diplomacy where 20 bureaus of the State Department sent this class problems that we were trying to solve.  And these remarkable students over the course of a semester or even a year worked to solve them.  And bringing that approach, bringing that perspective brought forward answers that I don’t think we would have come to doing it on our own in Washington.  So we need to make this shift too, and the changes we’re making at State I think will help us to do that.</p>
<p>If there’s one thing I want to leave you with today, it’s this:  For the Biden-Harris administration, this is not a standalone diplomatic issue.  It’s not just another line of effort.  We’re weaving cyber and technology diplomacy into our work across the board.  Nothing is more consequential to our competitiveness, to our security, and ultimately, to our democracy.</p>
<p>We’re in the early days of this endeavor.  All of us in the national security community have a tremendous amount to learn and even more to do.  We intend to secure American leadership.  We intend to get results for the American people.  And as we do, we will build upon the work of this commission and continue to work in partnership with you.</p>
<p>Thank you so much for listening.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
