<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – April 8, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-april-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=333088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. I have one update at the top, and then I’ll start with taking your questions. I<a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia"></a> would like to start off by addressing the missile strike by Russia’s forces that reportedly killed at least 50 civilians and injured many more at the Kramatorsk railway station in eastern Ukraine, where thousands of civilians were on a platform waiting to be evacuated. I want to express our deep condolences to the families of those killed or injured, and to the people of Ukraine who continue to suffer terribly from the Russian Government’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war.</p>
<p>We are horrified by this latest atrocity, but we can no longer be surprised by the Kremlin’s repugnant disregard for human life. This is just yet another example of the Russian Government’s unjustified, brutal war sowing senseless death and destruction in Ukraine, and unraveling the fabric of normal life on schools, on homes, on hospitals, and on workplaces. Civilians are killed when they stay in their homes, and they’re killed when they tried to leave. Actions like these demonstrate why Russia did not belong on the UN Human Rights Council, and they also reinforced the U.S. assessment that members of Russian – Russia’s forces are committing war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This tragedy has also further increased our resolve to do everything we can to assist those investigating potential war crimes, see those responsible held accountable for atrocities, and support the people of Ukraine in their just cause: the defense of their country, their democracy, and their free and sovereign future.</p>
<p>Let’s first go to the line of Cindy Saine, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you. Jalina, Prime Minister – Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan just spoke to the nation, and he has renewed allegations that the U.S. encouraged the no-confidence vote, saying that he has a cable to prove it. Could you please comment? And thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Cindy. <a id="post-333088-Pakistan"></a>Let me just say very bluntly there is absolutely no truth to these allegations. Of course, we continue to follow these developments, and we respect and support Pakistan’s constitutional process and rule of law. But again, these allegations are absolutely not true.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And next we’ll go to the line of Endale Getahun with KETO FM International. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much. Good morning. Good morning, everyone, and a Happy Friday. Thank you for taking my call. I am asking regarding the situation, as you know, that’s in East Africa, Ethiopia. I don’t know if you know, but there was – a meeting took place between the second in command on Ethiopian military and Eritrean. And so do you know any information or have you heard on – or do you want to comment on regarding the general who visited Eritrea with the state – given the statements on state media and Ethiopian TV that they are preparing to do a second phase there to invade Tigray, as we speak? Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>The second one I have: Have you seen the Human Rights and Amnesty International released about the (inaudible) was taken based on their statements, ethnic cleansing and what have you, on – for the neighboring state, for Amhara militants or vigilantes, and they were – and western Tigray, which is still occupied by Eritreans and by the – with the Amhara? So what is your comments on that statement and also on the general, the second in command in Ethiopia, that made the statements on they are heading to the second phase, even as there’s a ceasefire according to Ethiopian Government, and also on the human – that was my question, but if you have any comments on World Food Program. They’re still having issues for delivering food. Only 26 trucks head on to Tigray. What’s your comment on that too? And thank you so much, appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for all of those robust questions. <a id="post-333088-Ethiopia"></a>I’ll do my best to give you an overview of what we have from here. I’ll just start off by saying that we certainly welcome the humanitarian truce in Tigray.</p>
<p>Second, to your question on the joint Human Rights report and Amnesty International report, we’re certainly aware of these reports on ethnically motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in the western Tigray and in Ethiopia, and we also reiterate our grave concerns over findings in this report, which we will carefully review. In fact, we have some principals in the building, including Under Secretary Zeya, who is our Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights, along with our Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and a couple other principals in our department are actually meeting with representatives of Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International today to hear more about this report.</p>
<p>I’ll also say that the U.S. has consistently called out human rights abuses by all armed actors in this conflict, and we will continue to do this. Victims deserve justice, and those responsible for these abuses must be held accountable through transparent and inclusive processes.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Secretary Blinken on I believe it was March 23rd said that the State Department determined the Russians had committed war crimes in Ukraine. When do you intend to release those assessments of specific determinations of war crimes?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Laura. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia2"></a>Well, we certainly don’t have a timeline for this. But I’ll say that we continue to investigate Russia’s ongoing and unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine. But we have no – nothing to preview as far as timelines.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. The nominee for ambassador to South Korea, Ambassador Phillip Goldberg, at the Senate nomination hearing yesterday said comprehensive, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization are goals in – when it comes to North Korea. So is comprehensible, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization the Biden administration’s official term for describing the goal in negotiations with North Korea? Is the Biden administration officially replacing “complete” with “comprehensive” in defining this goal?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks for your question, Eunjong. <a id="post-333088-Koreas"></a>We have no change – the Biden-Harris administration has no change in our policy, and we continue to urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activities and of course instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Jenny Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for calling on me. The Ukrainian foreign minister just called for Russia to be expelled from the OSCE, saying that if the OSCE lacks an appropriate suspension mechanism, then they should set up a process to get them out. Does the U.S. support suspending Russia from the OSCE or creating a mechanism to do so?</p>
<p>And then secondly, do you have an update on the American citizens detained in Russia? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Jenny. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia3"></a>To your first question on the OSCE, I’m learning about that in real time so we don’t have anything to respond to at the moment.</p>
<p>But what I will say about – to your second question, of course, is our top priority is and has always been the safety and the security of Americans overseas, and we continue to engage the Russian Government on cases of Americans who are currently detained.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, Jalina. Two questions on – just following up on what you said at the top about the strike on the train station in Kramatorsk. First, you said it reinforces the assessment that Russia is committing war crimes. Are you calling this strike a war crime?</p>
<p>And then second, you attributed it to Russia. The Kremlin has obviously denied responsibility. Just wondering if you will respond to their denial. Any more information you can provide on why you are attributing it to them? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. I’ll say, to your question on the war crime question, assessing individual criminal liability in specific cases is the responsibility of courts as well as other investigatory bodies. But as the Secretary, Secretary Blinken, has said, those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine will be held to account. We won’t make any public comments on our war crimes assessment of specific acts or reports, nor discuss any information that’s reviewed at this time.</p>
<p>And then to your second question on a response – yeah, we just don’t have a response to give at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Joseph Akbush.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for this. Two questions. One, is there any comment on the two attacks which targeted U.S. servicemembers in Syria and Iraq over the last two days, I guess? And on that note, any updates to the Vienna talks?</p>
<p>And then my second question is on Ukraine. And are there still – is the U.S. still concerned about China providing military support to Russia or circumventing international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So for your first question, I would have to refer you to the DOD. To your second question on any updates in – on <a id="post-333088-Iran"></a>the status of talks and Iran, we don’t have any updates to share at this time other than it’s obviously been a significant process, but an agreement is neither imminent nor certain at this time.</p>
<p>And to your last question on <a id="post-333088-ChinaRussiaUkraine"></a>Chinese military to assist the Russians, I think we’ve been pretty clear on our stance when it comes to any support in this activity, and that hasn’t changed at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. One follow-up for you on Iran. Can you say whether the Biden administration shares General Milley’s view that the IRGC’s Qods Force specifically should remain on the U.S. list of terror organizations?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Elizabeth. <a id="post-333088-Iran2"></a>I’d say that the President shares the chairman’s view that IRGC Qods Forces are terrorists, and beyond that we aren’t going to comment on any of the topics in the nuclear talks. But what I would say is out of the 107 Biden administration designations in relation to Iran, 86 have specifically targeted the IRGC-related persons as well as affiliates.</p>
<p>Thank you all so much for joining today. That concludes today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a good weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:19 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. I have one update at the top, and then I’ll start with taking your questions. I<a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia"></a> would like to start off by addressing the missile strike by Russia’s forces that reportedly killed at least 50 civilians and injured many more at the Kramatorsk railway station in eastern Ukraine, where thousands of civilians were on a platform waiting to be evacuated. I want to express our deep condolences to the families of those killed or injured, and to the people of Ukraine who continue to suffer terribly from the Russian Government’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war.</p>
<p>We are horrified by this latest atrocity, but we can no longer be surprised by the Kremlin’s repugnant disregard for human life. This is just yet another example of the Russian Government’s unjustified, brutal war sowing senseless death and destruction in Ukraine, and unraveling the fabric of normal life on schools, on homes, on hospitals, and on workplaces. Civilians are killed when they stay in their homes, and they’re killed when they tried to leave. Actions like these demonstrate why Russia did not belong on the UN Human Rights Council, and they also reinforced the U.S. assessment that members of Russian – Russia’s forces are committing war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This tragedy has also further increased our resolve to do everything we can to assist those investigating potential war crimes, see those responsible held accountable for atrocities, and support the people of Ukraine in their just cause: the defense of their country, their democracy, and their free and sovereign future.</p>
<p>Let’s first go to the line of Cindy Saine, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you. Jalina, Prime Minister – Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan just spoke to the nation, and he has renewed allegations that the U.S. encouraged the no-confidence vote, saying that he has a cable to prove it. Could you please comment? And thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Cindy. <a id="post-333088-Pakistan"></a>Let me just say very bluntly there is absolutely no truth to these allegations. Of course, we continue to follow these developments, and we respect and support Pakistan’s constitutional process and rule of law. But again, these allegations are absolutely not true.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And next we’ll go to the line of Endale Getahun with KETO FM International. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much. Good morning. Good morning, everyone, and a Happy Friday. Thank you for taking my call. I am asking regarding the situation, as you know, that’s in East Africa, Ethiopia. I don’t know if you know, but there was – a meeting took place between the second in command on Ethiopian military and Eritrean. And so do you know any information or have you heard on – or do you want to comment on regarding the general who visited Eritrea with the state – given the statements on state media and Ethiopian TV that they are preparing to do a second phase there to invade Tigray, as we speak? Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>The second one I have: Have you seen the Human Rights and Amnesty International released about the (inaudible) was taken based on their statements, ethnic cleansing and what have you, on – for the neighboring state, for Amhara militants or vigilantes, and they were – and western Tigray, which is still occupied by Eritreans and by the – with the Amhara? So what is your comments on that statement and also on the general, the second in command in Ethiopia, that made the statements on they are heading to the second phase, even as there’s a ceasefire according to Ethiopian Government, and also on the human – that was my question, but if you have any comments on World Food Program. They’re still having issues for delivering food. Only 26 trucks head on to Tigray. What’s your comment on that too? And thank you so much, appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for all of those robust questions. <a id="post-333088-Ethiopia"></a>I’ll do my best to give you an overview of what we have from here. I’ll just start off by saying that we certainly welcome the humanitarian truce in Tigray.</p>
<p>Second, to your question on the joint Human Rights report and Amnesty International report, we’re certainly aware of these reports on ethnically motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in the western Tigray and in Ethiopia, and we also reiterate our grave concerns over findings in this report, which we will carefully review. In fact, we have some principals in the building, including Under Secretary Zeya, who is our Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights, along with our Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and a couple other principals in our department are actually meeting with representatives of Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International today to hear more about this report.</p>
<p>I’ll also say that the U.S. has consistently called out human rights abuses by all armed actors in this conflict, and we will continue to do this. Victims deserve justice, and those responsible for these abuses must be held accountable through transparent and inclusive processes.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Secretary Blinken on I believe it was March 23rd said that the State Department determined the Russians had committed war crimes in Ukraine. When do you intend to release those assessments of specific determinations of war crimes?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Laura. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia2"></a>Well, we certainly don’t have a timeline for this. But I’ll say that we continue to investigate Russia’s ongoing and unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine. But we have no – nothing to preview as far as timelines.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. The nominee for ambassador to South Korea, Ambassador Phillip Goldberg, at the Senate nomination hearing yesterday said comprehensive, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization are goals in – when it comes to North Korea. So is comprehensible, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization the Biden administration’s official term for describing the goal in negotiations with North Korea? Is the Biden administration officially replacing “complete” with “comprehensive” in defining this goal?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks for your question, Eunjong. <a id="post-333088-Koreas"></a>We have no change – the Biden-Harris administration has no change in our policy, and we continue to urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activities and of course instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Jenny Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for calling on me. The Ukrainian foreign minister just called for Russia to be expelled from the OSCE, saying that if the OSCE lacks an appropriate suspension mechanism, then they should set up a process to get them out. Does the U.S. support suspending Russia from the OSCE or creating a mechanism to do so?</p>
<p>And then secondly, do you have an update on the American citizens detained in Russia? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Jenny. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia3"></a>To your first question on the OSCE, I’m learning about that in real time so we don’t have anything to respond to at the moment.</p>
<p>But what I will say about – to your second question, of course, is our top priority is and has always been the safety and the security of Americans overseas, and we continue to engage the Russian Government on cases of Americans who are currently detained.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, Jalina. Two questions on – just following up on what you said at the top about the strike on the train station in Kramatorsk. First, you said it reinforces the assessment that Russia is committing war crimes. Are you calling this strike a war crime?</p>
<p>And then second, you attributed it to Russia. The Kremlin has obviously denied responsibility. Just wondering if you will respond to their denial. Any more information you can provide on why you are attributing it to them? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. I’ll say, to your question on the war crime question, assessing individual criminal liability in specific cases is the responsibility of courts as well as other investigatory bodies. But as the Secretary, Secretary Blinken, has said, those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine will be held to account. We won’t make any public comments on our war crimes assessment of specific acts or reports, nor discuss any information that’s reviewed at this time.</p>
<p>And then to your second question on a response – yeah, we just don’t have a response to give at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Joseph Akbush.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for this. Two questions. One, is there any comment on the two attacks which targeted U.S. servicemembers in Syria and Iraq over the last two days, I guess? And on that note, any updates to the Vienna talks?</p>
<p>And then my second question is on Ukraine. And are there still – is the U.S. still concerned about China providing military support to Russia or circumventing international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So for your first question, I would have to refer you to the DOD. To your second question on any updates in – on <a id="post-333088-Iran"></a>the status of talks and Iran, we don’t have any updates to share at this time other than it’s obviously been a significant process, but an agreement is neither imminent nor certain at this time.</p>
<p>And to your last question on <a id="post-333088-ChinaRussiaUkraine"></a>Chinese military to assist the Russians, I think we’ve been pretty clear on our stance when it comes to any support in this activity, and that hasn’t changed at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. One follow-up for you on Iran. Can you say whether the Biden administration shares General Milley’s view that the IRGC’s Qods Force specifically should remain on the U.S. list of terror organizations?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Elizabeth. <a id="post-333088-Iran2"></a>I’d say that the President shares the chairman’s view that IRGC Qods Forces are terrorists, and beyond that we aren’t going to comment on any of the topics in the nuclear talks. But what I would say is out of the 107 Biden administration designations in relation to Iran, 86 have specifically targeted the IRGC-related persons as well as affiliates.</p>
<p>Thank you all so much for joining today. That concludes today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a good weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:19 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Palau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerry-and-assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-palau/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Palau April 12-15 to lead the U.S. delegation to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>, co-hosted by the United States and the Republic of Palau.  He will be joined by Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina, who will travel to Palau April 10-16.</p>
<p>The Our Ocean Conference, taking place April 13-14, will focus on combating climate change, promoting sustainable fisheries, creating sustainable blue economies, advancing marine protected areas, achieving a safe and secure ocean, and confronting marine pollution.  The importance of ocean-based climate solutions and the centrality of a healthy ocean to small island developing states – and all places where the ocean is a primary source of sustenance – will be cross-cutting themes.</p>
<p>At the conference, Secretary Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina will engage with government counterparts, private sector actors, and civil society partners to advance efforts related to ocean conservation and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Palau April 12-15 to lead the U.S. delegation to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>, co-hosted by the United States and the Republic of Palau.  He will be joined by Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina, who will travel to Palau April 10-16.</p>
<p>The Our Ocean Conference, taking place April 13-14, will focus on combating climate change, promoting sustainable fisheries, creating sustainable blue economies, advancing marine protected areas, achieving a safe and secure ocean, and confronting marine pollution.  The importance of ocean-based climate solutions and the centrality of a healthy ocean to small island developing states – and all places where the ocean is a primary source of sustenance – will be cross-cutting themes.</p>
<p>At the conference, Secretary Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina will engage with government counterparts, private sector actors, and civil society partners to advance efforts related to ocean conservation and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Counselor Chollet’s Meeting with NUG Representatives</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/counselor-chollets-meeting-with-nug-representatives-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 19:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Counselor Derek Chollet met today with NUG representatives Aung Myo Min and Moe Zaw Oo.  The Counselor expressed deep sympathy for the victims of the military regime’s brutal atrocities across Burma.  He pledged the United States’ strong support for the people of Burma and discussed ways to step up assistance to the people, promote a return to Burma’s path of democratic transition, and advance peaceful resolution to the ongoing human rights and humanitarian crises the military caused by its February 2021 military coup.  In addition, the Counselor voiced appreciation for the NUG’s robust leadership and its efforts to promote respect for the human rights of all individuals in Burma, regardless of ethnicity or religion.  They also discussed Secretary Blinken’s recent announcement of the U.S. determination that members of the military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya and exchanged views on ways to further promote accountability and justice for the military’s atrocities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Counselor Derek Chollet met today with NUG representatives Aung Myo Min and Moe Zaw Oo.  The Counselor expressed deep sympathy for the victims of the military regime’s brutal atrocities across Burma.  He pledged the United States’ strong support for the people of Burma and discussed ways to step up assistance to the people, promote a return to Burma’s path of democratic transition, and advance peaceful resolution to the ongoing human rights and humanitarian crises the military caused by its February 2021 military coup.  In addition, the Counselor voiced appreciation for the NUG’s robust leadership and its efforts to promote respect for the human rights of all individuals in Burma, regardless of ethnicity or religion.  They also discussed Secretary Blinken’s recent announcement of the U.S. determination that members of the military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya and exchanged views on ways to further promote accountability and justice for the military’s atrocities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reports of Mass Atrocities in Western Tigray</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/reports-of-mass-atrocities-in-western-tigray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 17:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its grave concern over continuing reports of ethnically-motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in western Tigray, Ethiopia, including those described in the recent joint report by Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International.  In particular, we are deeply troubled by the report’s finding that these acts amount to ethnic cleansing.</p>
<p>We note with the utmost alarm that thousands of Ethiopians of Tigrayan ethnicity reportedly continue to be detained arbitrarily in life-threatening conditions in western Tigray.  We urge the immediate release of any such remaining detainees and call on relevant authorities to grant international monitors access to all detention facilities. It remains our firm position that there must be credible investigations into and accountability for atrocities committed by any party to the conflict as part of any lasting solution to the crisis.  We urge the Government of Ethiopia to cooperate with the UN Commission of Experts on Human Rights in Ethiopia.</p>
<p>Continued reports of atrocities underscore the urgency of ending the military conflict.  We strongly support the declarations of a cessation of hostilities by the Government of Ethiopia and the Tigray regional authority and welcome the news that they have been followed by initial convoys of life-saving assistance.  In keeping with these declarations, we renew our call on all armed actors to renounce and end human rights abuses and violence against civilians.  The United States reiterates its call for all foreign forces to withdraw from Ethiopia as well as for the regional state authorities to remove their security forces from neighboring regions.</p>
<p>We continue to urge all parties to take necessary steps to ensure the cessation of hostilities, unhindered and sustained humanitarian access, transparent investigations into human rights abuses and violations by all actors, and a negotiated resolution to the conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its grave concern over continuing reports of ethnically-motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in western Tigray, Ethiopia, including those described in the recent joint report by Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International.  In particular, we are deeply troubled by the report’s finding that these acts amount to ethnic cleansing.</p>
<p>We note with the utmost alarm that thousands of Ethiopians of Tigrayan ethnicity reportedly continue to be detained arbitrarily in life-threatening conditions in western Tigray.  We urge the immediate release of any such remaining detainees and call on relevant authorities to grant international monitors access to all detention facilities. It remains our firm position that there must be credible investigations into and accountability for atrocities committed by any party to the conflict as part of any lasting solution to the crisis.  We urge the Government of Ethiopia to cooperate with the UN Commission of Experts on Human Rights in Ethiopia.</p>
<p>Continued reports of atrocities underscore the urgency of ending the military conflict.  We strongly support the declarations of a cessation of hostilities by the Government of Ethiopia and the Tigray regional authority and welcome the news that they have been followed by initial convoys of life-saving assistance.  In keeping with these declarations, we renew our call on all armed actors to renounce and end human rights abuses and violence against civilians.  The United States reiterates its call for all foreign forces to withdraw from Ethiopia as well as for the regional state authorities to remove their security forces from neighboring regions.</p>
<p>We continue to urge all parties to take necessary steps to ensure the cessation of hostilities, unhindered and sustained humanitarian access, transparent investigations into human rights abuses and violations by all actors, and a negotiated resolution to the conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary McKeon’s Meeting with World Health Organization Director-General Ghebreyesus</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-mckeons-meeting-with-world-health-organization-director-general-ghebreyesus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 15:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brain P. McKeon met with World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Dr. Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus to discuss WHO sustainable financing and reform priorities. Deputy Secretary McKeon also expressed commitment to the pandemic instrument process, the continued efforts on amendments to the International Health Regulations, ongoing studies of COVID-19 origins, and Taiwan’s inclusion as an observer to the World Health Assembly.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brain P. McKeon met with World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Dr. Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus to discuss WHO sustainable financing and reform priorities. Deputy Secretary McKeon also expressed commitment to the pandemic instrument process, the continued efforts on amendments to the International Health Regulations, ongoing studies of COVID-19 origins, and Taiwan’s inclusion as an observer to the World Health Assembly.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Communiqué of the Special Representatives and Envoys for Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/communique-of-the-special-representatives-and-envoys-for-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 14:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The text of the following communiqué was agreed upon by the Special Representatives and Envoys for Afghanistan from the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, Norway, the United Kingdom and the United States in Brussels, April 5, 2022. </i></p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Special Envoys of the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, Norway, the United Kingdom and the United States met in Brussels on 5 April 2022 to discuss the situation in Afghanistan. Deborah Lyons, SRSG for Afghanistan, also attended the meeting, which included technical sessions with the World Bank and UNICEF.</p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Envoys:</p>
<ol>
<li>Reaffirmed their strong commitment to the Afghan people and the need to continue to address the humanitarian crisis in Afghanistan; the importance of adherence to International Humanitarian Law and the independence of humanitarian operations; stressed the importance of all humanitarian staff, including female staff, having unhindered access to any areas of the country necessary to perform their jobs effectively and the need for all Afghans in need to have unhindered access to humanitarian aid; and called for any remaining obstacle to the provision of humanitarian assistance to be removed immediately.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>Condemned the Taliban’s decision on 23 March 2022 to continue denying Afghan girls the ability to attend secondary education, which contradicts the Taliban’s assurances to the Afghan people and to the international community; affirmed that every Afghan citizen, in all provinces of the country and regardless of gender, has an equal right to education at all levels; called for an immediate reversal of the ban on education for girls above grade 6; and emphasised that the type and scope of international donor assistance will depend, among other things, on the right and ability of girls to attend equal education at all levels.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>Noted that their governments and organisations had already substantially increased humanitarian and basic needs support, including for healthcare, to the Afghan people to mitigate Afghanistan’s humanitarian and economic crisis and to ensure the continuation of basic services. Highlighted that 2.23 billion EUR were raised at the international humanitarian pledging conference on 31 March 2022, and nearly two thirds (1.42 billion EUR) of this total came from the combined pledges of the EU, EU Member States, Norway, the United Kingdom and the United States.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li>Reaffirmed that progress towards normalised relations between the Taliban and the international community will depend mostly on the Taliban’s actions and their delivery on commitments and obligations to the Afghan people and to the international community.</li>
<li>Raised strong concerns about the continued structural and systemic abuse of Afghans’ economic, social, legal, political and cultural rights, recognised in the international conventions to which Afghanistan is a State Party, including rights of ethnic and religious minorities and groups; and noted that such violations and abuses include killings, arbitrary detentions, enforced disappearances, physical abuse, torture, and the shrinking space for civil society, freedom of peaceful assembly and of movement.</li>
<li>Specifically condemned violations and abuses of the rights of Afghan women and girls in the country, including restrictions on freedom of movement, as well as exclusion from political, economic, educational and social spaces, and acknowledging also that women and girls are disproportionally affected by the humanitarian and economic crisis in Afghanistan.</li>
<li>Expressed concern over restrictions on freedom of opinion and freedom of expression, notably through media crackdowns, the increasing restrictions on broadcasters, journalists and media workers, particularly restrictions on women working in the media, as well as unjust detentions of journalists, and the prohibition on some international media outlets within Afghanistan.</li>
<li>Raised the importance of a genuine and credible inclusive political process in Afghanistan with the meaningful participation of women and religious groups and minorities, that leads to national reconciliation and broad-based and representative governance; emphasised that an inclusive and representative government is crucial for lasting peace and stability in the country; and noted the importance of the Taliban engaging regularly with other political and civil society leaders in a sincere dialogue that leads to an inclusive political system in which the rights of all Afghans are respected.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="9">
<li>Discussed additional ways to help the Afghan people in sustaining their livelihood by stabilizing the economy and increasing liquidity in the country, and particularly highlighted the necessity of the Taliban creating favourable conditions, including an enabling environment for stimulating investment and other economic activity by adherence to rule of law; made clear that the Taliban expanding the capability and professionalism of the Afghan Central Bank, free from political interference, will be an important step toward stabilisation of the financial sector; agreed to further explore ways of addressing the macro-economic and financial sector crisis in the country and to closely coordinate on this issue.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li>Noted that the type and scope of future non-humanitarian development assistance to Afghanistan will be determined in large part by the Taliban’s actions and their upholding of the rights of all Afghans, particularly women, girls and members of minority groups.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="11">
<li>Underscored that the Taliban must fulfil their counterterrorism commitments as well as their commitments to counter drug production and trafficking and welcomed the Taliban’s recent decision to ban opium cultivation.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="12">
<li>Reaffirmed their expectations that the Taliban must allow safe, secure and orderly travel to and from Afghanistan, of both Afghans and foreign nationals, in full respect of freedom of movement and travel, policies to which the Taliban have committed in the past, as was highlighted in the UN Security Council Resolution 2593 (2021).</li>
</ol>
<ol start="13">
<li>Highlighted the need for the neighbours of Afghanistan, the countries of the region, other Muslim-majority countries and all international partners to cooperate in Afghanistan with the interest of the Afghan people in mind, in view of alleviating their humanitarian and economic situation, meeting their basic needs, and promoting their human rights.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="14">
<li>Welcomed the expanded role for the United Nations work in Afghanistan as spelled out in the Security Council Resolution 2626 (2022) renewing the mandate of UNAMA, and by the appointment by the Human Rights Council (HRC) of Richard Bennett as Special Rapporteur on the human rights situation in Afghanistan, and emphasised the importance of the United Nations, including the Special Rapporteur, having unhindered access throughout the territory of Afghanistan and to all Afghans.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="15">
<li>Expressed their appreciation to the European Union for organizing these consultations and hosting the meeting.</li>
</ol>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The text of the following communiqué was agreed upon by the Special Representatives and Envoys for Afghanistan from the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, Norway, the United Kingdom and the United States in Brussels, April 5, 2022. </i></p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Special Envoys of the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, Norway, the United Kingdom and the United States met in Brussels on 5 April 2022 to discuss the situation in Afghanistan. Deborah Lyons, SRSG for Afghanistan, also attended the meeting, which included technical sessions with the World Bank and UNICEF.</p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Envoys:</p>
<ol>
<li>Reaffirmed their strong commitment to the Afghan people and the need to continue to address the humanitarian crisis in Afghanistan; the importance of adherence to International Humanitarian Law and the independence of humanitarian operations; stressed the importance of all humanitarian staff, including female staff, having unhindered access to any areas of the country necessary to perform their jobs effectively and the need for all Afghans in need to have unhindered access to humanitarian aid; and called for any remaining obstacle to the provision of humanitarian assistance to be removed immediately.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>Condemned the Taliban’s decision on 23 March 2022 to continue denying Afghan girls the ability to attend secondary education, which contradicts the Taliban’s assurances to the Afghan people and to the international community; affirmed that every Afghan citizen, in all provinces of the country and regardless of gender, has an equal right to education at all levels; called for an immediate reversal of the ban on education for girls above grade 6; and emphasised that the type and scope of international donor assistance will depend, among other things, on the right and ability of girls to attend equal education at all levels.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>Noted that their governments and organisations had already substantially increased humanitarian and basic needs support, including for healthcare, to the Afghan people to mitigate Afghanistan’s humanitarian and economic crisis and to ensure the continuation of basic services. Highlighted that 2.23 billion EUR were raised at the international humanitarian pledging conference on 31 March 2022, and nearly two thirds (1.42 billion EUR) of this total came from the combined pledges of the EU, EU Member States, Norway, the United Kingdom and the United States.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li>Reaffirmed that progress towards normalised relations between the Taliban and the international community will depend mostly on the Taliban’s actions and their delivery on commitments and obligations to the Afghan people and to the international community.</li>
<li>Raised strong concerns about the continued structural and systemic abuse of Afghans’ economic, social, legal, political and cultural rights, recognised in the international conventions to which Afghanistan is a State Party, including rights of ethnic and religious minorities and groups; and noted that such violations and abuses include killings, arbitrary detentions, enforced disappearances, physical abuse, torture, and the shrinking space for civil society, freedom of peaceful assembly and of movement.</li>
<li>Specifically condemned violations and abuses of the rights of Afghan women and girls in the country, including restrictions on freedom of movement, as well as exclusion from political, economic, educational and social spaces, and acknowledging also that women and girls are disproportionally affected by the humanitarian and economic crisis in Afghanistan.</li>
<li>Expressed concern over restrictions on freedom of opinion and freedom of expression, notably through media crackdowns, the increasing restrictions on broadcasters, journalists and media workers, particularly restrictions on women working in the media, as well as unjust detentions of journalists, and the prohibition on some international media outlets within Afghanistan.</li>
<li>Raised the importance of a genuine and credible inclusive political process in Afghanistan with the meaningful participation of women and religious groups and minorities, that leads to national reconciliation and broad-based and representative governance; emphasised that an inclusive and representative government is crucial for lasting peace and stability in the country; and noted the importance of the Taliban engaging regularly with other political and civil society leaders in a sincere dialogue that leads to an inclusive political system in which the rights of all Afghans are respected.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="9">
<li>Discussed additional ways to help the Afghan people in sustaining their livelihood by stabilizing the economy and increasing liquidity in the country, and particularly highlighted the necessity of the Taliban creating favourable conditions, including an enabling environment for stimulating investment and other economic activity by adherence to rule of law; made clear that the Taliban expanding the capability and professionalism of the Afghan Central Bank, free from political interference, will be an important step toward stabilisation of the financial sector; agreed to further explore ways of addressing the macro-economic and financial sector crisis in the country and to closely coordinate on this issue.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li>Noted that the type and scope of future non-humanitarian development assistance to Afghanistan will be determined in large part by the Taliban’s actions and their upholding of the rights of all Afghans, particularly women, girls and members of minority groups.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="11">
<li>Underscored that the Taliban must fulfil their counterterrorism commitments as well as their commitments to counter drug production and trafficking and welcomed the Taliban’s recent decision to ban opium cultivation.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="12">
<li>Reaffirmed their expectations that the Taliban must allow safe, secure and orderly travel to and from Afghanistan, of both Afghans and foreign nationals, in full respect of freedom of movement and travel, policies to which the Taliban have committed in the past, as was highlighted in the UN Security Council Resolution 2593 (2021).</li>
</ol>
<ol start="13">
<li>Highlighted the need for the neighbours of Afghanistan, the countries of the region, other Muslim-majority countries and all international partners to cooperate in Afghanistan with the interest of the Afghan people in mind, in view of alleviating their humanitarian and economic situation, meeting their basic needs, and promoting their human rights.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="14">
<li>Welcomed the expanded role for the United Nations work in Afghanistan as spelled out in the Security Council Resolution 2626 (2022) renewing the mandate of UNAMA, and by the appointment by the Human Rights Council (HRC) of Richard Bennett as Special Rapporteur on the human rights situation in Afghanistan, and emphasised the importance of the United Nations, including the Special Rapporteur, having unhindered access throughout the territory of Afghanistan and to all Afghans.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="15">
<li>Expressed their appreciation to the European Union for organizing these consultations and hosting the meeting.</li>
</ol>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Roma Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/international-roma-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 12:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States, I extend best wishes to Roma everywhere on this special day when we celebrate the rich culture, language, heritage, and aspirations of Roma globally, including the generations of Romani Americans who have helped build and continue to enhance the United States.</p>
<p>We also recognize today that many of the world’s Roma continue to suffer from marginalization, systemic discrimination, statelessness, and violence. This treatment and exclusion prevent many Roma from reaching their full potential in political, social, and economic spheres. As Europe’s largest ethnic minority, we acknowledge the challenges experienced by Roma who have fled Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s unjustified and brutal attack on that country. In addition to the trauma of war, they must frequently cope with a lack of documentation and stigmatization along their evacuation routes.</p>
<p>The United States calls on all governments to uphold their international obligations, respect the human rights of all people, and provide equitable access to civil registration, housing, health care, and public services. We condemn bigotry in any form—including persistent anti-Roma bigotry—and underscore our support of the<em> Action Plan on Improving the Situation of Roma and Sinti within the OSCE Area</em>.</p>
<p>Every individual is born free and equal in dignity and rights, and the United States remains devoted to inclusion and equity for members of all races and ethnicities, both at home and abroad. To commemorate International Roma Day, we reaffirm this commitment to Roma throughout the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States, I extend best wishes to Roma everywhere on this special day when we celebrate the rich culture, language, heritage, and aspirations of Roma globally, including the generations of Romani Americans who have helped build and continue to enhance the United States.</p>
<p>We also recognize today that many of the world’s Roma continue to suffer from marginalization, systemic discrimination, statelessness, and violence. This treatment and exclusion prevent many Roma from reaching their full potential in political, social, and economic spheres. As Europe’s largest ethnic minority, we acknowledge the challenges experienced by Roma who have fled Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s unjustified and brutal attack on that country. In addition to the trauma of war, they must frequently cope with a lack of documentation and stigmatization along their evacuation routes.</p>
<p>The United States calls on all governments to uphold their international obligations, respect the human rights of all people, and provide equitable access to civil registration, housing, health care, and public services. We condemn bigotry in any form—including persistent anti-Roma bigotry—and underscore our support of the<em> Action Plan on Improving the Situation of Roma and Sinti within the OSCE Area</em>.</p>
<p>Every individual is born free and equal in dignity and rights, and the United States remains devoted to inclusion and equity for members of all races and ethnicities, both at home and abroad. To commemorate International Roma Day, we reaffirm this commitment to Roma throughout the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Further Targeting Russian State-Owned Enterprises</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/further-targeting-russian-state-owned-enterprises/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 03:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States and over 30 allies and partners across the world have levied the most impactful, coordinated, and wide-ranging economic restrictions in history in response to the Russian government&#8217;s war against Ukraine.  Today, we take additional actions to raise the economic cost on President Putin.  We are imposing blocking sanctions on two Russian state-owned enterprises:  Joint Stock Company United Shipbuilding Corporation (USC), as well as 28 USC subsidiaries and eight members of the USC board of directors; and Public Joint Stock Company Alrosa.</p>
<p>USC is one of Russia’s largest state-owned enterprises, and it developed and constructed the warships that have bombarded Ukraine’s cities.  Alrosa is a diamond-mining company, controlled by the Russian government, the proceeds of which help to finance the Russian government’s war and atrocities against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Our actions today, alongside the actions we have taken since the beginning of President Putin’s brutal and unjustified war in Ukraine, are designed to reinforce each other and intensify over time.  We remain committed to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and condemn Russia’s atrocities and disregard for life.  We support accountability for the Kremlin’s wrongdoing in this war of choice.  As long as the Kremlin continues its brutal assault on Ukraine and its people, we stand united with our allies and partners in imposing additional costs on Russia.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0707" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and the State Department <a href="https://www.state.gov/additional-state-department-designations-targeting-russian-state-owned-defense-shipbuilding-enterprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">fact sheet</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States and over 30 allies and partners across the world have levied the most impactful, coordinated, and wide-ranging economic restrictions in history in response to the Russian government&#8217;s war against Ukraine.  Today, we take additional actions to raise the economic cost on President Putin.  We are imposing blocking sanctions on two Russian state-owned enterprises:  Joint Stock Company United Shipbuilding Corporation (USC), as well as 28 USC subsidiaries and eight members of the USC board of directors; and Public Joint Stock Company Alrosa.</p>
<p>USC is one of Russia’s largest state-owned enterprises, and it developed and constructed the warships that have bombarded Ukraine’s cities.  Alrosa is a diamond-mining company, controlled by the Russian government, the proceeds of which help to finance the Russian government’s war and atrocities against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Our actions today, alongside the actions we have taken since the beginning of President Putin’s brutal and unjustified war in Ukraine, are designed to reinforce each other and intensify over time.  We remain committed to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and condemn Russia’s atrocities and disregard for life.  We support accountability for the Kremlin’s wrongdoing in this war of choice.  As long as the Kremlin continues its brutal assault on Ukraine and its people, we stand united with our allies and partners in imposing additional costs on Russia.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0707" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and the State Department <a href="https://www.state.gov/additional-state-department-designations-targeting-russian-state-owned-defense-shipbuilding-enterprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">fact sheet</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming Saudi Arabia and the UAE’s Economic and Humanitarian Support for Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-saudi-arabia-and-the-uaes-economic-and-humanitarian-support-for-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 23:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the pledge by Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates to provide $2 billion in economic support for the Central Bank of Yemen, as well as the pledge by Saudi Arabia to provide $1 billion for development projects and fuel support. This economic support will help stabilize the economy, improve Yemenis’ access to basic services, and ease the economic crisis that causes so much suffering. The United States looks forward to working with regional, international, and private sector partners to strengthen the Yemeni economy.</p>
<p>At a time when funding gaps have forced humanitarians to cut life-saving assistance for millions of Yemenis, the United States also welcomes Saudi Arabia’s pledge to provide $300 million for the UN’s humanitarian response plan. We hope that this support reaches Yemenis in need as soon as possible. The Yemen humanitarian appeal remains less than forty percent funded, and the United States urges more donors to contribute generously and expeditiously to address the suffering of Yemenis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the pledge by Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates to provide $2 billion in economic support for the Central Bank of Yemen, as well as the pledge by Saudi Arabia to provide $1 billion for development projects and fuel support. This economic support will help stabilize the economy, improve Yemenis’ access to basic services, and ease the economic crisis that causes so much suffering. The United States looks forward to working with regional, international, and private sector partners to strengthen the Yemeni economy.</p>
<p>At a time when funding gaps have forced humanitarians to cut life-saving assistance for millions of Yemenis, the United States also welcomes Saudi Arabia’s pledge to provide $300 million for the UN’s humanitarian response plan. We hope that this support reaches Yemenis in need as soon as possible. The Yemen humanitarian appeal remains less than forty percent funded, and the United States urges more donors to contribute generously and expeditiously to address the suffering of Yemenis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Terrorist Attack in Tel Aviv, Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/terrorist-attack-in-tel-aviv-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Americans are, once again, grieving with the Israeli people in the wake of another deadly terrorist attack, which took the lives of two innocent victims and wounded many more in Tel Aviv. Our hearts go out to the families and other loved ones of those killed, and we wish a speedy recovery to the injured. We are closely following developments and will continue to be in regular contact with our Israeli partners, with whom we stand resolutely in the face of senseless terrorism and violence.</p>
<p>May the memories of those who passed be a blessing.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Americans are, once again, grieving with the Israeli people in the wake of another deadly terrorist attack, which took the lives of two innocent victims and wounded many more in Tel Aviv. Our hearts go out to the families and other loved ones of those killed, and we wish a speedy recovery to the injured. We are closely following developments and will continue to be in regular contact with our Israeli partners, with whom we stand resolutely in the face of senseless terrorism and violence.</p>
<p>May the memories of those who passed be a blessing.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
