<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:42:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on Russia’s War of Aggression Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-russias-war-of-aggression-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in Bucha and a number of other Ukrainian towns. Haunting images of civilian deaths, victims of torture, and apparent executions, as well as reports of sexual violence and destruction of civilian infrastructure show the true face of Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine and its people. The massacres in the town of Bucha and other Ukrainian towns will be inscribed in the list of atrocities and severe violations of international law, including international humanitarian law and human rights, committed by the aggressor on Ukrainian soil.</p>
<p align="left">In the presence of the Foreign Minister of Ukraine, Dmytro Kuleba, we expressed today our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our deepest condolences to the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and express our readiness to assist further, including with military equipment and financial means, to allow Ukraine to defend itself against Russia’s aggression and to rebuild Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">We underscore that those responsible for these heinous acts and atrocities, including any attacks targeting civilians and destruction of civilian infrastructure, will be held accountable and prosecuted. We welcome and support the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence of these and other potential war crimes and crimes against humanity, including by the ICC Office of the Prosecutor, the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the Human Rights Monitoring Mission Ukraine of the OHCHR, and the OSCE’s mission of experts mandated by OSCE Participating States. We will provide investigative support, technical experts and funding. We will continue to promote accountability for all those complicit in Moscow’s war of choice, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. We are convinced that now is the time to suspend Russian membership of the Human Rights Council.</p>
<p align="left">Russia must immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine. Further, we urge Russia to withdraw completely its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p align="left">We warn against any threat or use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons. We recall Russia’s obligations under international treaties of which it is a party, and which protect us all. Any use by Russia of such a weapon would be unacceptable and result in severe consequences. We condemn Russia’s unsubstantiated claims and false allegations against Ukraine, a respected member of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention and the Chemical Weapons Convention that is in compliance with its legal obligations under those instruments. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p align="left">We express our gravest concern with Russia forcefully seizing control of nuclear facilities, and other violent actions in connection with a number of nuclear facilities, nuclear and other radioactive material, which have caused and continue to pose serious and direct threats to the safety and security of these facilities and their civilian personnel, significantly raising the risk of a nuclear accident or incident, which endangers the population of Ukraine, neighboring States and the international community.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our demand that Russia upholds its obligations under international humanitarian law and desists from further blatant abuses. The Russian leadership must immediately provide for safe, rapid and unimpeded humanitarian access and make safe passages work, enabling humanitarian aid to be delivered to besieged cities and civilians to reach safety.</p>
<p align="left">We commit to supporting the Government of Ukraine’s humanitarian coordination structure and to disburse humanitarian support quickly. We ask others to join in this effort. A humanitarian push including more funding is urgently needed for Ukraine and beyond as Russia’s ruthless war and actions are having massive consequences on global commodity and food prices. The resulting rise in food insecurity is being felt disproportionately by the most vulnerable. We stand in solidarity with our partners across the world who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food insecurity, keep markets open, and build resilience in the agriculture sector on all continents. We will actively counter Russia’s narrative that Western sanctions have caused the rise in global food prices and call it out for what it is: a blatant lie.</p>
<p align="left">In light of Russia’s ongoing aggression against Ukraine, carried out with Belarus’ complicity, we have already adopted unprecedented and coordinated economic and financial sanctions against Russia that impose a significant cost on its economy. We stress the necessity of further increasing the economic pressure inflicted on Russia and the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. Together with international partners, the G7 will sustain and increase pressure on Russia by imposing coordinated additional restrictive measures to effectively thwart Russian abilities to continue the aggression against Ukraine. We will work together to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions or to aid Russia by other means. We are taking further steps to expedite plans to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end.</p>
<p align="left">We commend those neighboring states to Ukraine that demonstrated great solidarity and humanity by welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals affected by the conflict. We confirm the need for increased international assistance and will continue to support these countries, including by receiving more refugees. President Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine has already forced millions of civilians, especially women, children, and elderly, to flee their homes. Over 4.2 million crossed the border to other countries, almost all of them to the EU and the Republic of Moldova. We reiterate our concern about the risk to this vulnerable population, including the risk of human trafficking and our commitment to protect these refugees.</p>
<p align="left">Ministers paid special attention to the Republic of Moldova, which hosts the largest group of refugees from Ukraine per capita. The Ministers agreed to further coordinate their assistance for Moldova’s humanitarian response and long-term resilience following the Moldova Support Conference co-hosted by Germany, France and Romania on 5 April in Berlin and the establishment of the Moldova Support Platform.</p>
<p align="left"><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in Bucha and a number of other Ukrainian towns. Haunting images of civilian deaths, victims of torture, and apparent executions, as well as reports of sexual violence and destruction of civilian infrastructure show the true face of Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine and its people. The massacres in the town of Bucha and other Ukrainian towns will be inscribed in the list of atrocities and severe violations of international law, including international humanitarian law and human rights, committed by the aggressor on Ukrainian soil.</p>
<p align="left">In the presence of the Foreign Minister of Ukraine, Dmytro Kuleba, we expressed today our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our deepest condolences to the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and express our readiness to assist further, including with military equipment and financial means, to allow Ukraine to defend itself against Russia’s aggression and to rebuild Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">We underscore that those responsible for these heinous acts and atrocities, including any attacks targeting civilians and destruction of civilian infrastructure, will be held accountable and prosecuted. We welcome and support the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence of these and other potential war crimes and crimes against humanity, including by the ICC Office of the Prosecutor, the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the Human Rights Monitoring Mission Ukraine of the OHCHR, and the OSCE’s mission of experts mandated by OSCE Participating States. We will provide investigative support, technical experts and funding. We will continue to promote accountability for all those complicit in Moscow’s war of choice, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. We are convinced that now is the time to suspend Russian membership of the Human Rights Council.</p>
<p align="left">Russia must immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine. Further, we urge Russia to withdraw completely its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p align="left">We warn against any threat or use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons. We recall Russia’s obligations under international treaties of which it is a party, and which protect us all. Any use by Russia of such a weapon would be unacceptable and result in severe consequences. We condemn Russia’s unsubstantiated claims and false allegations against Ukraine, a respected member of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention and the Chemical Weapons Convention that is in compliance with its legal obligations under those instruments. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p align="left">We express our gravest concern with Russia forcefully seizing control of nuclear facilities, and other violent actions in connection with a number of nuclear facilities, nuclear and other radioactive material, which have caused and continue to pose serious and direct threats to the safety and security of these facilities and their civilian personnel, significantly raising the risk of a nuclear accident or incident, which endangers the population of Ukraine, neighboring States and the international community.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our demand that Russia upholds its obligations under international humanitarian law and desists from further blatant abuses. The Russian leadership must immediately provide for safe, rapid and unimpeded humanitarian access and make safe passages work, enabling humanitarian aid to be delivered to besieged cities and civilians to reach safety.</p>
<p align="left">We commit to supporting the Government of Ukraine’s humanitarian coordination structure and to disburse humanitarian support quickly. We ask others to join in this effort. A humanitarian push including more funding is urgently needed for Ukraine and beyond as Russia’s ruthless war and actions are having massive consequences on global commodity and food prices. The resulting rise in food insecurity is being felt disproportionately by the most vulnerable. We stand in solidarity with our partners across the world who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food insecurity, keep markets open, and build resilience in the agriculture sector on all continents. We will actively counter Russia’s narrative that Western sanctions have caused the rise in global food prices and call it out for what it is: a blatant lie.</p>
<p align="left">In light of Russia’s ongoing aggression against Ukraine, carried out with Belarus’ complicity, we have already adopted unprecedented and coordinated economic and financial sanctions against Russia that impose a significant cost on its economy. We stress the necessity of further increasing the economic pressure inflicted on Russia and the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. Together with international partners, the G7 will sustain and increase pressure on Russia by imposing coordinated additional restrictive measures to effectively thwart Russian abilities to continue the aggression against Ukraine. We will work together to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions or to aid Russia by other means. We are taking further steps to expedite plans to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end.</p>
<p align="left">We commend those neighboring states to Ukraine that demonstrated great solidarity and humanity by welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals affected by the conflict. We confirm the need for increased international assistance and will continue to support these countries, including by receiving more refugees. President Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine has already forced millions of civilians, especially women, children, and elderly, to flee their homes. Over 4.2 million crossed the border to other countries, almost all of them to the EU and the Republic of Moldova. We reiterate our concern about the risk to this vulnerable population, including the risk of human trafficking and our commitment to protect these refugees.</p>
<p align="left">Ministers paid special attention to the Republic of Moldova, which hosts the largest group of refugees from Ukraine per capita. The Ministers agreed to further coordinate their assistance for Moldova’s humanitarian response and long-term resilience following the Moldova Support Conference co-hosted by Germany, France and Romania on 5 April in Berlin and the establishment of the Moldova Support Platform.</p>
<p align="left"><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with UK National Security Adviser Lovegrove</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-uk-national-security-adviser-lovegrove/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 01:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK National Security Adviser Sir Stephen Lovegrove today in Washington.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and NSA Lovegrove continued their close coordination in responding to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and atrocities the Russian Federation forces have committed.  The Deputy Secretary and NSA Lovegrove reaffirmed the strategic importance of the Indo-Pacific region and ensuring the AUKUS partnership delivers critical security and technology capabilities to address challenges in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK National Security Adviser Sir Stephen Lovegrove today in Washington.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and NSA Lovegrove continued their close coordination in responding to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and atrocities the Russian Federation forces have committed.  The Deputy Secretary and NSA Lovegrove reaffirmed the strategic importance of the Indo-Pacific region and ensuring the AUKUS partnership delivers critical security and technology capabilities to address challenges in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Honolulu, Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-honolulu-hawaii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Additional Russian Financial Institutions, Officials, and Other Individuals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-additional-russian-financial-institutions-officials-and-other-individuals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea Sung Kim on Recent Developments in the DPRK and U.S. Efforts to Advance Denuclearization on the Korean Peninsula</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-special-representative-for-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-korea-sung-kim-on-recent-developments-in-the-dprk-and-u-s-efforts-to-advance-denuclearization-on-the-korean-penins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sung Kim, Acting Assistant Secretary  Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 18:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sung Kim, Acting Assistant Secretary  Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:  </b>Good morning, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s press call. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim is visiting Washington this week for a series of engagements and is here to discuss U.S. policy toward the DPRK.  We’re very glad to have the special representative with us on the line today to tell you a little bit more about his visit.  Ambassador Kim will start with some opening remarks and then proceed with taking your questions.  I’d like to also take this opportunity to remind everyone that while this call is on the record, the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the end of the call.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Special Representative Kim.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:  </b>Great, thank you very much, Jalina.  And thank – many thanks to all of you for joining us this morning.  Let me start by saying a few words on where we are and where we are heading in our work on the DPRK, and then I’d be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>Since taking office, the Biden-Harris administration has made clear its priority to reduce the threat posed by the DPRK.  We are determined to protect the security of the United States, along with that of our allies and partners in the region and beyond.  We are of course closely following developments in the DPRK, and we maintain the ultimate goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>We know there are challenges, and these will not be easily resolved, but we remain fully committed to working closely with our allies and partners in a global effort to make progress toward this end goal.  Our efforts involve both diplomatic outreach and threat reduction.  And while it is clear the DPRK leadership is determined to advance its illegal weapons programs, we know that our efforts are constraining their progress.  At the same time, we have not closed the door on diplomacy.  We are committed to pursuing serious and sustained dialogue.  As we have said many times, we are prepared to meet the DPRK without preconditions.  But Pyongyang must make the choice to halt its destabilizing actions and instead choose engagement.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government at all levels has engaged vigorously on the DPRK with our allies and partners around the world.  The Secretary, Deputy Secretary Sherman, and I have consulted regularly with our counterparts in the ROK and Japan bilaterally as well as trilaterally.  We have repeatedly offered to meet the DPRK to discuss any and all issues, and yet the DPRK has declined our invitation to dialogue.  Instead, they have initiated a series of missile tests that recently culminated in at least three ICBM launches.  These actions pose a serious threat to regional stability.</p>
<p>The U.S. strongly condemns these tests, each of which was a blatant violation of multiple Security Council resolutions.  These launches demonstrate the DPRK continues to prioritize its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs at the expense of regional and international security.  This prioritization is also at the expense of the North Korean people.  The government has chosen to deploy its limited resources to fund illegal weapons programs even as the humanitarian situation in the country has grown increasingly dire.</p>
<p>The potential range of these ICBMs should also remind us that the DPRK’s actions are a global security concern.  It is not merely about the United States and the DPRK.</p>
<p>In response to DPRK’s recent escalatory actions and as part of our effort to impede the DPRK’s ability to advance its missile program, we have taken a series of diplomatic, economic, and military measures.  As of March 25, we have raised the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches at the UN Security Council six times this year.  Russia and the PRC have consistently blocked our efforts to produce a UN public statement.  And in spite of this, we’ve worked with a growing group of like-minded countries to draw attention to the DPRK’s irresponsible behavior.</p>
<p>On March 7th, the U.S. Indo-Pacific Command, INDOPACOM, ordered intensified intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance collection activities in the Yellow Sea.  USINDOPACOM also enhanced readiness among our ballistic missile defense forces in the region to help ensure the security of our allies.</p>
<p>A week later, on March 15th, USINDOPACOM announced it had conducted a carrier-based air demonstration in the Yellow Sea as a demonstration of resolve and commitment to our regional allies.  The U.S. Department of Treasury and the Department of State have also announced several new actions to help prevent the DPRK from accessing foreign items and technology that enable it to advance its prohibited weapons programs.  We have placed sanctions on a number of individuals and entities as well.</p>
<p>We will also continue to work closely with our allies and partners to address the critical issue of the DPRK’s cyber program, which poses a sophisticated and agile espionage, cyber crime, and attack threat.  The illicit revenues from the DPRK’s malicious cyber activities directly fund its unlawful WMD and ballistic missile programs.</p>
<p>Our actions are intended to make clear to the DPRK that its escalatory behavior has consequences and that the international community will not accept the DPRK’s ongoing weapons development as normal.  Most importantly, we want to make clear to the DPRK that its only viable path forward is through diplomacy.  We harbor no hostile intent towards the DPRK.  This administration is willing to listen to the DPRK’s full range of concerns and address difficult topics, but this can only happen through dialogue.</p>
<p>The DPRK finds itself isolated in unprecedented ways and has shut itself off during the COVID pandemic.  Only the resumption of diplomacy can break this isolation, and only then can we pick up the important work that has been done before, building on the Singapore Joint Statement.</p>
<p>But even as we take steps to further deter the DPRK and reduce its threat, the threat that it poses to the region and beyond, we will continue to reach out with a sincere commitment to diplomacy.  I sincerely hope this message will make its way to Pyongyang and that they will respond positively.</p>
<p>Be happy to take your questions now.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our first question from Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Just what is the U.S. interpretation of or reaction to the recent statements from Kim Yo-jong which appeared designed to threaten South Korea?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.  Her statement in response to some comments that the ROK defense minister made – I obviously was concerned by Kim Yo-jong’s statements.  They were provocative.  We obviously hope that instead of making such provocative statements, that they would focus instead on some serious engagement that will address our common goal of denuclearization – and may promote stability on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our next question from Janne Pak, please.  Janne Pak, USA Journal Korea.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b> One moment.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Hi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, can you – hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  Nice to hear from you.  And hi, Ambassador Kim.  I have two questions on North Korea.  Recently, North Korea has declared long-term confrontation rather than dialogue.  If North Korea does not come to the table of negotiation, how will the United States diplomatic solution proceed?</p>
<p>And the second question:  You said that you will not close the U.S. diplomacy.  In the meantime, North Korea has continued to develop nuclear missile in the background while having dialogue with the United States.  Do you believe that North Korea will give its nuclear weapons through dialogue?  If so, what is the reason?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Ms. Pak.  So we remain committed to the path of dialogue, and we believe, along with our allies and partners, that the only viable path forward is through diplomacy, and we hope that the North Koreans will accept our invitation to engage in a serious and sustained dialogue to advance our shared goals on the peninsula, starting with, of course, the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  But as I indicated in my opening remarks, we are willing and prepared to address any serious concerns that they may have about their situation on the peninsula.</p>
<p>With your question of – the second question about if they don’t give up through diplomacy, well, I mean, we – we and our allies and partners are determined to continue to seek the path of diplomacy.  We believe that that is the only viable path forward to achieve denuclearization on the peninsula and to maintain peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Ryohei Takagi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, thank you for briefing, Ambassador Kim.  We support you are trying to persuade China to join the new UN Security Council resolution against North Korea.  So what was your Chinese counterpart’s reaction to possible sanction resolution?</p>
<p>And secondly, I’m just wondering whether you had any good suggestions from Chinese counterparts to encourage the DPRK to engage in meaningful negotiations?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Takagi-san.  So I had a very long and detailed discussion with Special Representative Liu Xiaoming yesterday.  We covered a number of issues, including our work in the UN Security Council to achieve a new UN Security Council resolution.  We believe that the unprecedented number of DPRK ballistic missile launches this year and the instability they belong to the Korean Peninsula are obviously in nobody’s interest, and we call on the PRC as well as Russia to work with us to send a very clear message to the Security Council that North Korea’s actions are unacceptable.</p>
<p>The U.S. and China have a very important shared interest in maintaining stability on the Korean Peninsula, and through my many years of involvement in this issue, I’m convinced that Beijing shares our goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  So I look forward to working with Special Representative Liu and his colleagues in Beijing to make progress towards that goal.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s now go to the line of Doug Byun.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hello, Ambassador.  Thank you for doing this.  I was wondering if the – I mean, you kind of mentioned this, but I was wondering if North Korea has responded in any way, negative or positive, to U.S. overtures, and also if the United States is sending any private messages instead of just messaging over public messaging.</p>
<p>And I have one more question regarding the – Secretary Blinken’s meeting with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts last month in Hawaii.  At the time, the sides said they had discussed new ideas to bring North Korea back to the dialogue table.  I was wondering if you could share some of what some of those new ideas were and if there has been any progress in your discussions on those ideas.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Doug.  We have not received any response from Pyongyang, which is very disappointing because we have sent several messages, both public and private, inviting them to a dialogue without any conditions.  We made very clear that we’re willing to address their concerns, but also chart a path forward on how we can achieve progress on the denuclearization goal.</p>
<p>I still hope that they will respond positively to our many outreaches, but thus far they have not.</p>
<p>The Secretary, as you mentioned, had very productive meetings with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts in Hawaii a couple of months ago.  In fact, I think that is another example of the close coordination and communication that we have enjoyed with our allies on this very difficult issue.  I don’t want to go into the details of those discussions, but I can assure you that all three of us are committed to exploring all possible avenues to jumpstart a serious diplomatic process.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Edward Wong, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello.  I was wondering, with the change in administration in Seoul, what is your assessment of the direction that Seoul would now like to take their policy on the DPRK?  And how much of it is a departure from the policy of the Moon administration?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Yeah, thanks, Edward.  It’s tempting, but I don’t think it’s my place to predict the incoming South Korean government’s policies on this issue.  What I can say is that we have enjoyed very close cooperation and coordination with the ROK, and I fully expect that with the incoming administration that close coordination will continue on this very important issue.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sangmin Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) to several measure to North Korea to hold DPRK accountable for their provocative action, shooting ICBM.  So the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-Korean military exercises is – can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Hi, if you’re still on the line, can you please repeat your question for us?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We can hear you now.  If you’re able to repeat your question, that would be wonderful.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, okay.  So the – Ambassador, you mentioned about several measure to hold DPRK accountable for their provocations.  So do you think that the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-ROK joint military exercises can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Sangmin.  So the U.S.-ROK joint military exercises, as you know, are defensive and they’re done to make sure that we have the combined deterring capability necessary to deal with any contingency on the peninsula.  So these are extremely important exercises, and I know that both militaries are committed to continuing those efforts going forward.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Michelle Nichols, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thanks so much for the call.  I’m the Reuters correspondent up here at the UN, so I just wanted to follow up on the earlier question about the resolution.  Is China and Russia engaging on the draft resolution?  What exactly are you proposing?  Are you seeing any spillover from the Ukraine conflict?</p>
<p>And this call – you mentioned earlier that you’re hoping this – Pyongyang will get a message that the U.S. wants to talk.  Is that why you’re doing this call, to sort of publicly get a message to them because they’re not responding?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much.  As I mentioned earlier, I think the escalatory and provocative actions by the North Koreans require us to have a decisive response in the Security Council, and this is why we have, in cooperation with our partners, proposed a new UN Security Council resolution.  We have had discussions with the PRC and Russia.  Unfortunately, I cannot report that we have had productive discussions with them thus far, but I would defer to my very capable colleagues in New York to continue that effort.  I know that there is overwhelming consensus that the Security Council needs to respond to these blatant violations of multiple Security Council resolutions, and we hope that Russia and China will agree that it’s in their interest to work with us on this new Security Council resolution.</p>
<p>The purpose of doing this call, I think, is to try to address any questions and comments that the press corps may have about the status of our North Korea-related efforts.  It’s not necessarily to send a public message to the North Koreans, because I think we have made ourselves very clear through both public statements and private messages to the DPRK that we are ready to engage them in a serious and meaningful dialogue.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sho Watanabe, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, do you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, thank you for doing that.  I have two questions.  One, that North Korea’s anniversary on April 15th is now approaching, and there are also the concerns about further provocations.  So in your meeting with your Chinese counterparts, did you ask China to urge North Korea not to conduct any tests or even nuclear tests, and you persuaded China to use their own leverage to North Korea?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  Do you think there are any concrete steps that can be taken further by the three countries – Japan, U.S., and the South Korea – to increase our deterrence towards North Korea?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Watanabe.  So we are worried that, in connection with the upcoming April 15th anniversary, that the DPRK may be tempted to take another provocative action.  We obviously hope not, but we will be prepared.</p>
<p>Part of their preparation is related to your second question about the importance of trilateral cooperation among the U.S., the ROK, and Japan.  As I mentioned earlier, we have had closest possible communication and coordination with both governments, Tokyo and Seoul, and that will continue, especially as we anticipate that there may be further provocative actions by the DPRK.  And I think those possible measures include a number of different areas and I know that our colleagues in the military are also considering what we can be doing together bilaterally as well as trilaterally – more strengthen our deterrent capability.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Jinmyung Kim, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  This is Jinmyung Kim from South Korea’s <i>Chosunilbo</i>, and thank you for doing this.  Ambassador Kim, I have a question about the UN Security Council resolution you are seeking with South Korea’s Special Representative Noh Kyu-duk.  And so what is the nature of this resolution?  Do you seek to impose new, substantial sanctions on North Korea?  Or do you simply aim to have a kind of declaratory statement that condemns North Korea’s action?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  So everybody knows that it is probably unachievable right now because of the lack of cooperation – Russia’s cooperation.  So why do you still pursue this resolution while you know that it may not go through?  And my second question is:  In your dialogue with Chinese special representative, have you seen any positive signs that China has already engaged in direct communication with DPRK to help bring back them to the negotiating table?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Ms. Kim.  So the new UN Security Council resolution is intended to address a number of things, especially their continued missile activities, ballistic missile activities, because this resolution is in response to the escalatory, provocative actions that they have taken through a series of missile launches this year.  They’re up to 13 launches just this year, deeply concerning, and at least three of those have been ICBM launches.  I think it’s important for the Security Council to respond to such behavior that are clearly a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>You may be right that the PRC and Russia will not cooperate despite our earnest efforts, but I think it’s still important for us to do what is responsible.  This actually affects more than the DPRK issue.  This is about the credibility of the United Nations.  When a country violates multiple Security Council resolutions in addition to their own commitments under the Six-Party Talks as well as the Singapore joint declaration, I think we need to hold them accountable.  And this is why we’re pushing the resolution despite the fact that so far, we have received very little cooperation from Beijing and Moscow.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We have time for a final question, and let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hey, Ambassador.  Just first brief follow-ups to some of my colleagues’ questions.  When you said that you were worried about provocative action perhaps next week on the anniversary, is that concern specifically of a nuclear test?  When you talk about no response from North Korea, I’m just wondering why you think that they haven’t responded.</p>
<p>And then finally, you referenced the Singapore declaration in your opening remarks.  Do you think that that declaration should form the basis for future negotiations despite what some people see as its flaws and its vague language?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks, Conor.  So in terms of the upcoming anniversary and the provocation – provocative actions the DPRK may take, I don’t want to speculate too much, but I think it could be another missile launch, it could be a nuclear test.  The important thing is that we, in cooperation and coordination with our allies and partners, are prepared to deal with whatever they may undertake.  And I want to emphasize that we obviously hope that they will refrain from further provocation.  They’ve already done quite a bit this year – 13 launches.  So hopefully the anniversary can pass without any further escalation.</p>
<p>And I – it’s always hard for me to speculate on why Pyongyang does what it does or what it doesn’t do.  I mean, we have indicated very sincerely our interest in a diplomatic effort with them, and hope that they will respond.  I mean, I would just speculate that given that the country has been a – complete shutdown for the past two years due to the COVID pandemic, perhaps that’s a factor in the fact that they have not responded.  But I will limit my speculation to that.</p>
<p>On the Singapore declaration, I mean, you’re right about there’s been criticism that the document was too vague, not detailed enough.  But we believe that it would form a useful basis to build on, because that is one document in which the dear leader Kim Jong-un has personally made a commitment towards denuclearization.  So I think it would appropriately form a basis for a further effort to develop a viable diplomatic path and roadmap towards the complete denuclearization goal.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Thank you, everyone.  That concludes today’s briefing.  The embargo is now lifted.  Special Representative Kim, thank you so much for your time, and I hope you all have a great day ahead.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sung Kim, Acting Assistant Secretary  Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:  </b>Good morning, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s press call. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim is visiting Washington this week for a series of engagements and is here to discuss U.S. policy toward the DPRK.  We’re very glad to have the special representative with us on the line today to tell you a little bit more about his visit.  Ambassador Kim will start with some opening remarks and then proceed with taking your questions.  I’d like to also take this opportunity to remind everyone that while this call is on the record, the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the end of the call.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Special Representative Kim.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:  </b>Great, thank you very much, Jalina.  And thank – many thanks to all of you for joining us this morning.  Let me start by saying a few words on where we are and where we are heading in our work on the DPRK, and then I’d be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>Since taking office, the Biden-Harris administration has made clear its priority to reduce the threat posed by the DPRK.  We are determined to protect the security of the United States, along with that of our allies and partners in the region and beyond.  We are of course closely following developments in the DPRK, and we maintain the ultimate goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>We know there are challenges, and these will not be easily resolved, but we remain fully committed to working closely with our allies and partners in a global effort to make progress toward this end goal.  Our efforts involve both diplomatic outreach and threat reduction.  And while it is clear the DPRK leadership is determined to advance its illegal weapons programs, we know that our efforts are constraining their progress.  At the same time, we have not closed the door on diplomacy.  We are committed to pursuing serious and sustained dialogue.  As we have said many times, we are prepared to meet the DPRK without preconditions.  But Pyongyang must make the choice to halt its destabilizing actions and instead choose engagement.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government at all levels has engaged vigorously on the DPRK with our allies and partners around the world.  The Secretary, Deputy Secretary Sherman, and I have consulted regularly with our counterparts in the ROK and Japan bilaterally as well as trilaterally.  We have repeatedly offered to meet the DPRK to discuss any and all issues, and yet the DPRK has declined our invitation to dialogue.  Instead, they have initiated a series of missile tests that recently culminated in at least three ICBM launches.  These actions pose a serious threat to regional stability.</p>
<p>The U.S. strongly condemns these tests, each of which was a blatant violation of multiple Security Council resolutions.  These launches demonstrate the DPRK continues to prioritize its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs at the expense of regional and international security.  This prioritization is also at the expense of the North Korean people.  The government has chosen to deploy its limited resources to fund illegal weapons programs even as the humanitarian situation in the country has grown increasingly dire.</p>
<p>The potential range of these ICBMs should also remind us that the DPRK’s actions are a global security concern.  It is not merely about the United States and the DPRK.</p>
<p>In response to DPRK’s recent escalatory actions and as part of our effort to impede the DPRK’s ability to advance its missile program, we have taken a series of diplomatic, economic, and military measures.  As of March 25, we have raised the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches at the UN Security Council six times this year.  Russia and the PRC have consistently blocked our efforts to produce a UN public statement.  And in spite of this, we’ve worked with a growing group of like-minded countries to draw attention to the DPRK’s irresponsible behavior.</p>
<p>On March 7th, the U.S. Indo-Pacific Command, INDOPACOM, ordered intensified intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance collection activities in the Yellow Sea.  USINDOPACOM also enhanced readiness among our ballistic missile defense forces in the region to help ensure the security of our allies.</p>
<p>A week later, on March 15th, USINDOPACOM announced it had conducted a carrier-based air demonstration in the Yellow Sea as a demonstration of resolve and commitment to our regional allies.  The U.S. Department of Treasury and the Department of State have also announced several new actions to help prevent the DPRK from accessing foreign items and technology that enable it to advance its prohibited weapons programs.  We have placed sanctions on a number of individuals and entities as well.</p>
<p>We will also continue to work closely with our allies and partners to address the critical issue of the DPRK’s cyber program, which poses a sophisticated and agile espionage, cyber crime, and attack threat.  The illicit revenues from the DPRK’s malicious cyber activities directly fund its unlawful WMD and ballistic missile programs.</p>
<p>Our actions are intended to make clear to the DPRK that its escalatory behavior has consequences and that the international community will not accept the DPRK’s ongoing weapons development as normal.  Most importantly, we want to make clear to the DPRK that its only viable path forward is through diplomacy.  We harbor no hostile intent towards the DPRK.  This administration is willing to listen to the DPRK’s full range of concerns and address difficult topics, but this can only happen through dialogue.</p>
<p>The DPRK finds itself isolated in unprecedented ways and has shut itself off during the COVID pandemic.  Only the resumption of diplomacy can break this isolation, and only then can we pick up the important work that has been done before, building on the Singapore Joint Statement.</p>
<p>But even as we take steps to further deter the DPRK and reduce its threat, the threat that it poses to the region and beyond, we will continue to reach out with a sincere commitment to diplomacy.  I sincerely hope this message will make its way to Pyongyang and that they will respond positively.</p>
<p>Be happy to take your questions now.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our first question from Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Just what is the U.S. interpretation of or reaction to the recent statements from Kim Yo-jong which appeared designed to threaten South Korea?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.  Her statement in response to some comments that the ROK defense minister made – I obviously was concerned by Kim Yo-jong’s statements.  They were provocative.  We obviously hope that instead of making such provocative statements, that they would focus instead on some serious engagement that will address our common goal of denuclearization – and may promote stability on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our next question from Janne Pak, please.  Janne Pak, USA Journal Korea.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b> One moment.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Hi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, can you – hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  Nice to hear from you.  And hi, Ambassador Kim.  I have two questions on North Korea.  Recently, North Korea has declared long-term confrontation rather than dialogue.  If North Korea does not come to the table of negotiation, how will the United States diplomatic solution proceed?</p>
<p>And the second question:  You said that you will not close the U.S. diplomacy.  In the meantime, North Korea has continued to develop nuclear missile in the background while having dialogue with the United States.  Do you believe that North Korea will give its nuclear weapons through dialogue?  If so, what is the reason?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Ms. Pak.  So we remain committed to the path of dialogue, and we believe, along with our allies and partners, that the only viable path forward is through diplomacy, and we hope that the North Koreans will accept our invitation to engage in a serious and sustained dialogue to advance our shared goals on the peninsula, starting with, of course, the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  But as I indicated in my opening remarks, we are willing and prepared to address any serious concerns that they may have about their situation on the peninsula.</p>
<p>With your question of – the second question about if they don’t give up through diplomacy, well, I mean, we – we and our allies and partners are determined to continue to seek the path of diplomacy.  We believe that that is the only viable path forward to achieve denuclearization on the peninsula and to maintain peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Ryohei Takagi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, thank you for briefing, Ambassador Kim.  We support you are trying to persuade China to join the new UN Security Council resolution against North Korea.  So what was your Chinese counterpart’s reaction to possible sanction resolution?</p>
<p>And secondly, I’m just wondering whether you had any good suggestions from Chinese counterparts to encourage the DPRK to engage in meaningful negotiations?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Takagi-san.  So I had a very long and detailed discussion with Special Representative Liu Xiaoming yesterday.  We covered a number of issues, including our work in the UN Security Council to achieve a new UN Security Council resolution.  We believe that the unprecedented number of DPRK ballistic missile launches this year and the instability they belong to the Korean Peninsula are obviously in nobody’s interest, and we call on the PRC as well as Russia to work with us to send a very clear message to the Security Council that North Korea’s actions are unacceptable.</p>
<p>The U.S. and China have a very important shared interest in maintaining stability on the Korean Peninsula, and through my many years of involvement in this issue, I’m convinced that Beijing shares our goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  So I look forward to working with Special Representative Liu and his colleagues in Beijing to make progress towards that goal.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s now go to the line of Doug Byun.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hello, Ambassador.  Thank you for doing this.  I was wondering if the – I mean, you kind of mentioned this, but I was wondering if North Korea has responded in any way, negative or positive, to U.S. overtures, and also if the United States is sending any private messages instead of just messaging over public messaging.</p>
<p>And I have one more question regarding the – Secretary Blinken’s meeting with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts last month in Hawaii.  At the time, the sides said they had discussed new ideas to bring North Korea back to the dialogue table.  I was wondering if you could share some of what some of those new ideas were and if there has been any progress in your discussions on those ideas.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Doug.  We have not received any response from Pyongyang, which is very disappointing because we have sent several messages, both public and private, inviting them to a dialogue without any conditions.  We made very clear that we’re willing to address their concerns, but also chart a path forward on how we can achieve progress on the denuclearization goal.</p>
<p>I still hope that they will respond positively to our many outreaches, but thus far they have not.</p>
<p>The Secretary, as you mentioned, had very productive meetings with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts in Hawaii a couple of months ago.  In fact, I think that is another example of the close coordination and communication that we have enjoyed with our allies on this very difficult issue.  I don’t want to go into the details of those discussions, but I can assure you that all three of us are committed to exploring all possible avenues to jumpstart a serious diplomatic process.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Edward Wong, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello.  I was wondering, with the change in administration in Seoul, what is your assessment of the direction that Seoul would now like to take their policy on the DPRK?  And how much of it is a departure from the policy of the Moon administration?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Yeah, thanks, Edward.  It’s tempting, but I don’t think it’s my place to predict the incoming South Korean government’s policies on this issue.  What I can say is that we have enjoyed very close cooperation and coordination with the ROK, and I fully expect that with the incoming administration that close coordination will continue on this very important issue.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sangmin Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) to several measure to North Korea to hold DPRK accountable for their provocative action, shooting ICBM.  So the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-Korean military exercises is – can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Hi, if you’re still on the line, can you please repeat your question for us?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We can hear you now.  If you’re able to repeat your question, that would be wonderful.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, okay.  So the – Ambassador, you mentioned about several measure to hold DPRK accountable for their provocations.  So do you think that the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-ROK joint military exercises can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Sangmin.  So the U.S.-ROK joint military exercises, as you know, are defensive and they’re done to make sure that we have the combined deterring capability necessary to deal with any contingency on the peninsula.  So these are extremely important exercises, and I know that both militaries are committed to continuing those efforts going forward.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Michelle Nichols, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thanks so much for the call.  I’m the Reuters correspondent up here at the UN, so I just wanted to follow up on the earlier question about the resolution.  Is China and Russia engaging on the draft resolution?  What exactly are you proposing?  Are you seeing any spillover from the Ukraine conflict?</p>
<p>And this call – you mentioned earlier that you’re hoping this – Pyongyang will get a message that the U.S. wants to talk.  Is that why you’re doing this call, to sort of publicly get a message to them because they’re not responding?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much.  As I mentioned earlier, I think the escalatory and provocative actions by the North Koreans require us to have a decisive response in the Security Council, and this is why we have, in cooperation with our partners, proposed a new UN Security Council resolution.  We have had discussions with the PRC and Russia.  Unfortunately, I cannot report that we have had productive discussions with them thus far, but I would defer to my very capable colleagues in New York to continue that effort.  I know that there is overwhelming consensus that the Security Council needs to respond to these blatant violations of multiple Security Council resolutions, and we hope that Russia and China will agree that it’s in their interest to work with us on this new Security Council resolution.</p>
<p>The purpose of doing this call, I think, is to try to address any questions and comments that the press corps may have about the status of our North Korea-related efforts.  It’s not necessarily to send a public message to the North Koreans, because I think we have made ourselves very clear through both public statements and private messages to the DPRK that we are ready to engage them in a serious and meaningful dialogue.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sho Watanabe, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, do you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, thank you for doing that.  I have two questions.  One, that North Korea’s anniversary on April 15th is now approaching, and there are also the concerns about further provocations.  So in your meeting with your Chinese counterparts, did you ask China to urge North Korea not to conduct any tests or even nuclear tests, and you persuaded China to use their own leverage to North Korea?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  Do you think there are any concrete steps that can be taken further by the three countries – Japan, U.S., and the South Korea – to increase our deterrence towards North Korea?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Watanabe.  So we are worried that, in connection with the upcoming April 15th anniversary, that the DPRK may be tempted to take another provocative action.  We obviously hope not, but we will be prepared.</p>
<p>Part of their preparation is related to your second question about the importance of trilateral cooperation among the U.S., the ROK, and Japan.  As I mentioned earlier, we have had closest possible communication and coordination with both governments, Tokyo and Seoul, and that will continue, especially as we anticipate that there may be further provocative actions by the DPRK.  And I think those possible measures include a number of different areas and I know that our colleagues in the military are also considering what we can be doing together bilaterally as well as trilaterally – more strengthen our deterrent capability.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Jinmyung Kim, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  This is Jinmyung Kim from South Korea’s <i>Chosunilbo</i>, and thank you for doing this.  Ambassador Kim, I have a question about the UN Security Council resolution you are seeking with South Korea’s Special Representative Noh Kyu-duk.  And so what is the nature of this resolution?  Do you seek to impose new, substantial sanctions on North Korea?  Or do you simply aim to have a kind of declaratory statement that condemns North Korea’s action?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  So everybody knows that it is probably unachievable right now because of the lack of cooperation – Russia’s cooperation.  So why do you still pursue this resolution while you know that it may not go through?  And my second question is:  In your dialogue with Chinese special representative, have you seen any positive signs that China has already engaged in direct communication with DPRK to help bring back them to the negotiating table?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Ms. Kim.  So the new UN Security Council resolution is intended to address a number of things, especially their continued missile activities, ballistic missile activities, because this resolution is in response to the escalatory, provocative actions that they have taken through a series of missile launches this year.  They’re up to 13 launches just this year, deeply concerning, and at least three of those have been ICBM launches.  I think it’s important for the Security Council to respond to such behavior that are clearly a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>You may be right that the PRC and Russia will not cooperate despite our earnest efforts, but I think it’s still important for us to do what is responsible.  This actually affects more than the DPRK issue.  This is about the credibility of the United Nations.  When a country violates multiple Security Council resolutions in addition to their own commitments under the Six-Party Talks as well as the Singapore joint declaration, I think we need to hold them accountable.  And this is why we’re pushing the resolution despite the fact that so far, we have received very little cooperation from Beijing and Moscow.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We have time for a final question, and let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hey, Ambassador.  Just first brief follow-ups to some of my colleagues’ questions.  When you said that you were worried about provocative action perhaps next week on the anniversary, is that concern specifically of a nuclear test?  When you talk about no response from North Korea, I’m just wondering why you think that they haven’t responded.</p>
<p>And then finally, you referenced the Singapore declaration in your opening remarks.  Do you think that that declaration should form the basis for future negotiations despite what some people see as its flaws and its vague language?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks, Conor.  So in terms of the upcoming anniversary and the provocation – provocative actions the DPRK may take, I don’t want to speculate too much, but I think it could be another missile launch, it could be a nuclear test.  The important thing is that we, in cooperation and coordination with our allies and partners, are prepared to deal with whatever they may undertake.  And I want to emphasize that we obviously hope that they will refrain from further provocation.  They’ve already done quite a bit this year – 13 launches.  So hopefully the anniversary can pass without any further escalation.</p>
<p>And I – it’s always hard for me to speculate on why Pyongyang does what it does or what it doesn’t do.  I mean, we have indicated very sincerely our interest in a diplomatic effort with them, and hope that they will respond.  I mean, I would just speculate that given that the country has been a – complete shutdown for the past two years due to the COVID pandemic, perhaps that’s a factor in the fact that they have not responded.  But I will limit my speculation to that.</p>
<p>On the Singapore declaration, I mean, you’re right about there’s been criticism that the document was too vague, not detailed enough.  But we believe that it would form a useful basis to build on, because that is one document in which the dear leader Kim Jong-un has personally made a commitment towards denuclearization.  So I think it would appropriately form a basis for a further effort to develop a viable diplomatic path and roadmap towards the complete denuclearization goal.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Thank you, everyone.  That concludes today’s briefing.  The embargo is now lifted.  Special Representative Kim, thank you so much for your time, and I hope you all have a great day ahead.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Transnational Criminal to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-transnational-criminal-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Australian Foreign Minister Payne</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-australian-foreign-minister-payne-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 16:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>50th Anniversary of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/50th-anniversary-of-the-biological-and-toxin-weapons-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
