<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 03:44:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-chung-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 03:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Republic of Korea (ROK) Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Honolulu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Chung reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance in tackling today’s most pressing global challenges and ensuring a peaceful, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region. They highlighted our shared commitment to combatting the COVID-19 pandemic, including through the KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership. They also affirmed bilateral cooperation in this decisive decade for action to combat the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK) recent ballistic missile launches, which were in violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions, and reaffirmed openness to diplomacy and dialogue with the DPRK. The Secretary also emphasized close cooperation with the Republic of Korea and other allies and partners towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the ironclad U.S. commitment to the defense of the ROK. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed the need to deepen trilateral cooperation with Japan as we work together to address our shared challenges. On Burma, the Secretary stressed the importance of working with international partners to address human rights abuses and press the regime to cease the violence, release all those unjustly detained, allow unhindered humanitarian access, and restore Burma’s path to democracy. Secretary Blinken also shared concerns about Russia’s efforts to destabilize Ukraine and emphasized the importance of responding swiftly, effectively, and in a united way to further Russian aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Republic of Korea (ROK) Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Honolulu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Chung reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance in tackling today’s most pressing global challenges and ensuring a peaceful, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region. They highlighted our shared commitment to combatting the COVID-19 pandemic, including through the KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership. They also affirmed bilateral cooperation in this decisive decade for action to combat the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK) recent ballistic missile launches, which were in violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions, and reaffirmed openness to diplomacy and dialogue with the DPRK. The Secretary also emphasized close cooperation with the Republic of Korea and other allies and partners towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the ironclad U.S. commitment to the defense of the ROK. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed the need to deepen trilateral cooperation with Japan as we work together to address our shared challenges. On Burma, the Secretary stressed the importance of working with international partners to address human rights abuses and press the regime to cease the violence, release all those unjustly detained, allow unhindered humanitarian access, and restore Burma’s path to democracy. Secretary Blinken also shared concerns about Russia’s efforts to destabilize Ukraine and emphasized the importance of responding swiftly, effectively, and in a united way to further Russian aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-chung-eui-yong-before-their-meeting-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 02:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to have this opportunity to be with our friends and partners.  Eui-yong and I have been working very closely together for many months now and – just a testament to the absolute vitality of the relationship, the partnership between the United States and the Republic of Korea.  I’d like to say one of the hallmarks is the fact that we have what is truly a global partnership.  Of course, we work on bilateral issues, we’re working on regional issues together, but we&#8217;re also working on global issues – everything from COVID to climate.  So we have a lot to talk about.  I was very much looking forward to this opportunity to compare notes with you, and then we’ll be spending time with our colleague from Japan in our trilateral.  But thank you for being here and I look forward to good conversation.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:  </b>Well, thank you, Tony, for inviting (inaudible) my delegation to Hawaii.  It’s a real treat for us to be here.  Well, first of all, I thank you for your concern and interest in the safety of Koreans living in the United States.  We do appreciate your effort to provide safety for all (inaudible).  And I also thank you and welcome (inaudible) to such a seasoned diplomat like Mr. Philip Goldberg as new U.S. ambassador to Korea.  We are very much looking forward to closely working with the new ambassador, and I hope he’ll be installed soon.  And I will also say that we hope to continue our consultations on how to further strengthen our bilateral relationship, not only to (inaudible), but also promote our global partnership.  We have a lot to cover.  And we are very concerned about the – all of the situation of the Korean Peninsula in particular, and I hope we can also have – with exchange of views in how to deal with the situation.</p>
<p>And I&#8217;m also very happy to have a trilat meeting (inaudible) in the region.  I had a good meeting with Minister Hayashi (inaudible).  Although we have differences – and it&#8217;s not easy for us to get over with all these differences – but we agreed to continue our close diplomatic consultation.  And I think that is a very positive (inaudible), and I&#8217;m very much looking forward to having this close trilateral cooperation amongst three of us.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to have this opportunity to be with our friends and partners.  Eui-yong and I have been working very closely together for many months now and – just a testament to the absolute vitality of the relationship, the partnership between the United States and the Republic of Korea.  I’d like to say one of the hallmarks is the fact that we have what is truly a global partnership.  Of course, we work on bilateral issues, we’re working on regional issues together, but we&#8217;re also working on global issues – everything from COVID to climate.  So we have a lot to talk about.  I was very much looking forward to this opportunity to compare notes with you, and then we’ll be spending time with our colleague from Japan in our trilateral.  But thank you for being here and I look forward to good conversation.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:  </b>Well, thank you, Tony, for inviting (inaudible) my delegation to Hawaii.  It’s a real treat for us to be here.  Well, first of all, I thank you for your concern and interest in the safety of Koreans living in the United States.  We do appreciate your effort to provide safety for all (inaudible).  And I also thank you and welcome (inaudible) to such a seasoned diplomat like Mr. Philip Goldberg as new U.S. ambassador to Korea.  We are very much looking forward to closely working with the new ambassador, and I hope he’ll be installed soon.  And I will also say that we hope to continue our consultations on how to further strengthen our bilateral relationship, not only to (inaudible), but also promote our global partnership.  We have a lot to cover.  And we are very concerned about the – all of the situation of the Korean Peninsula in particular, and I hope we can also have – with exchange of views in how to deal with the situation.</p>
<p>And I&#8217;m also very happy to have a trilat meeting (inaudible) in the region.  I had a good meeting with Minister Hayashi (inaudible).  Although we have differences – and it&#8217;s not easy for us to get over with all these differences – but we agreed to continue our close diplomatic consultation.  And I think that is a very positive (inaudible), and I&#8217;m very much looking forward to having this close trilateral cooperation amongst three of us.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Assistant Secretary Akunna Cook Leads State Department Prosper Africa Economic Diplomacy Delegation to Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-assistant-secretary-akunna-cook-leads-state-department-prosper-africa-economic-diplomacy-delegation-to-africa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 20:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Assistant Secretary of State Akunna Cook and Prosper Africa Acting Chief Operating Officer Leslie Marbury will travel to Nigeria, Kenya, South Africa, and Namibia on a State Department Prosper Africa economic diplomacy visit, February 14 &#8211; March 1. The delegation will meet with entrepreneurs, women-owned and small and medium-sized enterprises, investors, and policy-makers to drive U.S. trade and investment in Africa’s creative industries, ICT and digital technologies, and energy and infrastructure, among other fast-growing sectors.</p>
<p>Last November, Secretary Antony Blinken traveled to the continent signaling the United States’ commitment to strengthen economic, social, and political ties with our partners in Africa. The delegation will advance this commitment by connecting businesses and investors with Prosper Africa tools and resources to remove trade and investment barriers, drive transactions forward, and promote market opportunities.</p>
<p>This is the first in a series of economic diplomacy visits the State Department will undertake to advance U.S. trade and investment with Africa as part of the whole-of-government Prosper Africa initiative. By working hand-in-hand with the private sector and our African partners, the U.S. government is driving investment in African innovation, opportunity, and creative solutions to the world’s most pressing problems.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Assistant Secretary of State Akunna Cook and Prosper Africa Acting Chief Operating Officer Leslie Marbury will travel to Nigeria, Kenya, South Africa, and Namibia on a State Department Prosper Africa economic diplomacy visit, February 14 &#8211; March 1. The delegation will meet with entrepreneurs, women-owned and small and medium-sized enterprises, investors, and policy-makers to drive U.S. trade and investment in Africa’s creative industries, ICT and digital technologies, and energy and infrastructure, among other fast-growing sectors.</p>
<p>Last November, Secretary Antony Blinken traveled to the continent signaling the United States’ commitment to strengthen economic, social, and political ties with our partners in Africa. The delegation will advance this commitment by connecting businesses and investors with Prosper Africa tools and resources to remove trade and investment barriers, drive transactions forward, and promote market opportunities.</p>
<p>This is the first in a series of economic diplomacy visits the State Department will undertake to advance U.S. trade and investment with Africa as part of the whole-of-government Prosper Africa initiative. By working hand-in-hand with the private sector and our African partners, the U.S. government is driving investment in African innovation, opportunity, and creative solutions to the world’s most pressing problems.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UK Foreign Secretary Truss</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-uk-foreign-secretary-truss-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today about acute and shared concerns that Russia may be considering launching further military aggression against Ukraine in the coming days. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of working with our NATO Allies and European partners in the region to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. They also discussed that international efforts should continue to seek a meaningful dialogue with Russia on mutual security concerns that could lead to a diplomatic resolution. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed that any decision the United States makes in Europe will be in consultation with our Allies and partners. The two also discussed UK-EU negotiations over the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocol and preserving the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday agreement, as well the importance of reaching a successful conclusion on talks with Iran on mutual return to full implementation of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today about acute and shared concerns that Russia may be considering launching further military aggression against Ukraine in the coming days. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of working with our NATO Allies and European partners in the region to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. They also discussed that international efforts should continue to seek a meaningful dialogue with Russia on mutual security concerns that could lead to a diplomatic resolution. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed that any decision the United States makes in Europe will be in consultation with our Allies and partners. The two also discussed UK-EU negotiations over the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocol and preserving the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday agreement, as well the importance of reaching a successful conclusion on talks with Iran on mutual return to full implementation of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Senior State Department Official On Our Diplomatic Presence in Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/a-senior-state-department-official-on-our-diplomatic-presence-in-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Good morning, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s background briefing.  Today we will be joined by a senior administration official who will discuss the recent decision regarding the ordered departure at the U.S. Embassy in Kyiv, Ukraine.  To reiterate, the contents of this briefing this morning are on background and they are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>For your information, however not for reporting purposes, I’d like to let you know that we are joined by .  Please refer to the  as the senior State Department official.  We’ll start with some opening remarks and afterwards we will resume to taking your questions.</p>
<p>, take it away.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</b>  Thank you, .  Good morning, pleased to be with you this morning, and really appreciate your attention to this important issue.</p>
<p>Last night on – late on February 11 in Washington, as you have seen, we directed most remaining embassy staff still located in Ukraine to depart the country immediately.  And as you have seen in parallel with that direction, we have updated our Travel Advisory to note that change in the official U.S. Government posture and presence in the country, and to again reiterate that American citizens should leave immediately via commercial means or private vehicle.</p>
<p>As of Sunday, February 13, we are suspending consular services at Embassy Ukraine, so American citizens will not be able to secure routine support with passport issues, visa services, any of the other routine consular services that we customarily provide from our embassies.</p>
<p>As part of our enduring commitment to support our fellow citizens, we will continue to maintain some capacity to provide emergency consular services in Lviv.  But I want to stress these will be emergency consular services, and routine services will only be available for American citizens who might be in Ukraine today, in neighboring countries at our diplomatic and consular facilities in those countries.</p>
<p>Now these developments mean for private American citizens that it isn’t just time to leave Ukraine; it is past time for private citizens to leave Ukraine.  We have no higher priority than the safety and security of our fellow citizens, including our fellow U.S. Government employees, and we do a great deal to provide support for our fellow citizens.  But as you know, there are real limits to what we are able to do in a war zone.  We fervently hope and continue to work intensively to try to ensure that Ukraine does not become a war zone, and as you saw Secretary Blinken working actively this morning to try to prevent that outcome with Foreign Minister Lavrov.</p>
<p>However, it appears increasingly likely that this is where this situation is headed, towards some kind of active conflict.  And that is why we are reducing our staff to a bare minimum while we still have the ability to get our official people out safely and in a predictable fashion.</p>
<p>Even while we are taking these steps to reduce our official footprint, we’re of course continuing to support the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people consistent with our strategic partnership with Ukraine and consistent with our principled support for Ukrainian sovereignty and its territorial integrity.</p>
<p>Security assistance continues to flow into the country with deliveries of ammunition yesterday and, I believe, scheduled for today.  And so that continues moving in even as we bring our own people out and encourage private citizens to leave.</p>
<p>Let me say one other thing before I turn to your questions.  I’ve spent a fair bit of time in war zones as an official American.  They are inherently volatile, they’re unpredictable, and they are extremely dangerous, by definition, as a war zone.  And once a country or a region, in terms of a region within a country, becomes an active conflict zone, we will have very little ability, we have very little ability, to help our fellow citizens.</p>
<p>And so that is why you are continuing to see this constant drumbeat to encourage our American citizens to leave and to help them have realistic expectations about what the U.S. Government will and will not be able to do for them in a conflict.  And you’ve seen colleagues from the White House reiterating that American citizens should not expect the U.S. military is going to come rescue them in Ukraine at the last minute.  That’s not going to be happening in this scenario and that’s why it is past time for them to leave Ukraine.</p>
<p>So with that, I’m happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s start with the line of Christina Ruffini, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Christina Ruffini, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  Once again, Christina Ruffini, your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Yes, I’m speaking.  Can you hear me?  Hello?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Okay.  Thank you.  Thank you, everybody.  I’m wondering if you can say, when did you notify Ukraine you would be evacuating the embassy?  And can you give us any idea of how many embassy staff are going to stay behind in Lviv?  Is the chargé going to relocate there as well?  And is the number of Americans who’ve registered with the U.S. Government saying “hey, we’re here, we’re in Ukraine” still around 7,000, or is that increased in recent days?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Sure.  So as you would expect, we’ve been in constant contact and dialogue with the Ukrainian Government, with senior Ukrainian officials, about many facets of this unfolding crisis, but to include our own posture within the country. And we – those discussions, that dialogue with them, included discussions yesterday about our plans to further reduce our footprint in the country.</p>
<p>I want to emphasize – you used the term “evacuating” the embassy.  We are not closing the embassy.  We are not suspending operations of the embassy within the country.  We are further reducing at this time the number of staff that we have in country to conduct only the most essential business at this time.  We will have some staff relocating to Lviv.  For reasons of security I’m not going to get into specific details of how many people we’re going to have in Lviv and how many will be staying in Kyiv at this time.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Matt Lee, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi, good morning.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Yes, I can, Matt.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi.  Hi, .  Listen, I know you don’t want to get into the numbers, but can you just say – can you give us just an idea of the people who will stay in Kyiv?  What are they going to be doing – not the numbers, but what actually will they be doing?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Sure.  So we’re planning to try to maintain the core functions of our embassy as long as possible with a reduced number of people.  So we are going to maintain staff sufficient to be able to continue working closely with the Ukrainian Government to be able to ensure we’ve got the best possible information for our senior leaders and the President about what’s happening broadly in society, what the Ukrainian Government is telling us about how the situation is unfolding.</p>
<p>As I noted, we are going to maintain personnel so we can provide emergency consular services, and then we will have sufficient staff to provide the security and support and communications required to enable the team that remains behind to stay in touch with Washington, and to do so as safely as we can under the circumstances.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s go to Nick Schifrin.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Nick Schifrin, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thanks very much.  Good morning.  I’m wondering if you would describe the diplomats and the consulate in Lviv as kind of a fallback, or if you would not be comfortable with that language.</p>
<p>And then a larger question because you’re talking about the conversations with the Ukrainian Government – obviously, the Ukrainian Government has been very public about some of the disagreements that it’s had with U.S. intelligence.  From your perspective, can you characterize the nature of the conversation between U.S. officials and Ukrainian officials, and whether you believe that they’re on the same page?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>So I wouldn’t characterize the presence we will have in Lviv as a fallback.  I would characterize it as ensuring that we can maintain our ability to perform core diplomatic functions in a period of great uncertainty where, in that space where Russia takes military action, I think prudence requires us to assume, to plan for, and prepare for a worse-case scenario.  And a worse-case scenario would obviously involve substantial Russian attacks on the Ukrainian capital.</p>
<p>And Russia has a very capable military with substantial combat power, and should it choose to utilize a significant piece of that combat power against the Ukrainian capital, there’s plenty of opportunities, even with restraint and respect for diplomatic facilities, for things to go wrong.  So we are essentially diffusing our people to reduce the risk that – should this tip quickly into an active conflict – that we have reduced the risk to official personnel to the best of our ability under the circumstances.</p>
<p>With regard to our conversations with Ukrainian officials about this matter, they’ve been very professional, and the Ukrainians understand why we are taking these steps even if all of them don’t necessarily agree, as you noted, with our threat assessment and with our assessment of the extent to which potential conflict is imminent.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Let’s go to Kylie Atwood, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Kylie Atwood, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good morning.  Thank you for doing this call.  A question about the embassy in Kyiv.  What kind of actions are – excuse me – is the State Department taking now to assure safety of any documents there?  Is there any document destruction that has begun?</p>
<p>And can you just be a little bit clearer?  I mean, did you pick Lviv because it is on the western side of Ukraine, which would be further away from any potential impending fighting?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</b>  Sure.  So we in all of our diplomatic facilities constantly maintain a close eye on the classified equipment and classified information holdings that the embassy has in a period of – has actively in the embassy.  And every embassy has guidelines to keep those holdings to the minimum required for normal operations.  When we get into these kinds of situations we always, as a matter of course, reduce those holdings, reduce that volume of equipment appropriately to reflect the unpredictability of the situation.  And just as we do in other circumstances, have done in other circumstances like this in the past, we’re taking those appropriate, prudent steps as part of our contingency planning for those worst cases that I mentioned.</p>
<p>With regard to Lviv, we’re shifting some people there in part because of its closer proximity to U.S. diplomatic and consular facilities in neighboring countries so we can maintain close coordination with colleagues in those neighboring countries and ensure that, should military action on the part of Russia begin, we can move those people safely should we decide to do so.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Let’s go to Missy Ryan.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Missy Ryan, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much.  I just wanted to ask, I know that you said that you and also Jake Sullivan said yesterday that the U.S. military is not going to be coming in to help Americans.  But is the United States doing anything currently to organize departures for American citizens other than providing information about commercial routes out?  Are you organizing buses or anything like that in the way that’s happened in the past in order to facilitate the departure of folks from Ukraine?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</b>  Sure, good question.  We are not engaged in those activities, because up to this point in time there have been ample opportunities via normal commercial means, whether that’s commercial flights, whether that’s train service to neighboring countries, whether that’s the ability to leave via private vehicle driving across neighboring – the border to neighboring countries.</p>
<p>All of those options have been available to American citizens, and very few of the American citizens who have been in touch with us in recent days have expressed an inability to physically get themselves out of the country.  Those who have been contacting us have been looking for help getting new passports or securing visas for non-American resident – or non-American citizen family members that they may have.  So it’s been of that nature in terms of the service and support we’ve been providing.</p>
<p>We are not going to be in a position, again, as we unfortunately are seeing increasing signs that we’re heading toward those worse-case scenarios even while we continue intensive efforts to prevent those from occurring.  Nonetheless, we’re not going to be in a position in those worse-case scenarios to be organizing evacuation convoys for Americans.  And that is, again, why we are reiterating to them that it is past time for them to leave.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Let’s go to Vivian Salama.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Vivian Patami, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thanks, .  Thanks, everyone, for doing the call.  I wanted to actually follow up on something that Nick and Kylie had asked, and then I’ll ask another question, if possible.</p>
<p>Just with regard to the facility in Lviv, obviously we don’t have a consulate, if I’m not mistaken, there.  And so is this a facility that – a makeshift facility that you all created because of the need to move staff there?  I mean, if you could explain a little bit more of sort of where they’re going to be operating out of, and whether or not this was something that was established a while ago, or is it something established just in response to this crisis?</p>
<p>And my main question that I wanted to ask because I’m just a bit unclear:  Are those who are being ordered to leave, are they coming back to D.C. or are they going to other countries?  Is it a mixed bag?  If you can kind of shed light on where they’re going to actually be stationed in the interim until things go back to normal, I guess.  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Sure.  So most of the personnel who are – who are departing Ukraine will be at least temporarily coming back to the States, where they will continue – many of them – to work on Ukraine.  As this crisis continues to unfold, we’ve got an enormous amount of policy work, an enormous amount of operational coordination to support the many lines of effort the U.S. Government has underway.  And so they’ll be supplementing colleagues who are already assigned in Washington in performing a lot of that work.</p>
<p>Some of them may go to neighboring countries to support their colleagues in our embassies and consulates there, depending on how this situation unfolds.  I can envision a number of scenarios in which our ongoing efforts to both support Americans who have managed to depart Ukraine, but also through our efforts to continue to provide assistance to the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people, that’s going to create additional work for those embassies and consulates, and we want to make sure we’re staffed appropriately to conduct those activities.</p>
<p>With regard to the work we’re going to be doing from Lviv, I want to be really upfront, straightforward here:  It is not a facility.  It is not something we have constructed, leased, planned for for a substantial period of time.  Conceptually, this is much more like a group of people from the embassy temporarily working in another city, just as we would if we had a visit by senior U.S. Government officials or members of Congress or a trade show or some other activity that required a group of our people to temporarily work from another location.  We – in normal times, we deploy our personnel to different parts of a country from – other than the capital city or the city in which we might have a consulate.  And that’s what we’re doing here.  We’re just unfortunately having to do it in conditions that are frankly much more perilous for the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s take a final question from Charlotte (inaudible).</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Charlotte, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi, thanks for doing this call.  I was wondering if American citizens have been following your advice to leave Ukraine and if you know how many are remaining.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Thank you.  We don’t keep track of how many American citizens are located in any country consistent with our democratic values and principles.  So we rely on American citizens to tell us when they are present in a particular country, and we have a couple of ways we try to get them to do that.  But of course, they’re free to advise us or not.</p>
<p>So very difficult for us to estimate at any given time how many American citizens are present in any country, and that includes Ukraine.  A couple thousand American citizens have informed us in recent days that they are present in the country.  We’re in active contact with them to understand whether or not they are planning to leave.  A percentage of them have indicated they wanted to leave.  Some of those people have left already.  Some of those people we have, again, provided services to to enable them to leave.</p>
<p>And there’s another substantial part of that group that have said they’re choosing to remain in Ukraine.  And even while we strongly urge them to reconsider and advise them to leave because of the dangers that we foresee, we fully respect their right to make their own choices.  And people have – there are many reasons why people might resist leaving, including if they’re long-term residents of Ukraine.</p>
<p>But again, from our perspective, we are doing everything possible to underscore to American citizens the dangers of remaining in the country due to the unfolding crisis and the escalating crisis, and reiterating to them that our ability to help them through that crisis, during that crisis, is going to be extremely limited, and they cannot have any reasonable expectation that the U.S. Government is going to be able to rescue them if they find themselves in harm’s way in a war zone.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you all again for joining today’s background briefing.  The briefing has concluded and the embargo is lifted.  Have a great rest of your Saturday.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Good morning, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s background briefing.  Today we will be joined by a senior administration official who will discuss the recent decision regarding the ordered departure at the U.S. Embassy in Kyiv, Ukraine.  To reiterate, the contents of this briefing this morning are on background and they are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>For your information, however not for reporting purposes, I’d like to let you know that we are joined by .  Please refer to the  as the senior State Department official.  We’ll start with some opening remarks and afterwards we will resume to taking your questions.</p>
<p>, take it away.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</b>  Thank you, .  Good morning, pleased to be with you this morning, and really appreciate your attention to this important issue.</p>
<p>Last night on – late on February 11 in Washington, as you have seen, we directed most remaining embassy staff still located in Ukraine to depart the country immediately.  And as you have seen in parallel with that direction, we have updated our Travel Advisory to note that change in the official U.S. Government posture and presence in the country, and to again reiterate that American citizens should leave immediately via commercial means or private vehicle.</p>
<p>As of Sunday, February 13, we are suspending consular services at Embassy Ukraine, so American citizens will not be able to secure routine support with passport issues, visa services, any of the other routine consular services that we customarily provide from our embassies.</p>
<p>As part of our enduring commitment to support our fellow citizens, we will continue to maintain some capacity to provide emergency consular services in Lviv.  But I want to stress these will be emergency consular services, and routine services will only be available for American citizens who might be in Ukraine today, in neighboring countries at our diplomatic and consular facilities in those countries.</p>
<p>Now these developments mean for private American citizens that it isn’t just time to leave Ukraine; it is past time for private citizens to leave Ukraine.  We have no higher priority than the safety and security of our fellow citizens, including our fellow U.S. Government employees, and we do a great deal to provide support for our fellow citizens.  But as you know, there are real limits to what we are able to do in a war zone.  We fervently hope and continue to work intensively to try to ensure that Ukraine does not become a war zone, and as you saw Secretary Blinken working actively this morning to try to prevent that outcome with Foreign Minister Lavrov.</p>
<p>However, it appears increasingly likely that this is where this situation is headed, towards some kind of active conflict.  And that is why we are reducing our staff to a bare minimum while we still have the ability to get our official people out safely and in a predictable fashion.</p>
<p>Even while we are taking these steps to reduce our official footprint, we’re of course continuing to support the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people consistent with our strategic partnership with Ukraine and consistent with our principled support for Ukrainian sovereignty and its territorial integrity.</p>
<p>Security assistance continues to flow into the country with deliveries of ammunition yesterday and, I believe, scheduled for today.  And so that continues moving in even as we bring our own people out and encourage private citizens to leave.</p>
<p>Let me say one other thing before I turn to your questions.  I’ve spent a fair bit of time in war zones as an official American.  They are inherently volatile, they’re unpredictable, and they are extremely dangerous, by definition, as a war zone.  And once a country or a region, in terms of a region within a country, becomes an active conflict zone, we will have very little ability, we have very little ability, to help our fellow citizens.</p>
<p>And so that is why you are continuing to see this constant drumbeat to encourage our American citizens to leave and to help them have realistic expectations about what the U.S. Government will and will not be able to do for them in a conflict.  And you’ve seen colleagues from the White House reiterating that American citizens should not expect the U.S. military is going to come rescue them in Ukraine at the last minute.  That’s not going to be happening in this scenario and that’s why it is past time for them to leave Ukraine.</p>
<p>So with that, I’m happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s start with the line of Christina Ruffini, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Christina Ruffini, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  Once again, Christina Ruffini, your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Yes, I’m speaking.  Can you hear me?  Hello?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Okay.  Thank you.  Thank you, everybody.  I’m wondering if you can say, when did you notify Ukraine you would be evacuating the embassy?  And can you give us any idea of how many embassy staff are going to stay behind in Lviv?  Is the chargé going to relocate there as well?  And is the number of Americans who’ve registered with the U.S. Government saying “hey, we’re here, we’re in Ukraine” still around 7,000, or is that increased in recent days?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Sure.  So as you would expect, we’ve been in constant contact and dialogue with the Ukrainian Government, with senior Ukrainian officials, about many facets of this unfolding crisis, but to include our own posture within the country. And we – those discussions, that dialogue with them, included discussions yesterday about our plans to further reduce our footprint in the country.</p>
<p>I want to emphasize – you used the term “evacuating” the embassy.  We are not closing the embassy.  We are not suspending operations of the embassy within the country.  We are further reducing at this time the number of staff that we have in country to conduct only the most essential business at this time.  We will have some staff relocating to Lviv.  For reasons of security I’m not going to get into specific details of how many people we’re going to have in Lviv and how many will be staying in Kyiv at this time.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Matt Lee, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi, good morning.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Yes, I can, Matt.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi.  Hi, .  Listen, I know you don’t want to get into the numbers, but can you just say – can you give us just an idea of the people who will stay in Kyiv?  What are they going to be doing – not the numbers, but what actually will they be doing?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Sure.  So we’re planning to try to maintain the core functions of our embassy as long as possible with a reduced number of people.  So we are going to maintain staff sufficient to be able to continue working closely with the Ukrainian Government to be able to ensure we’ve got the best possible information for our senior leaders and the President about what’s happening broadly in society, what the Ukrainian Government is telling us about how the situation is unfolding.</p>
<p>As I noted, we are going to maintain personnel so we can provide emergency consular services, and then we will have sufficient staff to provide the security and support and communications required to enable the team that remains behind to stay in touch with Washington, and to do so as safely as we can under the circumstances.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s go to Nick Schifrin.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Nick Schifrin, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thanks very much.  Good morning.  I’m wondering if you would describe the diplomats and the consulate in Lviv as kind of a fallback, or if you would not be comfortable with that language.</p>
<p>And then a larger question because you’re talking about the conversations with the Ukrainian Government – obviously, the Ukrainian Government has been very public about some of the disagreements that it’s had with U.S. intelligence.  From your perspective, can you characterize the nature of the conversation between U.S. officials and Ukrainian officials, and whether you believe that they’re on the same page?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>So I wouldn’t characterize the presence we will have in Lviv as a fallback.  I would characterize it as ensuring that we can maintain our ability to perform core diplomatic functions in a period of great uncertainty where, in that space where Russia takes military action, I think prudence requires us to assume, to plan for, and prepare for a worse-case scenario.  And a worse-case scenario would obviously involve substantial Russian attacks on the Ukrainian capital.</p>
<p>And Russia has a very capable military with substantial combat power, and should it choose to utilize a significant piece of that combat power against the Ukrainian capital, there’s plenty of opportunities, even with restraint and respect for diplomatic facilities, for things to go wrong.  So we are essentially diffusing our people to reduce the risk that – should this tip quickly into an active conflict – that we have reduced the risk to official personnel to the best of our ability under the circumstances.</p>
<p>With regard to our conversations with Ukrainian officials about this matter, they’ve been very professional, and the Ukrainians understand why we are taking these steps even if all of them don’t necessarily agree, as you noted, with our threat assessment and with our assessment of the extent to which potential conflict is imminent.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Let’s go to Kylie Atwood, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Kylie Atwood, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good morning.  Thank you for doing this call.  A question about the embassy in Kyiv.  What kind of actions are – excuse me – is the State Department taking now to assure safety of any documents there?  Is there any document destruction that has begun?</p>
<p>And can you just be a little bit clearer?  I mean, did you pick Lviv because it is on the western side of Ukraine, which would be further away from any potential impending fighting?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</b>  Sure.  So we in all of our diplomatic facilities constantly maintain a close eye on the classified equipment and classified information holdings that the embassy has in a period of – has actively in the embassy.  And every embassy has guidelines to keep those holdings to the minimum required for normal operations.  When we get into these kinds of situations we always, as a matter of course, reduce those holdings, reduce that volume of equipment appropriately to reflect the unpredictability of the situation.  And just as we do in other circumstances, have done in other circumstances like this in the past, we’re taking those appropriate, prudent steps as part of our contingency planning for those worst cases that I mentioned.</p>
<p>With regard to Lviv, we’re shifting some people there in part because of its closer proximity to U.S. diplomatic and consular facilities in neighboring countries so we can maintain close coordination with colleagues in those neighboring countries and ensure that, should military action on the part of Russia begin, we can move those people safely should we decide to do so.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Let’s go to Missy Ryan.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Missy Ryan, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much.  I just wanted to ask, I know that you said that you and also Jake Sullivan said yesterday that the U.S. military is not going to be coming in to help Americans.  But is the United States doing anything currently to organize departures for American citizens other than providing information about commercial routes out?  Are you organizing buses or anything like that in the way that’s happened in the past in order to facilitate the departure of folks from Ukraine?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</b>  Sure, good question.  We are not engaged in those activities, because up to this point in time there have been ample opportunities via normal commercial means, whether that’s commercial flights, whether that’s train service to neighboring countries, whether that’s the ability to leave via private vehicle driving across neighboring – the border to neighboring countries.</p>
<p>All of those options have been available to American citizens, and very few of the American citizens who have been in touch with us in recent days have expressed an inability to physically get themselves out of the country.  Those who have been contacting us have been looking for help getting new passports or securing visas for non-American resident – or non-American citizen family members that they may have.  So it’s been of that nature in terms of the service and support we’ve been providing.</p>
<p>We are not going to be in a position, again, as we unfortunately are seeing increasing signs that we’re heading toward those worse-case scenarios even while we continue intensive efforts to prevent those from occurring.  Nonetheless, we’re not going to be in a position in those worse-case scenarios to be organizing evacuation convoys for Americans.  And that is, again, why we are reiterating to them that it is past time for them to leave.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Let’s go to Vivian Salama.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Vivian Patami, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thanks, .  Thanks, everyone, for doing the call.  I wanted to actually follow up on something that Nick and Kylie had asked, and then I’ll ask another question, if possible.</p>
<p>Just with regard to the facility in Lviv, obviously we don’t have a consulate, if I’m not mistaken, there.  And so is this a facility that – a makeshift facility that you all created because of the need to move staff there?  I mean, if you could explain a little bit more of sort of where they’re going to be operating out of, and whether or not this was something that was established a while ago, or is it something established just in response to this crisis?</p>
<p>And my main question that I wanted to ask because I’m just a bit unclear:  Are those who are being ordered to leave, are they coming back to D.C. or are they going to other countries?  Is it a mixed bag?  If you can kind of shed light on where they’re going to actually be stationed in the interim until things go back to normal, I guess.  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Sure.  So most of the personnel who are – who are departing Ukraine will be at least temporarily coming back to the States, where they will continue – many of them – to work on Ukraine.  As this crisis continues to unfold, we’ve got an enormous amount of policy work, an enormous amount of operational coordination to support the many lines of effort the U.S. Government has underway.  And so they’ll be supplementing colleagues who are already assigned in Washington in performing a lot of that work.</p>
<p>Some of them may go to neighboring countries to support their colleagues in our embassies and consulates there, depending on how this situation unfolds.  I can envision a number of scenarios in which our ongoing efforts to both support Americans who have managed to depart Ukraine, but also through our efforts to continue to provide assistance to the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people, that’s going to create additional work for those embassies and consulates, and we want to make sure we’re staffed appropriately to conduct those activities.</p>
<p>With regard to the work we’re going to be doing from Lviv, I want to be really upfront, straightforward here:  It is not a facility.  It is not something we have constructed, leased, planned for for a substantial period of time.  Conceptually, this is much more like a group of people from the embassy temporarily working in another city, just as we would if we had a visit by senior U.S. Government officials or members of Congress or a trade show or some other activity that required a group of our people to temporarily work from another location.  We – in normal times, we deploy our personnel to different parts of a country from – other than the capital city or the city in which we might have a consulate.  And that’s what we’re doing here.  We’re just unfortunately having to do it in conditions that are frankly much more perilous for the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Let’s take a final question from Charlotte (inaudible).</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Charlotte, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi, thanks for doing this call.  I was wondering if American citizens have been following your advice to leave Ukraine and if you know how many are remaining.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Thank you.  We don’t keep track of how many American citizens are located in any country consistent with our democratic values and principles.  So we rely on American citizens to tell us when they are present in a particular country, and we have a couple of ways we try to get them to do that.  But of course, they’re free to advise us or not.</p>
<p>So very difficult for us to estimate at any given time how many American citizens are present in any country, and that includes Ukraine.  A couple thousand American citizens have informed us in recent days that they are present in the country.  We’re in active contact with them to understand whether or not they are planning to leave.  A percentage of them have indicated they wanted to leave.  Some of those people have left already.  Some of those people we have, again, provided services to to enable them to leave.</p>
<p>And there’s another substantial part of that group that have said they’re choosing to remain in Ukraine.  And even while we strongly urge them to reconsider and advise them to leave because of the dangers that we foresee, we fully respect their right to make their own choices.  And people have – there are many reasons why people might resist leaving, including if they’re long-term residents of Ukraine.</p>
<p>But again, from our perspective, we are doing everything possible to underscore to American citizens the dangers of remaining in the country due to the unfolding crisis and the escalating crisis, and reiterating to them that our ability to help them through that crisis, during that crisis, is going to be extremely limited, and they cannot have any reasonable expectation that the U.S. Government is going to be able to rescue them if they find themselves in harm’s way in a war zone.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you all again for joining today’s background briefing.  The briefing has concluded and the embargo is lifted.  Have a great rest of your Saturday.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with New Zealand Foreign Minister Mahuta</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-new-zealand-foreign-minister-mahuta-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 13:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with New Zealand Foreign Minister Nanaia Mahuta to discuss the United States and New Zealand&#8217;s shared priorities in the Indo-Pacific. The Secretary highlighted U.S. and New Zealand’s joint efforts to respond to the collective challenges of the Indo-Pacific. He also briefed Foreign Minister Mahuta on the current situation on Ukraine&#8217;s borders, and the two discussed their shared commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with New Zealand Foreign Minister Nanaia Mahuta to discuss the United States and New Zealand&#8217;s shared priorities in the Indo-Pacific. The Secretary highlighted U.S. and New Zealand’s joint efforts to respond to the collective challenges of the Indo-Pacific. He also briefed Foreign Minister Mahuta on the current situation on Ukraine&#8217;s borders, and the two discussed their shared commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-russian-foreign-minister-lavrov-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 13:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov today by phone to discuss acute and shared concerns that Russia may be considering launching further military aggression against Ukraine in the coming days. The Secretary made clear that a diplomatic path to resolving the crisis remained open, but it would require Moscow to deescalate and engage in good-faith discussions. He reiterated that should Moscow pursue the path of aggression and further invade Ukraine, it would result in a resolute, massive, and united Transatlantic response.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov today by phone to discuss acute and shared concerns that Russia may be considering launching further military aggression against Ukraine in the coming days. The Secretary made clear that a diplomatic path to resolving the crisis remained open, but it would require Moscow to deescalate and engage in good-faith discussions. He reiterated that should Moscow pursue the path of aggression and further invade Ukraine, it would result in a resolute, massive, and united Transatlantic response.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Meet and Greet with Mission Fiji Personnel and Families</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-meet-and-greet-with-mission-fiji-personnel-and-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Suva, Fiji</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Suva</p>
<p><b>MR GREUBEL:  </b>Those were our LE staff, they were not professionals.  They should be professionals, but they were an embassy staff.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Izumi and I welcome you and all of our honored guests to U.S. Embassy Suva.  I wish to especially thank our FSNA president, Laisani, and our – Laisani, please raise your hand – (applause) – and our honor guard for this memorable and traditional Fijian welcome.</p>
<p>Our local staff are so excited and honored to perform for you on the occasion of this historic visit.  Our American staff and family members are so proud to serve the United States in this increasingly geostrategic region of the globe.  Your visit reinforces the importance of the Pacific Islands and our jobs.</p>
<p>Again, welcome, and <i>bula</i>, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Secretary Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I am quite literally at a loss for words.  We’ve had a few greetings in the last year at missions around the world, but I think that really takes the cake.</p>
<p>I was tempted to say welcome to a typical morning at the State Department, that’s how we start the day.  (Laughter.)  But the truth is thank you, and that will stay with – I think – stay with all of us for a long time.</p>
<p>And to each and every one of you, to the locally employed staff, the performers, for that <i>sevusevu</i> and <i>meke</i>.  Amazing.</p>
<p>Tony, it’s great to be with you.  Thank you so much for your leadership of this mission at what is not just a critical time, but I think a time of incredible opportunity I wanted to try to and underscore by being here today.  But you’re carrying forward with this team, with all of you, that work every single day.</p>
<p>It was striking to me, as I mentioned, that it has been a little while since someone in my position has been here.  You have to go back to Secretary Shultz nearly four decades ago.  But I’m here for a very clear purpose:  the Indo-Pacific, is simply, going to write the story of the 21st century.  Fiji is a big part of that.  It has been and remains a remarkable force in the region itself with the Pacific Island Forum, with the University of the South Pacific, the regional mission of the IMF, and as we were talking about just a little while ago, remarkable leadership role on climate on the world stage, the first country to ratify Paris.  It has a strong voice.  And as a result, the work that each and every one of you is doing every day is not only helping to magnify that voice; it’s helping to build a stronger, deeper partnership between the United States and Fiji, and as a result as well between the United States and the entire region.</p>
<p>And as I said, we really see the future as being here – 60 percent of global GDP, 50 percent of the world’s population.  The future is here.  And as a result of the work that you’re doing, the future is now.  And I’m grateful for it.</p>
<p>You’re supporting local organizations to help lead an economy recovery after what has been and remains an incredibly challenging time.  You’re building mentorship programs for women entrepreneurs and making a difference and helping people find a way to make a difference in their lives.  The work that’s being done to boost cyber security awareness here at the embassy, all our partners in Fiji and civil society, training officials to fight human trafficking.  And of course, throughout, you’ve been doing this in the context of COVID, quarantine, curfews, pain and suffering, and the loss of loved ones, extreme weather.  I’ve heard about the extraordinary history of the cyclone season, volcanic eruption.</p>
<p>But through all of it, I really wanted to say thank you, because you’ve done it with incredible resilience, you’ve done it by sticking together, you’ve done it by having each other’s backs.  And it’s not lost on any of us, even though we’re a distance away, what you’ve done, how you’re doing it.  And I really wanted to stop by and say thank you for doing it so well and so effectively.</p>
<p>What really strikes me as I’ve had the opportunity to go from embassy to embassy around the world in this time of COVID, is this common denominator that I’m seeing of people caring for each other, having each other’s backs, collecting food and supplies, finances to support those who are in need, getting vaccinated to protect one another – 100 percent vaccination in this embassy by June of 2021.  And I want to say a special thanks to the medical unit here.  You’ve done such a remarkable job.  Andrea, Emily, Reapi, I think – I’m not sure if you’re here this evening, but I really want to thank you for everything you’ve done to make sure that this team, this mission, is safe and protected.</p>
<p>And thank you as well to the Foreign Service National Association, led by Laisani, a big part of community life here at the embassy, and of course, this truly remarkable local staff.  We find talent in all sorts of ways.  This was, again, almost overwhelming.  I really want to thank you for sharing that with me tonight.</p>
<p>But I also want to recognize a few people for their extraordinary service and partnership with us:   Kesaia Tauilagi, 33 years of service to the embassy; Jiva, 32 years; Iane Rigamoto, 31 years of service.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for everything that you’ve done building the partnership between our countries.</p>
<p>And let me just say to all of you, whether you are Foreign Service, Civil Service, locally employed staff, family, colleagues from USAID and other partnered and sister agencies, the Peace Corps:  thank you, thank you, thank you for everything you’re doing every single day to build this relationship, to do it so well, to do it so effectively, to do it in this challenging time.  As we say, “We’re from the Federal Government, we’re here to help.”  I’m here to say thank you.</p>
<p>I know how much work goes into these visits.  It often seems to those of us on the receiving end of all your work that everything is incredibly smooth.  We never see all the churn that goes on underneath the – underneath it all.  But I know that it’s there and it happens.  And mostly, I want to say to you have a really, really great wheels-up party when we take off.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you, everyone.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Suva, Fiji</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Suva</p>
<p><b>MR GREUBEL:  </b>Those were our LE staff, they were not professionals.  They should be professionals, but they were an embassy staff.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Izumi and I welcome you and all of our honored guests to U.S. Embassy Suva.  I wish to especially thank our FSNA president, Laisani, and our – Laisani, please raise your hand – (applause) – and our honor guard for this memorable and traditional Fijian welcome.</p>
<p>Our local staff are so excited and honored to perform for you on the occasion of this historic visit.  Our American staff and family members are so proud to serve the United States in this increasingly geostrategic region of the globe.  Your visit reinforces the importance of the Pacific Islands and our jobs.</p>
<p>Again, welcome, and <i>bula</i>, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Secretary Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I am quite literally at a loss for words.  We’ve had a few greetings in the last year at missions around the world, but I think that really takes the cake.</p>
<p>I was tempted to say welcome to a typical morning at the State Department, that’s how we start the day.  (Laughter.)  But the truth is thank you, and that will stay with – I think – stay with all of us for a long time.</p>
<p>And to each and every one of you, to the locally employed staff, the performers, for that <i>sevusevu</i> and <i>meke</i>.  Amazing.</p>
<p>Tony, it’s great to be with you.  Thank you so much for your leadership of this mission at what is not just a critical time, but I think a time of incredible opportunity I wanted to try to and underscore by being here today.  But you’re carrying forward with this team, with all of you, that work every single day.</p>
<p>It was striking to me, as I mentioned, that it has been a little while since someone in my position has been here.  You have to go back to Secretary Shultz nearly four decades ago.  But I’m here for a very clear purpose:  the Indo-Pacific, is simply, going to write the story of the 21st century.  Fiji is a big part of that.  It has been and remains a remarkable force in the region itself with the Pacific Island Forum, with the University of the South Pacific, the regional mission of the IMF, and as we were talking about just a little while ago, remarkable leadership role on climate on the world stage, the first country to ratify Paris.  It has a strong voice.  And as a result, the work that each and every one of you is doing every day is not only helping to magnify that voice; it’s helping to build a stronger, deeper partnership between the United States and Fiji, and as a result as well between the United States and the entire region.</p>
<p>And as I said, we really see the future as being here – 60 percent of global GDP, 50 percent of the world’s population.  The future is here.  And as a result of the work that you’re doing, the future is now.  And I’m grateful for it.</p>
<p>You’re supporting local organizations to help lead an economy recovery after what has been and remains an incredibly challenging time.  You’re building mentorship programs for women entrepreneurs and making a difference and helping people find a way to make a difference in their lives.  The work that’s being done to boost cyber security awareness here at the embassy, all our partners in Fiji and civil society, training officials to fight human trafficking.  And of course, throughout, you’ve been doing this in the context of COVID, quarantine, curfews, pain and suffering, and the loss of loved ones, extreme weather.  I’ve heard about the extraordinary history of the cyclone season, volcanic eruption.</p>
<p>But through all of it, I really wanted to say thank you, because you’ve done it with incredible resilience, you’ve done it by sticking together, you’ve done it by having each other’s backs.  And it’s not lost on any of us, even though we’re a distance away, what you’ve done, how you’re doing it.  And I really wanted to stop by and say thank you for doing it so well and so effectively.</p>
<p>What really strikes me as I’ve had the opportunity to go from embassy to embassy around the world in this time of COVID, is this common denominator that I’m seeing of people caring for each other, having each other’s backs, collecting food and supplies, finances to support those who are in need, getting vaccinated to protect one another – 100 percent vaccination in this embassy by June of 2021.  And I want to say a special thanks to the medical unit here.  You’ve done such a remarkable job.  Andrea, Emily, Reapi, I think – I’m not sure if you’re here this evening, but I really want to thank you for everything you’ve done to make sure that this team, this mission, is safe and protected.</p>
<p>And thank you as well to the Foreign Service National Association, led by Laisani, a big part of community life here at the embassy, and of course, this truly remarkable local staff.  We find talent in all sorts of ways.  This was, again, almost overwhelming.  I really want to thank you for sharing that with me tonight.</p>
<p>But I also want to recognize a few people for their extraordinary service and partnership with us:   Kesaia Tauilagi, 33 years of service to the embassy; Jiva, 32 years; Iane Rigamoto, 31 years of service.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for everything that you’ve done building the partnership between our countries.</p>
<p>And let me just say to all of you, whether you are Foreign Service, Civil Service, locally employed staff, family, colleagues from USAID and other partnered and sister agencies, the Peace Corps:  thank you, thank you, thank you for everything you’re doing every single day to build this relationship, to do it so well, to do it so effectively, to do it in this challenging time.  As we say, “We’re from the Federal Government, we’re here to help.”  I’m here to say thank you.</p>
<p>I know how much work goes into these visits.  It often seems to those of us on the receiving end of all your work that everything is incredibly smooth.  We never see all the churn that goes on underneath the – underneath it all.  But I know that it’s there and it happens.  And mostly, I want to say to you have a really, really great wheels-up party when we take off.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you, everyone.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Acting Fijian Prime Minister Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum At a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-acting-fijian-prime-minister-aiyaz-sayed-khaiyum-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Denarau Island, Fiji</p>
<p>Sofitel Fiji Resort</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>The Acting Prime Minister of Fiji, the U.S. Secretary of State, and members of the media, <i>bula vinaka</i> to you all.  A special welcome to the Secretary of State Blinken and members of his delegation and the accompanying media, too.  I welcome you to our joint press conference, ladies and gentlemen.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, I now invite the Acting Prime Minister of Fiji, the Honorable Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum, to deliver his address.  You have the floor, sir.</p>
<p><b>ACTING PRIME MINISTER SAYED-KHAIYUM:  </b>Thank you.  <i>Bula vinaka</i> and good evening, ladies and gentlemen.  I wish to welcome Secretary Blinken and his delegation and the American media to Fiji in particular.</p>
<p>We are at the crossroads of a 40 million square kilometer patch of the Pacific Ocean that is governed by the Pacific Islands and our neighbors, Australia and New Zealand.  Most of world maps cut our region right down the middle.  So you may not know by looking, but we are the largest ocean continent in the world.</p>
<p>That big, blue responsibility is linked to the well-being of every person on Earth.  Despite that, Fiji and our small-state neighbors have felt at times, to borrow an American term, like a flyover country.  Small dots spotted from plane windows of leaders en route to meetings where they spoke about us, rather than with us, if they spoke of us at all.</p>
<p>When the USA signaled its intent to leave the Paris Agreement, we felt forgotten by a superpower.  So of course, we welcome President Biden’s promise to the world that America was back.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, your being here shows that promise was more than words.  We have just held the most historic and comprehensive meeting ever between Fiji and the USA and a wider meeting with our fellow Pacific leaders.  We believe that both mark the start of more direct partnership between Fiji and the USA, and a new era for America in the blue frontier of the Pacific.</p>
<p>The last significant American presence we felt in Fiji were soldiers we welcomed here during the Second World War.  We face a new war today, a climate war that is devastating our people unlike any conflict before it.  There is no region of the world, not in the Pacific, not in Europe, not in the Americas, that will be spared its consequences.</p>
<p>Fourteen cyclones have struck Fiji since we signed the Paris Agreement, each storm driving home the urgency of adapting and curbing global emissions.  This week, Ba Town, an hour’s drive away from here, was flooded for the third time in three months.  Six communities in Fiji have been moved to escape the rising seas with 14 others in the queue, not to mention the diminishing reefs and the erratic weather patterns that threaten our people’s livelihoods and ways of life.</p>
<p>We, of course, aren’t alone:  The Pacific Islands are sinking; Texas is freezing; California is burning; and New York is flooding.  When a superstorm misses Fiji, American Samoa is in the crosshairs.  And Hawaii, Guam, and FSM know many of Fiji’s struggles because they also live them.</p>
<p>Fiji and America are both working to support a more secure, stable Indo-Pacific region, and indeed a peaceful region.  There is far more we need to do together as partners in this battle of our lives.  As a nation that shares many of our struggles and our values, America is uniquely positioned to be a direct partner to Fiji for peace and climate security not only across the Indo-Pacific but here in the blue Pacific.</p>
<p>And not only because America is a large emitter that it must cut its carbon emissions, but because it is an innovator that can create climate solutions.  We need American might and its mind as well as pioneering solutions and investments here on the shores of this blue frontier.</p>
<p>Our discussions, ladies and gentlemen, covered our commitment to upholding the rule of law in our region, including the Law of Sea.  As we move to sustainably manage and protect our ocean, we sought to jointly up our game through our navies, militaries, and our Fiji police force through maritime surveillance cooperation to end illegal fishing, combat transnational crime, and ensure that this is an ocean dedicated to exploration and discovery, not exploitation and destruction.</p>
<p>In this respect, we also discussed the opportunities for greater participation from the USA in the Australian-funded Blackrock facility in Fiji to coordinate joint responses to the catastrophic events not just in Fiji but in the wider Pacific.</p>
<p>During our meeting we welcomed America’s net zero commitment as well as Mr. Blinken’s recent pledge to decarbonize operations within the State Department.</p>
<p>Fijians believe in leading by example as well, which is why, despite our emissions being negligible, we have committed to achieving net zero by 2050.  Mitigation and adaptation both require access to technology we do not have, and which major market powers like the USA can help us deploy, including (inaudible).  And that means jobs for Fijians, jobs in cutting-edge technology and from nature, that both can build the future.</p>
<p>We also spoke on Fiji’s role in leading a regional recovery from the pandemic.  With the support of the USA and our development partners, over 90 percent of Fijians over the age of 15 are fully vaccinated, which allowed us to welcome American visitors from the 1st of December last year, and we hope to welcome many more, including your families and the many Americans watching us today.</p>
<p>We are also keen to open more of the U.S. export market to our farmers.  We would love to export more of our kava (inaudible), as well as ginger, carob, turmeric, sugar, Fijian chocolates, cosmetics, and other Fijian-grown and Fijian-made products to the U.S.</p>
<p>We also welcome U.S. firms looking to participate in our growing outsourcing services sector.  We have young, well-spoken, English-speaking, tech-savvy and, frankly, very friendly people who would love the opportunity.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, this visit reaffirms that the ocean and islands that fall under our region’s responsibility are too vital for our people and for our planet for any leader to fly over or overlook.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, your visit to Fiji is the first in almost 40 years.  But today has not been about the last 40, 4 decades or 40 years.  It is about the many more to come, decades that our nations will meet together as enduring partners with shared values enlisted with humanity in overcoming the greatest challenges of our time.</p>
<p>It is now my privilege, ladies and gentlemen, to invite our friend, Secretary Blinken, to make his remarks.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, look, I am tempted to close my book, because it’s very hard to top the eloquence of the Acting Prime Minister.  I think he captured powerfully the afternoon that we’ve spent together but also the perspective that we share on the future, the future of the United States and Fiji, the future of the United States and all of our friends and partners in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>And I want to thank you not only for the incredible graciousness of your hospitality today, but also for your leadership of the, I think, truly extraordinary session that we had with friends and partners from throughout the region.  It was incredibly valuable to me, to our team, and I really thank you very much for that.</p>
<p>It’s a pleasure to be here, and not only to be, as it turns out, the first secretary of state to visit Fiji in 36 years, going back to Secretary Shultz.  And I really want to thank the people of Fiji for welcoming us today.</p>
<p>I’m going to spend a little bit of time, if I can, this evening covering the important ground that we walked on today as we look to the future.  Before I do that, I want to say a few words about something that is going on half a world away from here but that is profoundly relevant to this region, and that is the situation in and around Ukraine.</p>
<p>We continue to see very troubling signs of Russian escalation, including new forces arriving around Ukraine’s borders.  As I said yesterday, we are in the window when a Russian invasion could start at any time if President Putin so decides.  That includes in the coming days.  We don’t know whether President Putin has made that decision, but we do know that he has put in place the capacity to act on very short notice.</p>
<p>Throughout the trip that we’ve been on, I’ve been in very close coordination with the national security team back in Washington, including multiple discussions with President Biden on our plans and preparations and, of course, with our chargé in Kyiv.  I have also engaged with counterparts around the world on our ongoing diplomatic efforts.  In recent days I’ve spoken to the French Foreign Minister Le Drian, NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg, our Quad allies and partners, of course:  Australia, India, Japan.  I spoke earlier today with my Ukrainian counterpart, Foreign Minister Kuleba, and I’ll speak this evening with Foreign Secretary Truss of the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>We have a remarkable level of unity and common purpose.  We and our allies have made this crystal clear to Moscow.  If President Putin decides to take military action, we will swiftly impose severe economic sanctions in coordination with allies and partners around the world, we’ll bolster Ukraine’s ability to defend itself, we will reinforce our allies on the eastern flank of NATO.</p>
<p>I’ll underscore this unity and resolve when I speak with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov a little bit later this evening.  I’ll also make clear, as I have consistently, that if Russia is genuinely interested in resolving this crisis of its own making through diplomacy and dialogue, we are prepared to do that.  In fact, that’s our preferred path.  It’s the right and responsible thing to do.  But it must take place in the context of de-escalation.  So far, we have only seen escalation from Moscow.</p>
<p>This is a pivotal moment.  We are prepared for whatever should happen.</p>
<p>As I’ve said throughout this trip, our return to the Indo-Pacific now, even as we continue to work relentlessly to resolve the crisis in Ukraine, is, in itself, a demonstration of our commitment to staying focused on this region.  And that includes the Pacific Islands.</p>
<p>When Secretary Shultz was here in 1985, he praised Fiji for being a diverse democracy and, as he put it – and I quote – “a member of the international community that’s done your share and more as a peacekeeper in a troubled world.”  And he expressed hope that the ties of friendship and cooperation between Fiji and the United States would grow closer and stronger in the years ahead.</p>
<p>Today Fiji is again a democracy, which is a credit to the perseverance and determination of its people.  Fiji has been a proud contributor to peacekeeping operations around the world for 43 years and counting.  Just in the past few months you have sent help to Tonga after the eruption and tsunami, and to the Solomon Islands to help bring an end to recent violence.  And just as Secretary Shultz hoped, the ties between our countries, between Fiji and the United States, have grown stronger and closer, including on security, on health, climate, trade and investment, promoting regional and global cooperation.  That partnership serves not only our countries but many others, because Fiji and all the Pacific Island nations are a vital part of the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>A few months ago, when I was in Indonesia, I had a chance to preview my country’s approach to this vast and vital part of the world.  I laid out the five core elements of our engagement:  first, advancing a free and open Indo-Pacific; second, forging stronger connections within and beyond the region; third, promoting broad-based prosperity; fourth, helping build resilience; and fifth, bolstering security.</p>
<p>Today the United States is releasing our Indo-Pacific Strategy in full.  It’s the result of a year of intensive engagement and consultation with allies and partners across the region and beyond, and hearing directly from its people about what’s most important to them.  And it reflects the fundamental truth that no region on Earth will affect the lives and livelihoods of Americans more than the Indo-Pacific, which accounts for 60 percent of the global economy, two-thirds of all economic growth over the last five years.</p>
<p>Every defining issue of the 21st century runs through this region:  the climate crisis, global health, the future of technology, whether nations will be free to chart their own path or be subject to coercion by more powerful nations.  Our strategy is built on collaboration.  We want to develop sustained, innovative, mutually reinforcing partnerships across the Indo-Pacific with our allies, our partners; with regional institutions like ASEAN, APEC, which the United States will host next year; the Pacific Islands Forum, which Fiji is chairing this year.</p>
<p>The Acting Prime Minister and I just came from a meeting of the Pacific Islands Forum where I reinforced my country’s commitment to the region and the PIF’s critical role in driving regional action.  We welcome the decision of the Micronesian States to pause their withdrawal from the PIF to allow for continued discussions.</p>
<p>We’re strengthening our relationships in every corner of the region.  We’re building our longstanding ties in Northeast Asia and Australia and New Zealand, investing more deeply in the Pacific Islands, Southeast Asia, and South Asia.</p>
<p>We’re also forging new connections across continents, between our European and Indo-Pacific partners, as only the United States can do.  The European Union’s first-ever Indo-Pacific strategy aligns with our own.  And the United States is increasingly speaking with one voice with our NATO allies and our G7 partners when it comes to Indo-Pacific matters.</p>
<p>You can see the strength of that commitment to the Indo-Pacific throughout the past year.  Just look at some of the key markers on our calendar, from President Biden being the first U.S. president to address the Pacific Islands Forum to our increasing engagement with the Quad, whose ministers I just met with in Melbourne, to deepening our cooperation on a range of security and defense priorities through AUKUS.</p>
<p>We also intend to open a U.S. embassy in the Solomon Islands, in its capital city, to deepen our cooperation with Pacific Island partners.</p>
<p>And these steps are only the beginning.  We’ll continue to advance our engagement and investments in the Indo-Pacific.  That includes in the Pacific Islands because what happens here matters to the United States.  We share a history.  It was here on these beaches that Americans braved some of the hardest-fought battles of the Second World War.  Our people are closely tied together by a large Pacific Islander diaspora in the United States.</p>
<p>As much as any other place in the world, these islands are ground zero for the devastating impact of climate change.  And I heard that so powerfully and eloquently from our colleagues this afternoon.  It resonates not just as something that we think about but something that actually touches us here, because for so many of our partners here this is truly the existential issue of our times.  And we’re committed to tackling that challenge, to meeting it head on, to doing it together.</p>
<p>And here in the Pacific Islands we see a clear example of why standing up for a free and open Indo-Pacific matters for real people.  Pacific Islanders are proud.  They believe that no matter their size, they alone should be able to choose their path, whether that’s how they manage their natural resources or who they partner with.  We share that belief, and we think the world is a more secure and prosperous place when core international principles like that are respected, whether that’s here in the Pacific, in Ukraine, or anywhere else.</p>
<p>You see the strength of our commitment to the region in our partnership with Fiji.  Together our countries are taking on major issues facing not only us, but countries throughout the region and, indeed, beyond.  On COVID-19, for example, the United States has provided more than 700,000 vaccine doses to Pacific Island countries, including Fiji.  We’re working together to build Fiji’s capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to future health emergencies.</p>
<p>On security, just this week three shipriders from Fiji are joining the crew of the U.S. Coast Guard Cutter <i>Stratton</i> to conduct patrols in support of maritime sovereignty and security.  The United States is proud that several of Fiji’s future leaders are being trained in our military academies.</p>
<p>On climate, Fiji and other Pacific Island nations have been leading voices, powerful voices, calling for the world’s major economies to take strong action to limit warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius.  Fiji was the first country in the world to ratify the Paris Agreement.  In Glasgow the United States announced our goal of mobilizing $150 billion in public and private climate finance by 2030, and we intend for a substantial portion of that money to support climate adaptation in Fiji and throughout the Pacific region.</p>
<p>The thread that runs through all of our engagements with Fiji is that we’re working together in a spirit of partnership, in a spirit of respect, to tackle shared challenges, to build upon shared opportunities, to deliver concrete results for people on issues that actually affect their lives.  And that’s the approach behind our Indo-Pacific strategy, as a whole.  This isn’t about opposing any country.  It’s about the shared future we want to build together for people across this region.  We’re proud to be building that future with Fiji.</p>
<p>So thank you again, Acting Prime Minister.  Thank you to all the people here for such a warm welcome.  I look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, Acting Prime Minister and Secretary Blinken, for your statements this evening.  Given the time constraints and also that Secretary Blinken has got other engagements tonight, I would ask or inform the – our media that there are only two questions that we will have.  I will ask the first question, and Mr. Ned Price will ask the second.</p>
<p>So the first question, I will ask Mr. Nasokia to ask your question.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) Secretary Blinken, you just returned from the Quad meeting, which has (inaudible) a lot on security.  What do you see as Fiji’s role in this strategy?  What is it for us, the people of Fiji?</p>
<p>And in addition to that, as climate change and natural disaster relief being the top priorities of Pacific Island countries including Fiji, did you establish a concrete commitment on such issues from the U.S. during this visit?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m happy to start.  I think what’s most important, whether it is the Quad countries, whether it’s our partnership and relationship with Fiji, whether it’s what we’re doing here with Pacific Island partners and nations – all of which is reflected in our Indo-Pacific strategy – is that we are – we start with a shared commitment to the same values, to democracy, to human rights, to the rule of law, to regional peace and stability.  That is the common denominator that joins the Quad, that joins our relationship.</p>
<p>And together we are committed to a free and open Indo-Pacific in which people can live their lives freely and make their own decisions, in which countries can engage together and choose with whom they work and associate, and in which we together try to build an affirmative vision for the future, and one that actually delivers concrete results for our people, both in meeting the challenges that we’re facing that are very evident to everyone now, starting with COVID, climate, the impact of emerging technologies on all of our lives – as well as finding the opportunity that I think is so powerful in this region.  We have incredibly young populations, a great human resource to work with.  We have throughout the region economies that represent 60 percent of world GDP, and that have been the fastest growing before the COVID crisis.  We’re going to emerge and bounce back better from that.</p>
<p>But a big part of this, I think, is for all of us to uphold some of the basic principles that are critical to peace and security and stability, and that’s what we’re committed to doing, as well.  We’ve talked about that with the Quad, and we talked about that today as well, with our colleagues and partners here.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  There was more for Secretary Blinken.  (Inaudible) the first one.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Oh, I’m sorry.  Would you – I apologize.  Can you repeat the – is there a second part of the question?</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Yes, climate change and natural disaster relief being the top priorities of the Pacific.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So yes, I think we spent a lot of time talking about climate change, about what we’re doing together to meet that, both in terms of the meeting that we had, but also in the meeting with all of our Pacific Island partners.  There are a number of common themes that jumped out, but that was certainly at the very, very top of the list.  So let just say this.</p>
<p>First, as you’ve seen over the last year, President Biden, the United States, is committed to leading this effort around the world to deal with climate change, to make sure that we meet the existential challenge of our time.  We’ve raised our own ambitions as one of the leading emitters in the world, and historically the largest emitter.  It is our responsibility to do that.  We’re encouraging and working with other countries to do the same.</p>
<p>We’re making it very clear that, for all of the objectives that we set for 2045 or 2050, if we don’t take these steps now over the next years, over the next decade, we’re not going to get there, we’re not going to be able to meet the goal that we set of keeping warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius.  So the United States remains committed to leading, to working with others on that.</p>
<p>But at the same time we also have a responsibility to help – countries adapt, to build resilience, to make sure that they have the resources, that they have access to the financing and the technology to strengthen themselves, to be able to both resist the immediate impacts of climate change, and to adjust and adapt their economies, their systems, going forward.  So we’ve done a lot of work about – on that.  We talked about that today at some length.  The President announced a commitment to work with our Congress to provide $3 billion every year by 2024 for what we call the Prepare Program.  And through Prepare we’re going to help more than 500 million people adapt and manage the impacts of climate change by 2030.</p>
<p>One aspect of this – this is something we talked about today – is strengthening access to finance, which we know is one of the top priorities.  We’ve heard that repeatedly from colleagues today.  USAID is working to help countries obtain direct accreditation to apply for and manage multilateral climate finance.  To date, we’ve helped mobilize more than $220 million in projects here in the Pacific.</p>
<p>So we have a comprehensive approach to this.  We have a commitment to this.  We have a responsibility to this.  And what I want to just conclude with is that I think we’ve seen Fiji set the example, the first country to ratify Paris, but also signing onto, giving its voice to, the major initiatives that are necessary if we are going to really address this crisis.  For example, the Global Methane Pledge.  Fiji’s not a large emitter, but the fact that it’s added its voice to this pledge I think is going to inspire other countries to take the pledge and make a very big contribution to curbing global warming.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Our question goes to Humeyra Pamuk of Reuters.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  I have a couple of questions.  They’re very quick, but please bear with me.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Will the United States be evacuating its embassy in Kyiv?  Regarding your call with Foreign Minister Lavrov, what can the West possibly offer Putin so that he can walk away from this crisis saving face?</p>
<p>Yesterday you said an invasion of Ukraine by Russia during the Olympics is now possible, so does the United States believe that Putin has gotten some sort of a blessing from China during his meeting with Xi at the Olympics last week?</p>
<p>And finally, to both of you on the Indo-Pacific, it seems U.S. only tries to grow its presence in the region when it perceives security threats – Japan during World War II and now China.  How does the U.S. maintain authentic engagement that speaks to the real needs of the islanders?  How can U.S. help them with climate change, for example, and also in balancing China’s presence here?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, I’ll see if I can – I’ll start.  Let’s see if I can remember the excellent multipart question.</p>
<p>First with regard to our embassy, as I noted I think last night when we last spoke, we’ve been continuing to focus on our embassy, and I think this is something we’re focused on as we speak.  I’ll have more to say about that.  We’ll have more to say about that in the coming hours.</p>
<p>With regard to my conversation with Foreign Minister Lavrov a short time from now, and where Russia goes from here, we have been as clear as we possibly can be throughout this crisis – a crisis, again, created by Russia’s actions in massing forces along Ukraine’s borders – that there are two paths forward, and it is ultimately up to President Putin to decide which path to follow.  One is diplomacy and dialogue to try to resolve the differences through dialogue, through diplomacy.</p>
<p>We’ve been very focused on, in close coordination with all of our partners and allies, making clear that we’re prepared – we’re prepared to do that.  We shared ideas with Russia that address some of its concerns that raised the many concerns that we have about actions that Russia has taken to undermine security, and that looks at possible ways forward that on a reciprocal basis could actually strengthen collective security.</p>
<p>Russia said that it would respond to some of the ideas we put forward.  We still have not seen that response.  I’ll be asking Minister Lavrov if we can anticipate seeing a response in the coming days to see to see if we can carry the dialogue forward.</p>
<p>But as we’ve done that we’ve been equally clear that if Russia chooses the path of aggression it will face massive consequences, which we have outlined repeatedly, and again, not just from us, but from allies and partners around the world.  And we’re, as I noted, in very close coordination and collaboration with them.</p>
<p>So President Putin will have to decide which path to follow.  We are prepared either way.  It’s clear what the responsible path is.  But as I said, we’re prepared either way.</p>
<p>I don’t know what was said between China and Russia when the meeting took place between President Xi and President Putin.  But as I noted the other day, we hear very often from Beijing the primacy it places on the sovereignty of nations.  It says that’s the most important element in the international system.  You would think, given that, that it would have expressed concerns to Russia about its threatened violation, renewed violation, of Ukraine’s sovereignty.  But you’ll have to ask President Xi if he shared that with President Putin.</p>
<p>President Putin, as I said earlier, has put in place the capacity to act very quickly if he so chooses.  We are very focused on that, and I continue to hope that he will not choose the path of renewed aggression, that he’ll choose the path of diplomacy and dialogue.  But if he doesn’t, we’re prepared.</p>
<p><b>ACTING PRIME MINISTER SAYED-KHAIYUM:  </b>I cannot comment about Ukraine.  (Laughter.)<b></b></p>
<p>But most certainly we welcome the U.S. coming back into the Paris Agreement fold, and for us that’s critically important.  I think that Secretary Blinken’s presence here signifies that.  And for us, climate finance, for example – we talked about finance equates to development finance – and the ability to get some of the larger countries to be able to participate in the Paris Agreement, and their willingness to listen, understand, and indeed engage with Pacific Island countries is most welcome, as we welcome any other country that is very much in the same space as us in respect of addressing issues pertaining to climate change.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And just to come back to the – I apologize, I had forgotten the last part of the multipart question.  This is not at all a case of us being here, coming here, being focused here for security reasons.  It’s much more fundamental than that.  When we are looking at this region that we share, we see it as the region from the future, vital to our own – our own prosperity, vital to our own progress.  Sixty percent of global GDP is here.  Fifty percent of the world’s population is here.  And for all the challenges that we have at the moment that we’re working on together, it’s also a source of tremendous opportunity.  And that’s what the strategy that we put out is all about.</p>
<p>It is about, as I said, building a free and open Indo-Pacific, defending it with democratic institutions, with transparency, with commitment to a rules-based order that we share.  It’s about connecting our countries together, deepening and stitching together different partnerships and alliances.  It’s about building shared prosperity, new approaches to economic integration, some of which we talked about today, with high standards.  Yes, it is about security, and we’ve been – we’re working through the strategy to deepen integrated deterrence across the region, the inter-interoperability of our forces.</p>
<p>And ultimately, it’s also about resilience – coming together to end COVID, coming together to deal with the climate crisis, coming together to build back better from the economic crisis that has resulted from COVID.  So this is a strategy for the long term because we see our long-term future in the Indo-Pacific.  It’s as simple and basic as that.  Thank you.&lt;/span<br />
<b>MODERATOR:</b>  Ladies and gentlemen, we’ve come to the end of the press conference this evening.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Denarau Island, Fiji</p>
<p>Sofitel Fiji Resort</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>The Acting Prime Minister of Fiji, the U.S. Secretary of State, and members of the media, <i>bula vinaka</i> to you all.  A special welcome to the Secretary of State Blinken and members of his delegation and the accompanying media, too.  I welcome you to our joint press conference, ladies and gentlemen.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, I now invite the Acting Prime Minister of Fiji, the Honorable Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum, to deliver his address.  You have the floor, sir.</p>
<p><b>ACTING PRIME MINISTER SAYED-KHAIYUM:  </b>Thank you.  <i>Bula vinaka</i> and good evening, ladies and gentlemen.  I wish to welcome Secretary Blinken and his delegation and the American media to Fiji in particular.</p>
<p>We are at the crossroads of a 40 million square kilometer patch of the Pacific Ocean that is governed by the Pacific Islands and our neighbors, Australia and New Zealand.  Most of world maps cut our region right down the middle.  So you may not know by looking, but we are the largest ocean continent in the world.</p>
<p>That big, blue responsibility is linked to the well-being of every person on Earth.  Despite that, Fiji and our small-state neighbors have felt at times, to borrow an American term, like a flyover country.  Small dots spotted from plane windows of leaders en route to meetings where they spoke about us, rather than with us, if they spoke of us at all.</p>
<p>When the USA signaled its intent to leave the Paris Agreement, we felt forgotten by a superpower.  So of course, we welcome President Biden’s promise to the world that America was back.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, your being here shows that promise was more than words.  We have just held the most historic and comprehensive meeting ever between Fiji and the USA and a wider meeting with our fellow Pacific leaders.  We believe that both mark the start of more direct partnership between Fiji and the USA, and a new era for America in the blue frontier of the Pacific.</p>
<p>The last significant American presence we felt in Fiji were soldiers we welcomed here during the Second World War.  We face a new war today, a climate war that is devastating our people unlike any conflict before it.  There is no region of the world, not in the Pacific, not in Europe, not in the Americas, that will be spared its consequences.</p>
<p>Fourteen cyclones have struck Fiji since we signed the Paris Agreement, each storm driving home the urgency of adapting and curbing global emissions.  This week, Ba Town, an hour’s drive away from here, was flooded for the third time in three months.  Six communities in Fiji have been moved to escape the rising seas with 14 others in the queue, not to mention the diminishing reefs and the erratic weather patterns that threaten our people’s livelihoods and ways of life.</p>
<p>We, of course, aren’t alone:  The Pacific Islands are sinking; Texas is freezing; California is burning; and New York is flooding.  When a superstorm misses Fiji, American Samoa is in the crosshairs.  And Hawaii, Guam, and FSM know many of Fiji’s struggles because they also live them.</p>
<p>Fiji and America are both working to support a more secure, stable Indo-Pacific region, and indeed a peaceful region.  There is far more we need to do together as partners in this battle of our lives.  As a nation that shares many of our struggles and our values, America is uniquely positioned to be a direct partner to Fiji for peace and climate security not only across the Indo-Pacific but here in the blue Pacific.</p>
<p>And not only because America is a large emitter that it must cut its carbon emissions, but because it is an innovator that can create climate solutions.  We need American might and its mind as well as pioneering solutions and investments here on the shores of this blue frontier.</p>
<p>Our discussions, ladies and gentlemen, covered our commitment to upholding the rule of law in our region, including the Law of Sea.  As we move to sustainably manage and protect our ocean, we sought to jointly up our game through our navies, militaries, and our Fiji police force through maritime surveillance cooperation to end illegal fishing, combat transnational crime, and ensure that this is an ocean dedicated to exploration and discovery, not exploitation and destruction.</p>
<p>In this respect, we also discussed the opportunities for greater participation from the USA in the Australian-funded Blackrock facility in Fiji to coordinate joint responses to the catastrophic events not just in Fiji but in the wider Pacific.</p>
<p>During our meeting we welcomed America’s net zero commitment as well as Mr. Blinken’s recent pledge to decarbonize operations within the State Department.</p>
<p>Fijians believe in leading by example as well, which is why, despite our emissions being negligible, we have committed to achieving net zero by 2050.  Mitigation and adaptation both require access to technology we do not have, and which major market powers like the USA can help us deploy, including (inaudible).  And that means jobs for Fijians, jobs in cutting-edge technology and from nature, that both can build the future.</p>
<p>We also spoke on Fiji’s role in leading a regional recovery from the pandemic.  With the support of the USA and our development partners, over 90 percent of Fijians over the age of 15 are fully vaccinated, which allowed us to welcome American visitors from the 1st of December last year, and we hope to welcome many more, including your families and the many Americans watching us today.</p>
<p>We are also keen to open more of the U.S. export market to our farmers.  We would love to export more of our kava (inaudible), as well as ginger, carob, turmeric, sugar, Fijian chocolates, cosmetics, and other Fijian-grown and Fijian-made products to the U.S.</p>
<p>We also welcome U.S. firms looking to participate in our growing outsourcing services sector.  We have young, well-spoken, English-speaking, tech-savvy and, frankly, very friendly people who would love the opportunity.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, this visit reaffirms that the ocean and islands that fall under our region’s responsibility are too vital for our people and for our planet for any leader to fly over or overlook.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, your visit to Fiji is the first in almost 40 years.  But today has not been about the last 40, 4 decades or 40 years.  It is about the many more to come, decades that our nations will meet together as enduring partners with shared values enlisted with humanity in overcoming the greatest challenges of our time.</p>
<p>It is now my privilege, ladies and gentlemen, to invite our friend, Secretary Blinken, to make his remarks.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, look, I am tempted to close my book, because it’s very hard to top the eloquence of the Acting Prime Minister.  I think he captured powerfully the afternoon that we’ve spent together but also the perspective that we share on the future, the future of the United States and Fiji, the future of the United States and all of our friends and partners in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>And I want to thank you not only for the incredible graciousness of your hospitality today, but also for your leadership of the, I think, truly extraordinary session that we had with friends and partners from throughout the region.  It was incredibly valuable to me, to our team, and I really thank you very much for that.</p>
<p>It’s a pleasure to be here, and not only to be, as it turns out, the first secretary of state to visit Fiji in 36 years, going back to Secretary Shultz.  And I really want to thank the people of Fiji for welcoming us today.</p>
<p>I’m going to spend a little bit of time, if I can, this evening covering the important ground that we walked on today as we look to the future.  Before I do that, I want to say a few words about something that is going on half a world away from here but that is profoundly relevant to this region, and that is the situation in and around Ukraine.</p>
<p>We continue to see very troubling signs of Russian escalation, including new forces arriving around Ukraine’s borders.  As I said yesterday, we are in the window when a Russian invasion could start at any time if President Putin so decides.  That includes in the coming days.  We don’t know whether President Putin has made that decision, but we do know that he has put in place the capacity to act on very short notice.</p>
<p>Throughout the trip that we’ve been on, I’ve been in very close coordination with the national security team back in Washington, including multiple discussions with President Biden on our plans and preparations and, of course, with our chargé in Kyiv.  I have also engaged with counterparts around the world on our ongoing diplomatic efforts.  In recent days I’ve spoken to the French Foreign Minister Le Drian, NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg, our Quad allies and partners, of course:  Australia, India, Japan.  I spoke earlier today with my Ukrainian counterpart, Foreign Minister Kuleba, and I’ll speak this evening with Foreign Secretary Truss of the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>We have a remarkable level of unity and common purpose.  We and our allies have made this crystal clear to Moscow.  If President Putin decides to take military action, we will swiftly impose severe economic sanctions in coordination with allies and partners around the world, we’ll bolster Ukraine’s ability to defend itself, we will reinforce our allies on the eastern flank of NATO.</p>
<p>I’ll underscore this unity and resolve when I speak with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov a little bit later this evening.  I’ll also make clear, as I have consistently, that if Russia is genuinely interested in resolving this crisis of its own making through diplomacy and dialogue, we are prepared to do that.  In fact, that’s our preferred path.  It’s the right and responsible thing to do.  But it must take place in the context of de-escalation.  So far, we have only seen escalation from Moscow.</p>
<p>This is a pivotal moment.  We are prepared for whatever should happen.</p>
<p>As I’ve said throughout this trip, our return to the Indo-Pacific now, even as we continue to work relentlessly to resolve the crisis in Ukraine, is, in itself, a demonstration of our commitment to staying focused on this region.  And that includes the Pacific Islands.</p>
<p>When Secretary Shultz was here in 1985, he praised Fiji for being a diverse democracy and, as he put it – and I quote – “a member of the international community that’s done your share and more as a peacekeeper in a troubled world.”  And he expressed hope that the ties of friendship and cooperation between Fiji and the United States would grow closer and stronger in the years ahead.</p>
<p>Today Fiji is again a democracy, which is a credit to the perseverance and determination of its people.  Fiji has been a proud contributor to peacekeeping operations around the world for 43 years and counting.  Just in the past few months you have sent help to Tonga after the eruption and tsunami, and to the Solomon Islands to help bring an end to recent violence.  And just as Secretary Shultz hoped, the ties between our countries, between Fiji and the United States, have grown stronger and closer, including on security, on health, climate, trade and investment, promoting regional and global cooperation.  That partnership serves not only our countries but many others, because Fiji and all the Pacific Island nations are a vital part of the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>A few months ago, when I was in Indonesia, I had a chance to preview my country’s approach to this vast and vital part of the world.  I laid out the five core elements of our engagement:  first, advancing a free and open Indo-Pacific; second, forging stronger connections within and beyond the region; third, promoting broad-based prosperity; fourth, helping build resilience; and fifth, bolstering security.</p>
<p>Today the United States is releasing our Indo-Pacific Strategy in full.  It’s the result of a year of intensive engagement and consultation with allies and partners across the region and beyond, and hearing directly from its people about what’s most important to them.  And it reflects the fundamental truth that no region on Earth will affect the lives and livelihoods of Americans more than the Indo-Pacific, which accounts for 60 percent of the global economy, two-thirds of all economic growth over the last five years.</p>
<p>Every defining issue of the 21st century runs through this region:  the climate crisis, global health, the future of technology, whether nations will be free to chart their own path or be subject to coercion by more powerful nations.  Our strategy is built on collaboration.  We want to develop sustained, innovative, mutually reinforcing partnerships across the Indo-Pacific with our allies, our partners; with regional institutions like ASEAN, APEC, which the United States will host next year; the Pacific Islands Forum, which Fiji is chairing this year.</p>
<p>The Acting Prime Minister and I just came from a meeting of the Pacific Islands Forum where I reinforced my country’s commitment to the region and the PIF’s critical role in driving regional action.  We welcome the decision of the Micronesian States to pause their withdrawal from the PIF to allow for continued discussions.</p>
<p>We’re strengthening our relationships in every corner of the region.  We’re building our longstanding ties in Northeast Asia and Australia and New Zealand, investing more deeply in the Pacific Islands, Southeast Asia, and South Asia.</p>
<p>We’re also forging new connections across continents, between our European and Indo-Pacific partners, as only the United States can do.  The European Union’s first-ever Indo-Pacific strategy aligns with our own.  And the United States is increasingly speaking with one voice with our NATO allies and our G7 partners when it comes to Indo-Pacific matters.</p>
<p>You can see the strength of that commitment to the Indo-Pacific throughout the past year.  Just look at some of the key markers on our calendar, from President Biden being the first U.S. president to address the Pacific Islands Forum to our increasing engagement with the Quad, whose ministers I just met with in Melbourne, to deepening our cooperation on a range of security and defense priorities through AUKUS.</p>
<p>We also intend to open a U.S. embassy in the Solomon Islands, in its capital city, to deepen our cooperation with Pacific Island partners.</p>
<p>And these steps are only the beginning.  We’ll continue to advance our engagement and investments in the Indo-Pacific.  That includes in the Pacific Islands because what happens here matters to the United States.  We share a history.  It was here on these beaches that Americans braved some of the hardest-fought battles of the Second World War.  Our people are closely tied together by a large Pacific Islander diaspora in the United States.</p>
<p>As much as any other place in the world, these islands are ground zero for the devastating impact of climate change.  And I heard that so powerfully and eloquently from our colleagues this afternoon.  It resonates not just as something that we think about but something that actually touches us here, because for so many of our partners here this is truly the existential issue of our times.  And we’re committed to tackling that challenge, to meeting it head on, to doing it together.</p>
<p>And here in the Pacific Islands we see a clear example of why standing up for a free and open Indo-Pacific matters for real people.  Pacific Islanders are proud.  They believe that no matter their size, they alone should be able to choose their path, whether that’s how they manage their natural resources or who they partner with.  We share that belief, and we think the world is a more secure and prosperous place when core international principles like that are respected, whether that’s here in the Pacific, in Ukraine, or anywhere else.</p>
<p>You see the strength of our commitment to the region in our partnership with Fiji.  Together our countries are taking on major issues facing not only us, but countries throughout the region and, indeed, beyond.  On COVID-19, for example, the United States has provided more than 700,000 vaccine doses to Pacific Island countries, including Fiji.  We’re working together to build Fiji’s capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to future health emergencies.</p>
<p>On security, just this week three shipriders from Fiji are joining the crew of the U.S. Coast Guard Cutter <i>Stratton</i> to conduct patrols in support of maritime sovereignty and security.  The United States is proud that several of Fiji’s future leaders are being trained in our military academies.</p>
<p>On climate, Fiji and other Pacific Island nations have been leading voices, powerful voices, calling for the world’s major economies to take strong action to limit warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius.  Fiji was the first country in the world to ratify the Paris Agreement.  In Glasgow the United States announced our goal of mobilizing $150 billion in public and private climate finance by 2030, and we intend for a substantial portion of that money to support climate adaptation in Fiji and throughout the Pacific region.</p>
<p>The thread that runs through all of our engagements with Fiji is that we’re working together in a spirit of partnership, in a spirit of respect, to tackle shared challenges, to build upon shared opportunities, to deliver concrete results for people on issues that actually affect their lives.  And that’s the approach behind our Indo-Pacific strategy, as a whole.  This isn’t about opposing any country.  It’s about the shared future we want to build together for people across this region.  We’re proud to be building that future with Fiji.</p>
<p>So thank you again, Acting Prime Minister.  Thank you to all the people here for such a warm welcome.  I look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, Acting Prime Minister and Secretary Blinken, for your statements this evening.  Given the time constraints and also that Secretary Blinken has got other engagements tonight, I would ask or inform the – our media that there are only two questions that we will have.  I will ask the first question, and Mr. Ned Price will ask the second.</p>
<p>So the first question, I will ask Mr. Nasokia to ask your question.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) Secretary Blinken, you just returned from the Quad meeting, which has (inaudible) a lot on security.  What do you see as Fiji’s role in this strategy?  What is it for us, the people of Fiji?</p>
<p>And in addition to that, as climate change and natural disaster relief being the top priorities of Pacific Island countries including Fiji, did you establish a concrete commitment on such issues from the U.S. during this visit?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m happy to start.  I think what’s most important, whether it is the Quad countries, whether it’s our partnership and relationship with Fiji, whether it’s what we’re doing here with Pacific Island partners and nations – all of which is reflected in our Indo-Pacific strategy – is that we are – we start with a shared commitment to the same values, to democracy, to human rights, to the rule of law, to regional peace and stability.  That is the common denominator that joins the Quad, that joins our relationship.</p>
<p>And together we are committed to a free and open Indo-Pacific in which people can live their lives freely and make their own decisions, in which countries can engage together and choose with whom they work and associate, and in which we together try to build an affirmative vision for the future, and one that actually delivers concrete results for our people, both in meeting the challenges that we’re facing that are very evident to everyone now, starting with COVID, climate, the impact of emerging technologies on all of our lives – as well as finding the opportunity that I think is so powerful in this region.  We have incredibly young populations, a great human resource to work with.  We have throughout the region economies that represent 60 percent of world GDP, and that have been the fastest growing before the COVID crisis.  We’re going to emerge and bounce back better from that.</p>
<p>But a big part of this, I think, is for all of us to uphold some of the basic principles that are critical to peace and security and stability, and that’s what we’re committed to doing, as well.  We’ve talked about that with the Quad, and we talked about that today as well, with our colleagues and partners here.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  There was more for Secretary Blinken.  (Inaudible) the first one.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Oh, I’m sorry.  Would you – I apologize.  Can you repeat the – is there a second part of the question?</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Yes, climate change and natural disaster relief being the top priorities of the Pacific.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So yes, I think we spent a lot of time talking about climate change, about what we’re doing together to meet that, both in terms of the meeting that we had, but also in the meeting with all of our Pacific Island partners.  There are a number of common themes that jumped out, but that was certainly at the very, very top of the list.  So let just say this.</p>
<p>First, as you’ve seen over the last year, President Biden, the United States, is committed to leading this effort around the world to deal with climate change, to make sure that we meet the existential challenge of our time.  We’ve raised our own ambitions as one of the leading emitters in the world, and historically the largest emitter.  It is our responsibility to do that.  We’re encouraging and working with other countries to do the same.</p>
<p>We’re making it very clear that, for all of the objectives that we set for 2045 or 2050, if we don’t take these steps now over the next years, over the next decade, we’re not going to get there, we’re not going to be able to meet the goal that we set of keeping warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius.  So the United States remains committed to leading, to working with others on that.</p>
<p>But at the same time we also have a responsibility to help – countries adapt, to build resilience, to make sure that they have the resources, that they have access to the financing and the technology to strengthen themselves, to be able to both resist the immediate impacts of climate change, and to adjust and adapt their economies, their systems, going forward.  So we’ve done a lot of work about – on that.  We talked about that today at some length.  The President announced a commitment to work with our Congress to provide $3 billion every year by 2024 for what we call the Prepare Program.  And through Prepare we’re going to help more than 500 million people adapt and manage the impacts of climate change by 2030.</p>
<p>One aspect of this – this is something we talked about today – is strengthening access to finance, which we know is one of the top priorities.  We’ve heard that repeatedly from colleagues today.  USAID is working to help countries obtain direct accreditation to apply for and manage multilateral climate finance.  To date, we’ve helped mobilize more than $220 million in projects here in the Pacific.</p>
<p>So we have a comprehensive approach to this.  We have a commitment to this.  We have a responsibility to this.  And what I want to just conclude with is that I think we’ve seen Fiji set the example, the first country to ratify Paris, but also signing onto, giving its voice to, the major initiatives that are necessary if we are going to really address this crisis.  For example, the Global Methane Pledge.  Fiji’s not a large emitter, but the fact that it’s added its voice to this pledge I think is going to inspire other countries to take the pledge and make a very big contribution to curbing global warming.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Our question goes to Humeyra Pamuk of Reuters.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  I have a couple of questions.  They’re very quick, but please bear with me.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Will the United States be evacuating its embassy in Kyiv?  Regarding your call with Foreign Minister Lavrov, what can the West possibly offer Putin so that he can walk away from this crisis saving face?</p>
<p>Yesterday you said an invasion of Ukraine by Russia during the Olympics is now possible, so does the United States believe that Putin has gotten some sort of a blessing from China during his meeting with Xi at the Olympics last week?</p>
<p>And finally, to both of you on the Indo-Pacific, it seems U.S. only tries to grow its presence in the region when it perceives security threats – Japan during World War II and now China.  How does the U.S. maintain authentic engagement that speaks to the real needs of the islanders?  How can U.S. help them with climate change, for example, and also in balancing China’s presence here?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, I’ll see if I can – I’ll start.  Let’s see if I can remember the excellent multipart question.</p>
<p>First with regard to our embassy, as I noted I think last night when we last spoke, we’ve been continuing to focus on our embassy, and I think this is something we’re focused on as we speak.  I’ll have more to say about that.  We’ll have more to say about that in the coming hours.</p>
<p>With regard to my conversation with Foreign Minister Lavrov a short time from now, and where Russia goes from here, we have been as clear as we possibly can be throughout this crisis – a crisis, again, created by Russia’s actions in massing forces along Ukraine’s borders – that there are two paths forward, and it is ultimately up to President Putin to decide which path to follow.  One is diplomacy and dialogue to try to resolve the differences through dialogue, through diplomacy.</p>
<p>We’ve been very focused on, in close coordination with all of our partners and allies, making clear that we’re prepared – we’re prepared to do that.  We shared ideas with Russia that address some of its concerns that raised the many concerns that we have about actions that Russia has taken to undermine security, and that looks at possible ways forward that on a reciprocal basis could actually strengthen collective security.</p>
<p>Russia said that it would respond to some of the ideas we put forward.  We still have not seen that response.  I’ll be asking Minister Lavrov if we can anticipate seeing a response in the coming days to see to see if we can carry the dialogue forward.</p>
<p>But as we’ve done that we’ve been equally clear that if Russia chooses the path of aggression it will face massive consequences, which we have outlined repeatedly, and again, not just from us, but from allies and partners around the world.  And we’re, as I noted, in very close coordination and collaboration with them.</p>
<p>So President Putin will have to decide which path to follow.  We are prepared either way.  It’s clear what the responsible path is.  But as I said, we’re prepared either way.</p>
<p>I don’t know what was said between China and Russia when the meeting took place between President Xi and President Putin.  But as I noted the other day, we hear very often from Beijing the primacy it places on the sovereignty of nations.  It says that’s the most important element in the international system.  You would think, given that, that it would have expressed concerns to Russia about its threatened violation, renewed violation, of Ukraine’s sovereignty.  But you’ll have to ask President Xi if he shared that with President Putin.</p>
<p>President Putin, as I said earlier, has put in place the capacity to act very quickly if he so chooses.  We are very focused on that, and I continue to hope that he will not choose the path of renewed aggression, that he’ll choose the path of diplomacy and dialogue.  But if he doesn’t, we’re prepared.</p>
<p><b>ACTING PRIME MINISTER SAYED-KHAIYUM:  </b>I cannot comment about Ukraine.  (Laughter.)<b></b></p>
<p>But most certainly we welcome the U.S. coming back into the Paris Agreement fold, and for us that’s critically important.  I think that Secretary Blinken’s presence here signifies that.  And for us, climate finance, for example – we talked about finance equates to development finance – and the ability to get some of the larger countries to be able to participate in the Paris Agreement, and their willingness to listen, understand, and indeed engage with Pacific Island countries is most welcome, as we welcome any other country that is very much in the same space as us in respect of addressing issues pertaining to climate change.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And just to come back to the – I apologize, I had forgotten the last part of the multipart question.  This is not at all a case of us being here, coming here, being focused here for security reasons.  It’s much more fundamental than that.  When we are looking at this region that we share, we see it as the region from the future, vital to our own – our own prosperity, vital to our own progress.  Sixty percent of global GDP is here.  Fifty percent of the world’s population is here.  And for all the challenges that we have at the moment that we’re working on together, it’s also a source of tremendous opportunity.  And that’s what the strategy that we put out is all about.</p>
<p>It is about, as I said, building a free and open Indo-Pacific, defending it with democratic institutions, with transparency, with commitment to a rules-based order that we share.  It’s about connecting our countries together, deepening and stitching together different partnerships and alliances.  It’s about building shared prosperity, new approaches to economic integration, some of which we talked about today, with high standards.  Yes, it is about security, and we’ve been – we’re working through the strategy to deepen integrated deterrence across the region, the inter-interoperability of our forces.</p>
<p>And ultimately, it’s also about resilience – coming together to end COVID, coming together to deal with the climate crisis, coming together to build back better from the economic crisis that has resulted from COVID.  So this is a strategy for the long term because we see our long-term future in the Indo-Pacific.  It’s as simple and basic as that.  Thank you.&lt;/span<br />
<b>MODERATOR:</b>  Ladies and gentlemen, we’ve come to the end of the press conference this evening.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>COVID-19 Global Action Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/covid-19-global-action-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 22:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As we enter the third year of the COVID-19 <wbr />pandemic, the Omicron variant’<wbr />s rapid spread has had far-reaching impacts around the world, and gaps in the global response hinder our efforts to counter this crisis. Ending the acute phase of the COVID-19 pandemic is a top priority for the United States, but we cannot do this alone.</p>
<p>We know the urgency of this fight. We know what needs to be done to stop the pandemic. Now, we have to do it. Enhanced engagement, better donor coordination, and action-oriented leadership are urgent and essential. A global pandemic requires a global action plan, which is why I will convene a virtual COVID-19 Global Action Meeting on February 14.</p>
<p>This pandemic is not just a health crisis. It is a humanitarian, development, and security crisis as well. Health security is national security, and foreign ministers must play a central role in bringing the acute phase of this pandemic to an end and preparing for the future. My counterparts and leaders from regional and international organizations will discuss the leadership roles and actions we will take under the COVID-19 Global Action Plan (GAP), which builds on President Biden’s Global COVID-19 Summit themes of vaccinating the world, saving lives now, and building better health security.  Specifically, we are asking countries to step up with us to: (1) Get Shots in Arms; (2) Bolster Supply Chain Resilience; (3) Address Information Gaps; (4) Support Health Care Workers; (5) Ensure Acute Non-Vaccine Interventions; and (6) <wbr />Strengthen the Global Health Security Architecture. We will <wbr />coordinate responsibility for sectoral, <wbr />regional, and global leadership in each line of effort, building on the momentum generated by the COVID-19 Summit and continuing regular engagement among foreign ministers to address health security.</p>
<p><em>Secretary Blinken’s opening remarks will be streamed on State.gov at 08:30 EST on February 14, 2022.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As we enter the third year of the COVID-19 <wbr />pandemic, the Omicron variant’<wbr />s rapid spread has had far-reaching impacts around the world, and gaps in the global response hinder our efforts to counter this crisis. Ending the acute phase of the COVID-19 pandemic is a top priority for the United States, but we cannot do this alone.</p>
<p>We know the urgency of this fight. We know what needs to be done to stop the pandemic. Now, we have to do it. Enhanced engagement, better donor coordination, and action-oriented leadership are urgent and essential. A global pandemic requires a global action plan, which is why I will convene a virtual COVID-19 Global Action Meeting on February 14.</p>
<p>This pandemic is not just a health crisis. It is a humanitarian, development, and security crisis as well. Health security is national security, and foreign ministers must play a central role in bringing the acute phase of this pandemic to an end and preparing for the future. My counterparts and leaders from regional and international organizations will discuss the leadership roles and actions we will take under the COVID-19 Global Action Plan (GAP), which builds on President Biden’s Global COVID-19 Summit themes of vaccinating the world, saving lives now, and building better health security.  Specifically, we are asking countries to step up with us to: (1) Get Shots in Arms; (2) Bolster Supply Chain Resilience; (3) Address Information Gaps; (4) Support Health Care Workers; (5) Ensure Acute Non-Vaccine Interventions; and (6) <wbr />Strengthen the Global Health Security Architecture. We will <wbr />coordinate responsibility for sectoral, <wbr />regional, and global leadership in each line of effort, building on the momentum generated by the COVID-19 Summit and continuing regular engagement among foreign ministers to address health security.</p>
<p><em>Secretary Blinken’s opening remarks will be streamed on State.gov at 08:30 EST on February 14, 2022.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
