<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:40:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks at a Press Availability with Moroccan Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/remarks-at-a-press-availability-with-moroccan-foreign-minister-nasser-bourita/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Good afternoon. Thank you for being here.</p>
<p>It’s wonderful to be back in Morocco for my first visit as Deputy Secretary of State, and on this day of International Women’s Day, as the Minister said, I am the first woman Deputy Secretary of State. And I trust that Morocco will do it faster than we did, since it took me getting white hair to be the first woman.</p>
<p>I also want to give a shoutout to all the women in Morocco, who are here today and listening, for all that you contribute to your families, to your society, to this great country, and to the men who support you to do so, which I am grateful for in my own case.</p>
<p>I also want to echo the Secretary of State who, earlier today, made a special tribute to the women of Ukraine, so many who have traveled hours after hours to take their children to safety, or who stayed to be able to join the fight. I cannot imagine, as a mother and a grandmother, doing what these women have done. And so, on this International Women’s Day, I want to join the Secretary in paying tribute to them.</p>
<p>I want to begin these formal remarks by thanking Foreign Minister Bourita for his hospitality, and a truly spectacular lunch, and for meeting with me today to convene a new round of the Morocco-U.S. Strategic Dialogue on Regional Political Issues.</p>
<p>The friendship between our countries is the longest unbroken diplomatic relationship in the United States’ history, beginning with the Treaty of Peace and Friendship in 1787.</p>
<p>Morocco and the United States have strong shared interests in promoting regional peace, security, and prosperity, and the Foreign Minister and I had the chance today to discuss a wide range of priorities in our bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>We discussed our ongoing cooperation to combat the COVID-19 pandemic. The United States is proud to support Morocco’s highly successful vaccination campaign. We have donated 1.5 million Pfizer vaccine doses to Morocco to date through COVAX and have also contributed refrigeration units that can store more than 2 million vaccine doses.</p>
<p>The United States applauds King Mohammed VI’s leadership in advancing an ambitious and far- reaching reform agenda. The Foreign Minister and I discussed our shared commitment to gender equality and promoting the rights of women and girls. I’m very glad to be here in Morocco on International Women’s Day, and am looking forward to traveling to Casablanca later today to speak at a conference of Moroccan women entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Finally, we discussed our critical partnership in security and defense. Morocco participates in more than 100 military exercises and events with the United States each year. Planning is well underway for African Lion 2022, our largest annual training exercise in Africa, and we are grateful to Morocco for continuing to host this event.</p>
<p>We discussed Morocco’s leadership in maintaining regional peace and security. The United States welcomes the normalization of relations between the Kingdom of Morocco and Israel, and appreciates the steps the two countries are taking as they work toward upgrading their diplomatic liaison offices to full embassies.</p>
<p>On the Western Sahara, the United States and Morocco both strongly support the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the United Nations’ Secretary General’s Personal Envoy for Western Sahara, and we do so with an open mind to find a resolution that will lead to an enduring and dignified outcome for all parties. We continue to view Morocco’s autonomy plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and a potential approach to satisfy the aspirations of the people of the region.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomes Morocco’s positive role in supporting the UN’s efforts on the political process in Libya and in hosting the inter-Libyan dialogue.</p>
<p>Finally, of course, we discussed the biggest security challenge facing the global community today, and that is President Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>The United States is united with Ukraine, which has done absolutely nothing to threaten Russia. We worked for months with our allies and partners to offer President Putin a diplomatic path to address Russia’s legitimate security concerns in a reciprocal manner.</p>
<p>But President Putin rejected diplomacy and chose instead to launch a massive assault on a sovereign nation. And not only are Ukrainians bearing the consequences of that decision, but the Russian people, with whom we have no fight, are as well.</p>
<p>The United States is coordinating on an ongoing basis with our allies and partners around the world to impose severe costs and consequences on President Putin and his enablers for the unprovoked war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>We call on President Putin to agree to a ceasefire, immediately withdraw his troops from Ukraine, and move the forces he’s built up away from Ukraine’s borders—and, as Morocco has, we call for dialogue to get to peace.</p>
<p>Thank you.<input type="hidden" data-filter="1111110011" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Good afternoon. Thank you for being here.</p>
<p>It’s wonderful to be back in Morocco for my first visit as Deputy Secretary of State, and on this day of International Women’s Day, as the Minister said, I am the first woman Deputy Secretary of State. And I trust that Morocco will do it faster than we did, since it took me getting white hair to be the first woman.</p>
<p>I also want to give a shoutout to all the women in Morocco, who are here today and listening, for all that you contribute to your families, to your society, to this great country, and to the men who support you to do so, which I am grateful for in my own case.</p>
<p>I also want to echo the Secretary of State who, earlier today, made a special tribute to the women of Ukraine, so many who have traveled hours after hours to take their children to safety, or who stayed to be able to join the fight. I cannot imagine, as a mother and a grandmother, doing what these women have done. And so, on this International Women’s Day, I want to join the Secretary in paying tribute to them.</p>
<p>I want to begin these formal remarks by thanking Foreign Minister Bourita for his hospitality, and a truly spectacular lunch, and for meeting with me today to convene a new round of the Morocco-U.S. Strategic Dialogue on Regional Political Issues.</p>
<p>The friendship between our countries is the longest unbroken diplomatic relationship in the United States’ history, beginning with the Treaty of Peace and Friendship in 1787.</p>
<p>Morocco and the United States have strong shared interests in promoting regional peace, security, and prosperity, and the Foreign Minister and I had the chance today to discuss a wide range of priorities in our bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>We discussed our ongoing cooperation to combat the COVID-19 pandemic. The United States is proud to support Morocco’s highly successful vaccination campaign. We have donated 1.5 million Pfizer vaccine doses to Morocco to date through COVAX and have also contributed refrigeration units that can store more than 2 million vaccine doses.</p>
<p>The United States applauds King Mohammed VI’s leadership in advancing an ambitious and far- reaching reform agenda. The Foreign Minister and I discussed our shared commitment to gender equality and promoting the rights of women and girls. I’m very glad to be here in Morocco on International Women’s Day, and am looking forward to traveling to Casablanca later today to speak at a conference of Moroccan women entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Finally, we discussed our critical partnership in security and defense. Morocco participates in more than 100 military exercises and events with the United States each year. Planning is well underway for African Lion 2022, our largest annual training exercise in Africa, and we are grateful to Morocco for continuing to host this event.</p>
<p>We discussed Morocco’s leadership in maintaining regional peace and security. The United States welcomes the normalization of relations between the Kingdom of Morocco and Israel, and appreciates the steps the two countries are taking as they work toward upgrading their diplomatic liaison offices to full embassies.</p>
<p>On the Western Sahara, the United States and Morocco both strongly support the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the United Nations’ Secretary General’s Personal Envoy for Western Sahara, and we do so with an open mind to find a resolution that will lead to an enduring and dignified outcome for all parties. We continue to view Morocco’s autonomy plan as serious, credible, and realistic, and a potential approach to satisfy the aspirations of the people of the region.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomes Morocco’s positive role in supporting the UN’s efforts on the political process in Libya and in hosting the inter-Libyan dialogue.</p>
<p>Finally, of course, we discussed the biggest security challenge facing the global community today, and that is President Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>The United States is united with Ukraine, which has done absolutely nothing to threaten Russia. We worked for months with our allies and partners to offer President Putin a diplomatic path to address Russia’s legitimate security concerns in a reciprocal manner.</p>
<p>But President Putin rejected diplomacy and chose instead to launch a massive assault on a sovereign nation. And not only are Ukrainians bearing the consequences of that decision, but the Russian people, with whom we have no fight, are as well.</p>
<p>The United States is coordinating on an ongoing basis with our allies and partners around the world to impose severe costs and consequences on President Putin and his enablers for the unprovoked war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>We call on President Putin to agree to a ceasefire, immediately withdraw his troops from Ukraine, and move the forces he’s built up away from Ukraine’s borders—and, as Morocco has, we call for dialogue to get to peace.</p>
<p>Thank you.<input type="hidden" data-filter="1111110011" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming the Launch of UN Consultations on Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-the-launch-of-un-consultations-on-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s launch of inclusive consultations by UN Special Envoy for Yemen Hans Grundberg.  Through consultations with a wide range of Yemeni political and civil society groups over the next few weeks, the UN Special Envoy seeks to finalize a new, comprehensive peace process framework. These consultations provide a valuable opportunity for Yemenis to discuss a renewed vision for a political resolution to the conflict.</p>
<p>We call on all Yemeni groups to participate fully, meaningfully, and in good faith in the UN consultations. There is no military solution to the Yemen conflict; the only path forward is through dialogue and compromise. The destruction and suffering caused by over seven years of war is overwhelming. The parties must put the interest of the Yemeni people first and seize this opportunity to help bring this conflict to an end.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s launch of inclusive consultations by UN Special Envoy for Yemen Hans Grundberg.  Through consultations with a wide range of Yemeni political and civil society groups over the next few weeks, the UN Special Envoy seeks to finalize a new, comprehensive peace process framework. These consultations provide a valuable opportunity for Yemenis to discuss a renewed vision for a political resolution to the conflict.</p>
<p>We call on all Yemeni groups to participate fully, meaningfully, and in good faith in the UN consultations. There is no military solution to the Yemen conflict; the only path forward is through dialogue and compromise. The destruction and suffering caused by over seven years of war is overwhelming. The parties must put the interest of the Yemeni people first and seize this opportunity to help bring this conflict to an end.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Designation of Former Nairobi Governor Sonko for Involvement in Significant Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/designation-of-former-nairobi-governor-sonko-for-involvement-in-significant-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is designating former-Nairobi Governor Mike Sonko Gidion Mbuvi Kioko due to his involvement in significant corruption.  While in office, Governor Sonko solicited bribes and kickbacks in exchange for awarding government contracts to his associates.  His actions undermined the rule of law and the public’s faith in Kenya’s democratic institutions and public processes.</p>
<p>This designation is made under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  Under this authority, designated officials of foreign governments involved in significant corruption and their immediate family members are ineligible for entry into the United States.  The Department of State is also announcing the designation of the following members of Sonko’s immediate family: his wife Primrose Mwelu Nyamu Mbuvi; their daughters Saumu Agnes Mbuvi and Salma Wanjiru Mbuvi; and Sonko’s minor child.</p>
<p>These designations reaffirm the commitment of the United States to combatting corruption and supporting the rule of law while strengthening democratic institutions in Kenya. We will continue to use all available tools to promote accountability for corrupt actors in this region and globally.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is designating former-Nairobi Governor Mike Sonko Gidion Mbuvi Kioko due to his involvement in significant corruption.  While in office, Governor Sonko solicited bribes and kickbacks in exchange for awarding government contracts to his associates.  His actions undermined the rule of law and the public’s faith in Kenya’s democratic institutions and public processes.</p>
<p>This designation is made under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  Under this authority, designated officials of foreign governments involved in significant corruption and their immediate family members are ineligible for entry into the United States.  The Department of State is also announcing the designation of the following members of Sonko’s immediate family: his wife Primrose Mwelu Nyamu Mbuvi; their daughters Saumu Agnes Mbuvi and Salma Wanjiru Mbuvi; and Sonko’s minor child.</p>
<p>These designations reaffirm the commitment of the United States to combatting corruption and supporting the rule of law while strengthening democratic institutions in Kenya. We will continue to use all available tools to promote accountability for corrupt actors in this region and globally.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Estonian Prime Minister Kaja Kallas Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-estonian-prime-minister-kaja-kallas-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 11:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Tallinn, Estonia</p>
<p>Stenbock House</p>
<p><b>PRIME MINISTER KALLAS:</b>  Okay.  So welcome.  It is my great, great honor to welcome you to Estonia.  I’ve been a great admirer of all of your work.  I have quoted you many times over these weeks (inaudible).  I think you’ve made very, very important points.</p>
<p>We are here because of the security situation that we need to adapt to, and I really welcome you coming to also visit us and talk to us directly on how we can support Ukraine, but also how we can enhance our defense posture at the eastern flank.  So welcome.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Kaja, thank you.  And it’s really wonderful (inaudible) but I wish it was under different circumstances.  But we have been working so closely together these many months to prepare, if necessary, for the aggression that we saw coming from Russia and Putin.  We hoped for the best in avoiding that aggression, but we prepared for the worst.  And now we’re – we’ve been acting on it.  Acting on it in our support for Ukraine, acting on it in making sure that we exerted maximum pressure on Putin to end the war, prepared for it in terms of making sure that our alliance is strong and prepared to defend every inch of NATO territory if a NATO country is (inaudible).</p>
<p>So we’ve done a lot of work already, but we have a lot more to do to sustain what we’ve already done, and to build on it.  And I’m grateful to be here (inaudible).</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Tallinn, Estonia</p>
<p>Stenbock House</p>
<p><b>PRIME MINISTER KALLAS:</b>  Okay.  So welcome.  It is my great, great honor to welcome you to Estonia.  I’ve been a great admirer of all of your work.  I have quoted you many times over these weeks (inaudible).  I think you’ve made very, very important points.</p>
<p>We are here because of the security situation that we need to adapt to, and I really welcome you coming to also visit us and talk to us directly on how we can support Ukraine, but also how we can enhance our defense posture at the eastern flank.  So welcome.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Kaja, thank you.  And it’s really wonderful (inaudible) but I wish it was under different circumstances.  But we have been working so closely together these many months to prepare, if necessary, for the aggression that we saw coming from Russia and Putin.  We hoped for the best in avoiding that aggression, but we prepared for the worst.  And now we’re – we’ve been acting on it.  Acting on it in our support for Ukraine, acting on it in making sure that we exerted maximum pressure on Putin to end the war, prepared for it in terms of making sure that our alliance is strong and prepared to defend every inch of NATO territory if a NATO country is (inaudible).</p>
<p>So we’ve done a lot of work already, but we have a lot more to do to sustain what we’ve already done, and to build on it.  And I’m grateful to be here (inaudible).</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to offer continued support to the people and government of Ukraine and to condemn Russia’s attacks on Ukrainian cities and mounting civilian deaths.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop Putin’s war of choice.  The Secretary reiterated the United States’ steadfast solidarity with the brave people of Ukraine, as they continue to resist Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked attacks.  <input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to offer continued support to the people and government of Ukraine and to condemn Russia’s attacks on Ukrainian cities and mounting civilian deaths.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop Putin’s war of choice.  The Secretary reiterated the United States’ steadfast solidarity with the brave people of Ukraine, as they continue to resist Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked attacks.  <input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kingdom of Bahrain Signs the Artemis Accords</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/kingdom-of-bahrain-signs-the-artemis-accords/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 21:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Wednesday, March 2, the Kingdom of Bahrain became the 17th nation, and the third nation in the Middle East, to sign the Artemis Accords. After approval from the Cabinet, National Space Science Agency (NSSA) CEO Dr. Mohamed Al Aseeri signed the Accords on behalf of Bahrain, demonstrating his nation’s commitment to the peaceful, safe, and responsible exploration and utilization of outer space.</p>
<p>Vice President Kamala Harris welcomed Bahrain’s affirmation of the principles espoused in the Artemis Accords at a joint news conference with Crown Prince and Prime Minister Salman bin Hamad Al Khalif, following the U.S.-Bahrain Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p>Grounded in the Outer Space Treaty of 1967, the Artemis Accords are a set of nonbinding commitments to important principles for civil space actors, ensuring that activity in outer space remains safe for all space-faring nations and benefits all of humanity. Led by the Department of State and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the Accords play an important role in NASA’s Artemis program which seeks to create a sustainable and robust presence on the Moon while preparing to conduct a historic human mission to Mars – all with significant contributions by international partners.</p>
<p>The other signatories of the Artemis Accords are Australia, Brazil, Canada, Israel, Italy, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Luxembourg, Mexico, New Zealand, Poland, Romania, Ukraine, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</p>
<p>For more information, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Wednesday, March 2, the Kingdom of Bahrain became the 17th nation, and the third nation in the Middle East, to sign the Artemis Accords. After approval from the Cabinet, National Space Science Agency (NSSA) CEO Dr. Mohamed Al Aseeri signed the Accords on behalf of Bahrain, demonstrating his nation’s commitment to the peaceful, safe, and responsible exploration and utilization of outer space.</p>
<p>Vice President Kamala Harris welcomed Bahrain’s affirmation of the principles espoused in the Artemis Accords at a joint news conference with Crown Prince and Prime Minister Salman bin Hamad Al Khalif, following the U.S.-Bahrain Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p>Grounded in the Outer Space Treaty of 1967, the Artemis Accords are a set of nonbinding commitments to important principles for civil space actors, ensuring that activity in outer space remains safe for all space-faring nations and benefits all of humanity. Led by the Department of State and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the Accords play an important role in NASA’s Artemis program which seeks to create a sustainable and robust presence on the Moon while preparing to conduct a historic human mission to Mars – all with significant contributions by international partners.</p>
<p>The other signatories of the Artemis Accords are Australia, Brazil, Canada, Israel, Italy, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Luxembourg, Mexico, New Zealand, Poland, Romania, Ukraine, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</p>
<p>For more information, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Lapid</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-israeli-foreign-minister-and-alternate-prime-minister-lapid-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 20:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Riga, Latvia with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid to exchange views regarding how to stop the premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack by Putin’s military forces on Ukraine and its people as well as the urgent need for Russia to cease its aggression, allow for humanitarian corridors, and fully withdraw from Ukrainian territory.  They also discussed challenges posed by Iran, and both agreed that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  Secretary Blinken reiterated the Administration’s ironclad commitment to Israel’s security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Riga, Latvia with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid to exchange views regarding how to stop the premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack by Putin’s military forces on Ukraine and its people as well as the urgent need for Russia to cease its aggression, allow for humanitarian corridors, and fully withdraw from Ukrainian territory.  They also discussed challenges posed by Iran, and both agreed that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  Secretary Blinken reiterated the Administration’s ironclad commitment to Israel’s security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Terrorist Designation of Katibat al Tawhid wal Jihad</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/terrorist-designation-of-katibat-al-tawhid-wal-jihad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 19:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is committed to addressing terrorist activity in ungoverned spaces in Syria through the judicious use of our counterterrorism tools and constructive engagement with our partners.</p>
<p>In keeping with that commitment, the Department of State is designating Katibat al Tawhid wal Jihad (KTJ) as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) pursuant to Executive Order 13224, as amended. In addition to this SDGT designation, KTJ has also been added to the UNSC 1267/1989/2253/2610 ISIL (Da’esh) and Al-Qaida Sanctions List, requiring all UN member states to implement an assets freeze, a travel ban, and an arms embargo against KTJ.</p>
<p>Affiliated with al-Qa’ida, KTJ operates primarily in Idlib Province, Syria alongside Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham and cooperates with other designated terrorist groups such as Katibat al-Imam al-Bukhari and Islamic Jihad Group. In addition to engaging in terrorist activities in Syria, KTJ has also been responsible for conducting external attacks, such as the Saint Petersburg metro attack in April 2017 which killed 14 passengers and injured 50 others, as well as a suicide car bombing of the Chinese Embassy in Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan in August 2016 which wounded three people.</p>
<p>As a result of the SDGT designation, all property and interests in property of KTJ that are subject to U.S. jurisdiction are blocked, and U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in any transactions with it. Foreign financial institutions that knowingly conduct or facilitate any significant transaction on behalf of KTJ could also be subject to U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>Designations of terrorist individuals and groups expose and isolate them and deny them access to the resources they need to carry out attacks. Moreover, designations can assist the law enforcement actions of other U.S. agencies and governments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is committed to addressing terrorist activity in ungoverned spaces in Syria through the judicious use of our counterterrorism tools and constructive engagement with our partners.</p>
<p>In keeping with that commitment, the Department of State is designating Katibat al Tawhid wal Jihad (KTJ) as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) pursuant to Executive Order 13224, as amended. In addition to this SDGT designation, KTJ has also been added to the UNSC 1267/1989/2253/2610 ISIL (Da’esh) and Al-Qaida Sanctions List, requiring all UN member states to implement an assets freeze, a travel ban, and an arms embargo against KTJ.</p>
<p>Affiliated with al-Qa’ida, KTJ operates primarily in Idlib Province, Syria alongside Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham and cooperates with other designated terrorist groups such as Katibat al-Imam al-Bukhari and Islamic Jihad Group. In addition to engaging in terrorist activities in Syria, KTJ has also been responsible for conducting external attacks, such as the Saint Petersburg metro attack in April 2017 which killed 14 passengers and injured 50 others, as well as a suicide car bombing of the Chinese Embassy in Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan in August 2016 which wounded three people.</p>
<p>As a result of the SDGT designation, all property and interests in property of KTJ that are subject to U.S. jurisdiction are blocked, and U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in any transactions with it. Foreign financial institutions that knowingly conduct or facilitate any significant transaction on behalf of KTJ could also be subject to U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>Designations of terrorist individuals and groups expose and isolate them and deny them access to the resources they need to carry out attacks. Moreover, designations can assist the law enforcement actions of other U.S. agencies and governments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-israeli-foreign-minister-yair-lapid-before-their-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Yair Lapid, Israeli Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 19:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Yair Lapid, Israeli Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Riga, Latvia</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:</b>  Okay, I’ll go first.  So I came here to meet with a friend and a partner in a moment in which world order is changing.  The war that is going on in the Ukraine – in Ukraine and the nuclear talks in Vienna are events that are changing the world as we know it.</p>
<p>And I want to thank the administration to you, my friend, for the leadership you have demonstrated in these days.  There is no real alternative to American leadership determined to prevent wars and bloodshed.</p>
<p>Israel is totally committed to do everything possible to stop the war in Ukraine.  We have condemned the Russian invasion, and we still do.  And Israel is a partner in the global effort to make sure and verify that this war must be stopped.</p>
<p>The way to stop a war is to negotiate.  Israel is speaking with both sides, both with Russia and Ukraine, and we are working in full coordination with our greatest ally, the United States, and with our European partners.  And we will also discuss the status of the nuclear talks in Vienna.  It’s no secret we have our differences on this, but it’s a conversation between allies that have a common goal, which is preventing Iran from becoming a nuclear threshold country, and to stop Iran’s ability to spread terror and instability around the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thank you, Yair.  It’s great to see you anywhere – in Israel, in the United States, anywhere in between – and we’ve met on a few occasions in different places.  And very much appreciate all of your engagement in the effort to stop this Russian aggression in Ukraine, a war that has already done tremendous damage to Ukraine, to its people, that continues as we speak with more than a million and a half people having fled the country because of the Russian war of choice, and so many more who are in danger at this moment.  People killed, people injured.</p>
<p>So it’s imperative that this war come to an end, and Russia has to end it because it started it with no provocation, unwarranted, and – but also premeditated.  So we very much appreciate the efforts that any of our close partners and friends and allies can make to see if there is any opening to end the war, consistent, of course, with the principles that we’ve all established, starting with the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people, who must have their sovereignty, their independence, and their territorial integrity.</p>
<p>So I look forward to hearing your ideas, hearing about some of the engagements that Israel has had, but we appreciate all efforts by friends and allies to look for a diplomatic resolution.  That’s clearly – that’s always been preferable, from the start.  Unfortunately, Russia chose not to pursue the path of diplomacy.  It chose aggression, and now we have to all contend with that.</p>
<p>And I also look forward to speaking to you about, in the time we have, some of the other issues and challenges that we’re facing together.  And we’re united and committed to the proposition that Iran must never obtain a nuclear weapon, and I look forward to bringing you up to date on the latest on where we are on the talks with the Europeans, the Iranians, Russia, and China on the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So it’s great to see you, and thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Yair Lapid, Israeli Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Riga, Latvia</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:</b>  Okay, I’ll go first.  So I came here to meet with a friend and a partner in a moment in which world order is changing.  The war that is going on in the Ukraine – in Ukraine and the nuclear talks in Vienna are events that are changing the world as we know it.</p>
<p>And I want to thank the administration to you, my friend, for the leadership you have demonstrated in these days.  There is no real alternative to American leadership determined to prevent wars and bloodshed.</p>
<p>Israel is totally committed to do everything possible to stop the war in Ukraine.  We have condemned the Russian invasion, and we still do.  And Israel is a partner in the global effort to make sure and verify that this war must be stopped.</p>
<p>The way to stop a war is to negotiate.  Israel is speaking with both sides, both with Russia and Ukraine, and we are working in full coordination with our greatest ally, the United States, and with our European partners.  And we will also discuss the status of the nuclear talks in Vienna.  It’s no secret we have our differences on this, but it’s a conversation between allies that have a common goal, which is preventing Iran from becoming a nuclear threshold country, and to stop Iran’s ability to spread terror and instability around the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thank you, Yair.  It’s great to see you anywhere – in Israel, in the United States, anywhere in between – and we’ve met on a few occasions in different places.  And very much appreciate all of your engagement in the effort to stop this Russian aggression in Ukraine, a war that has already done tremendous damage to Ukraine, to its people, that continues as we speak with more than a million and a half people having fled the country because of the Russian war of choice, and so many more who are in danger at this moment.  People killed, people injured.</p>
<p>So it’s imperative that this war come to an end, and Russia has to end it because it started it with no provocation, unwarranted, and – but also premeditated.  So we very much appreciate the efforts that any of our close partners and friends and allies can make to see if there is any opening to end the war, consistent, of course, with the principles that we’ve all established, starting with the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people, who must have their sovereignty, their independence, and their territorial integrity.</p>
<p>So I look forward to hearing your ideas, hearing about some of the engagements that Israel has had, but we appreciate all efforts by friends and allies to look for a diplomatic resolution.  That’s clearly – that’s always been preferable, from the start.  Unfortunately, Russia chose not to pursue the path of diplomacy.  It chose aggression, and now we have to all contend with that.</p>
<p>And I also look forward to speaking to you about, in the time we have, some of the other issues and challenges that we’re facing together.  And we’re united and committed to the proposition that Iran must never obtain a nuclear weapon, and I look forward to bringing you up to date on the latest on where we are on the talks with the Europeans, the Iranians, Russia, and China on the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So it’s great to see you, and thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Strategic Dialogue between the United States and Austria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-strategic-dialogue-between-the-united-states-and-austria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Austria on the occasion of the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Austria held the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 3, 2022, which included virtual consultations between Austrian Secretary General for Foreign Affairs Peter Launsky-Tieffenthal and U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman.</p>
<p>The United States and Austria, also in its capacity as a member state of the European Union, are dedicated to deepening the Transatlantic relationship and strengthening our commitment to our shared values of advancing democracy and human rights and condemning Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked and premeditated war against Ukraine, including through multilateral action at the United Nations. Both parties expressed firm dedication to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. We acknowledge the European aspirations of Ukraine, welcome its European choice, and support its political association and economic integration with the EU. The United States and Austria support the democratic aspirations of the Belarusian people. We fully support the objective of European integration of the Western Balkan countries.</p>
<p>In the framework of our Strategic Partnership, the United States and Austria emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Austria relationship in addressing Transatlantic issues. The Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. focused on common interests and shared values, reaffirming the dedicated bilateral relationship between the United States and Austria and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, such as establishing a civil society dialogue and fostering educational and people-to-people exchanges.</p>
<p>Topics discussed during the Strategic Dialogue included global and regional security issues, including Russia’s attack on Ukraine; the Western Balkans; energy security, including climate change; economic prosperity; and strengthening democratic values and institutions through the OSCE in Europe and Eurasia and in our own countries. The United States and Austria highlighted their common concern about ongoing disregard for the Helsinki Final Act by Russia and Belarus and consulted on the importance of the OSCE in reaching diplomatic resolutions to regional conflicts. Concerning the ongoing Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) negotiations, both sides reaffirmed the need to come to a swift conclusion. The United States thanked Austria for hosting the JCPOA talks.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue was hosted by the U.S. Department of State and included interagency and inter-ministerial representatives from both governments. The meeting featured senior U.S. representatives from the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Commerce, and from the Austrian side, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the Ministry of Finance.</p>
<p>Both sides expressed a strong interest in continuing and deepening the bilateral strategic partnership. The parties plan to hold the next meeting in Vienna in the first half of 2023.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Austria on the occasion of the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Austria held the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 3, 2022, which included virtual consultations between Austrian Secretary General for Foreign Affairs Peter Launsky-Tieffenthal and U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman.</p>
<p>The United States and Austria, also in its capacity as a member state of the European Union, are dedicated to deepening the Transatlantic relationship and strengthening our commitment to our shared values of advancing democracy and human rights and condemning Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked and premeditated war against Ukraine, including through multilateral action at the United Nations. Both parties expressed firm dedication to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. We acknowledge the European aspirations of Ukraine, welcome its European choice, and support its political association and economic integration with the EU. The United States and Austria support the democratic aspirations of the Belarusian people. We fully support the objective of European integration of the Western Balkan countries.</p>
<p>In the framework of our Strategic Partnership, the United States and Austria emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Austria relationship in addressing Transatlantic issues. The Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. focused on common interests and shared values, reaffirming the dedicated bilateral relationship between the United States and Austria and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, such as establishing a civil society dialogue and fostering educational and people-to-people exchanges.</p>
<p>Topics discussed during the Strategic Dialogue included global and regional security issues, including Russia’s attack on Ukraine; the Western Balkans; energy security, including climate change; economic prosperity; and strengthening democratic values and institutions through the OSCE in Europe and Eurasia and in our own countries. The United States and Austria highlighted their common concern about ongoing disregard for the Helsinki Final Act by Russia and Belarus and consulted on the importance of the OSCE in reaching diplomatic resolutions to regional conflicts. Concerning the ongoing Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) negotiations, both sides reaffirmed the need to come to a swift conclusion. The United States thanked Austria for hosting the JCPOA talks.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue was hosted by the U.S. Department of State and included interagency and inter-ministerial representatives from both governments. The meeting featured senior U.S. representatives from the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Commerce, and from the Austrian side, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the Ministry of Finance.</p>
<p>Both sides expressed a strong interest in continuing and deepening the bilateral strategic partnership. The parties plan to hold the next meeting in Vienna in the first half of 2023.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
